<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<data>
	<table name="WikiRevision">
		<col name="CompanyID" type="Int" default="Zero" />
		<col name="PageID" type="UniqueIdentifier" />
		<col name="Language" type="VarChar(50)" />
		<col name="PageRevisionID" type="Int" />
		<col name="Content" type="NVarChar(MAX)" />
		<col name="ContentHtml" type="NVarChar(MAX)" nullable="true" />
		<col name="PlainText" type="NVarChar(MAX)" />
		<col name="ApprovalByID" type="UniqueIdentifier" nullable="true" />
		<col name="ApprovalDateTime" type="DateTime" nullable="true" />
		<col name="CreatedByID" type="UniqueIdentifier" />
		<col name="CreatedDateTime" type="DateTime" />
		<col name="CompanyMask" type="VarBinary(32)" default="CompanyMaskReadOnly" />
		<col name="UID" type="UniqueIdentifier" />
		<col name="RecordSourceID" type="SmallInt" nullable="true" />
	</table>
	<rows>
		<row PageID="51314298-4111-4892-a2a1-b20f1cdb1d4b" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" Content="&#xA;This guide includes information about the configuration and usage of customer contracts that you create to bill your customers recurrently.&#xA;==In This Guide==[anchor|#_3bb58666-50bd-48ea-94fb-a306db299f3d]&#xA;*[HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__CON_Contract_PriorConf|Preliminary Configuration]&#xA;*[HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__CON_Contract_Preparation|Contract Preparation]&#xA;*[HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__con_Contract_Life_Cycle|Contract Life Cycle]&#xA;*[HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__CON_Contract_Signing|Contract Setup and Activation]&#xA;*[HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__CON_Contract_Usage|Contract Usage Recording]&#xA;*[HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__con_Contract_Billing|Contract Billing]&#xA;*[HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__CON_Contract_Upgrade|Changes to Contract Services ]&#xA;*[HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__CON_Contract_Renewal|Contract Renewal]&#xA;*[HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__CON_Contracts_Examples|Contract Examples]&#xA;" PlainText="Contract Management Guide This guide includes information about the configuration and usage of customer contracts that     you create to bill your customers recurrently. In This Guide Preliminary ConfigurationContract PreparationContract Life CycleContract Setup and ActivationContract Usage RecordingContract BillingChanges to Contract Services Contract RenewalContract Examples" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="9ff8e03b-cc43-6d5b-17f4-f49b738a52de" RecordSourceID="22377" />
		<row PageID="99b985c8-89a1-4af0-8bd2-489e9a67f841" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="1d7ae20a-ef69-97fa-73f0-0a411fe1a80f" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
By using Acumatica ERP contracts, you can bill your customers recurrently. You can configure different combinations of terms and services to satisfy your companies needs and those of your customers. {br}

Some contracts may include services that your company provides—such as cable TV service, Internet access, or web account hosting—to customers during a specified period of time. Other contracts may contain service agreements to maintain and repair a product during the warranty period of the manufacturer or after it has expired. Such contracts include a number of cases (often called tickets) that may be solved during the warranty period. A case is used to track efforts, such as work time spent to repair a device and related phone calls and emails, to resolve a particular issue.{br}

To start using contracts, you need to activate the ''Contract Management'' feature on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) form. Contract-related forms appear on the site map after you have activated this feature.{br}

This chapter will help you to configure and use contracts. It describes contract preparation, the contract life cycle, and the most common contract-related tasks.]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Managing Contracts By using  Acumatica ERP contracts, you can bill your customers recurrently. You can configure different         combinations of terms and services to satisfy your companies needs and those of your         customers.  Some contracts may include services that your company provides—such as cable TV service,    Internet access, or web account hosting—to customers during a specified period of time. Other    contracts may contain service agreements to maintain and repair a product during the warranty    period of the manufacturer or after it has expired. Such contracts include a number of cases    (often called tickets) that may be solved during the warranty period. A case is used to track    efforts, such as work time spent to repair a device and related phone calls and emails, to    resolve a particular issue. To start using contracts, you need to activate the  Contract Management  feature on the             ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features (CS100000) form. Contract-related forms appear on the         site map after you have activated this feature. This chapter will help you to configure and use contracts. It describes contract preparation,       the contract life cycle, and the most common contract-related tasks. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="eaefcc43-69bb-4316-bba5-e62cb0c11930" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="65464644-111b-1188-57ca-ec99a3735499" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
Contracts come in various types, depending on the industry and company, but most contain similar elements and are maintained similarly. Acumatica ERP provides capabilities that ease the processes of contract creation and maintenance.{br}

You need to configure the following Acumatica ERP entities before you create a contract:[anchor|#ul_o42_xqm_gn]
*''Contract Template'': A contract template serves as the base for a contract and provides it with the default settings. For each type of contract (such as a service agreement or support plan) your company has with its customers, you can set up a contract template. Then, when you create a contract, you select the appropriate contract template, which causes the default settings to be filled in. A contract template may also provide a list of products and services that you want to sell. These services and products are represented by contract items, which you configure separately. 
*''Customer Account'': The customer account that you select for a contract provides the billing and location details that are specific to the customer. When you create a contract, in addition to specifying the contract template, you specify the customer account, which causes the system to fill in appropriate settings that are specific to the customer. For details on managing customer accounts, see [HelpRoot_Financials\Customer_Mapref|Creating a Customer].
*''Discount'': If you want to give the customer a discount for services provided recurrently through the contract, you should configure a discount code, which determines the discount rate, the application rules, and the non-stock items it is applied to. You can later specify this discount code when you create a contract. For details on configuring discounts, see [HelpRoot_PricesAndDiscounts\PriceDiscount_CustomerDiscounts_GeneralInfo|Customer Discounts: General Information].

This section will help you to configure contract templates and contract items.
==Related Articles==
*[HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__CON_Contract_Templates|Contract Templates]
*[HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__CON_Contract_Items|Contract Items]]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Preliminary Configuration Contracts come in various types, depending on the industry and company, but most contain     similar elements and are maintained similarly.  Acumatica ERP     provides capabilities that ease the processes of contract creation and maintenance. You need to configure the following  Acumatica ERP     entities before you create a contract: Contract Template : A contract template serves as the base for a contract and provides      it with the default settings. For each type of contract (such as a service agreement or support      plan) your company has with its customers, you can set up a contract template. Then, when you      create a contract, you select the appropriate contract template, which causes the default      settings to be filled in. A contract template may also provide a list of products and services      that you want to sell. These services and products are represented by contract items, which you      configure separately.  Customer Account : The customer account that you select for a contract provides the      billing and location details that are specific to the customer. When you create a contract, in      addition to specifying the contract template, you specify the customer account, which causes      the system to fill in appropriate settings that are specific to the customer. For details on      managing customer accounts, see  Creating a Customer. Discount : If you want to give the customer a discount for services provided      recurrently through the contract, you should configure a discount code, which determines the      discount rate, the application rules, and the non-stock items it is applied to. You can later      specify this discount code when you create a contract. For details on configuring discounts,      see  Customer Discounts: General Information. This section will help you to configure contract templates and contract items. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="e6b7dfda-d75e-4bc2-abec-f8188a499969" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="71a17ce4-c403-b0c4-e0a5-b827c272696a" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
A contract template, which is required for creating a contract, provides billing, refund, and renewal settings. A template for a particular type of contract can include as many details as are needed for a typical contract of the type. A template might provide all the contract details except for the customer name and location, or it may contain only a few settings in addition to the required ones.{br}

A contract template may or may not contain the list of contract details, which are the services and products that you want to sell. These services and products are represented by contract items, which you configure separately. The list of details is created by adding the contract items to a contract template. When you are creating a contract and you select the contract template it is based on, the list is copied to the contract. You can modify the list of items if the settings of the contract template permit it (that is, if the '''Enable Template Items Override''' check box is selected).{br}

To prepare a contract template, you do the following: [anchor|#ul_p4p_h1d_dn]
*Configure the contract template
*Define the formulas the system uses to generate the invoice and line descriptions
*Configure the contract items that you want to add to the contract template, if any
*Add the contract items to the contract template

==Use of Formulas to Generate Descriptions==
In Acumatica ERP, users can customize the descriptions of invoices and invoice lines for invoices created during contract billing by specifying the formulas that the system uses to generate these descriptions. These formulas can be defined in the '''Invoice Description''' box and '''Line Description''' box on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_20_20_00|Contract Templates] ([~/?ScreenId=CT202000|CT202000]) form. The default formulas in a contract, which are provided by the applicable template, can be overridden on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_10_00|Customer Contracts] ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) form if the '''Enable Overriding Formulas in Contracts''' check box has been selected for the template on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_20_20_00|Contract Templates] form. For more information about the entities and values available when you define the description formula, see [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_20_20_00|Contract Templates].]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Contract Templates A contract template, which is required for creating a contract, provides billing, refund, and     renewal settings. A template for a particular type of contract can include as many details as     are needed for a typical contract of the type. A template might provide all the contract details     except for the customer name and location, or it may contain only a few settings in addition to     the required ones. A contract template may or may not contain the list of contract details, which are the     services and products that you want to sell. These services and products are represented by     contract items, which you configure separately. The list of details is created by adding the     contract items to a contract template. When you are creating a contract and you select the     contract template it is based on, the list is copied to the contract. You can modify the list of     items if the settings of the contract template permit it (that is, if the  Enable      Template Items Override  check box is selected). To prepare a contract template, you do the following:  Configure the contract template Define the formulas the system uses to generate the invoice and line descriptions Configure the contract items that you want to add to the contract template, if any Add the contract items to the contract template Use of Formulas to Generate Descriptions In  Acumatica ERP,     users can customize the descriptions of invoices and invoice lines for invoices created during     contract billing by specifying the formulas that the system uses to generate these descriptions.     These formulas can be defined in the  Invoice Description  box and       Line Description  box on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT202000|CT202000]) Contract Templates     (CT202000) form. The default formulas in a contract, which are provided by the applicable     template, can be overridden on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) Customer Contracts (CT301000) form if the       Enable Overriding Formulas in Contracts  check box has been selected for     the template on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT202000|CT202000]) Contract Templates form. For more information about the     entities and values available when you define the description formula, see   ([~/?ScreenId=CT202000|CT202000]) Contract Templates. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="e9de393f-bc80-470c-8677-44dd1c97fb6d" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="5a03e862-8b19-14d7-e7de-4c0981727c06" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
You use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_20_20_00|Contract Templates] ([~/?ScreenId=CT202000|CT202000]) form to create a contract template.[anchor|#_c481daa3-1ef2-4db4-8229-ca3b2aee4d23]((({S:Hint}To open any form, you can navigate to it or search for it (by its name or by its form ID without periods). For more information about search capabilities, see [HelpRoot_Interface\UIG__con_New_UI_Search|Search].
)))
==Before You Proceed==
Make sure that the contract items you want to include in the contract template have been properly configured. For details, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__HOW_Configure_Contract_Item|To Configure a Contract Item].{br}

If you want to bill customers for the number of cases, you should also configure a designated non-stock item. For details see, [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__HOW_Billing_Per_Number_Cases|To Set Up Billing by the Number of Cases].
==To Configure a Contract Template==[anchor|#ol_tky_ldq_jm]
#Open the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_20_20_00|Contract Templates] ([~/?ScreenId=CT202000|CT202000]) form.
#Click '''Add New Record''' on the form toolbar.
#Optional: Specify the identifier manually in the '''Contract Template''' box.
#:The unique identifier of a contract template is formed in accordance with the ''TMCONTRACT'' segmented key. If the '''Contract Template''' box contains the {{<NEW>}} placeholder, it means that auto-numbering is enabled for the key segment and the identifier is assigned automatically. 
#In the '''Description''' box, type a brief description of this contract template, including any relevant comments.
#In the '''Contract Settings''' section of the '''Summary''' tab, do the following: 
##In the '''Contract Type''' box, select the expiration policy. The following options are available:
##*''Renewable'': Select this option if you are going to renew contracts based on this template. The renewal process changes the expiration date of a contract of this type and generates an invoice for the renewal fee, if there is one. A contract should be renewed during its grace period; otherwise, the renewal process changes the contract status to ''Expired'' and creates a copy of the contract with the ''Draft'' status. 
##*''Expiring'': Select this option if you are not going to renew contracts based on this template. If you run the renewal process for such a contract, the contract status changes to ''Expired'' and a copy of the contract is created with the ''Draft'' status.
##*''Unlimited'': Select this option if you want contracts based on this template to have no expiration date. A contract of this type can be terminated only.
##In the '''Duration''' boxes, type the number of units and select the duration unit to specify the period when a contract based on this template is valid.
##Select the '''Refundable''' check box if you want to refund the setup and renewal fee when a contract based on this template is terminated. The setup fee is refunded if both the contract and the contract item are marked as refundable. If a renewal fee is collected on activation, it is refunded along with the setup fee. If the contract is terminated, recurring charges are refunded in proportion to the unused services.
##If you have selected the '''Refundable''' check box, type the appropriate number of days in the '''Refund Period''' box. If a contract based on this template is terminated during this period, the customer may claim a refund.
##Select the '''Mass Renewal''' check box if you want contracts based on the template to be available for mass processing and displayed on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_50_20_00|Renew Contracts] ([~/?ScreenId=CT502000|CT502000]) form.
##If you have selected the '''Mass Renewal''' check box, type the appropriate number of days in the '''Renewal Point''' box to specify the number of days before the contract expiration date when the contract is displayed on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_50_20_00|Renew Contracts] form.
##In the '''Grace Period''' box, type the number of days after the expiration date when services under the contract are still provided and the contract can be renewed according to its type. When you invoke the '''Renew Contract''' action after the end of the grace period, a copy of the contract with the ''Draft'' status is created, regardless of the contract type.
##In the '''Currency''' box, select the currency to be used for billing the customer. The customer&rsquo;s currency should match the template currency. You can include only contract items priced in the same currency.
##Select the '''Enable Template Item Override''' check box if you want to allow users to modify the list of contract items for each contract based on this template.
##Select the '''Automatically Release AR Documents''' check box if you want Accounts Receivable documents generated during contract billing to be released automatically; otherwise, they will keep the ''Balanced'' status until they are released.
##:((({S:Warn}The '''Undo Last Action''' command on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_10_00|Customer Contracts] ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) form is not available for actions that involve released documents.
)))
##Optional: In the '''Effective From''' and '''Discontinue After''' boxes, specify the period of time when the contract template is available for the creation of contracts based on it.
#In the '''Billing Settings''' area, do the following:
##In the '''Billing Period''' box, select the time period the contract billing schedule should be divided into. The following options are available: ''Week'', ''Month'', ''Quarter'', ''Half a Year'', ''Year'', ''Statement-Based'', and ''On Demand''. With the ''On Demand'' option, billing is not scheduled and you can bill a contract on any date. This option cannot be used with contract items that have recurring pricing configured, except for items that are tied up with a deposit item or have a default quantity of zero.
##In the '''Bill to''' box, select the account that is to be billed for the contract. The following options are available: ''Parent Account'', ''Customer Account'', and ''Specific Account''. 
##In the '''Billing Schedule Starts On''' box, select the starting point of the contract billing schedule. The following options are available: ''Setup Date'' and ''Activation Date''. The contract expiration date is calculated based on this setting. 
##In the '''Billing Format''' box, select the format of invoices for billing contracts based on the template. The following options are available:
##*''Summary'': Contract item usage is summed and shown as one line with the total quantity and total sum. The expense claims are shown individually.
##*''Detail'': Each contract item usage occurrence is shown as a separate line.
##Optional: In the '''Invoice Description''' box, select the needed entities and values to define the specific formula for generating the description of invoices created when a user runs contract billing for contracts based on this contract template. 
##:((({S:Warn}By default, this box contains the following formula: {{Action + Contract CD + Contract Description}}.
)))
##Optional: In the '''Line Description''' box, select the needed entities and values to define the specific formula for generating the description for the lines of invoices created when a user runs contract billing for contracts based on this contract template. 
##:((({S:Warn}By default, this box contains the following formula: {{Prefix + Action + Inventory Item Description}}
)))
##Optional: Select the '''Enable Overriding Formulas in Contracts''' check box to allow the formulas defined in the '''Invoice Description''' and '''Line Description''' boxes of the current form to be overridden on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_10_00|Customer Contracts] form for a particular contract based on this template.
#In the '''Case Count Item''' box, select the non-stock item to be used for counting cases associated with the contract. You can bill a customer for the number of cases accumulated. For details, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__HOW_Billing_Per_Number_Cases|To Set Up Billing by the Number of Cases]. 
#To add contract items to a contract template, on the '''Details''' tab, do the following:
##On the table toolbar, click '''Add Row'''.
##In the '''Item Code''' column, select the contract item you want to offer to customers. The system fills related columns with the appropriate values automatically. You can change the item description and quantity within the allowed limits.
##Repeat the previous substeps for each contract item you want include in the contract template.
#In the Summary area, select the '''Active''' check box to make the template available for creating contracts based on it.
#On the form toolbar, click '''Save'''.

Now you can proceed to contract preparation. ]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[To Configure a Contract Template You use the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT202000|CT202000]) Contract Templates (CT202000) form to create a                 contract template. To open any form, you can navigate to it             or search for it (by its name or by its form ID without periods). For more information             about search capabilities, see  Search. Before You Proceed Make sure that the contract items you want to include in the contract template have                 been properly configured. For details, see  To Configure a Contract Item. If you want to bill customers for the number of cases, you should also configure a                 designated non-stock item. For details see,  To Set Up Billing by the Number of Cases. To Configure a Contract Template Open the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT202000|CT202000]) Contract Templates (CT202000) form. Click  Add New Record  on the form toolbar. Optional: Specify the identifier manually in the  Contract                         Template  box. The unique identifier of a contract template is                         formed in accordance with the  TMCONTRACT  segmented key. If the                              Contract Template  box contains the                              <NEW>  placeholder, it means that auto-numbering is                         enabled for the key segment and the identifier is assigned automatically.                      In the  Description  box, type a brief description of this                     contract template, including any relevant comments. In the  Contract Settings  section of the                          Summary  tab, do the following:  In the  Contract Type  box, select the expiration                             policy. The following options are available: Renewable : Select this option if you are going to renew                                     contracts based on this template. The renewal process changes                                     the expiration date of a contract of this type and generates an                                     invoice for the renewal fee, if there is one. A contract should                                     be renewed during its grace period; otherwise, the renewal                                     process changes the contract status to  Expired  and                                     creates a copy of the contract with the  Draft  status.  Expiring : Select this option if you are not going to                                     renew contracts based on this template. If you run the renewal                                     process for such a contract, the contract status changes to                                          Expired  and a copy of the contract is created with                                     the  Draft  status. Unlimited : Select this option if you want contracts based                                     on this template to have no expiration date. A contract of this                                     type can be terminated only. In the  Duration  boxes, type the number of units                             and select the duration unit to specify the period when a contract based                             on this template is valid. Select the  Refundable  check box if you want to                             refund the setup and renewal fee when a contract based on this template                             is terminated. The setup fee is refunded if both the contract and the                             contract item are marked as refundable. If a renewal fee is collected on                             activation, it is refunded along with the setup fee. If the contract is                             terminated, recurring charges are refunded in proportion to the unused                             services. If you have selected the  Refundable  check box,                             type the appropriate number of days in the  Refund                                 Period  box. If a contract based on this template is                             terminated during this period, the customer may claim a refund. Select the  Mass Renewal  check box if you want                             contracts based on the template to be available for mass processing and                             displayed on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT502000|CT502000]) Renew Contracts (CT502000)                             form. If you have selected the  Mass Renewal  check box,                             type the appropriate number of days in the  Renewal                                 Point  box to specify the number of days before the                             contract expiration date when the contract is displayed on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT502000|CT502000]) Renew Contracts form. In the  Grace Period  box, type the number of days                             after the expiration date when services under the contract are still                             provided and the contract can be renewed according to its type. When you                             invoke the  Renew Contract  action after the end of                             the grace period, a copy of the contract with the  Draft  status is                             created, regardless of the contract type. In the  Currency  box, select the currency to be                             used for billing the customer. The customer's currency should match the                             template currency. You can include only contract items priced in the                             same currency. Select the  Enable Template Item Override  check                             box if you want to allow users to modify the list of contract items for                             each contract based on this template. Select the  Automatically Release AR Documents                              check box if you want Accounts Receivable documents generated during                             contract billing to be released automatically; otherwise, they will keep                             the  Balanced  status until they are released. The                                      Undo Last Action  command on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) Customer Contracts (CT301000) form is not available                                 for actions that involve released documents. Optional: In the  Effective From  and                                  Discontinue After  boxes, specify the period                             of time when the contract template is available for the creation of                             contracts based on it. In the  Billing Settings  area, do the following: In the  Billing Period  box, select the time period                             the contract billing schedule should be divided into. The following                             options are available:  Week ,  Month ,  Quarter ,                                  Half a Year ,  Year ,  Statement-Based , and  On                                 Demand . With the  On Demand  option, billing is not                             scheduled and you can bill a contract on any date. This option cannot be                             used with contract items that have recurring pricing configured, except                             for items that are tied up with a deposit item or have a default                             quantity of zero. In the  Bill to  box, select the account that is to                             be billed for the contract. The following options are available:                                  Parent Account ,  Customer Account , and  Specific                                 Account .  In the  Billing Schedule Starts On  box, select the                             starting point of the contract billing schedule. The following options                             are available:  Setup Date  and  Activation Date . The                             contract expiration date is calculated based on this setting.  In the  Billing Format  box, select the format of                             invoices for billing contracts based on the template. The following                             options are available: Summary : Contract item usage is summed and shown as one                                     line with the total quantity and total sum. The expense claims                                     are shown individually. Detail : Each contract item usage occurrence is shown as a                                     separate line. Optional: In the  Invoice Description  box, select                             the needed entities and values to define the specific formula for                             generating the description of invoices created when a user runs contract                             billing for contracts based on this contract template.  By default,                                 this box contains the following formula:  Action + Contract                                     CD + Contract Description . Optional: In the  Line Description  box, select the                             needed entities and values to define the specific formula for generating                             the description for the lines of invoices created when a user runs                             contract billing for contracts based on this contract template.  By                                 default, this box contains the following formula:  Prefix +                                     Action + Inventory Item Description Optional: Select the  Enable Overriding Formulas in                                 Contracts  check box to allow the formulas defined in the                                  Invoice Description  and  Line                                 Description  boxes of the current form to be overridden                             on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) Customer Contracts form for a particular contract                             based on this template. In the  Case Count Item  box, select the non-stock item to                     be used for counting cases associated with the contract. You can bill a customer                     for the number of cases accumulated. For details, see  To Set Up Billing by the Number of Cases.  To add contract items to a contract template, on the                          Details  tab, do the following: On the table toolbar, click  Add Row . In the  Item Code  column, select the contract item                             you want to offer to customers. The system fills related columns with                             the appropriate values automatically. You can change the item                             description and quantity within the allowed limits. Repeat the previous substeps for each contract item you want include in                             the contract template. In the Summary area, select the  Active  check box to make                     the template available for creating contracts based on it. On the form toolbar, click  Save . Now you can proceed to contract preparation.  ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="c0639f61-13d5-4339-8d60-cb9398938661" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="56777701-42fe-4eb2-a2ab-18b99e7380d7" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
In Acumatica ERP, a contract item defines the services and products, along with price and provision policies, that you want to offer to customers. A service or product provided as part of a contract is defined as a non-stock item. Thus, before you create contract items, you should consider what services and products you will offer to your customers through contracts; you then create non-stock items for each product and service. For each non-stock item, you specify the base price (which is used to calculate the contract item price) and the General Ledger sales account and subaccount used to record item-related transactions. For details on configuring non-stock items, see [HelpRoot_InvMgmt\Entity_OrderMgmt_Non_Stock_Items_GeneralInfo|Creating Non-Stock Items: General Information].((({S:Warn}You cannot use non-stock items that are kits in a contract item.
))){br}

Once you have configured the appropriate non-stock items, you configure the contract items. A contract item has three parts:[anchor|#ul_utk_1nj_4n]
*'''Setup''': You configure this part of a contract item to specify the non-stock item you want to provide during contract setup and define the pricing policy to be used to calculate the setup price. Also, this part of the contract item is used to configure the deposit contract item used in retainer contracts.
*'''Renewal''': When you configure this part of a contract item, you specify the non-stock item you want to provide during contract renewal and define the pricing policy to be used to calculate the renewal price. You can configure the renewal price to be dependent on the setup price. 
*'''Recurring''': When you configure this part of a contract item, you define the policy for the recurring billing, specify the non-stock item you want to provide recurrently, and define the pricing policy to be used to calculate the recurring price. For items that are provided recurrently, you can specify a price for extra usage. When item usage exceeds the included usage, the extra amount can be billed at another price. You can configure both the recurring and extra usage prices to be dependent on the setup price. 
((({S:Warn}All non-stock items included in a contract item should be priced in the same currency.
)))
For a contract item, you can configure all three of the parts listed above, any two parts, or only one part. For example, you might provide a customer with the Acumatica ERP Financial Suite first and then provide support services recurrently. In this case, you would assign the Acumatica ERP Financial Suite to the setup part and support services to the recurring part of the contract item.]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Contract Items In  Acumatica ERP,     a contract item defines the services and products, along with price and provision policies, that     you want to offer to customers. A service or product provided as part of a contract is defined     as a non-stock item. Thus, before you create contract items, you should consider what services     and products you will offer to your customers through contracts; you then create non-stock items     for each product and service. For each non-stock item, you specify the base price (which is used     to calculate the contract item price) and the General Ledger sales account and subaccount used     to record item-related transactions. For details on configuring non-stock items, see  Creating Non-Stock Items: General Information. You cannot use non-stock items that are kits      in a contract item. Once you have configured the appropriate non-stock items, you configure the contract items. A     contract item has three parts: Setup : You configure this part of a contract item to specify the      non-stock item you want to provide during contract setup and define the pricing policy to be      used to calculate the setup price. Also, this part of the contract item is used to configure      the deposit contract item used in retainer contracts. Renewal : When you configure this part of a contract item, you specify      the non-stock item you want to provide during contract renewal and define the pricing policy to      be used to calculate the renewal price. You can configure the renewal price to be dependent on      the setup price.  Recurring : When you configure this part of a contract item, you      define the policy for the recurring billing, specify the non-stock item you want to provide      recurrently, and define the pricing policy to be used to calculate the recurring price. For      items that are provided recurrently, you can specify a price for extra usage. When item usage      exceeds the included usage, the extra amount can be billed at another price. You can configure      both the recurring and extra usage prices to be dependent on the setup price.  All non-stock items included in a contract item should be priced in the same     currency. For a contract item, you can configure all three of the parts listed above, any     two parts, or only one part. For example, you might provide a customer with the  Acumatica ERP     Financial Suite first and then provide support services recurrently. In this case, you would     assign the  Acumatica ERP     Financial Suite to the setup part and support services to the recurring part of the contract     item. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="ebf92222-9b3f-409a-b6ee-2893ba10ceb7" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="e60c2c96-19f2-e319-48f4-08ef84676c90" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
You use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_20_10_00|Contract Items] ([~/?ScreenId=CT201000|CT201000]) form to configure the prices and provisions for services and products. 
==Before You Proceed==
Make sure that non-stock items are properly configured for each service you want to include in a contract item. For details on configuring non-stock items, see [HelpRoot_InvMgmt\Entity_OrderMgmt_Non_Stock_Items_GeneralInfo|Creating Non-Stock Items: General Information].[anchor|#_c62bdade-e9f3-4cfc-b0d3-6a1e4d59333c]((({S:Hint}To open any form, you can navigate to it or search for it (by its name or by its form ID without periods). For more information about search capabilities, see [HelpRoot_Interface\UIG__con_New_UI_Search|Search].
)))
==To Configure a Contract Item==((({S:Warn}The offered instruction is divided into four parts: general settings (required), setup, renewal, and setting up recurring billing. You can refer to the parts that you need to configure the contract item you want to offer and skip other parts.
)))[anchor|#ol_tky_ldq_jm]
#Open the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_20_10_00|Contract Items] ([~/?ScreenId=CT201000|CT201000]) form. 
#Click '''Add New Record''' on the form toolbar.
#Optional: Specify the identifier manually in the '''Contract Item''' box. 
#:The unique identifier of a contract item is formed in accordance with the ''CONTRACTITEM'' segmented key. If the '''Contract Item''' box contains the {{<NEW>}} placeholder, it means that auto-numbering is enabled for the key segment and the identifier is assigned automatically. 
#In the '''Description''' box, type a brief description of the services included.
#In the Summary area of the '''Price Options''' tab, do the following: 
##In the '''Maximum Allowed Quantity''' and '''Minimum Allowed Quantity''' boxes, type the quantity limits for the provided services.
##In the '''Default Quantity''' box, type the service quantity that is included in the contract by default. 
##:This value can be modified in a template or a contract within the allowed limits (which are defined by '''Maximum Allowed Quantity '''and '''Minimum Allowed Quantity'''). If service usage has exceeded the included quantity, the difference is considered extra usage. Allowed quantity limits are not applied to extra usage.
##In the '''Currency ID''' box, select the currency of this contract item. You should use non-stock items priced in one currency within each contract item.
#To set up pricing for a service to be provided as a part of contract setup, on the '''Setup and Renewal''' area, do the following:
##In the '''Setup Item''' box, select the non-stock item you want to provide and bill when contract setup occurs.
##In the '''Setup Pricing''' box, select the pricing policy. The following options are available: 
##*''Use Item Price'': Select this option if you want to use the applicable sales price of the non-stock item. If a sales price is not found, the default price of the non-stock item is used. For details, see [HelpRoot_PricesAndDiscounts\PriceDiscount_Reviewing_Sales_Prices_GeneralInfo|Sales Prices: General Information].
##*''Percent of Item Price'': Select this option if you want the price to be calculated by applying the percent specified in the '''Item Price/Percent''' box to the base price of the non-stock item.
##*''Enter Manually'': Select this option if you want to specify the price manually in the '''Item Price/Percent''' box. Selecting this option also allows users to modify the price later in the contract.
##(Skip this step if you have selected ''Use Item Price'' in the '''Setup Pricing''' box.) In the '''Item Price/Percent''' box, type the item price or percent, depending on the pricing policy you have selected.
##Skip the '''Retain Rate''' and '''Deposit''' elements, which are used only for creating a contract item to serve as a prepayment. For details, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__HOW_Configure_Deposit|To Create a Deposit Contract Item].
##Select the '''Refundable''' check box if you want to allow the amount the customer paid for setup to be refunded in case of contract termination. The setup fee is refunded if both the contract template and this contract item are marked as refundable. If the renewal fee is collected on activation, it is refunded along with the setup fee. Recurring charges are refunded in proportion to unused services in case of termination.
##Select the '''Prorate Setup''' check box if you want to allow the amount the customer paid for setup to be billed in proportion to unused services in case of termination or changes in contract terms.
##Optional: If you have finished specifying settings for the contract item, click '''Save''' on the form toolbar. Otherwise, proceed with the part of instruction you need.
#To set up pricing for a service to be provided when contract renewal occurs, on the '''Setup and Renewal''' area, do the following:
##In the '''Renewal Item''' box, select the non-stock item you want to provide and bill when contract renewal occurs.
##Select the '''Collect Renewal Fee on Activation''' check box if you want to bill the customer for services provided on renewal both at the moment of contract activation and at contract renewal. For a usage example, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__CON_Fixed_Price_Contracts|Fixed-Price Contracts].
##In the '''Renewal Pricing''' box, select the pricing policy. The following options are available: 
##*''Use Item Price'': Select this option if you want to use the applicable sales price of the non-stock item. If a sales price is not found, the default price of the non-stock item is used. For details, see [HelpRoot_PricesAndDiscounts\PriceDiscount_Reviewing_Sales_Prices_GeneralInfo|Sales Prices: General Information].
##*''Percent of Item Price'': Select this option if you want the price to be calculated by applying the percent specified in the '''Item Price/Percent''' box to the price of the non-stock item.
##*''Percent of Setup Price'': Select this option if you want the price to be calculated by applying the percent specified in the '''Item Price/Percent''' box to the setup price of the contract item.
##*''Enter Manually'': Select this option if you want to specify the price manually in the '''Item Price/Percent''' box. Selecting this option also allows you to modify the price later in the contract.
##(Skip this step if you have selected the ''Use Item Price'' option in the '''Renewal Pricing''' box.) In the '''Item Price/Percent''' box, type the item price or percent, depending on the pricing policy you selected.
##Optional: If you have finished specifying settings for the contract item, click '''Save''' on the form toolbar. Otherwise, proceed with the part of the instruction you need.
#To set up pricing for service to be provided recurrently, on the '''Recurring Billing''' area, do the following: 
##In the '''Billing Type''' box select the billing policy. The following options are available:
##*''None'': Select this option if you are not going to bill the customer recurrently, and the elements of the '''Recurring Billing''' area become unavailable.
##*''Prepaid'': Select this option if you want to bill the customer at the beginning of the scheduled billing period. 
##*''Postpaid'': Select this option if the customer is billed at the end of the scheduled billing period.
##In the '''Recurring Item''' box, select the non-stock item that you want to provide and bill recurrently.
##Select the '''Reset Usage on Billing''' check box if you want the contract item usage to be reset after the billing for a previous billing period has been performed. If this check box is selected, the included quantity is set per billing period. If this check box is cleared, the included quantity is set for the whole duration of the contract, so clear the check box only if the billing period is equal to the contract duration.
##In the '''Recurring Pricing''' box, select the pricing policy. The following options are available: 
##*''Use Item Price'': Select this option if you want to use the applicable sales price of the non-stock item. If a sales price is not found, the default price of the non-stock item is used. For details, see [HelpRoot_PricesAndDiscounts\PriceDiscount_Reviewing_Sales_Prices_GeneralInfo|Sales Prices: General Information].
##*''Percent of Item Price'': Select this option if you want the system to calculate the price by applying the percent specified in the '''Item Price/Percent''' box to the price of the non-stock item.
##*''Percent of Setup Price'': Select this option if you want the system to calculate the price by applying the percent specified in the '''Item Price/Percent''' box to the setup price of the contract item.
##*''Enter Manually'': Select this option if you want to specify the price manually in the '''Item Price/Percent''' box. Selecting this option also allows to modify the price later in the contract.
##(Skip this step if you have selected ''Use Item Price'' in the '''Recurring Pricing''' box.) In the '''Item Price/Percent''' box, type the item price or percent, depending on the pricing policy selected.
##In the '''Extra Usage Pricing''' box, select the pricing policy to be applied to the service price if the customer has exceeded the service included quantity. The following options are available:
##*''Use Item Price'': Select this option if you want to use the applicable sales price of the non-stock item. If a sales price is not found, the default price of the non-stock item is used. For details, see [HelpRoot_PricesAndDiscounts\PriceDiscount_Reviewing_Sales_Prices_GeneralInfo|Sales Prices: General Information].
##*''Percent of Item Price'': Select this option if you want the system to calculate the price by applying the percent specified in the '''Item Price/Percent''' box to the price of the non-stock item.
##*''Percent of Setup Price'': Select this option if you want the system to calculate the price by applying the percent specified in the '''Item Price/Percent''' box to the setup price of the contract item.
##*''Enter Manually'': Select this option if you want to specify the price manually in the '''Item Price/Percent''' box. Selecting this option also allows to modify the price later in the contract.
##(Skip this step if you have selected ''Use Item Price'' in the '''Extra Usage Pricing''' box.) In the '''Item Price/Percent''' box, type the item price or percent, depending on the pricing policy selected.
##Optional: In the '''Deposit Item''' box, select the deposit contract item you want to tie to the contract item you are configuring.
##:((({S:Warn}The deposit item is used only with contract items that offer service provided recurrently. For details on configuring, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__CON_Deposit_Contract|Retainer Contracts].
)))
#On the form toolbar, click '''Save'''.
]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[To Configure a Contract Item You use the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT201000|CT201000]) Contract Items (CT201000) form to configure the prices                 and provisions for services and products.  Before You Proceed Make sure that non-stock items are properly configured for each service you want to                 include in a contract item. For details on configuring non-stock items, see  Creating Non-Stock Items: General Information. To open any form, you can navigate to it             or search for it (by its name or by its form ID without periods). For more information             about search capabilities, see  Search. To Configure a Contract Item The offered instruction is divided into four parts: general settings (required),                 setup, renewal, and setting up recurring billing. You can refer to the parts that                 you need to configure the contract item you want to offer and skip other                 parts. Open the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT201000|CT201000]) Contract Items (CT201000) form.  Click  Add New Record  on the form toolbar. Optional: Specify the identifier manually in the  Contract                         Item  box.  The unique identifier of a contract item is formed                         in accordance with the  CONTRACTITEM  segmented key. If the                              Contract Item  box contains the                              <NEW>  placeholder, it means that auto-numbering is                         enabled for the key segment and the identifier is assigned automatically.                      In the  Description  box, type a brief description of the                     services included. In the Summary area of the  Price Options  tab, do the                     following:  In the  Maximum Allowed Quantity  and                                  Minimum Allowed Quantity  boxes, type the                             quantity limits for the provided services. In the  Default Quantity  box, type the service                             quantity that is included in the contract by default.  This value can                                 be modified in a template or a contract within the allowed limits                                 (which are defined by  Maximum Allowed Quantity                                  and  Minimum Allowed Quantity ). If                                 service usage has exceeded the included quantity, the difference is                                 considered extra usage. Allowed quantity limits are not applied to                                 extra usage. In the  Currency ID  box, select the currency of                             this contract item. You should use non-stock items priced in one                             currency within each contract item. To set up pricing for a service to be provided as a part of contract setup, on                     the  Setup and Renewal  area, do the following: In the  Setup Item  box, select the non-stock item                             you want to provide and bill when contract setup occurs. In the  Setup Pricing  box, select the pricing                             policy. The following options are available:  Use Item Price : Select this option if you want to use the                                     applicable sales price of the non-stock item. If a sales price                                     is not found, the default price of the non-stock item is used.                                     For details, see  Sales Prices: General Information. Percent of Item Price : Select this option if you want the                                     price to be calculated by applying the percent specified in the                                          Item Price/Percent  box to the base                                     price of the non-stock item. Enter Manually : Select this option if you want to specify                                     the price manually in the  Item                                         Price/Percent  box. Selecting this option also                                     allows users to modify the price later in the contract. (Skip this step if you have selected  Use Item Price  in the                                  Setup Pricing  box.) In the  Item                                 Price/Percent  box, type the item price or percent,                             depending on the pricing policy you have selected. Skip the  Retain Rate  and                                  Deposit  elements, which are used only for                             creating a contract item to serve as a prepayment. For details, see                                  To Create a Deposit Contract Item. Select the  Refundable  check box if you want to                             allow the amount the customer paid for setup to be refunded in case of                             contract termination. The setup fee is refunded if both the contract                             template and this contract item are marked as refundable. If the renewal                             fee is collected on activation, it is refunded along with the setup fee.                             Recurring charges are refunded in proportion to unused services in case                             of termination. Select the  Prorate Setup  check box if you want to                             allow the amount the customer paid for setup to be billed in proportion                             to unused services in case of termination or changes in contract                             terms. Optional: If you have finished specifying settings for the contract                             item, click  Save  on the form toolbar. Otherwise,                             proceed with the part of instruction you need. To set up pricing for a service to be provided when contract renewal occurs, on                     the  Setup and Renewal  area, do the following: In the  Renewal Item  box, select the non-stock                             item you want to provide and bill when contract renewal occurs. Select the  Collect Renewal Fee on Activation                              check box if you want to bill the customer for services provided on                             renewal both at the moment of contract activation and at contract                             renewal. For a usage example, see  Fixed-Price Contracts. In the  Renewal Pricing  box, select the pricing                             policy. The following options are available:  Use Item Price : Select this option if you want to use the                                     applicable sales price of the non-stock item. If a sales price                                     is not found, the default price of the non-stock item is used.                                     For details, see  Sales Prices: General Information. Percent of Item Price : Select this option if you want the                                     price to be calculated by applying the percent specified in the                                          Item Price/Percent  box to the price                                     of the non-stock item. Percent of Setup Price : Select this option if you want                                     the price to be calculated by applying the percent specified in                                     the  Item Price/Percent  box to the setup                                     price of the contract item. Enter Manually : Select this option if you want to specify                                     the price manually in the  Item                                         Price/Percent  box. Selecting this option also                                     allows you to modify the price later in the contract. (Skip this step if you have selected the  Use Item Price  option in                             the  Renewal Pricing  box.) In the  Item                                 Price/Percent  box, type the item price or percent,                             depending on the pricing policy you selected. Optional: If you have finished specifying settings for the contract                             item, click  Save  on the form toolbar. Otherwise,                             proceed with the part of the instruction you need. To set up pricing for service to be provided recurrently, on the                          Recurring Billing  area, do the following:  In the  Billing Type  box select the billing                             policy. The following options are available: None : Select this option if you are not going to bill the                                     customer recurrently, and the elements of the                                          Recurring Billing  area become                                     unavailable. Prepaid : Select this option if you want to bill the                                     customer at the beginning of the scheduled billing period.  Postpaid : Select this option if the customer is billed at                                     the end of the scheduled billing period. In the  Recurring Item  box, select the non-stock                             item that you want to provide and bill recurrently. Select the  Reset Usage on Billing  check box if                             you want the contract item usage to be reset after the billing for a                             previous billing period has been performed. If this check box is                             selected, the included quantity is set per billing period. If this check                             box is cleared, the included quantity is set for the whole duration of                             the contract, so clear the check box only if the billing period is equal                             to the contract duration. In the  Recurring Pricing  box, select the pricing                             policy. The following options are available:  Use Item Price : Select this option if you want to use the                                     applicable sales price of the non-stock item. If a sales price                                     is not found, the default price of the non-stock item is used.                                     For details, see  Sales Prices: General Information. Percent of Item Price : Select this option if you want the                                     system to calculate the price by applying the percent specified                                     in the  Item Price/Percent  box to the                                     price of the non-stock item. Percent of Setup Price : Select this option if you want                                     the system to calculate the price by applying the percent                                     specified in the  Item Price/Percent  box                                     to the setup price of the contract item. Enter Manually : Select this option if you want to specify                                     the price manually in the  Item                                         Price/Percent  box. Selecting this option also                                     allows to modify the price later in the contract. (Skip this step if you have selected  Use Item Price  in the                                  Recurring Pricing  box.) In the                                  Item Price/Percent  box, type the item price                             or percent, depending on the pricing policy selected. In the  Extra Usage Pricing  box, select the                             pricing policy to be applied to the service price if the customer has                             exceeded the service included quantity. The following options are                                 available: Use Item Price : Select this option if you want to use the                                     applicable sales price of the non-stock item. If a sales price                                     is not found, the default price of the non-stock item is used.                                     For details, see  Sales Prices: General Information. Percent of Item Price : Select this option if you want the                                     system to calculate the price by applying the percent specified                                     in the  Item Price/Percent  box to the                                     price of the non-stock item. Percent of Setup Price : Select this option if you want                                     the system to calculate the price by applying the percent                                     specified in the  Item Price/Percent  box                                     to the setup price of the contract item. Enter Manually : Select this option if you want to specify                                     the price manually in the  Item                                         Price/Percent  box. Selecting this option also                                     allows to modify the price later in the contract. (Skip this step if you have selected  Use Item Price  in the                                  Extra Usage Pricing  box.) In the                                  Item Price/Percent  box, type the item price                             or percent, depending on the pricing policy selected. Optional: In the  Deposit Item  box, select the                             deposit contract item you want to tie to the contract item you are                                 configuring. The deposit item is used only with contract items                                 that offer service provided recurrently. For details on configuring,                                 see  Retainer Contracts. On the form toolbar, click  Save . ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="9f33e6ff-9953-4f0f-9d4e-48563ae1b799" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="627df8ff-f7b8-cddb-d18d-ce834faa32f6" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
Once the prior configuration is done, you proceed with the contract configuration.{br}

In this topic, you will find details on the segmented key for contract identifiers, the selection of discounts that apply to contracts, and the contract configuration process. {br}{TOC}
==Contract Identifiers==
Contract identifiers are based on the ''CONTRACT'' segmented key, which inherits its structure from the ''PROJECT'' segmented key. To be able to distinguish contracts from projects in lookup lists, reserve one segment of the key for a value designating whether an identifier belongs to projects or contracts. Consider the following examples of defining the keys: [anchor|#ol_rgs_z1h_xh]
#You can configure two segments in the ''PROJECT'' segmented key: a two-letter segment with two possible values (''PR'' and ''CT'') to designate the type of identifier, and a 10-character auto-numbered segment to identify the particular project or contract. For the second segment of the ''CONTRACT'' key, you can assign a different numbering sequence to maintain the numbers for contracts independently from those of projects.
#If you decide to define a one-segment structure for the ''PROJECT'' key with an auto-numbered segment, you can assign different numbering sequences to the ''PROJECT'' and ''CONTRACT'' keys. Create the sequence intended for projects with ''PR'' as a prefix, and define the sequence intended for contracts with the ''CT'' prefix.

==Contract Configuration==
To create a new contract, on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_10_00|Customer Contracts] ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) form, you select a template and a customer account. This form is filled in with the default values provided by the selected template and the customer account. You may then change the included quantity of contract items within the allowed limits and modify billing information. You can modify the list of contract items if such modifications are allowed in the selected contract template. Also, you can change the prices if the pricing policy of the contract item allows it. A newly created contract has the ''Draft'' status.
==Discount Selection==
You can specify a discount code in the '''Promo Code''' box on the '''Details''' tab on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_10_00|Customer Contracts] form. If you specify a promo code, the system forms the list of available discount codes to be displayed in '''Promo Code''' options as follows:[anchor|#ol_jbv_b5n_ds]
#The system selects all discount codes with the ''Line'' type that have at least one active discount sequence. 
#The system checks the conditions defined in the active discount sequences found and leaves for the selection those discount codes that are applicable to any of the following:
#*The customer account for which you prepare a contract.
#*The customer price class to which the customer account belongs.
#*The non-stock items used in the contract items.
#*The item price class to which the non-stock item belongs.
#*:((({S:Warn}The system displays in the selector for the '''Promo Code''' box all discount codes that may be applicable to the items in the contract. In other words, the selector might show some discount codes that aren’t suitable for any of the contract items at the current moment.
)))
#If an applicable discount sequence is marked as promotional, the system leaves only those for which the contract start date is in the promotional range. 

If you have not specified a discount code for a contract, the system will apply the best active line discount when you run the contract billing process. If you have specified a discount code for a contract, the system will apply the specified discount, even if a better discount is available.{br}

The system applies the specified discount to only the non-stock items used in contract items. If you record the usage (for a contract) of a non-stock item that is not included in the contract, the system will apply the best available discount for this non-stock item.{br}

For details on discount configuration, application, and calculation, see [HelpRoot_PricesAndDiscounts\PriceDiscount_Review_Customer_Discounts_Mapref|Configuring and Applying Customer Discounts].
==Related Articles==
*[HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__HOW_Configure_Contract_Item|To Configure a Contract Item]
*[HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__HOW_Configure_Contract_Template|To Configure a Contract Template]
*[HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__HOW_Prepare_Contract|To Configure a Contract]
*[HelpRoot_PricesAndDiscounts\PriceDiscount_Review_Customer_Discounts_Mapref|Configuring and Applying Customer Discounts]]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Contract Preparation Once the prior configuration is done, you proceed with the contract configuration. In this topic, you will find details on the segmented key for contract identifiers, the         selection of discounts that apply to contracts, and the contract configuration process.  Contract Identifiers Contract identifiers are based on the  CONTRACT  segmented key, which inherits its         structure from the  PROJECT  segmented key. To be able to distinguish contracts from         projects in lookup lists, reserve one segment of the key for a value designating whether an         identifier belongs to projects or contracts. Consider the following examples of defining the         keys:  You can configure two segments in the  PROJECT  segmented key: a two-letter segment           with two possible values ( PR  and  CT ) to designate the type of identifier,           and a 10-character auto-numbered segment to identify the particular project or contract.           For the second segment of the  CONTRACT  key, you can assign a different numbering           sequence to maintain the numbers for contracts independently from those of projects. If you decide to define a one-segment structure for the  PROJECT  key with an           auto-numbered segment, you can assign different numbering sequences to the  PROJECT            and  CONTRACT  keys. Create the sequence intended for projects with  PR  as a           prefix, and define the sequence intended for contracts with the  CT  prefix. Contract Configuration To create a new contract, on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) Customer Contracts (CT301000) form, you         select a template and a customer account. This form is filled in with the default values         provided by the selected template and the customer account. You may then change the included         quantity of contract items within the allowed limits and modify billing information. You can         modify the list of contract items if such modifications are allowed in the selected contract         template. Also, you can change the prices if the pricing policy of the contract item allows         it. A newly created contract has the  Draft  status. Discount Selection You can specify a discount code in the  Promo Code  box on the            Details  tab on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) Customer Contracts form. If you         specify a promo code, the system forms the list of available discount codes to be displayed         in  Promo Code  options as follows: The system selects all discount codes with the  Line  type that have at least one           active discount sequence.  The system checks the conditions defined in the active discount sequences found and           leaves for the selection those discount codes that are applicable to any of the             following: The customer account for which you prepare a contract. The customer price class to which the customer account belongs. The non-stock items used in the contract items. The item price class to which the non-stock item belongs. The system displays                 in the selector for the  Promo Code  box all discount codes                 that may be applicable to the items in the contract. In other words, the selector                 might show some discount codes that aren’t suitable for any of the contract items at                 the current moment. If an applicable discount sequence is marked as promotional, the system leaves only           those for which the contract start date is in the promotional range.  If you have not specified a discount code for a contract, the system will apply the best         active line discount when you run the contract billing process. If you have specified a         discount code for a contract, the system will apply the specified discount, even if a better         discount is available. The system applies the specified discount to only the non-stock items used in contract         items. If you record the usage (for a contract) of a non-stock item that is not included in         the contract, the system will apply the best available discount for this non-stock item. For details on discount configuration, application, and calculation, see  Configuring and Applying Customer Discounts. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="b6ea6cb1-e0ce-49b7-baf1-af57ed02c932" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="4ee16843-a0e9-db9f-3745-138d69c5f1a3" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
You use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_10_00|Customer Contracts] ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) form to configure a contract.[anchor|#_56c95ad2-90ad-457d-854a-893714a6bd33]((({S:Hint}To open any form, you can navigate to it or search for it (by its name or by its form ID without periods). For more information about search capabilities, see [HelpRoot_Interface\UIG__con_New_UI_Search|Search].
)))
==Before You Proceed==
On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_20_20_00|Contract Templates] ([~/?ScreenId=CT202000|CT202000]) form, make sure of the following:[anchor|#ul_pbx_1vp_lhb]
*The contract template you want to base the contract on is active (that is, the '''Active''' check box is selected).
*The date when you are creating this contract is later than the '''Effective From''' date and sooner than the '''Discontinue After''' date of the template. (You can find these dates in the '''Contract Settings '''section of the '''Summary''' tab.)
*The template currency (also in the '''Contract Settings '''section of the '''Summary''' tab) matches the customer currency, which can be found on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AR_30_30_00|Customers] ([~/?ScreenId=AR303000|AR303000]) form ('''Financial Settings''' section of the '''General Info''' tab).
{br}

Also, if you want to apply a discount to the contract, make sure that the discount is properly configured.
==To Configure a Contract==[anchor|#ol_acq_k1h_nm]
#Open the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_10_00|Customer Contracts] ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) form.
#Click '''Add New Record''' on the form toolbar.
#Optional: Specify the identifier manually in the '''Contract ID''' box. If the box contains the {{<NEW>}} placeholder, it means that auto-numbering is enabled for a key segment and the system will assign the identifier automatically. 
#In the Summary area, do the following: 
##In the '''Contract Template''' box, select the contract template that the new contract should be based on. The system automatically inserts the following default values from the selected contract template: the billing policy settings on the '''Summary''' tab, the list of services on the '''Details''' tab, and the item quantity for each service (that is, for each row in the table) in the '''Included''' column of this tab. 
##In the '''Customer''' box, select the customer account you want to configure the contract with.
##Optional: Change the customer location and contract description.
#On the '''Summary''' tab, do the following:
##In the '''Setup Date''' box (and optionally the '''Activation Date''' box), specify the dates of the contract being signed and the start services being provided. These dates are to be displayed by default and can be changed in the '''Activate Contract''' dialog box, which opens when you invoke the '''Set Up Contract''' or '''Activate Contract''' action. The boxes become read-only after the respective action has been performed. 
##Optional: Modify the following settings if needed: '''Mass Renewal''', '''Renewal Point''', '''Grace Period''', and '''Billing Information'''.
##Optional: In the '''Contract Management '''section, assign the contract owner and salesperson. 
#On the '''Details''' tab, do the following:
##In the '''Promo Code''' box, select the discount to be applied to the prices of items.
##If the contract template allows modification of the contract items included, change the quantity and description of items, add new items, and delete listed items, as needed. (Use the applicable buttons on the table toolbar to add and delete rows.) Also, you can enter new prices for non-stock items that have the pricing policy set to the ''Enter Manually'' option.
#On the form toolbar, click '''Save'''.

After the contract preparation is finished, you can proceed to signing and activating it.]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[To Configure a Contract You use the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) Customer Contracts (CT301000) form to configure a                     contract. To open any form, you can navigate to it             or search for it (by its name or by its form ID without periods). For more information             about search capabilities, see  Search. Before You Proceed On the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT202000|CT202000]) Contract Templates (CT202000) form, make sure of the                     following: The contract template you want to base the contract on is active (that is,                         the  Active  check box is selected). The date when you are creating this contract is later than the                              Effective From  date and sooner than the                              Discontinue After  date of the template. (You can                         find these dates in the  Contract Settings  section of                         the  Summary  tab.) The template currency (also in the  Contract Settings                          section of the  Summary  tab) matches the                         customer currency, which can be found on the   ([~/?ScreenId=AR303000|AR303000]) Customers                         (AR303000) form ( Financial Settings  section of the                              General Info  tab). Also, if you want to apply a discount to the contract, make sure that the discount is                 properly configured. To Configure a Contract Open the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) Customer Contracts (CT301000) form. Click  Add New Record  on the form toolbar. Optional: Specify the identifier manually in the  Contract                         ID  box. If the box contains the  <NEW>                      placeholder, it means that auto-numbering is enabled for a key segment and the                     system will assign the identifier automatically.  In the Summary area, do the following:  In the  Contract Template  box, select the contract                             template that the new contract should be based on. The system                             automatically inserts the following default values from the selected                             contract template: the billing policy settings on the                                  Summary  tab, the list of services on the                                  Details  tab, and the item quantity for each                             service (that is, for each row in the table) in the                                  Included  column of this tab.  In the  Customer  box, select the customer account                             you want to configure the contract with. Optional: Change the customer location and contract description. On the  Summary  tab, do the following: In the  Setup Date  box (and optionally the                                  Activation Date  box), specify the dates of                             the contract being signed and the start services being provided. These                             dates are to be displayed by default and can be changed in the                                  Activate Contract  dialog box, which opens                             when you invoke the  Set Up Contract  or                                  Activate Contract  action. The boxes become                             read-only after the respective action has been performed.  Optional: Modify the following settings if needed:  Mass                                 Renewal ,  Renewal Point ,                                  Grace Period , and  Billing                                 Information . Optional: In the  Contract Management  section,                             assign the contract owner and salesperson.  On the  Details  tab, do the following: In the  Promo Code  box, select the discount to be                             applied to the prices of items. If the contract template allows modification of the contract items                             included, change the quantity and description of items, add new items,                             and delete listed items, as needed. (Use the applicable buttons on the                             table toolbar to add and delete rows.) Also, you can enter new prices                             for non-stock items that have the pricing policy set to the  Enter                                 Manually  option. On the form toolbar, click  Save . After the contract preparation is finished, you can proceed to signing and activating                 it. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="fc89c9f4-87ad-44eb-9559-822aa45fec54" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="8686b893-fef1-9a7a-8a00-048ccabd693e" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
If you have a contract with the ''Draft'' status and the contract details reflect your agreement with a customer, you activate the contract to initiate its life cycle. The contract life cycle consists of mandatory stages: setup and activation, fulfillment, and expiration. The life cycle may include the following optional stages: changes to contract services, contract renewal, and contract termination. This article describes the contract life cycle stages in detail.{br}

A contract life cycle can include the following stages:[anchor|#ul_cyf_324_lm]
#''Setup and activation'' (mandatory): Once you have prepared a contract, you can initiate it. If the services covered by a contract require setup before contract activation, you may initiate billing for the setup separately. For example, contracts involving Internet access may require the installation of a router or other equipment. You initiate the contract setup: the contract becomes effective and the customer is billed for any services associated with setup. At this point, you can no longer modify the terms and scope of the contract. When setup is finished, you activate the contract and start to bill the customer recurrently. If you do not need to separate the setup of the contract and the activation, these steps can be done simultaneously. For details, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__CON_Contract_Signing|Contract Setup and Activation].
#''Fulfillment'' (mandatory): During this stage, the longest of the contract life cycle, the customer uses the services described in the contract, and billing is performed according to the terms defined in the contract and the contract items. For details, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__CON_Contract_Usage|Contract Usage Recording] and [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__con_Contract_Billing|Contract Billing].
#''Changes to services'' (optional): You or the customer may want to change (upgrade or downgrade) a set of services within the scope of an active contract. Both contract upgrading and downgrading are done in two steps: preparation and activation. During preparation, contract billing and the provision of services are done according to the initial settings of the contract. For details, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__CON_Contract_Upgrade|Changes to Contract Services ].
#''Expiration'' (mandatory): Each time you run the contract billing process, it checks whether the next billing date exceeds or equals a contract expiration date. If it does, the contract billing process sets the next billing day equal to the contract expiration date. The next time you run the contract billing process, it generates invoice for the contract usage and changes the contract status to ''Expired''. You can not record any usage for expired contracts. Expired contracts can be either renewed or terminated:
#*''Renewal'' (optional): The renewal scenario depends on the expired contract type, which is defined by the contract template. There are three types of contracts: 
#**''Renewable'': During the renewal process, the system changes the expiration date of a contract and generates an invoice for the renewal fee, if any. After renewal is completed, the contract is again in the fulfillment stage. A contract should be renewed before its grace period ends; otherwise, the renewal process creates a copy of the contract with the ''Draft'' status. You need to activate the copied contract to start the provision of services.
#**''Expiring'': A contract of this type expires at the end of its duration, but it is available for a renewal operation—manual or automatic (if scheduled). When such a contract is renewed, a copy of the expired contract is created with the ''Draft'' status, and you need to activate the copied contract to start the provision of services.
#**''Unlimited'': A contract of this type has no expiration date and can be terminated only.For details about renewing contracts, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__CON_Contract_Renewal|Contract Renewal]. 
#*''Termination'' (optional): You can terminate an expired contract if you are not going to renew or copy it. Also, contract termination may be done at any point in the contract life cycle, if you or the customer decide to terminate the relationship defined by a contract. When you initiate contract termination, the system gathers information on the unbilled usage of a contract and issues an invoice or a credit memo, if needed. The termination date must be within the current billing period (between the '''Last Billing Date''' and the '''Next Billing Date''').
]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Contract Life Cycle If you have a contract with the  Draft  status and the contract details reflect your 				agreement with a customer, you activate the contract to initiate its life cycle. The 				contract life cycle consists of mandatory stages: setup and activation, fulfillment, 				and expiration. The life cycle may include the following optional stages: changes to 				contract services, contract renewal, and contract termination. This article 				describes the contract life cycle stages in detail. A contract life cycle can include the following stages: Setup and activation  (mandatory): Once you have prepared a contract, you 					can initiate it. If the services covered by a contract require setup before 					contract activation, you may initiate billing for the setup separately. For 					example, contracts involving Internet access may require the installation of a 					router or other equipment. You initiate the contract setup: the contract becomes 					effective and the customer is billed for any services associated with setup. At 					this point, you can no longer modify the terms and scope of the contract. When 					setup is finished, you activate the contract and start to bill the customer 					recurrently. If you do not need to separate the setup of the contract and the 					activation, these steps can be done simultaneously. For details, see  Contract Setup and Activation. Fulfillment  (mandatory): During this stage, the longest of the contract 					life cycle, the customer uses the services described in the contract, and 					billing is performed according to the terms defined in the contract and the 					contract items. For details, see  Contract Usage Recording and 						 Contract Billing. Changes to services  (optional): You or the customer may want to change 					(upgrade or downgrade) a set of services within the scope of an active contract. 					Both contract upgrading and downgrading are done in two steps: preparation and 					activation. During preparation, contract billing and the provision of services 					are done according to the initial settings of the contract. For details, see 						 Changes to Contract Services . Expiration  (mandatory): Each time you run the contract billing process, 					it checks whether the next billing date exceeds or equals a contract expiration 					date. If it does, the contract billing process sets the next billing day equal 					to the contract expiration date. The next time you run the contract billing 					process, it generates invoice for the contract usage and changes the contract 					status to  Expired . You can not record any usage for expired contracts. 					Expired contracts can be either renewed or terminated: Renewal  (optional): The renewal scenario depends on the expired 							contract type, which is defined by the contract template. There are 							three types of contracts:  Renewable : During the renewal process, the system changes 									the expiration date of a contract and generates an invoice for 									the renewal fee, if any. After renewal is completed, the 									contract is again in the fulfillment stage. A contract should be 									renewed before its grace period ends; otherwise, the renewal 									process creates a copy of the contract with the  Draft  									status. You need to activate the copied contract to start the 									provision of services. Expiring : A contract of this type expires at the end of 									its duration, but it is available for a renewal operation—manual 									or automatic (if scheduled). When such a contract is renewed, a 									copy of the expired contract is created with the  Draft  									status, and you need to activate the copied contract to start 									the provision of services. Unlimited : A contract of this type has no expiration date 									and can be terminated only. For details about renewing contracts, see  Contract Renewal.  Termination  (optional): You can terminate an expired contract if 							you are not going to renew or copy it. Also, contract termination may be 							done at any point in the contract life cycle, if you or the customer 							decide to terminate the relationship defined by a contract. When you 							initiate contract termination, the system gathers information on the 							unbilled usage of a contract and issues an invoice or a credit memo, if 							needed. The termination date must be within the current billing period 							(between the  Last Billing Date  and the 								 Next Billing Date ). ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="18aa4f4d-0918-421d-bda4-9ed3e436997f" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" PlainText="Contract Setup and Activation The way you initiate a contract may depend on the services you provide. You may want the     contract signing and the start of provision to occur at different times. For example, you might     need some time to install the equipment required for the provision of services and you may want     to bill the customer for this equipment before installation. In this case, the recurring billing     schedule should begin at the start date of provision. If you don't need to separate the time of     contract signing and service provision, then you can perform these two actions simultaneously.  In  Acumatica ERP,     contract signing is referred to as  contract setup . The date when the contract is signed     is called the  setup date . The start of the provision of services is referred to as       contract activation , and the date of contract activation is called the  activation      date . Note that you can record service usage for only activated contracts. " ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="9fc6be49-0b42-c875-c926-94738060dddd" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
The way you initiate a contract may depend on the services you provide. You may want the contract signing and the start of provision to occur at different times. For example, you might need some time to install the equipment required for the provision of services and you may want to bill the customer for this equipment before installation. In this case, the recurring billing schedule should begin at the start date of provision. If you don&rsquo;t need to separate the time of contract signing and service provision, then you can perform these two actions simultaneously. {br}

In Acumatica ERP, contract signing is referred to as ''contract setup''. The date when the contract is signed is called the ''setup date''. The start of the provision of services is referred to as ''contract activation'', and the date of contract activation is called the ''activation date''. Note that you can record service usage for only activated contracts.
==Related Articles==
*[HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__HOW_Setup_Contract|To Set Up a Contract]
*[HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__HOW_Activate_Contract|To Activate a Contract]
*[HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__HOW_Setup_Activate_Contract|To Set Up and Activate a Contract Simultaneously]]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="291767dc-3af8-4c33-975d-726a016b9a6b" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="14edbe27-9b2c-7ee2-1152-8121072452e2" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
You use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_10_00|Customer Contracts] ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) form to set up a contract. The setup operation is available for contracts that have the ''Draft'' status only.
==To Set Up a Contract==[anchor|#_67e8fa53-13e7-4eb4-8994-e7080efafbc1]
#Open the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_10_00|Customer Contracts] ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) form.
#In the '''Contract ID''' box, select a contract with the ''Draft'' status, which you want to initiate.
#Review the contract details to ensure that the contract meets the intentions of the parties, and make any needed changes. 
#Click '''Actions''', and select the '''Set Up Contract''' action.
#In the '''Setup Contract''' dialog box, specify the date of contract setup and click '''OK'''. 

When the operation completes, the following actions occur:[anchor|#ul_ktw_gvm_nm]
*The contract gets the ''Pending Activation'' status.
*The setup date becomes unavailable for editing.
*If the billing schedule starts on the setup date, the '''Expiration Date''' box and the '''Billing Schedule''' section are filled with details.
*An invoice is issued for any service to be provided on setup. If the billing schedule starts on the setup date, the invoice also includes a renewal fee if such a fee is configured to be collected on contract activation. You can view the invoice details on the '''AR History''' tab of the form.
You cannot enter contract usage at this point; to proceed, you need to activate the contract.]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[To Set Up a Contract You use the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) Customer Contracts (CT301000) form to set up a contract.                 The setup operation is available for contracts that have the  Draft  status                 only. To Set Up a Contract Open the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) Customer Contracts (CT301000) form. In the  Contract ID  box, select a contract with the  Draft  status,                 which you want to initiate. Review the contract details to ensure that the contract meets the intentions of the parties, and make any needed changes.  Click  Actions , and select the  Set Up Contract                  action. In the  Setup Contract  dialog box, specify the date of contract setup and                 click  OK .  When the operation completes, the following actions occur: The contract gets the  Pending Activation  status. The setup date becomes unavailable for editing. If the billing schedule starts on the setup date, the  Expiration                             Date  box and the  Billing Schedule                          section are filled with details. An invoice is issued for any service to be provided on setup. If the billing                         schedule starts on the setup date, the invoice also includes a renewal fee                         if such a fee is configured to be collected on contract activation. You can                         view the invoice details on the  AR History  tab of the                         form. You cannot enter contract usage at this point; to proceed, you need to activate                 the contract. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="80fdc000-7e43-4912-9552-bdc657bb2467" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="d9bece4b-1f92-8157-4f74-07ef6b76781a" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
You use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_10_00|Customer Contracts] ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) form to activate a contract. This operation is available for contracts with the ''Pending Activation'' status only.
==To Activate a Contract==[anchor|#_a93c4f68-125e-40b8-8a43-bc27e7782fda]
#Open the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_10_00|Customer Contracts] ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) form.
#In the '''Contract ID''' box, select the contract you want to activate.
#Click '''Actions''', and then select the '''Activate Contract''' action.
#In the '''Activate Contract''' dialog box, specify the date of contract activation and click '''OK'''.

When the operation completes, the following actions occur:[anchor|#ul_gq4_3xm_nm]
*The contract gets the ''Active'' status.
*The activation date becomes unavailable for editing.
*If the billing schedule starts on the activation date, the '''Expiration Date''' box and the '''Billing Schedule''' section are filled with details.
* An invoice for prepaid services is issued. If the billing schedule starts on the activation date, the invoice also includes a renewal fee if the fee is configured to be collected on contract activation. You can view the invoice details on the '''AR History''' tab of the form.
{br}

Now you can proceed with usage recording. For details, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__CON_Contract_Usage|Contract Usage Recording].]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[To Activate a Contract You use the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) Customer Contracts (CT301000) form to activate a                 contract. This operation is available for contracts with the  Pending                     Activation  status only. To Activate a Contract Open the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) Customer Contracts (CT301000) form. In the  Contract ID  box, select the contract you want to activate. Click  Actions , and then select the  Activate Contract  action. In the  Activate Contract  dialog box, specify the date of contract activation and click  OK . When the operation completes, the following actions occur: The contract gets the  Active  status. The activation date becomes unavailable for editing. If the billing schedule starts on the activation date, the                              Expiration Date  box and the  Billing                             Schedule  section are filled with details.  An invoice for prepaid services is issued. If the billing schedule starts                         on the activation date, the invoice also includes a renewal fee if the fee                         is configured to be collected on contract activation. You can view the                         invoice details on the  AR History  tab of the                         form. Now you can proceed with usage recording. For details, see  Contract Usage Recording. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="b8f88b6c-e678-4da8-86cd-0611165b42e0" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="2610eb45-692e-3282-5c08-e086dadce271" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_10_00|Customer Contracts] ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) form, you can simultaneously set up and activate a contract. This operation is available for contracts with the ''Draft'' status only.
==To Set Up and Activate a Contract==[anchor|#_73550374-8682-4527-9090-f22efe72632b]
#Open the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_10_00|Customer Contracts] ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) form.
#In the '''Contract ID''' box, select the contract you want to set up and activate.
#Review the contract details to ensure that the contract meets the intentions of the parties, and make any needed changes. 
#Click '''Actions''', and select the '''Set Up and Activate Contract''' action.
#In the '''Activate Contract''' dialog box, specify the date of contract activation and click '''OK'''. 
This operation triggers the following actions:[anchor|#ul_vjk_qxm_nm]
*The contract gets the ''Active'' status.
*The setup and activation dates become unavailable for editing.
*The '''Expiration Date''' box and the '''Billing Schedule''' section are filled with details based on the template settings.
*An invoice is issued for the setup and prepaid services. The invoice also includes a renewal fee if such a fee is configured to be collected on contract activation. You can view the invoice details on the '''AR History''' tab of the form.

Now you can proceed with usage recording. For details, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__CON_Contract_Usage|Contract Usage Recording].]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[To Set Up and Activate a Contract Simultaneously On the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) Customer Contracts (CT301000) form, you can simultaneously set                 up and activate a contract. This operation is available for contracts with the                      Draft  status only. To Set Up and Activate a Contract Open the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) Customer Contracts (CT301000) form. In the  Contract ID  box, select the contract you want to set up and activate. Review the contract details to ensure that the contract meets the intentions of the parties, and make any needed changes.  Click  Actions , and select the  Set Up and Activate                     Contract  action. In the  Activate Contract  dialog box, specify the date of contract activation and click  OK .  This operation triggers the following actions: The contract gets the  Active  status. The setup and activation dates become unavailable for editing. The  Expiration Date  box and the  Billing                         Schedule  section are filled with details based on the template                     settings. An invoice is issued for the setup and prepaid services. The invoice also                     includes a renewal fee if such a fee is configured to be collected on contract                     activation. You can view the invoice details on the  AR                         History  tab of the form. Now you can proceed with usage recording. For details, see  Contract Usage Recording. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="ba20f3e1-dc28-41d0-b3ec-76ef456d9eaf" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="82022b85-bb00-2de5-9855-6021254106e0" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
After contract activation, your company can start providing the services defined by the contract. The contract is billed in accordance with its billing schedule. Billing is performed for usage accumulated during a billing period. If the contract is billed on demand, billing is performed for usage accumulated up to the date of the billing.{br}

Contract usage is the sum of used units of each non-stock item associated with the contract. You can associate a non-stock item with the contract directly or through such system entities as cases, case activities, expense claims, and employee activities (available only if the Customer Management feature is disabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) form). {br}

You may want to track the usage of a particular non-stock item during a billing period or the whole duration of the contract. To track usage, you create a contract item, specify this non-stock item as the one that is provided recurrently, and add the item to a contract template. When a contract based on this template is activated, contract items that have non-stock items provided recurrently are listed on the '''Recurring Summary''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_10_00|Customer Contracts] ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) form. Here you can view the usage of the contract item, which is the sum of the used units of the non-stock item provided recurrently. {br}

You can affect the contract usage in the following ways:[anchor|#ul_dk3_h25_nm]
*''Using Cases'': You can associate a case with a contract. To recognize the billable time of the case as usage of a contract item, you should assign a non-stock item that is provided recurrently to a case class that is billed on a per-case basis. When a case of this class is closed and released, its billable time is added to the usage of the contract item. The billable time of cases associated with non-stock items that are not included in the contract is presented on the invoice as a separate line. For details on using contracts for case billing, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__CON_Usage_Contracts|Usage-Based Contracts].
*''Using Case Activities'': If a case belongs to a case class that is billed on a per-activity basis, you can associate the case with a contract as well. When a case activity is completed and released, the respective transaction can be viewed on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_30_00|Contract Usage] ([~/?ScreenId=CT303000|CT303000]) form. The billable time of activities associated with non-stock items that are not included in the contract is presented on the invoice as a separate line. For details on using contracts for activity billing, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__CON_Usage_Contracts|Usage-Based Contracts].
*''Using Expense Claims'': You can associate the details of expense claims with a contract. After an expense claim is billed, a transaction for the details associated with the contract can be viewed on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_30_00|Contract Usage] form. The quantity of details associated with non-stock items that are not included in the contract is presented on the invoice as a separate line. For details on managing expense claims, see [HelpRoot_Organization\EP__con_Claim_Processing|Processing Expense Claims].
*''Using Employee Time Activities'': You can associate a time activity of a particular employee with a contract. When the time activity is released, the respective transaction can be viewed on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_30_00|Contract Usage] form. The billable time of activities associated with non-stock items that are not included in the contract is presented on the invoice as a separate line. For details on managing the time activities of employees, see [HelpRoot_Organization\EP__MNG_Time|Reporting Time].
*:((({S:Warn}Associating an employee&rsquo;s time activity with a contract is available only if the Customer Management feature is disabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] form. 
)))
*''Using Non-Stock Items'': You can associate the usage of any non-stock item with a contract by using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_30_00|Contract Usage] form. The usage of non-stock items that are not included in the contract is presented on the invoice as a separate line. For details on entering usage transactions, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__HOW_Enter_Contract_Usage|To Enter Contract Usage].

You can enter item usage for past, current, and future billing periods. If you have entered transactions with a date in a past billing period, they will be invoiced in the next billing period. If you have entered a transaction with a date in the future, the transaction will be invoiced in the billing period that contains the date. When you run the contract billing process, the system checks the date of transactions and bills those with a date before or the same as the current business date. Records of usage transactions are presented as invoice details according to the billing format settings of the applicable contract template.
==Related Articles==
*[HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__HOW_Enter_Contract_Usage|To Enter Contract Usage]
*[HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__HOW_View_Contract_Usage|To View Contract Usage]]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Contract Usage Recording After contract activation, your company can start providing the services defined by the     contract. The contract is billed in accordance with its billing schedule. Billing is performed     for usage accumulated during a billing period. If the contract is billed on demand, billing is     performed for usage accumulated up to the date of the billing. Contract usage is the sum of used units of each non-stock item associated with the contract.     You can associate a non-stock item with the contract directly or through such system entities as     cases, case activities, expense claims, and employee activities (available only if the Customer     Management feature is disabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features (CS100000) form).  You may want to track the usage of a particular non-stock item during a billing period or the     whole duration of the contract. To track usage, you create a contract item, specify this     non-stock item as the one that is provided recurrently, and add the item to a contract template.     When a contract based on this template is activated, contract items that have non-stock items     provided recurrently are listed on the  Recurring Summary  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) Customer Contracts (CT301000) form. Here you can view the usage of the contract item,     which is the sum of the used units of the non-stock item provided recurrently.  You can affect the contract usage in the following ways: Using Cases : You can associate a case with a contract. To recognize the billable time      of the case as usage of a contract item, you should assign a non-stock item that is provided      recurrently to a case class that is billed on a per-case basis. When a case of this class is      closed and released, its billable time is added to the usage of the contract item. The billable      time of cases associated with non-stock items that are not included in the contract is      presented on the invoice as a separate line. For details on using contracts for case billing,      see  Usage-Based Contracts. Using Case Activities : If a case belongs to a case class that is billed on a      per-activity basis, you can associate the case with a contract as well. When a case activity is      completed and released, the respective transaction can be viewed on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT303000|CT303000]) Contract Usage (CT303000) form. The billable time of activities associated with      non-stock items that are not included in the contract is presented on the invoice as a separate      line. For details on using contracts for activity billing, see  Usage-Based Contracts. Using Expense Claims : You can associate the details of expense claims with a      contract. After an expense claim is billed, a transaction for the details associated with the      contract can be viewed on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT303000|CT303000]) Contract Usage form. The quantity of details      associated with non-stock items that are not included in the contract is presented on the      invoice as a separate line. For details on managing expense claims, see  Processing Expense Claims. Using Employee Time Activities : You can associate a time activity of a particular      employee with a contract. When the time activity is released, the respective transaction can be      viewed on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT303000|CT303000]) Contract Usage form. The billable time of activities associated      with non-stock items that are not included in the contract is presented on the invoice as a      separate line. For details on managing the time activities of employees, see  Reporting Time. Associating an employee's time activity with a contract is       available only if the Customer Management feature is disabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features form.  Using Non-Stock Items : You can associate the usage of any non-stock item with a      contract by using the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT303000|CT303000]) Contract Usage form. The usage of non-stock items that      are not included in the contract is presented on the invoice as a separate line. For details on      entering usage transactions, see  To Enter Contract Usage. You can enter item usage for past, current, and future billing periods. If you have entered     transactions with a date in a past billing period, they will be invoiced in the next billing     period. If you have entered a transaction with a date in the future, the transaction will be     invoiced in the billing period that contains the date. When you run the contract billing     process, the system checks the date of transactions and bills those with a date before or the     same as the current business date. Records of usage transactions are presented as invoice     details according to the billing format settings of the applicable contract template. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="2235278e-0eae-4667-8821-fe920f3410d7" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="3a991113-1576-44f1-8c24-d0fd9644950a" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
You use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_30_00|Contract Usage] (CT 30.30.00) form to enter contract usage. 
==To Enter a Usage Transaction==[anchor|#_fbd93a9d-fab2-4a5a-bf0d-67f72a69f0c4]
#Open the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_30_00|Contract Usage] ([~/?ScreenId=CT303000|CT303000]) form.
#In the '''Contract ID''' box, select the contract for which you want to enter usage.
#On the '''Unbilled Transactions''' tab, do the following for each transaction:
##Click '''Add Row''' on the table toolbar.
##:The branch from which you are signed in and the current business date are filled automatically. You can modify the values in all columns.
##In the '''Inventory ID''' column, select the non-stock item that you want to bill the customer for.
##In the '''Qauntity''' column, type the number of used units.
##On the form toolbar, click '''Save'''.

You run the contract billing process to bill entered transactions. For details on contract billing, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__con_Contract_Billing|Contract Billing].]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[To Enter Contract Usage You use the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT303000|CT303000]) Contract Usage (CT 30.30.00) form to enter contract                 usage.  To Enter a Usage Transaction Open the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT303000|CT303000]) Contract Usage (CT303000) form. In the  Contract ID  box, select the contract for which you                 want to enter usage. On the  Unbilled Transactions  tab, do the following for each                     transaction: Click  Add Row  on the table toolbar. The branch from                             which you are signed in and the current business date are filled                             automatically. You can modify the values in all columns. In the  Inventory ID  column, select the non-stock item                         that you want to bill the customer for. In the  Qauntity  column, type the number of used                         units. On the form toolbar, click  Save . You run the contract billing process to bill entered transactions. For details on                 contract billing, see  Contract Billing. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="5421a6e4-bf86-4e0f-9e02-f8063fd5da76" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="07b66042-acef-dfcd-294f-665236024378" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
You use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_30_00|Contract Usage] (CT 30.30.00) form to view all usage transactions associated with a contract. To view the usage of contract items provided recurrently, you use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_10_00|Customer Contracts] ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) form.
==To View All Contract Transactions==[anchor|#_434f3185-fa6d-4736-a5d0-45377def7f7c]
#Open the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_30_00|Contract Usage] ([~/?ScreenId=CT303000|CT303000]) form.
#In the '''Contract ID''' box, select the contract you want to view transactions for.
#To view unbilled transactions, click the '''Unbilled Transactions''' tab, which shows the list of transactions that have not yet been invoiced.
#To view invoiced transactions, click the '''Transactions History''' tab. 
#:You can select a post period to narrow the results.

==To View Contract Item Usage==[anchor|#_ffb40dfc-a760-41c0-ac58-3606058de50d]
#Open the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_10_00|Customer Contracts] ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) form.
#In the '''Contract ID''' box, select the contract for which you want to view usage.
#On the '''Recurring Summary''' tab, view the list of contract items provided recurrently in the table.
#:For each contract item listed in the table, you can view:[anchor|#_481eae6e-141d-4411-88af-5c0915c19669]
#*In the '''Included''' column, the usage included in the contract by default and billed at the recurring price. (If the included usage is exceeded, the customer is billed for additional units at the price for extra usage specified in the respective contract item.)
#*In the '''Unbilled''' column, the usage accumulated for the current billing period.
#*In the '''Used Total''' column, the total usage accumulated from the contract activation date. 
]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[To View Contract Usage You use the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT303000|CT303000]) Contract Usage (CT 30.30.00) form to view all usage                 transactions associated with a contract. To view the usage of contract items                 provided recurrently, you use the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) Customer Contracts (CT301000)                 form. To View All Contract Transactions Open the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT303000|CT303000]) Contract Usage (CT303000) form. In the  Contract ID  box, select the contract you want to view transactions for. To view unbilled transactions, click the  Unbilled Transactions  tab, which                 shows the list of transactions that have not yet been invoiced. To view invoiced transactions, click the  Transactions History  tab.  You can select a post period to narrow the results. To View Contract Item Usage Open the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) Customer Contracts (CT301000) form. In the  Contract ID  box, select the contract for which you want to view                 usage. On the  Recurring Summary  tab, view the list of contract items provided recurrently in the table. For each contract item listed in the table, you can view: In the  Included  column, the usage included in the contract by default and billed at the recurring price. (If the included usage is exceeded, the customer is billed for additional units at the price for extra usage specified in the respective contract item.) In the  Unbilled  column, the usage accumulated for the current billing period. In the  Used Total  column, the total usage accumulated from the contract activation date.  ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="ea1c99c8-fce7-49a7-b9b1-42b15e83d821" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="61dee489-0e94-20bc-8043-094bd500af71" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
After contract usage has been recorded, you should begin billing for the usage. When you run the contract billing process, the system produces an invoice. The invoice is generated with the ''Balanced'' status or with the ''On Hold'' status, if the '''Hold Documents on Entry''' check box is selected on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AR_10_10_00|Accounts Receivable Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=AR101000|AR101000]) form. {br}

You can then review and release a particular invoice by using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AR_30_10_00|Invoices and Memos] ([~/?ScreenId=AR301000|AR301000]) form. You can also release multiple invoices at a time, by using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AR_50_10_00|Release AR Documents] ([~/?ScreenId=AR501000|AR501000]) mass-processing form. {br}

This topic describes the source of invoice details and common billing scenarios.
==Source of Invoice Details==
The system gets most details for the invoice by using the non-stock item that is used to track this usage, as described in [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__CON_Contract_Usage|Contract Usage Recording]. The non-stock item provides the following information:[anchor|#ul_owp_1yz_wn]
*''Basis for Unit Price'': The unit price is calculated by using the price of the non-stock item. If the non-stock item is included in the contract item, then the system calculates the unit price by applying the rules specified in the contract item to the non-stock item price selected by the system. The rules used by the system for the price selection are described in [HelpRoot_PricesAndDiscounts\PriceDiscount_Sales_Price_Selection_GeneralInfo|Automatic Price Selection: Rules of Price Selection]. 
*''Sales Account'': This is the General Ledger account used to record sale transactions of this non-stock item. You specify the sales account by using the '''GL Accounts''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\IN_20_20_00|Non-Stock Items] ([~/?ScreenId=IN202000|IN202000]) form.
*''Sales Subaccount'': The sales subaccount is the subaccount used to record sale transactions of this non-stock item. The subaccount is combined automatically according the rule defined in the '''Combine Sales Sub.''' from box on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AR_10_10_00|Accounts Receivable Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=AR101000|AR101000]) form. 
*''Tax Category'': This is the category Acumatica ERP uses to calculate the taxes applied to supplying goods or services. For details, see [HelpRoot_Financials\Taxes_TaxZones_and_Categories_Mapref|Creating Tax Zones and Tax Categories].

==Common Billing Scenarios==
In Acumatica ERP, you can configure different billing scenarios to suit your business needs. You can bill a customer on a schedule or on demand, as described below:[anchor|#ul_gjw_42l_pm]
*''Scheduled billing'': Scheduled billing is the most common way to bill customers recurrently. The duration of the contract is divided into equal time intervals, which are the billing periods. Billing is performed once in a billing period, causing one invoice to be generated per billing period. The system calculates billing dates by using the date when the contract&rsquo;s billing schedule is started and the contract&rsquo;s billing period—which is used as an incrementation step. You can select one of the following steps: week, month, quarter, or year. The billing schedule for a contract can be viewed on the '''Summary''' tab on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_10_00|Customer Contracts] ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) form. Here you can see the start date of the billing schedule, the billing period, the date of the last invoice, and the date of the next invoice. When you run contract billing, the system generates an invoice with the next billing date and shifts the schedule dates on the incrementation step. Invoices can be viewed on the '''AR History''' tab of a contract. Additionally, you can define for each recurrent contract item whether it is billed at the beginning of the billing periods or at the end of it. If you have not billed a contract for two or more periods, you have to run the billing process for each missed period.
*:((({S:Warn}If the duration of the contract can not be divided into equal time intervals, that is the last billing period is longer or shorter, the system will prorate the invoiced amount for the recurring contract items respectively.
)))
*''Billing on demand'': You can provide services on demand, rather than recurrently. In this case, you might want to perform contract billing any time services have been provided. An invoice with the date you have specified is generated each time you run contract billing.

You can run contract billing for a particular contract on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_10_00|Customer Contracts] form, use the mass-processing [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_50_10_00|Run Contract Billing] form to run billing for multiple contracts, or configure the automation schedule functionality for contract billing.
==Related Articles==
*[HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__HOW_Run_Contract_Billing|To Run Contract Billing]
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_10_00|Customer Contracts] ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_50_10_00|Run Contract Billing] ([~/?ScreenId=CT501000|CT501000])]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Contract Billing After contract usage has been recorded, you should begin billing for the usage. When you 			run the contract billing process, the system produces an invoice. The invoice is 			generated with the  Balanced  status or with the  On Hold  status, if the 				 Hold Documents on Entry  check box is selected on the   ([~/?ScreenId=AR101000|AR101000]) Accounts Receivable Preferences (AR101000) form.  You can then review and release a particular invoice by using the   ([~/?ScreenId=AR301000|AR301000]) Invoices and Memos (AR301000) form. You can also release 			multiple invoices at a time, by using the   ([~/?ScreenId=AR501000|AR501000]) Release AR Documents 			(AR501000) mass-processing form.  This topic describes the source of invoice details and common billing scenarios. Source of Invoice Details The system gets most details for the invoice by using the non-stock item that is used 				to track this usage, as described in  Contract Usage Recording. The 				non-stock item provides the following information: Basis for Unit Price : The unit price is calculated by using the price of 					the non-stock item. If the non-stock item is included in the contract item, then 					the system calculates the unit price by applying the rules specified in the 					contract item to the non-stock item price selected by the system. The rules used 					by the system for the price selection are described in  Automatic Price Selection: Rules of Price Selection.  Sales Account : This is the General Ledger account used to record sale 					transactions of this non-stock item. You specify the sales account by using the 						 GL Accounts  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=IN202000|IN202000]) Non-Stock Items (IN202000) form. Sales Subaccount : The sales subaccount is the subaccount used to record 					sale transactions of this non-stock item. The subaccount is combined 					automatically according the rule defined in the  Combine Sales 						Sub.  from box on the   ([~/?ScreenId=AR101000|AR101000]) Accounts Receivable Preferences (AR101000) 					form.  Tax Category : This is the category  Acumatica ERP uses to calculate the taxes applied to supplying goods or services. For 					details, see  Creating Tax Zones and Tax Categories. Common Billing Scenarios In  Acumatica ERP, you can configure different billing scenarios to suit your business needs. You 				can bill a customer on a schedule or on demand, as described below: Scheduled billing : Scheduled billing is the most common way to bill 					customers recurrently. The duration of the contract is divided into equal time 					intervals, which are the billing periods. Billing is performed once in a billing 					period, causing one invoice to be generated per billing period. The system 					calculates billing dates by using the date when the contract's billing schedule 					is started and the contract's billing period—which is used as an 					incrementation step. You can select one of the following steps: week, month, 					quarter, or year. The billing schedule for a contract can be viewed on the 						 Summary  tab on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) Customer Contracts (CT301000) form. Here you can see the start date of the 					billing schedule, the billing period, the date of the last invoice, and the date 					of the next invoice. When you run contract billing, the system generates an 					invoice with the next billing date and shifts the schedule dates on the 					incrementation step. Invoices can be viewed on the  AR 						History  tab of a contract. Additionally, you can define for each 					recurrent contract item whether it is billed at the beginning of the billing 					periods or at the end of it. If you have not billed a contract for two or more 					periods, you have to run the billing process for each missed period. If the 						duration of the contract can not be divided into equal time intervals, that 						is the last billing period is longer or shorter, the system will prorate the 						invoiced amount for the recurring contract items respectively. Billing on demand : You can provide services on demand, rather than 					recurrently. In this case, you might want to perform contract billing any time 					services have been provided. An invoice with the date you have specified is 					generated each time you run contract billing. You can run contract billing for a particular contract on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) Customer Contracts form, use the mass-processing   ([~/?ScreenId=CT501000|CT501000]) Run Contract Billing form to run billing for multiple contracts, or 				configure the automation schedule functionality for contract billing.  ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000])  ([~/?ScreenId=CT501000|CT501000]) ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="dc9abf2a-10bd-4494-834a-e6d9840c198d" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="6679f782-1a6c-0d9f-350a-4d0918b14238" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
You use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_10_00|Customer Contracts] ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) form to run the billing process for a contract as long as the contract has the ''Active'' or ''Pending Upgrade'' status. You use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_50_10_00|Run Contract Billing] ([~/?ScreenId=CT501000|CT501000]) form to run the billing process for a number of contracts at once. 
==To Run Billing Process For a Contract ==[anchor|#_22da7a66-b734-42dc-a90c-115dc704034a]
#Open the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_10_00|Customer Contracts] ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) form.
#In the '''Contract ID''' box, select the contract you want to bill.
#Click '''Actions''' and then select '''Run Contract Billing'''.
#: If the selected contract is configured to be billed on demand, the '''Billing On Demand''' dialog box is displayed, where you can enter the invoice date. If the operation completes successfully, the green check mark appears on the form toolbar.

After the operation completes, you can view and further process the generated invoice on the '''AR History''' tab of the form.
==To Run Billing Process for Multiple Contracts==[anchor|#_6fcc2818-5b54-4bf3-b86e-5011edd3cbfb]
#Open the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_50_10_00|Run Contract Billing] ([~/?ScreenId=CT501000|CT501000]) form.
#In the '''Billing Date''' box in the Selection area, select the date of billing. The list of contracts that require billing on that date is generated.
#Optional: Narrow the list of contracts by selecting any combination of a contract template, a customer class, and a particular customer. 
#Do one of the following: 
#*To bill all listed contracts, click '''Process All'''.
#*To bill only selected contracts, select the unlabeled check boxes for the contracts you want to bill, and click '''Process'''. 
#:If the contracts were billed successfully, the system marks them with green check marks. When you initiate billing for all contracts or selected ones, invoices are generated for each contract and each customer involved. You can view and further process generated invoices on the '''AR History''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_10_00|Customer Contracts] ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) form for each contract. Also, you can use invoice-related forms for further processing. For details, see [HelpRoot_Financials\Finance_ARInvoices_Mapref|Processing AR Invoices].
]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[To Run Contract Billing You use the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) Customer Contracts (CT301000) form to run                 the billing process for a contract as long as the contract has the  Active  or                      Pending Upgrade  status. You use the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT501000|CT501000]) Run Contract Billing (CT501000) form to run the billing process for a number of                 contracts at once.  To Run Billing Process For a Contract  Open the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) Customer Contracts (CT301000) form. In the  Contract ID  box, select the contract you want to bill. Click  Actions  and then select  Run Contract Billing .  If the selected contract is configured to be billed on demand, the  Billing On Demand  dialog box is displayed, where you can enter the invoice date. If the operation completes successfully, the green check mark appears on the form toolbar. After the operation completes, you can view and further process the generated invoice                 on the  AR History  tab of the form. To Run Billing Process for Multiple Contracts Open the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT501000|CT501000]) Run Contract Billing (CT501000) form. In the  Billing Date  box in the Selection area, select the                 date of billing. The list of contracts that require billing on that date is                 generated. Optional: Narrow the list of contracts by selecting any combination of a contract                 template, a customer class, and a particular customer.  Do one of the following:  To bill all listed contracts, click  Process All . To bill only selected contracts, select the unlabeled check boxes for the                         contracts you want to bill, and click  Process .  If the contracts were billed successfully, the system marks them with green                     check marks. When you initiate billing for all contracts or selected ones,                     invoices are generated for each contract and each customer involved. You can                     view and further process generated invoices on the  AR                         History  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) Customer Contracts (CT301000) form for each contract. Also, you can use                     invoice-related forms for further processing. For details, see  Processing AR Invoices. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="e5aaba2f-a9e5-4ea9-bd25-30ab829ab75a" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="31f087e3-2d48-a779-cc61-9053722b68f8" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
Changing a contract&rsquo;s terms of provision may involve changes in services, prices, or quantities. You can add or delete services, change the included quantity, or apply a discount. Note that you can change the set of provided services for contracts that are based on templates that allow overriding of contract items. {br}

Contract upgrades and downgrades are performed in two stages: preparation and activation. During the preparation stage, you modify provisioning terms, but contract billing and service provision are performed according to the initial settings of the contract. When the changes are activated, contract billing and service provision are performed according to the new settings. 
==To Change a Contract Services ==
You use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_10_00|Customer Contracts] ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) form to change services of a contract with the ''Active'' status as follows:[anchor|#ol_d5f_btm_pm]
#On the '''Finance''' tab, click '''Accounts Receivable'''. In the navigation pane, click the '''Work Area''' tab and then navigate to '''Manage''' > '''Customer Contracts'''.
#In the '''Contract ID''' box, select the contract you want to upgrade.
#Click '''Actions''', and select '''Upgrade Contract'''. 
#:This gives the contract the ''Pending Upgrade'' status, which means that you can change the terms of provision.
#On the '''Details''' tab, modify the list of services or their quantity, or apply a discount.
#Click '''Save''' to save your changes.
#Click '''Actions''', and select the '''Activate Upgrade''' action. In the '''Activate Contract''' dialog box, specify the date of contract activation and click '''OK'''. 
#:If the operation is completed successfully, the green check mark appears on the form toolbar.
]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Changes to Contract Services  Changing a contract's terms of provision may involve changes in services, prices, or    quantities. You can add or delete services, change the included quantity, or apply a discount.    Note that you can change the set of provided services for contracts that are based on templates    that allow overriding of contract items.  Contract upgrades and downgrades are performed in two stages: preparation and activation.    During the preparation stage, you modify provisioning terms, but contract billing and service    provision are performed according to the initial settings of the contract. When the changes are    activated, contract billing and service provision are performed according to the new settings.  To Change a Contract Services  You use the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) Customer Contracts (CT301000) form to change     services of a contract with the  Active  status as follows: On the  Finance  tab, click  Accounts Receivable .      In the navigation pane, click the  Work Area  tab and then navigate to  Manage Customer Contracts . In the  Contract ID  box, select the contract you want to upgrade. Click  Actions , and select  Upgrade Contract .        This gives the contract the  Pending Upgrade  status, which means that you can change       the terms of provision. On the  Details  tab, modify the list of services or their quantity, or      apply a discount. Click  Save  to save your changes. Click  Actions , and select the  Activate Upgrade       action. In the  Activate Contract  dialog box, specify the date of      contract activation and click  OK .  If the operation is completed       successfully, the green check mark appears on the form toolbar. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="0738906a-388e-475d-9c5d-fff64fe5738e" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="125c6a3c-5c46-bcd1-7d90-5637a6f9431b" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
When a contract has expired or about to expire, your company and your customer may want to continue the relationship under the same terms. In this case, you can renew an expired contract to avoid the provision of services being interrupted. {br}

You can track contracts that are about to expire by using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_40_10_00|Expiring Customer Contracts] ([~/?ScreenId=CT401000|CT401000]) form.{br}

In this topic, you will read about details of renewing a contract.{br}{TOC}
==Setup of Contract Renewal==
You define a renewal fee by adding to a template (or to a contract) a contract item for which the renewal part is configured. For details, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__CON_Contract_Items|Contract Items].{br}

The contract renewal process and its outcome are defined by the contract type, which you specify in the contract template. Contracts of the ''Renewable'' or ''Expiring'' type can be renewed. For details, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__CON_Contract_Templates|Contract Templates].{br}

Also, by selecting the '''Mass Renewal''' check box on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_20_20_00|Contract Templates] ([~/?ScreenId=CT202000|CT202000]) form, you can indicate to the system that contracts to be based on the selected template are available for mass renewal—that is, they will be displayed on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_50_20_00|Renew Contracts] ([~/?ScreenId=CT502000|CT502000]) form. Additionally, in the '''Renewal Point''' box on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_20_20_00|Contract Templates] form, you can specify the number of days before the contract expiration date when the system starts to display the contract on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_50_20_00|Renew Contracts] form.
==Initiation of the Renewal Process==
You initiate the renewal process for a particular contract by clicking the '''Renew Contract''' action on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_10_00|Customer Contracts] ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) form.{br}

If the '''Mass Renewal''' check box is selected for the contract and the date when you want to renew the contract is the same as or later than the contract expiration date minus the number of days specified in the '''Renewal Point''' box, the contract is displayed on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_50_20_00|Renew Contracts] mass processing form.
==Renewal of Renewable Contracts==
The renewal process can be run for the contracts of the ''Renewable'' type that comply with the following:[anchor|#ol_z3k_kfs_cs]
*The contract status is ''Active'' or ''Expired''
*The contract fulfillment stage is in its last billing period

If a contract complies with these criteria, the '''Renew Contract''' action is available for the contract on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_10_00|Customer Contracts] form.{br}

You should specify the renewal date for a contract before you run the renewal process. The system uses this date to define whether the contract grace period has ended and to issue the invoice for a renewal fee (if any). Also, this date is used to record the renewal action on the '''Contract History''' tab.{br}

When you renew a contract of the ''Renewable'' type, the system compares the renewal date to the end date of the contract grace period.{br}

If the renewal date is earlier than or the same as the end date of the grace period, the system does the following:[anchor|#ul_qcz_grs_cs]
*Shifts the expiration date of the contract by the duration; otherwise, contract stays unchanged. 
*Bills the renewal fee, if one is configured, and issues the renewal invoice on the renewal date. 

After renewal is completed, the contract is again in the fulfillment stage and the recurring billing is performed according to the schedule defined in the '''Billing Schedule''' section on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_10_00|Customer Contracts] form.{br}

If you want to renew a contract after the end of the grace period, the system does the following:[anchor|#ul_ff2_ltx_cs]
*Creates a copy of the original contract with the ''Draft'' status.
*Leaves the current status of the original contract (''Active'' or ''Expired'') unchanged.

You can modify the new details of the contract, if required, and activate it on the date of your choice. For details on contract activation, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__CON_Contract_Signing|Contract Setup and Activation].{br}

If the status of the original contract is ''Active'' and it is fully billed, the system changes the status to ''Expired'' when you activate the new contract. If the original contract is not fully billed yet, the system warns you that the new contract could not be activated until the original contract is fully billed.
==Renewal of Expiring Contracts==
The renewal process can be run for the contracts of the ''Expiring'' type that comply with the following:[anchor|#ul_ebw_mkp_2s]
*The contract status is ''Active'' or ''Expired''
*The contract fulfillment stage is in its last billing period

If a contract complies with these criteria, the '''Renew Contract''' action is available for the contract on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_10_00|Customer Contracts] form.((({S:Warn}The '''Renew Contract''' action is always available for the contracts of the ''Expiring'' type with the billing period set to ''On Demand''.
)))
You specify the renewal date before you run the renewal process. The system uses this date to record the renewal action on the '''Contract History''' tab.{br}

When you renew a contract of the ''Expiring'' type, the system does the following:[anchor|#ul_jvw_w5x_cs]
*Creates a copy of the original contract with the ''Draft'' status.
*Leaves the current status of the original contract (''Active'' or ''Expired'') unchanged.

 You can modify the new contract details, if required, and activate the contract on the date of your choice. Before you activate the new contract, make sure that the original contract is fully billed. That is, make sure that the invoice for an included fee is issued and there is no usage that requires billing.((({S:Warn}You can delete unbilled usage if you are not going to bill it.
)))
==Related Articles==
*[HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__CON_Contract_Signing|Contract Setup and Activation]
*[HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__HOW_Renew_Contract|To Renew a Contract]
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_10_00|Customer Contracts] ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_50_20_00|Renew Contracts] ([~/?ScreenId=CT502000|CT502000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_40_10_00|Expiring Customer Contracts] ([~/?ScreenId=CT401000|CT401000])]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Contract Renewal When a contract has expired or about to expire, your company and your customer may want to     continue the relationship under the same terms. In this case, you can renew an expired contract     to avoid the provision of services being interrupted.  You can track contracts that are about to expire by using the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT401000|CT401000]) Expiring Customer Contracts     (CT401000) form. In this topic, you will read about details of renewing a contract. Setup of Contract Renewal You define a renewal fee by adding to a template (or to a contract) a contract item for which     the renewal part is configured. For details, see  Contract Items. The contract renewal process and its outcome are defined by the contract type, which you     specify in the contract template. Contracts of the  Renewable  or  Expiring  type can     be renewed. For details, see  Contract Templates. Also, by selecting the  Mass Renewal  check box on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT202000|CT202000]) Contract Templates (CT202000) form, you can indicate to the system that contracts to     be based on the selected template are available for mass renewal—that is, they will be     displayed on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT502000|CT502000]) Renew Contracts (CT502000) form. Additionally, in the       Renewal Point  box on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT202000|CT202000]) Contract Templates form, you can     specify the number of days before the contract expiration date when the system starts to display     the contract on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT502000|CT502000]) Renew Contracts form. Initiation of the Renewal Process You initiate the renewal process for a particular contract by clicking the  Renew      Contract  action on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) Customer Contracts (CT301000) form. If the  Mass Renewal  check box is selected for the contract and the date     when you want to renew the contract is the same as or later than the contract expiration date     minus the number of days specified in the  Renewal Point  box, the contract     is displayed on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT502000|CT502000]) Renew Contracts mass processing form. Renewal of Renewable Contracts The renewal process can be run for the contracts of the  Renewable  type that comply with     the following: The contract status is  Active  or  Expired The contract fulfillment stage is in its last billing period If a contract complies with these criteria, the  Renew Contract  action     is available for the contract on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) Customer Contracts form. You should specify the renewal date for a contract before you run the renewal process. The     system uses this date to define whether the contract grace period has ended and to issue the     invoice for a renewal fee (if any). Also, this date is used to record the renewal action on the       Contract History  tab. When you renew a contract of the  Renewable  type, the system compares the renewal date     to the end date of the contract grace period. If the renewal date is earlier than or the same as the end date of the grace period, the     system does the following: Shifts the expiration date of the contract by the duration; otherwise, contract stays      unchanged.  Bills the renewal fee, if one is configured, and issues the renewal invoice on the renewal      date.  After renewal is completed, the contract is again in the fulfillment stage and the recurring     billing is performed according to the schedule defined in the  Billing      Schedule  section on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) Customer Contracts form. If you want to renew a contract after the end of the grace period, the system does the     following: Creates a copy of the original contract with the  Draft  status. Leaves the current status of the original contract ( Active  or  Expired )      unchanged. You can modify the new details of the contract, if required, and activate it on the date of     your choice. For details on contract activation, see  Contract Setup and Activation. If the status of the original contract is  Active  and it is fully billed, the system     changes the status to  Expired  when you activate the new contract. If the original     contract is not fully billed yet, the system warns you that the new contract could not be     activated until the original contract is fully billed. Renewal of Expiring Contracts The renewal process can be run for the contracts of the  Expiring  type that comply with     the following: The contract status is  Active  or  Expired The contract fulfillment stage is in its last billing period If a contract complies with these criteria, the  Renew Contract  action     is available for the contract on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) Customer Contracts form. The  Renew Contract  action is always available for the contracts of     the  Expiring  type with the billing period set to  On Demand . You specify the renewal date before you run the renewal process. The system uses this date to     record the renewal action on the  Contract History  tab. When you renew a contract of the  Expiring  type, the system does the following: Creates a copy of the original contract with the  Draft  status. Leaves the current status of the original contract ( Active  or  Expired )      unchanged.  You can modify the new contract details, if required, and activate the contract on the date     of your choice. Before you activate the new contract, make sure that the original contract is     fully billed. That is, make sure that the invoice for an included fee is issued and there is no     usage that requires billing. You can delete unbilled usage if you are not going to bill it.  ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000])  ([~/?ScreenId=CT502000|CT502000])  ([~/?ScreenId=CT401000|CT401000]) ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="935ecf6e-daaa-4938-91f3-298a7842488c" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="0b8c67fc-980b-4ebc-b5a7-7237200ed845" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
You use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_10_00|Customer Contracts] ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) form to renew a single contract. To renew multiple contracts at once, you use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_50_20_00|Renew Contracts] ([~/?ScreenId=CT502000|CT502000]) form. 
==To Renew a Contract==[anchor|#_dd75055d-80e4-4c7e-b152-da0c54cf7929]
#Open the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_10_00|Customer Contracts] ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) form.
#In the '''Contract ID''' box, select the contract you want to renew.
#Click '''Actions''', and select '''Renew Contract'''. 
#In the '''Renew Contract''' dialog box, specify the date of the renewal in the '''Renewal Date''' box.
#Click '''OK'''. 

If the operation is completed successfully, one of the following occurs:[anchor|#ul_q3p_2lm_pm]
*For a renewable contract, the expiration date is shifted by its duration and the renewal fee is billed. After the renewal operation is completed, you can view and further process the generated invoice on the '''AR History''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_10_00|Customer Contracts] form.
*For an expiring contract, another contract (which is a copy of the expiring contract with a new identifier) is created with the ''Draft'' status. You can view all related contracts (both original and new) on the '''Contract History''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_10_00|Customer Contracts] form. 

==To Renew Multiple Contracts==
You can also renew multiple contracts at once, as long as each of the contracts has the '''Mass Renewal''' check box selected on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_10_00|Customer Contracts] form. To renew multiple contracts, do the following:[anchor|#_70fac408-7821-4a1c-8b65-515ff273ec11]
#Open the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_50_20_00|Renew Contracts] ([~/?ScreenId=CT502000|CT502000]) form.
#In the '''Renewal Date''' box in the Selection area, specify the date of the renewal. The table displays the list of contracts available for renewal on this date. 
#Optional: Narrow the list of contracts to be displayed by selecting a customer class, a contract template, or both.
#Do one of the following: 
#*To renew all listed contracts, click '''Process All'''.
#*To renew only selected contracts, select the unlabeled check boxes for the contracts you want to renew, and click '''Process'''. 
#:If the contracts are renewed successfully, the system marks them with green check marks. You can view and further process the generated invoices on the '''AR History''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_10_00|Customer Contracts] ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) form for each contract. Also, you can use invoice-related forms for further processing. For details, see [HelpRoot_Financials\Finance_ARInvoices_Mapref|Processing AR Invoices]. 
]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[To Renew a Contract You use the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) Customer Contracts (CT301000) form to renew                 a single contract. To renew multiple contracts at once, you use the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT502000|CT502000]) Renew Contracts (CT502000) form.  To Renew a Contract Open the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) Customer Contracts (CT301000) form. In the  Contract ID  box, select the contract you want to renew. Click  Actions , and select  Renew Contract .  In the  Renew Contract  dialog box, specify the date of the renewal in the  Renewal Date  box. Click  OK .  If the operation is completed successfully, one of the following occurs: For a renewable contract, the expiration date is shifted by its duration and                         the renewal fee is billed. After the renewal operation is completed, you can                         view and further process the generated invoice on the  AR                             History  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) Customer Contracts                         form. For an expiring contract, another contract (which is a copy of the expiring                         contract with a new identifier) is created with the  Draft  status. You                         can view all related contracts (both original and new) on the                              Contract History  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) Customer Contracts form.  To Renew Multiple Contracts You can also renew multiple contracts at once, as long as each of the contracts has                 the  Mass Renewal  check box selected on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) Customer Contracts form. To renew multiple contracts, do                 the following: Open the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT502000|CT502000]) Renew Contracts (CT502000) form. In the  Renewal Date  box in the Selection area, specify the                 date of the renewal. The table displays the list of contracts available for renewal                 on this date.  Optional: Narrow the list of contracts to be displayed by selecting a customer                 class, a contract template, or both. Do one of the following:  To renew all listed contracts, click  Process                         All . To renew only selected contracts, select the unlabeled check boxes for the                         contracts you want to renew, and click  Process .  If the contracts are renewed successfully, the system marks them with green                     check marks. You can view and further process the generated invoices on the                          AR History  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) Customer Contracts (CT301000) form for                     each contract. Also, you can use invoice-related forms for further processing.                     For details, see  Processing AR Invoices.                  ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="b1fb48b2-2169-434c-9370-ff609642245f" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="2fe4ee8e-8f98-441a-2f82-6402d2b15ed1" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
 Acumatica ERP provides you with different scenarios of billing a customer by using contracts, as the following sections describe.
==Contracts with Scheduled Billing==
Common examples of contracts with recurring billing that can be handled in Acumatica ERP include the following, each of which is described in its own topic:[anchor|#ul_cxr_qdf_zm]
*[HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__CON_Fixed_Price_Contracts|Fixed-Price Contracts]
*[HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__CON_Usage_Contracts|Usage-Based Contracts]
*[HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__CON_Deposit_Contract|Retainer Contracts]
*[HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__CON_LaborItemSelectionRules|Employee Rates for Contracts]

==Contracts with Billing on Demand==
You may want to have the ability to provide a customer with a service or solution at any time and bill the customer as needed. To implement such a scenario, do the following:[anchor|#ol_jzs_1ns_ym]
#Create an active contract template with the billing period set to ''On Demand'', and do not add any contract items. Prepare a contract with the ''Draft'' status based on this template. For details, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__CON_Contract_Preparation|Contract Preparation].
#:((({S:Warn}If you add recurring contract items to contracts that are billed on demand, we recommend to specify zero included quantity for these contract items.
)))
#Set up and activate the contract. The contract status is changed to ''Active'' and you can record contract usage. For more information, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__CON_Contract_Signing|Contract Setup and Activation].
#For the contract, enter the usage of the non-stock items that correspond to the services or solutions provided to this customer. For details, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__HOW_Enter_Contract_Usage|To Enter Contract Usage].
#Bill the contract any time you need to, as described in [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__HOW_Run_Contract_Billing|To Run Contract Billing].
]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Contract Examples  Acumatica ERP provides you with different scenarios of billing a customer by using contracts, as the         following sections describe. Contracts with Scheduled Billing Common examples of contracts with recurring billing that can be handled in  Acumatica ERP include the following, each of which is described in its own topic: Fixed-Price ContractsUsage-Based ContractsRetainer ContractsEmployee Rates for ContractsContracts with Billing on Demand You may want to have the ability to provide a customer with a service or solution at any         time and bill the customer as needed. To implement such a scenario, do the following: Create an active contract template with the billing period set to  On Demand , and           do not add any contract items. Prepare a contract with the  Draft  status based on           this template. For details, see  Contract Preparation. If             you add recurring contract items to contracts that are billed on demand, we recommend to             specify zero included quantity for these contract items. Set up and activate the contract. The contract status is changed to  Active  and           you can record contract usage. For more information, see  Contract Setup and Activation. For the contract, enter the usage of the non-stock items that correspond to the services           or solutions provided to this customer. For details, see  To Enter Contract Usage. Bill the contract any time you need to, as described in  To Run Contract Billing. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="b786a4d1-43a3-4302-a77e-ba9db83ff3e0" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="0f66d101-cd8d-5c7c-005b-b83925b9fcc4" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
You may offer services at a price that is not based on the service&rsquo;s usage, as with a fee for internet connection or domain name registration. You generally collect such a fee on a schedule—for example, once a year or on a monthly basis.{br}

 Consider an example: You offer domain name registration and maintenance for a year with renewal. To implement such a scenario, do the following:[anchor|#ol_hyb_1qy_ym]
#By using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\IN_20_20_00|Non-Stock Items] ([~/?ScreenId=IN202000|IN202000]) form, create ''Domain Name Registration'' and ''Maintenance'' non-stock items that represent services you offer.
#On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_20_10_00|Contract Items] ([~/?ScreenId=CT201000|CT201000]) form, configure a contract item as follows: 
#*In the '''Setup Item''' box, select the ''Domain Name Registration'' non-stock item, and specify the pricing policy for the setup item. You provide a domain name and bill for it during the contract setup stage.
#*In the '''Renewal Item''' box, select the ''Maintenance'' non-stock item, and specify the pricing policy for the renewal item. You provide a maintenance item only after renewal and bill for it when the contract is renewed.
#*To bill the customer for maintenance during the first year, select the '''Collect Renewal Fee on Activation''' check box. The fee for the renewal item will be included in the first invoice.
#*Fill in other required settings (and any optional ones) at your discretion. 
#:For details on configuring contract items, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__HOW_Configure_Contract_Item|To Configure a Contract Item].
#By using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_20_20_00|Contract Templates] ([~/?ScreenId=CT202000|CT202000]) form, create a contract template as follows:
#*Set the '''Contract Type''' to ''Renewable'' and the '''Duration''' to ''1 Year''.
#*Specify ''Year'' as the '''Billing Period'''.
#*In the '''Billing Schedule Starts On''' box, select ''Setup Date''.
#*Fill in other required settings (and any optional ones) at your discretion.
#*Add the contract item you have configured to the contract template.
#*:For details on configuring a contract template, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__HOW_Configure_Contract_Template|To Configure a Contract Template].
#Set up and activate the contract. An invoice for domain name registration and maintenance is issued automatically as the result of the setup procedure. For more information, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__CON_Contract_Signing|Contract Setup and Activation].
#Renew the contract in a year. An invoice for maintenance only is issued automatically as the result of the renewal procedure. For details, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__CON_Contract_Renewal|Contract Renewal].
{br}

You can combine fixed-price contract items with ones that are billed based on usage. For example, suppose that you provide bandwidth or disk space along with a domain name. In this case, you could include in one contract item a domain name as the setup item and some quantity of disk space as the recurring item, or you could create separate contract items.]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Fixed-Price Contracts You may offer services at a price that is not based on the service's usage, as with a fee for       internet connection or domain name registration. You generally collect such a fee on a       schedule—for example, once a year or on a monthly basis.  Consider an example: You offer domain name registration and maintenance for a year with       renewal. To implement such a scenario, do the following: By using the   ([~/?ScreenId=IN202000|IN202000]) Non-Stock Items (IN202000) form, create  Domain Name             Registration  and  Maintenance  non-stock items that represent services you           offer. On the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT201000|CT201000]) Contract Items (CT201000) form, configure a contract item as           follows:  In the  Setup Item  box, select the  Domain Name                 Registration  non-stock item, and specify the pricing policy for the setup item.               You provide a domain name and bill for it during the contract setup stage. In the  Renewal Item  box, select the  Maintenance                non-stock item, and specify the pricing policy for the renewal item. You provide a               maintenance item only after renewal and bill for it when the contract is renewed. To bill the customer for maintenance during the first year, select the                  Collect Renewal Fee on Activation  check box. The fee for the               renewal item will be included in the first invoice. Fill in other required settings (and any optional ones) at your discretion.  For details on configuring contract items, see  To Configure a Contract Item. By using the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT202000|CT202000]) Contract Templates (CT202000) form, create a contract           template as follows: Set the  Contract Type  to  Renewable  and the                  Duration  to  1 Year . Specify  Year  as the  Billing Period . In the  Billing Schedule Starts On  box, select  Setup                 Date . Fill in other required settings (and any optional ones) at your discretion. Add the contract item you have configured to the contract template. For details on                 configuring a contract template, see  To Configure a Contract Template. Set up and activate the contract. An invoice for domain name registration and           maintenance is issued automatically as the result of the setup procedure. For more           information, see  Contract Setup and Activation. Renew the contract in a year. An invoice for maintenance only is issued automatically as           the result of the renewal procedure. For details, see  Contract Renewal. You can combine fixed-price contract items with ones that are billed based on usage. For       example, suppose that you provide bandwidth or disk space along with a domain name. In this       case, you could include in one contract item a domain name as the setup item and some quantity       of disk space as the recurring item, or you could create separate contract items. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="8f7fdfff-630e-45a1-a234-0fbaec04728a" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="2f633859-92f8-5fa1-b8c6-c2936b3c809f" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
You may offer services at a price that depends on the usage of the service, such as support hours, disk space, or support cases. The contracts functionality of Acumatica ERP can help you to track and bill the usage of a particular service. You can bill customers for services at the regular price and at an extra usage price, and you can provide some quantity for free. You can track the usage of the services that are provided recurrently within a billing period as well as for the whole contract duration.{br}

Consider the examples below.{br}{TOC}[anchor|#free_hours_contract]
==Annual Support with Free Options==
If you offer annual support with free options, you can use Acumatica ERP to implement the following scenarios. Each scenario is described briefly below; see the [[#table_axb_1nl_bm|Settings for the Examples] table for the settings you would use to implement the scenario. You can also refer to procedures that walk you through implementation of each scenario.[anchor|#ul_jds_zhm_bn]
*'''Annual Support With Hours for Free''': To implement this example, use the settings listed in the appropriate column of the table below.
*:Annual support that includes free hours might be structured as follows:
**''The First 10 Hours for Free'': You could offer a contract for annual support with the first 10 hours free and additional hours billed at $100 per hour. The contract is billed monthly. 
**''10 Hours for Free Each Month'': You might offer a contract for annual support with 10 hours free each month and other hours billed at $100 per hour. The contract is billed monthly.
*:To implement examples in which the contract covers annual support with free hours, do the following:
**For a case class that is billed by case, follow the [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__HOW_Billing_Per_Case|To Set Up Billing By Case] procedure.
**For a case class that is billed by case activity, follow the [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__HOW_Billing_Per_Activity|To Set Up Billing By Case Activities] procedure. 
*'''Annual Support With Cases for Free''': To implement this example, too, you use the settings listed in the appropriate column of the table below.
*:Annual support that includes free cases might be structured as follows:
**''The First 10 Cases for Free'': You might offer a contract for annual support with the first 10 cases free and additional cases billed at $100 per case. The contract is billed monthly. 
**''10 Cases for Free Each Month'': You could offer a contract for annual support with 10 free cases each month and additional cases billed at $100 per case. The contract is billed monthly.
*:To implement an example in which the contract covers annual support with free cases, follow the [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__HOW_Billing_Per_Number_Cases|To Set Up Billing by the Number of Cases] procedure. 

==Settings for the Examples==
This table shows the settings you would use to implement each of the examples described above.[anchor|#table_axb_1nl_bm]
{| class="checklist" | width="100%" 
|- 
!width="20%" ! Entity
!width="40%" ! Annual Support With Hours for Free
!width="40%" ! Annual Support With Cases for Free
|- 
| '''Non-Stock Item''' (Use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\IN_20_20_00|Non-Stock Items] form.)
| [anchor|#ul_ixn_dnq_1n]
*'''Inventory ID'''=<tt>SUPPORTHOURS</tt>
*'''Item Status'''=''Active''
* '''Type'''=''Labor''
* '''UOMs'''=''Hours''

| [anchor|#ul_o5t_qcn_bn]
* '''Inventory ID'''=<tt>CASENUMBER</tt>
*'''Item Status'''=''Active''
* '''Type'''=''Non-Stock Item''
* '''UOMs'''=''ITEM''

|- 
|  '''Contract Item''' (Use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_20_10_00|Contract Items] form.)
| [anchor|#ul_lzl_wmq_1n]
*'''Default Quantity'''=''10''
* '''Recurring Item'''=''SUPPORTHOURS''
* '''Reset Usage on Billing''':
**Cleared for the ''The First 10 Hours For Free'' scenario
**Selected for the ''10 Hours For Free Each Month'' scenario
*'''Recurring Pricing'''=''Enter Manually''
* '''Item Price/Percent'''=''0''
* '''Extra Usage Pricing'''=''Enter Manually''
* '''Item Price/Percent'''=''100''

| [anchor|#ul_dnd_rcn_bn]
* '''Default Quantity'''=''10''
* '''Recurring Item'''=''CASENUMBER''
* '''Reset Usage on Billing''':
**Cleared for the ''The First 10 Cases for Free'' scenario
**Selected for the ''10 Cases for Free Each Month'' scenario 
*'''Recurring Pricing'''=''Enter Manually''
* '''Item Price/Percent'''=''0''
* '''Extra Usage Pricing'''=''Enter Manually''
* '''Item Price/Percent'''=''100''

|- 
|  '''Contract Template''' (Use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_20_20_00|Contract Templates] form.)
| [anchor|#ul_twt_lnq_1n]
*'''Duration'''=''1 Year''
* '''Billing Period'''=''Month''

| [anchor|#ul_cqp_rcn_bn]
* '''Duration'''=''1 Year''
* '''Billing Period'''=''Month''
* '''Case Count Item'''=''CASENUMBER''

|}((({S:Warn}Fill in settings that are not mentioned in the table at your discretion.
)))]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Usage-Based Contracts You may offer services at a price that depends on the usage of the service, such as support         hours, disk space, or support cases. The contracts functionality of  Acumatica ERP can help you to track and bill the usage of a particular service. You can bill customers         for services at the regular price and at an extra usage price, and you can provide some         quantity for free. You can track the usage of the services that are provided recurrently         within a billing period as well as for the whole contract duration. Consider the examples below. Annual Support with Free Options If you offer annual support with free options, you can use  Acumatica ERP to implement the following scenarios. Each scenario is described briefly below; see the            Settings for the Examples Settings for the Examples table for the settings you would use to implement the         scenario. You can also refer to procedures that walk you through implementation of each         scenario. Annual Support With Hours for Free : To implement this example, use the settings           listed in the appropriate column of the table below. Annual support that includes free             hours might be structured as follows: The First 10 Hours for Free : You could offer a contract for annual support               with the first 10 hours free and additional hours billed at $100 per hour. The               contract is billed monthly.  10 Hours for Free Each Month : You might offer a contract for annual support               with 10 hours free each month and other hours billed at $100 per hour. The contract is               billed monthly. To implement examples in which the contract covers annual support with free hours,             do the following: For a case class that is billed by case, follow the  To Set Up Billing By Case procedure. For a case class that is billed by case activity, follow the  To Set Up Billing By Case Activities procedure.  Annual Support With Cases for Free : To implement this example, too, you use the           settings listed in the appropriate column of the table below. Annual support that             includes free cases might be structured as follows: The First 10 Cases for Free : You might offer a contract for annual support               with the first 10 cases free and additional cases billed at $100 per case. The               contract is billed monthly.  10 Cases for Free Each Month : You could offer a contract for annual support               with 10 free cases each month and additional cases billed at $100 per case. The               contract is billed monthly. To implement an example in which the contract covers annual support with free             cases, follow the  To Set Up Billing by the Number of Cases procedure.            Settings for the Examples This table shows the settings you would use to implement each of the examples described         above. Entity Annual Support With Hours for Free Annual Support With Cases for Free Non-Stock Item  (Use the   ([~/?ScreenId=IN202000|IN202000]) Non-Stock Items                 form.) Inventory ID = SUPPORTHOURS Item Status = Active Type = Labor UOMs = Hours Inventory ID = CASENUMBER Item Status = Active Type = Non-Stock Item UOMs = ITEM Contract Item  (Use the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT201000|CT201000]) Contract Items                 form.) Default Quantity = 10 Recurring Item = SUPPORTHOURS Reset Usage on Billing : Cleared for the  The First 10 Hours For Free  scenario Selected for the  10 Hours For Free Each Month  scenario Recurring Pricing = Enter Manually Item Price/Percent = 0 Extra Usage Pricing = Enter Manually Item Price/Percent = 100 Default Quantity = 10 Recurring Item = CASENUMBER Reset Usage on Billing : Cleared for the  The First 10 Cases for Free  scenario Selected for the  10 Cases for Free Each Month  scenario  Recurring Pricing = Enter Manually Item Price/Percent = 0 Extra Usage Pricing = Enter Manually Item Price/Percent = 100 Contract Template  (Use the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT202000|CT202000]) Contract Templates                 form.) Duration = 1 Year Billing Period = Month Duration = 1 Year Billing Period = Month Case Count Item = CASENUMBER Fill in settings that are not mentioned in the table at your discretion. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="59e3ed63-5500-4187-a498-1d142ef635b8" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="0a59175e-50ea-b1a7-1547-20711bdc1aaf" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
 To bill a customer recurrently and on a per-case basis for time and overtime, perform the following steps: [anchor|#ol_e4m_ycj_1n]
#By using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\IN_20_20_00|Non-Stock Items] ([~/?ScreenId=IN202000|IN202000]) form, create a non-stock item of the ''Labor'' type to represent hours. For details, see [HelpRoot_Projects\Non_Stock_Item_Projects_Implem_Activity|Labor Items: To Configure a Labor Item].
#On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CR_20_60_00|Case Classes] ([~/?ScreenId=CR206000|CR206000]) form, configure a case class for cases that are billed on a per-case basis. Assign the non-stock item created in Step 1 to this case class. That is, specify the non-stock item in the '''Labor Item''' and '''Overtime Labor Item''' boxes on the '''Details''' tab.
#On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_20_10_00|Contract Items] ([~/?ScreenId=CT201000|CT201000]) form, create a contract item. In the '''Recurring Item''' box, specify the non-stock item created in Step 1 as the one provisioned recurrently. Also, specify the recurring and extra usage prices of this item. Fill in other required settings (and any optional ones) at your discretion. For details, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__HOW_Configure_Contract_Item|To Configure a Contract Item]. 
#By using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_20_20_00|Contract Templates] ([~/?ScreenId=CT202000|CT202000]) form, create an active contract template with scheduled billing. Add the contract item created in Step 3 to the contract template. For more information, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__HOW_Configure_Contract_Template|To Configure a Contract Template].
#Initiate the contract in the way that suits your needs; now you can proceed with the contract fulfillment. See [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__CON_Contract_Signing|Contract Setup and Activation] for details.
#As needed, enter contract usage by using the functionality of the Customer Management module as follows:
##On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CR_30_60_00|Cases] ([~/?ScreenId=CR306000|CR306000]) form, create a case, specifying the case class created in Step 2 and the applicable customer. Fill in other details at your discretion. 
##On the '''Additional Info''' tab, assign the contract to the case by using the '''Contract''' box. Mark the case as billable, and fill in other settings of this tab at your discretion. Save your changes.
##As work on the case is done, fill in the '''Billable Time''' and '''Billable Overtime''' (if applicable) boxes with the quantity, and save your changes.
##After work on the case is finished, close and release the case. 
##:The billable time of the case affects its contract item usage, and the usage transaction is displayed on the '''Unbilled Transactions''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_30_00|Contract Usage] ([~/?ScreenId=CT303000|CT303000]) form.
#Bill the contract according to its schedule, as described in [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__con_Contract_Billing|Contract Billing].
]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[To Set Up Billing By Case  To bill a customer recurrently and on a per-case basis for time and overtime,                 perform the following steps:  By using the   ([~/?ScreenId=IN202000|IN202000]) Non-Stock Items (IN202000) form, create a                         non-stock item of the  Labor  type to represent hours. For details, see                              Labor Items: To Configure a Labor Item. On the   ([~/?ScreenId=CR206000|CR206000]) Case Classes (CR206000) form, configure a case                         class for cases that are billed on a per-case basis. Assign the non-stock                         item created in Step 1 to this case class. That is, specify the non-stock                         item in the  Labor Item  and  Overtime Labor                             Item  boxes on the  Details  tab. On the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT201000|CT201000]) Contract Items (CT201000) form, create a contract                         item. In the  Recurring Item  box, specify the                         non-stock item created in Step 1 as the one provisioned recurrently. Also,                         specify the recurring and extra usage prices of this item. Fill in other                         required settings (and any optional ones) at your discretion. For details,                         see  To Configure a Contract Item.  By using the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT202000|CT202000]) Contract Templates (CT202000) form, create an                         active contract template with scheduled billing. Add the contract item                         created in Step 3 to the contract template. For more information, see  To Configure a Contract Template. Initiate the contract in the way that suits your needs; now you can proceed                         with the contract fulfillment. See  Contract Setup and Activation for details. As needed, enter contract usage by using the functionality of the Customer                         Management module as follows: On the   ([~/?ScreenId=CR306000|CR306000]) Cases (CR306000) form, create a                                 case, specifying the case class created in Step 2 and the applicable                                 customer. Fill in other details at your discretion.  On the  Additional Info  tab, assign the                                 contract to the case by using the  Contract                                  box. Mark the case as billable, and fill in other settings of this                                 tab at your discretion. Save your changes. As work on the case is done, fill in the  Billable                                     Time  and  Billable Overtime                                  (if applicable) boxes with the quantity, and save your changes. After work on the case is finished, close and release the case.                                      The billable time of the case affects its contract item                                     usage, and the usage transaction is displayed on the                                          Unbilled Transactions  tab of the                                           ([~/?ScreenId=CT303000|CT303000]) Contract Usage (CT303000) form. Bill the contract according to its schedule, as described in  Contract Billing. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="2c0f92d9-aa12-4200-94c9-0fcec1e7451f" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="becd5187-72e3-3b31-b12d-3438bdd1511e" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
To bill a customer recurrently and on a per-activity basis for time and overtime, perform the following steps:[anchor|#ol_xxx_ftj_1n]
#By using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\IN_20_20_00|Non-Stock Items] ([~/?ScreenId=IN202000|IN202000]) form, create a non-stock item of the ''Labor'' type to represent hours. For details, see [HelpRoot_Projects\Non_Stock_Item_Projects_Implem_Activity|Labor Items: To Configure a Labor Item].
#On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CR_20_60_00|Case Classes] ([~/?ScreenId=CR206000|CR206000]) form, configure a case class for cases that will be billed on a per-activity basis. On the '''Labor Items''' tab, add the ''Regular Hours'' earning type and associate it with the non-stock item created in Step 1. For more information, see [HelpRoot_Organization\EP__con_Time_Tracking|Time Activities].
#On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_20_10_00|Contract Items] ([~/?ScreenId=CT201000|CT201000]) form, create a contract item. In the '''Recurring Item''' box, specify the non-stock item created in Step 1 as the one provisioned recurrently, Also, specify the recurring and extra usage prices of this item. Fill in other required settings (and any optional ones) at your discretion. For details, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__HOW_Configure_Contract_Item|To Configure a Contract Item]. 
#By using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_20_20_00|Contract Templates] ([~/?ScreenId=CT202000|CT202000]) form, create an active contract template with scheduled billing. Add the contract item created in Step 3 to the contract template; see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__HOW_Configure_Contract_Template|To Configure a Contract Template] for more information.
#Initiate the contract in the way that suits your needs; now you can proceed with the contract fulfillment. For details, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__CON_Contract_Signing|Contract Setup and Activation].
#As needed, enter contract usage by using the functionality of the Customer Management module as follows:
##On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CR_30_60_00|Cases] ([~/?ScreenId=CR306000|CR306000]) form, create a case, specifying the case class you created in Step 2 and the applicable customer. Fill in other details at your discretion.
##On the '''Additional Info''' tab, assign the contract to the case by using the '''Contract''' box; fill in other details of this tab at your discretion. Save your changes.
##By using the '''Activities''' tab of the form, add an activity. For the activity, select the '''Track Time''' check box, and specify the billable time and the earning type you have assigned the labor item to. Save and release the activity. 
##:For details, see [HelpRoot_CRM\CR__con_Case_Billing|Case Billing]. The billable time of the activity affects its contract item usage, and the usage transaction is displayed on the '''Unbilled Transactions''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_30_00|Contract Usage] ([~/?ScreenId=CT303000|CT303000]) form. 
#Bill the contract according to its schedule. For more information, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__con_Contract_Billing|Contract Billing].
]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[To Set Up Billing By Case Activities To bill a customer recurrently and on a per-activity basis for time and overtime,                 perform the following steps: By using the   ([~/?ScreenId=IN202000|IN202000]) Non-Stock Items (IN202000) form, create a                         non-stock item of the  Labor  type to represent hours. For details, see                              Labor Items: To Configure a Labor Item. On the   ([~/?ScreenId=CR206000|CR206000]) Case Classes (CR206000) form, configure a case                         class for cases that will be billed on a per-activity basis. On the                              Labor Items  tab, add the  Regular Hours                          earning type and associate it with the non-stock item created in Step 1. For                         more information, see  Time Activities. On the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT201000|CT201000]) Contract Items (CT201000) form, create a contract                         item. In the  Recurring Item  box, specify the                         non-stock item created in Step 1 as the one provisioned recurrently, Also,                         specify the recurring and extra usage prices of this item. Fill in other                         required settings (and any optional ones) at your discretion. For details,                         see  To Configure a Contract Item.  By using the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT202000|CT202000]) Contract Templates (CT202000) form, create an                         active contract template with scheduled billing. Add the contract item                         created in Step 3 to the contract template; see  To Configure a Contract Template for more                         information. Initiate the contract in the way that suits your needs; now you can proceed                         with the contract fulfillment. For details, see  Contract Setup and Activation. As needed, enter contract usage by using the functionality of the Customer                         Management  module as follows: On the   ([~/?ScreenId=CR306000|CR306000]) Cases (CR306000) form, create a                                 case, specifying the case class you created in Step 2 and the                                 applicable customer. Fill in other details at your discretion. On the  Additional Info  tab, assign the                                 contract to the case by using the  Contract                                  box; fill in other details of this tab at your discretion. Save your                                 changes. By using the  Activities  tab of the form, add                                 an activity. For the activity, select the  Track                                     Time  check box, and specify the billable time and                                 the earning type you have assigned the labor item to. Save and                                 release the activity.  For details, see  Case Billing. The billable time of the                                     activity affects its contract item usage, and the usage                                     transaction is displayed on the  Unbilled                                         Transactions  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT303000|CT303000]) Contract Usage (CT303000) form.  Bill the contract according to its schedule. For more information, see  Contract Billing. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="dd3d67a2-fa03-44e5-811e-3957b42981c7" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="e247625e-ab5b-76c6-3866-10bc0f0c7eae" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
To bill a customer recurrently for a number of cases, perform the following steps:[anchor|#ol_mbl_f3k_1n]
#By using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\IN_20_20_00|Non-Stock Items] ([~/?ScreenId=IN202000|IN202000]) form, create a non-stock item. Specify the item's unit of measure and price, and fill in other details at your discretion. For details, see [HelpRoot_InvMgmt\Entity_OrderMgmt_Non_Stock_Items_GeneralInfo|Creating Non-Stock Items: General Information].
#On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_20_10_00|Contract Items] ([~/?ScreenId=CT201000|CT201000]) form, create a contract item. In the '''Recurring Item''' box, specify the non-stock item created in Step 1 as the one provisioned recurrently. Also, specify the recurring and extra usage price of this item. Fill in other required settings (and any optional ones) at your discretion. For details, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__HOW_Configure_Contract_Item|To Configure a Contract Item].
#By using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_20_20_00|Contract Templates] ([~/?ScreenId=CT202000|CT202000]) form, create an active contract template with scheduled billing. Add the contract item created in Step 2 to the contract template, and in the '''Case Count Item''' box, specify the non-stock item you created in Step 1. For details, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__HOW_Configure_Contract_Template|To Configure a Contract Template].
#Initiate the contract in the way that suits your needs; now you can proceed with the contract fulfillment. For more information, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__CON_Contract_Signing|Contract Setup and Activation].
#As needed, enter contract usage in the following ways:
#*By using the functionality of the Customer Management module as follows:
#*#On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CR_30_60_00|Cases] ([~/?ScreenId=CR306000|CR306000]) form, create a case, specifying the customer you have signed the contract with. Fill in other details at your discretion. 
#*#On the '''Additional Info''' tab, assign the contract to the case by using the '''Contract''' box. Mark the case as billable, and fill in other settings of this tab at your discretion. Save your changes.
#*#After the work is done, close and release the case. Releasing the case increments the usage of the non-stock item created and therefore the usage of the contract item created.
#*#: The respective usage transaction is displayed on the '''Unbilled Transactions''' tab on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_30_00|Contract Usage] form.
#*Directly for the non-stock item you have configured, by using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_30_00|Contract Usage] ([~/?ScreenId=CT303000|CT303000]) form. For details, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__HOW_Enter_Contract_Usage|To Enter Contract Usage].
#Bill the contract according to its schedule. For more information, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__con_Contract_Billing|Contract Billing].
]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[To Set Up Billing by the Number of Cases To bill a customer recurrently for a number of cases, perform the following steps: By using the   ([~/?ScreenId=IN202000|IN202000]) Non-Stock Items (IN202000) form, create a                         non-stock item. Specify the item's unit of measure and price, and fill in                         other details at your discretion. For details, see  Creating Non-Stock Items: General Information. On the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT201000|CT201000]) Contract Items (CT201000) form, create a contract                         item. In the  Recurring Item  box, specify the                         non-stock item created in Step 1 as the one provisioned recurrently. Also,                         specify the recurring and extra usage price of this item. Fill in other                         required settings (and any optional ones) at your discretion. For details,                         see  To Configure a Contract Item. By using the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT202000|CT202000]) Contract Templates (CT202000) form, create an                         active contract template with scheduled billing. Add the contract item                         created in Step 2 to the contract template, and in the  Case Count                             Item  box, specify the non-stock item you created in Step 1.                         For details, see  To Configure a Contract Template. Initiate the contract in the way that suits your needs; now you can proceed                         with the contract fulfillment. For more information, see  Contract Setup and Activation. As needed, enter contract usage in the following ways: By using the functionality of the Customer Management  module as                                     follows: On the   ([~/?ScreenId=CR306000|CR306000]) Cases (CR306000) form,                                         create a case, specifying the customer you have signed the                                         contract with. Fill in other details at your discretion.  On the  Additional Info  tab, assign                                         the contract to the case by using the                                              Contract  box. Mark the case as                                         billable, and fill in other settings of this tab at your                                         discretion. Save your changes. After the work is done, close and release the case.                                         Releasing the case increments the usage of the non-stock                                         item created and therefore the usage of the contract item                                             created.  The respective usage transaction is                                             displayed on the  Unbilled                                                 Transactions  tab on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT303000|CT303000]) Contract Usage form. Directly for the non-stock item you have configured, by using the                                       ([~/?ScreenId=CT303000|CT303000]) Contract Usage (CT303000) form. For details,                                 see  To Enter Contract Usage. Bill the contract according to its schedule. For more information, see  Contract Billing. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="02a6875b-647e-4942-8e65-ce43e8ae5f4a" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="c2cd4083-311c-2ea6-62c8-f542a93f77c6" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
In some cases, a contract includes a retainer (that is, a deposit or fee paid in advance to secure services) along with the services to be provided. The customer pays the retainer at contract setup. The customer is then charged for the actual usage of services according to its billing schedule, and the cost of provided services is deducted from the retainer.{br}

In this topic, you will read about the configuration of a retainer contract and its further maintenance.{br}{TOC}
==Retainer Contract Configuration==
In Acumatica ERP, a retainer is referred to as a ''deposit contract item''. You configure a contract item marked as a deposit by selecting the '''Deposit''' check box on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_20_10_00|Contract Items] ([~/?ScreenId=CT201000|CT201000]) form. This contract item represents a retainer that the customer should pay at contract setup. {br}

Then you assign this deposit contract item to contract items that represent services. That is, you specify a deposit contract item in the '''Deposit Item''' box for each contract item whose cost of usage is to be deducted from the retainer. After the required contract items are configured, you add them, except for the deposit contract item, to a contract template designed for retainer contracts. When you add a contract item to a contract template, the system checks whether the item has a deposit contract item assigned; if there is one, it checks whether it has been added to the template already. If a contract item has a deposit item assigned that is not yet present in the contract template, this deposit contract item is added automatically.{br}

 You create a retainer contract based on the contract template configured for retainer contracts and activate the contract. The detailed procedure is described in [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__HOW_Configure_Deposit_Contract|To Configure a Retainer Contract].
==Retainer Contract Billing==
By default, the billing process uses the included quantity of the recurring contract items to define which price (recurring or for the extra usage) should be used to bill the usage of the item. If you have recorded usage that exceeds the included quantity, the billing process will use the price defined for the extra usage to bill the excess quantity.{br}

The billing process for retainer contracts uses the retainer amount to define which price should be taken to bill the usage. If the entire amount of the retainer is not spent, the customer is billed for the recorded usage of each service according to the pricing policy defined in the '''Recurring Pricing''' box on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_20_10_00|Contract Items] form for the respective contract item. When the retainer has been spent, the customer is billed for each service usage according to the pricing policy defined in the '''Extra Usage Pricing''' box on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_20_10_00|Contract Items] form for the respective contract item.{br}

When you provide services to a customer, you record the usage of the services in the contract. You bill the customer according to the billing schedule, and the system issues invoices as a result of the billing process. The billable usage of each provided service and of the retainer are displayed as separate lines in the invoice.
==Retainer Contract Restrictions==
When you configure a retainer contract, make sure it complies with the following restrictions:{br}

[anchor|#ol_ykf_nhb_4n]
#The contract template must contain only one deposit contract item. The system does not allow a contract template to be saved if there are multiple deposit contract items.
#The included quantity of the recurring contract items should be zero. That is, for the contract item whose cost of usage is to be deducted from the retainer, you type 0 in the '''Default Quantity''' box on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_20_10_00|Contract Items] form. You can manage the included quantity of the recurring items in a contract template and a contract itself on the '''Details''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_20_20_00|Contract Templates] and [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_10_00|Customer Contracts] forms. 
#The contract must be of either the ''Expiring'' type or the ''Unlimited'' type. The contract type is defined by the '''Contract Type''' setting on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_20_20_00|Contract Templates] form for the contract template that the contract is based on.

==Retainer Replenishment==
If a customer wants to replenish a retainer, this can be done through the contract upgrade procedure. You can change the deposit contract item quantity if the contract template allows overriding of contract items. For details, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__CON_Contract_Upgrade|Changes to Contract Services ].]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Retainer Contracts In some cases, a contract includes a retainer (that is, a deposit or fee paid in advance to         secure services) along with the services to be provided. The customer pays the retainer at         contract setup. The customer is then charged for the actual usage of services according to         its billing schedule, and the cost of provided services is deducted from the retainer. In this topic, you will read about the configuration of a retainer contract and its further         maintenance. Retainer Contract Configuration In  Acumatica ERP, a retainer is referred to as a  deposit contract item . You configure a contract         item marked as a deposit by selecting the  Deposit  check box on the             ([~/?ScreenId=CT201000|CT201000]) Contract Items (CT201000) form. This contract item represents a         retainer that the customer should pay at contract setup.  Then you assign this deposit contract item to contract items that represent services. That         is, you specify a deposit contract item in the  Deposit Item  box for         each contract item whose cost of usage is to be deducted from the retainer. After the         required contract items are configured, you add them, except for the deposit contract item,         to a contract template designed for retainer contracts. When you add a contract item to a         contract template, the system checks whether the item has a deposit contract item assigned;         if there is one, it checks whether it has been added to the template already. If a contract         item has a deposit item assigned that is not yet present in the contract template, this         deposit contract item is added automatically.  You create a retainer contract based on the contract template configured for retainer         contracts and activate the contract. The detailed procedure is described in  To Configure a Retainer Contract. Retainer Contract Billing By default, the billing process uses the included quantity of the recurring contract items         to define which price (recurring or for the extra usage) should be used to bill the usage of         the item. If you have recorded usage that exceeds the included quantity, the billing process         will use the price defined for the extra usage to bill the excess quantity. The billing process for retainer contracts uses the retainer amount to define which price         should be taken to bill the usage. If the entire amount of the retainer is not spent, the         customer is billed for the recorded usage of each service according to the pricing policy         defined in the  Recurring Pricing  box on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT201000|CT201000]) Contract Items form for the respective contract item. When the retainer has         been spent, the customer is billed for each service usage according to the pricing policy         defined in the  Extra Usage Pricing  box on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT201000|CT201000]) Contract Items form for the respective contract item. When you provide services to a customer, you record the usage of the services in the         contract. You bill the customer according to the billing schedule, and the system issues         invoices as a result of the billing process. The billable usage of each provided service and         of the retainer are displayed as separate lines in the invoice. Retainer Contract Restrictions When you configure a retainer contract, make sure it complies with the following         restrictions: The contract template must contain only one deposit contract item. The system does not             allow a contract template to be saved if there are multiple deposit contract items. The included quantity of the recurring contract items should be zero. That is, for the             contract item whose cost of usage is to be deducted from the retainer, you type 0 in the                Default Quantity  box on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT201000|CT201000]) Contract Items             form. You can manage the included quantity of the recurring items in a contract template             and a contract itself on the  Details  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT202000|CT202000]) Contract Templates and   ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) Customer Contracts forms.  The contract must be of either the  Expiring  type or the  Unlimited  type.             The contract type is defined by the  Contract Type  setting on the                 ([~/?ScreenId=CT202000|CT202000]) Contract Templates form for the contract template that the contract is             based on. Retainer Replenishment If a customer wants to replenish a retainer, this can be done through the contract upgrade         procedure. You can change the deposit contract item quantity if the contract template allows         overriding of contract items. For details, see  Changes to Contract Services . ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="b2bc1af6-9329-40af-b8a0-73d52d03b085" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="71aeee02-2aec-ec34-cf72-7c58c5174e32" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
To configure a retainer contract, perform the following steps:{br}

[anchor|#ol_avg_vk3_xm]
#By using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\IN_20_20_00|Non-Stock Items] ([~/?ScreenId=IN202000|IN202000]) form, configure a non-stock item. In the '''Sales Account''' box on the '''GL Accounts''' tab, we recommend that you specify the preferred by the company liability account to post related transactions to instead of an income one.
#On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_20_10_00|Contract Items] ([~/?ScreenId=CT201000|CT201000]) form, create a deposit contract item. For details, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__HOW_Configure_Deposit|To Create a Deposit Contract Item].
#Also on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_20_10_00|Contract Items] form, create a service contract item that is provided recurrently, and while creating you select the deposit contract item in the '''Deposit Item''' box for it . For details, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__HOW_Configure_Contract_Item|To Configure a Contract Item]. 
#By using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_20_20_00|Contract Templates] ([~/?ScreenId=CT202000|CT202000]) form, create a contract template. You do not add the deposit contract item to a contract template directly; you instead add the service contract item to the contract template, and the deposit contract item assigned to it is added automatically. When you add the service contract item, specify 0 for it in the '''Quantity''' box. For details, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__HOW_Configure_Contract_Template|To Configure a Contract Template].
#By using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_10_00|Customer Contracts] ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) form, create a contract based on the contract template you have created in the previous step. For details, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__HOW_Prepare_Contract|To Configure a Contract].
#Initiate the contract in the way that suits your needs. The invoice that includes the prepayment sum is issued and you can proceed with contract fulfillment. For details, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__CON_Contract_Signing|Contract Setup and Activation].
#Enter the contract usage. For details, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__CON_Contract_Usage|Contract Usage Recording].
#Bill the contract according to its schedule. For details, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__con_Contract_Billing|Contract Billing].
]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[To Configure a Retainer Contract To configure a retainer contract, perform the following steps: By using the   ([~/?ScreenId=IN202000|IN202000]) Non-Stock Items (IN202000) form, configure a                         non-stock item. In the  Sales Account  box on the  GL Accounts                          tab, we recommend that you specify the preferred by the company liability                         account to post related transactions to instead of an income one. On the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT201000|CT201000]) Contract Items (CT201000) form, create a deposit                         contract item. For details, see  To Create a Deposit Contract Item. Also on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT201000|CT201000]) Contract Items form, create a service contract                         item that is provided recurrently, and while creating you select the deposit                         contract item in the  Deposit Item  box for it . For                         details, see  To Configure a Contract Item.  By using the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT202000|CT202000]) Contract Templates (CT202000) form, create a                         contract template. You do not add the deposit contract item to a contract                         template directly; you instead add the service contract item to the contract                         template, and the deposit contract item assigned to it is added                         automatically. When you add the service contract item, specify 0 for it in                         the  Quantity  box. For details, see  To Configure a Contract Template. By using the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) Customer Contracts (CT301000) form, create a                         contract based on the contract template you have created in the previous                         step. For details, see  To Configure a Contract. Initiate the contract in the way that suits your needs. The invoice that                         includes the prepayment sum is issued and you can proceed with contract                         fulfillment. For details, see  Contract Setup and Activation. Enter the contract usage. For details, see  Contract Usage Recording. Bill the contract according to its schedule. For details, see  Contract Billing. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="8a7d19bd-2d1d-4274-afbb-2c99e4bd1de5" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="28696ed5-0c0b-dfd6-ae97-8600831aba81" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
You use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_20_10_00|Contract Items] ([~/?ScreenId=CT201000|CT201000]) form to configure a deposit contract item.
==Before You Proceed==
By using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\IN_20_20_00|Non-Stock Items] ([~/?ScreenId=IN202000|IN202000]) form, you must create a non-stock item to be used for the creation of deposit contract items. We recommend that in the '''Sales Account''' box on the '''GL Accounts''' tab of the form, you specify the designated liability account to post deposit-related transactions to. For details on configuring non-stock items, see [HelpRoot_InvMgmt\Entity_OrderMgmt_Non_Stock_Items_GeneralInfo|Creating Non-Stock Items: General Information].
==To Configure the Deposit Contract Item==[anchor|#_8285f8ac-690e-4668-9dea-e271b3990674]
#Open the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_20_10_00|Contract Items] ([~/?ScreenId=CT201000|CT201000]) form.
#On the form toolbar, click '''Add New Record'''.
#Optional: In the '''Contract Item''' box, specify the unique identifier of the deposit contract item. 
#:Identifiers of contract items are formed in accordance with the ''CONTRACTITEM'' segmented key. If the '''Contract Item''' box contains the {{<NEW>}} placeholder, it means that auto-numbering is enabled for a key segment and the system will assign the identifier automatically. Otherwise, you should specify the identifier manually.
#In the '''Description''' box, type a brief description of the deposit contract item.
#In the Summary area of the '''Price Options''' tab, do the following: 
##In the '''Maximum Allowed Quantity''' and the '''Minimum Allowed Quantity''' boxes, type the limits of the retainer quantity.
##In the '''Default Quantity''' box, type the quantity of retainers that is included in the contract by default. This value can be modified in a contract template or a contract, as long as it stays within the allowed limits.
##In the '''Currency ID''' box, select the currency of the contract item. Within each contract item, you should use non-stock items priced in the same currency.
#In the '''Setup and Renewal''' section, do the following:
##In the '''Setup Item''' box, select the non-stock item you have configured.
##In the '''Setup Pricing''' box, select the pricing policy. The following options are available: 
##*''Use Item Price'': The base price of the non-stock item is used. If a price is configured for a customer price class and a customer that purchases this service belongs to this price class, then the price from the customer price class is used.
##*''Percent of Item Price'': The price is a percentage calculated by applying the percent specified in the '''Item Price/Percentage''' box to the base price of the non-stock item.
##*''Enter Manually'': The price is specified manually and can then be modified in a contract.
##Select the '''Deposit''' check box to indicate that this contract item will be used as the retainer.
##In the '''Retain Rate''' box, specify the percent of the deposit amount at which the user viewing contract details will receive a system warning.
##Select the '''Refundable''' check box if you want to allow the retainer to be refunded if the contract is terminated. The retainer is refunded if both the contract template and the deposit contract item are marked as refundable. The balance of the retainer at the date of termination is refunded.
#On the form toolbar, click '''Save'''.

Now you can create a contract item that represents a service provided recurrently. When you create the service contract item on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_20_10_00|Contract Items] ([~/?ScreenId=CT201000|CT201000]) form, you specify the deposit contract item you have created in the '''Deposit Item''' box on the '''Price Options''' tab of this form. ]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[To Create a Deposit Contract Item You use the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT201000|CT201000]) Contract Items (CT201000) form to configure a deposit                 contract item. Before You Proceed By using the   ([~/?ScreenId=IN202000|IN202000]) Non-Stock Items (IN202000) form, you must create a                 non-stock item to be used for the creation of deposit contract items. We recommend                 that in the  Sales Account  box on the  GL Accounts  tab of the form, you                 specify the designated liability account to post deposit-related transactions to.                 For details on configuring non-stock items, see  Creating Non-Stock Items: General Information. To Configure the Deposit Contract Item Open the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT201000|CT201000]) Contract Items (CT201000) form. On the form toolbar, click  Add New Record . Optional: In the  Contract Item  box, specify the unique identifier of the deposit contract item.  Identifiers of contract items are formed in accordance with the  CONTRACTITEM  segmented key. If the  Contract Item  box contains the  <NEW>  placeholder, it means that auto-numbering is enabled for a key segment and the system will assign the identifier automatically. Otherwise, you should specify the identifier manually. In the  Description  box, type a brief description of the deposit contract item. In the Summary area of the  Price Options  tab, do the following:  In the  Maximum Allowed Quantity  and the  Minimum Allowed Quantity  boxes, type the limits of the retainer quantity. In the  Default Quantity  box, type the quantity of retainers that is included in the contract by default. This value can be modified in a contract template or a contract, as long as it stays within the allowed limits. In the  Currency ID  box, select the currency of the contract item. Within each contract item, you should use non-stock items priced in the same currency. In the  Setup and Renewal  section, do the following: In the  Setup Item  box, select the non-stock item you                         have configured. In the  Setup Pricing  box, select the pricing policy.                         The following options are available:  Use Item Price : The base price of the non-stock item is used.                                 If a price is configured for a customer price class and a customer                                 that purchases this service belongs to this price class, then the                                 price from the customer price class is used. Percent of Item Price : The price is a percentage calculated                                 by applying the percent specified in the  Item                                     Price/Percentage  box to the base price of the                                 non-stock item. Enter Manually : The price is specified manually and can then                                 be modified in a contract. Select the  Deposit  check box to indicate that this                         contract item will be used as the retainer. In the  Retain Rate  box, specify the percent of the                         deposit amount at which the user viewing contract details will receive a                         system warning. Select the  Refundable  check box if you want to allow                         the retainer to be refunded if the contract is terminated. The retainer is                         refunded if both the contract template and the deposit contract item are                         marked as refundable. The balance of the retainer at the date of termination                         is refunded. On the form toolbar, click  Save . Now you can  create a contract item that represents a service provided recurrently.                 When you create the service contract item on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT201000|CT201000]) Contract Items                 (CT201000) form, you specify the deposit contract item you have created in the                      Deposit Item  box on the  Price                     Options  tab of this form.  ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="3c748acc-8625-45e6-80ea-771615b8d466" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="d260d894-bd8f-ba53-bf45-bbd75152f24c" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
In Acumatica ERP, you can associate the work of your employees with a contract by associating employee activities with a case (case activity) or, if the Customer Management module is disabled, by associating employee activities directly with a contract.{br}

An activity in Acumatica ERP includes information about the amount of billable time, the employee responsible for completing the activity, and the earning type, which represents the type of time spent. When you release an activity, the system starts searching for a non-stock item (of the ''Labor'' type) to use in order to create a usage transaction. The system uses the earning type and the employee ID from the activity as keys to determine the labor item. {br}

You can configure general rates of labor for an employee as well as rates specific to the case class or the contract. You define the rate by using the price of a non-stock item of the ''Labor'' type. You can explicitly specify which non-stock item the system should use for creating a usage transaction, depending on the earning type and the employee you specify in the activity. A non-stock item also has an assigned sales account and subaccount, which makes your sales recording more specific and transparent.{br}

You can specify the non-stock item to be used to create a usage transaction by using one of the following forms:[anchor|#ul_d2c_dqx_cr]
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\CR_20_60_00|Case Classes] ([~/?ScreenId=CR206000|CR206000]), if the Customer Management module is enabled
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_10_00|Customer Contracts] ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_30_00|Employees] ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000])
 To decide which form best suits to define rate for employee when you bill by activity, consider the description (in the next sections of this topic) of how the activity release process determines the labor item.{br}{TOC}
==Finding Labor Item to Bill Case Activity==
If the activity is associated with a case, when you release the activity, the release determines the labor item (to add a contract usage transaction) as follows:[anchor|#ol_fdp_zdb_xn]
#The system checks the list of earning types that are defined on the '''Labor Items''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CR_20_60_00|Case Classes] form for the case class associated with the activity. The system uses the earning type as a key to find the labor item to be used in the usage transaction. If the system finds the particular earning type, the system uses the labor item listed for it to create the usage transaction and does not search any further. 
#If a specific labor item for the case class has not been found, the system checks the contract associated with the case class on the '''Employees''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_10_00|Customer Contracts] form in two stages:
##The system checks the list on this tab, using the earning type and employee ID as the keys. If a listed combination includes the particular earning type and employee ID, the system uses the labor item from this row to create the usage transaction and does not search any further.
##If the combination has not been found, the system again checks the list, using as the keys the earning type and the ''All employees'' value for the employee ID. If a listed combination includes the particular earning type and ''All employees'', the system uses the labor item from this row to create the usage transaction and does not search any further.
#If the labor item specific to the contract has not been found, the system uses the employee associated with the activity being released to find the rate specified for the employee. The system checks the list of earning types on the '''Labor Item Overrides''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_30_00|Employees] form. It uses the earning type as the key. If a combination includes the particular earning type, the system uses the labor item from this combination to create the usage transaction and does not search any further.
#If the rate has not been found in previous steps, the system uses the default labor item specified for the employee, defined as the '''Labor Item''' on the '''General Info''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_30_00|Employees] form.

After the labor item was determined, the system adds a usage transaction for the time specified as billable in the activity with a cost specified in the labor item.{br}

The following diagram illustrates how the system determines the labor item to be used to record the usage transaction.{br}

[anchor|#image_ulv_b4z_wn][image:UserGuide/Images/LaborItemForActivityCostWithTabs.png|popup|Finding labor item to bill case activity|450px]{br}

For more details about setting up a contract with billing by case activity where the rate is defined for a case class (by using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CR_20_60_00|Case Classes] form), see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__HOW_Billing_Per_Activity|To Set Up Billing By Case Activities]. {br}

For information about setting up a contract with billing by case activity where the rate is defined for a contract (by using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_10_00|Customer Contracts] form), see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__HOW_SetUp_EmployeeRates_forContract|To Set Up Employee Rates for Contracts]. 
==Finding Labor Item to Bill Employee Activity==
If the activity is associated with a contract, when you release the activity, the release process determines the labor item (to add a contract usage transaction) as follows:[anchor|#ol_o3d_vzx_cr]
#To find the appropriate labor item to create the usage transaction, the system does the following on the '''Employees''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_10_00|Customer Contracts] form:
##The system checks the list on this tab, using the earning type and employee ID as the keys. If a listed combination includes the particular earning type and employee ID, the system uses the labor item from this row to create the usage transaction and does not search any further.
##If the combination has not been found, the system checks the list, using as the keys the earning type and the ''All employees'' value for the employee ID. If a listed combination includes the particular earning type and ''All employees'', the system uses the labor item from this combination to create the usage transaction and does not search any further.
#If the labor item specific to the contract has not been found, the system uses the employee associated with the released activity to find the rate specified for the employee. The system checks the list of earning types on the '''Labor Item Overrides''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_30_00|Employees] form. It uses the earning type as the key: If a row includes the particular earning type, the system uses the labor item from this row to create the usage transaction and does not search any further.
#If the rate has not been found in the previous steps, the system uses the default labor item specified for the employee: that is, the '''Labor Item''' on the '''General Info''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_30_00|Employees] form.

For information about setting up a contract with billing by time activity where the rate is defined for a contract (by using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_10_00|Customer Contracts] form), see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__HOW_SetUP_Billing_Per_Time_Activity|To Set Up Billing by Employee Time Activities]. ]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Employee Rates for Contracts In  Acumatica ERP,     you can associate the work of your employees with a contract by associating employee activities     with a case (case activity) or, if the Customer Management module is disabled, by associating     employee activities directly with a contract. An activity in  Acumatica ERP     includes information about the amount of billable time, the employee responsible for completing     the activity, and the earning type, which represents the type of time spent. When you release an     activity, the system starts searching for a non-stock item (of the  Labor  type) to use in     order to create a usage transaction. The system uses the earning type and the employee ID from     the activity as keys to determine the labor item.  You can configure general rates of     labor for an employee as well as rates specific to the case class or the contract. You define     the rate by using the price of a non-stock item of the  Labor  type. You can explicitly     specify which non-stock item the system should use for creating a usage transaction, depending     on the earning type and the employee you specify in the activity. A non-stock item also has an     assigned sales account and subaccount, which makes your sales recording more specific and     transparent. You can specify the non-stock item to be used to create a usage transaction     by using one of the following forms:  ([~/?ScreenId=CR206000|CR206000]) Case Classes (CR206000), if the Customer Management module is      enabled  ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) Customer Contracts (CT301000)  ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000]) Employees (EP203000)  To decide which form best suits to define rate for employee when you bill by activity,    consider the description (in the next sections of this topic) of how the activity release process    determines the labor item. Finding Labor Item to Bill Case Activity If the activity is associated with a case, when you release the activity, the release     determines the labor item (to add a contract usage transaction) as follows: The system checks the list of earning types that are defined on the  Labor       Items  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=CR206000|CR206000]) Case Classes form for the case class      associated with the activity. The system uses the earning type as a key to find the labor item      to be used in the usage transaction. If the system finds the particular earning type, the      system uses the labor item listed for it to create the usage transaction and does not search      any further.  If a specific labor item for the case class has not been found, the system checks the      contract associated with the case class on the  Employees  tab of the         ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) Customer Contracts form in two stages: The system checks the list on this tab, using the earning type and employee ID as the        keys. If a listed combination includes the particular earning type and employee ID, the        system uses the labor item from this row to create the usage transaction and does not search        any further. If the combination has not been found, the system again checks the list, using as the keys        the earning type and the  All employees  value for the employee ID. If a listed        combination includes the particular earning type and  All employees , the system uses        the labor item from this row to create the usage transaction and does not search any        further. If the labor item specific to the contract has not been found, the system uses the employee      associated with the activity being released to find the rate specified for the employee. The      system checks the list of earning types on the  Labor Item Overrides  tab      of the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000]) Employees form. It uses the earning type as the key. If a      combination includes the particular earning type, the system uses the labor item from this      combination to create the usage transaction and does not search any further. If the rate has not been found in previous steps, the system uses the default labor item      specified for the employee, defined as the  Labor Item  on the        General Info  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000]) Employees form. After the labor item was determined, the system adds a usage transaction for the time     specified as billable in the activity with a cost specified in the labor item. The following diagram illustrates how the system determines the labor item to be used to     record the usage transaction. Finding labor item to bill case activity For more details about setting up a contract with billing by case activity where the rate is     defined for a case class (by using the   ([~/?ScreenId=CR206000|CR206000]) Case Classes form), see  To Set Up Billing By Case Activities.  For information about setting up a contract with billing by case activity where the rate is     defined for a contract (by using the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) Customer Contracts form), see  To Set Up Employee Rates for Contracts.  Finding Labor Item to Bill Employee Activity If the activity is associated with a contract, when you release the activity, the release     process determines the labor item (to add a contract usage transaction) as follows: To find the appropriate labor item to create the usage transaction, the system does the      following on the  Employees  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) Customer Contracts       form: The system checks the list on this tab, using the earning type and employee ID as the        keys. If a listed combination includes the particular earning type and employee ID, the        system uses the labor item from this row to create the usage transaction and does not search        any further. If the combination has not been found, the system checks the list, using as the keys the        earning type and the  All employees  value for the employee ID. If a listed combination        includes the particular earning type and  All employees , the system uses the labor item        from this combination to create the usage transaction and does not search any further. If the labor item specific to the contract has not been found, the system uses the employee      associated with the released activity to find the rate specified for the employee. The system      checks the list of earning types on the  Labor Item Overrides  tab of the         ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000]) Employees form. It uses the earning type as the key: If a row includes      the particular earning type, the system uses the labor item from this row to create the usage      transaction and does not search any further. If the rate has not been found in the previous steps, the system uses the default labor item      specified for the employee: that is, the  Labor Item  on the        General Info  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000]) Employees form. For information about setting up a contract with billing by time activity where the rate is     defined for a contract (by using the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) Customer Contracts form), see  To Set Up Billing by Employee Time Activities.  ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="f77065af-0e07-40f2-bdbd-cb9d71c3f35c" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="a89554fc-de3e-6024-b624-4c53bc116b81" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
You may need to set up employee rates specific for a contract. Consider the example in the following sections of this topic.[anchor|#contract_config]
==To Configure a Contract with Specific Employee Rates==
Suppose that you offer a contract for annual support and bill customers monthly by case activity. You have first-line support engineers, who handle regular cases, and second-line support engineers, who handle complex problems. The second-line support engineers are John Smith and Jane Kent.{br}

The configuration matrix of employee rates is shown in the following table; when you set up billing by employee time, you can use a similar table for reference.[anchor|#table_yvl_fck_14]
===Employee Rate Matrix===
{| class="checklist" | width="100%" 
|- 
!width="33%" ! Earning Type
!width="33%" ! Labor Item
!width="33%" ! Employee
|- 
| Regular Hours (RG)
| 1stLineRate
| All Employees
|- 
| Regular Hours (RG)
| 2ndLineRate
| Jane Kent
|- 
| Regular Hours (RG)
| 2ndLineRate
| John Smith
|}{br}

To set up employee rates for the contract described above, you would perform the following steps:{br}

[anchor|#ol_xxx_ftj_1n]
#By using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\IN_20_20_00|Non-Stock Items] ([~/?ScreenId=IN202000|IN202000]) form, create two non-stock items of the ''Labor'' type (''1stLineRate'' and ''2ndLineRate'') to represent hours and define the respective rates. For details, see [HelpRoot_InvMgmt\Entity_OrderMgmt_Non_Stock_Items_Implem_Activity|Creating Non-Stock Items: Implementation Activity].
#On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CR_20_60_00|Case Classes] ([~/?ScreenId=CR206000|CR206000]) form, configure a case class that requires a contract and bills cases on a per-activity basis.
#By using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_20_20_00|Contract Templates] ([~/?ScreenId=CT202000|CT202000]) form, create an active contract template with scheduled billing. For details, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__HOW_Configure_Contract_Template|To Configure a Contract Template].
#On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_10_00|Customer Contracts] ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) form, create a contract based on the contract template configured in Step 3. For details, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__HOW_Prepare_Contract|To Configure a Contract].
#On the '''Employees''' tab, enter the appropriate combinations of earning type, labor item, and employee by using the ''Employee rate matrix'' table as a reference. Do the following:
##Add a row. The '''Employee''' column of the new row is filled with the ''All Employees'' value by default. You can change this value by selecting a particular employee from the lookup list.
##In the '''Earning Type''' column of the new row select needed earning type.
##In the '''Labor Item''' column of the new row select needed labor item.
##Save your changes.
#Repeat the previous step for all combinations of earning type, labor item, and employee you need. 
{br}

After the contract is set up, you can proceed with contract activation and recording usage by using case activities.
==To Record Usage by Using Case Activities==
[anchor|#ol_lsd_fgx_cr]
#Activate the contract in the way that suits your needs; now you can proceed with the contract fulfillment. For details, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__CON_Contract_Signing|Contract Setup and Activation].
#As needed, enter contract usage by using the functionality of the Customer Management module as follows:
##On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CR_30_60_00|Cases] ([~/?ScreenId=CR306000|CR306000]) form, create a case, specifying the case class that you created during contract configuration (see the previous section) and the applicable customer. Fill in other details at your discretion.
##On the '''Additional Info''' tab, assign the contract to the case by using the '''Contract''' box; fill in other details of this tab at your discretion. Save your changes.
##By using the '''Activities''' tab of the form, add an activity. For the activity, change the owner if needed, select the '''Track Time''' check box, and specify the billable time and the earning type. Save and release the activity. For details, see [HelpRoot_CRM\CR__con_Case_Billing|Case Billing]. 
##:The usage transaction is displayed on the '''Unbilled Transactions''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_30_00|Contract Usage] ([~/?ScreenId=CT303000|CT303000]) form. The system determines the labor item used to create the usage transaction by using the earning type and the owner of the released activity.
#Bill the contract according to its schedule. For more information, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__con_Contract_Billing|Contract Billing].
]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[To Set Up Employee Rates for Contracts You may need to set up employee rates specific for a contract. Consider the example                 in the following sections of this topic. To Configure a Contract with Specific Employee Rates Suppose that you offer a contract for annual support and bill customers monthly by                 case activity. You have first-line support engineers, who handle regular cases, and                 second-line support engineers, who handle complex problems. The second-line support                 engineers are John Smith and Jane Kent. The configuration matrix of employee rates is shown in the following table; when you                 set up billing by employee time, you can use a similar table for reference. Employee Rate Matrix Earning Type Labor Item Employee Regular Hours (RG) 1stLineRate All Employees Regular Hours (RG) 2ndLineRate Jane Kent Regular Hours (RG) 2ndLineRate John Smith To set up employee rates for the contract described above, you would perform the                 following steps: By using the   ([~/?ScreenId=IN202000|IN202000]) Non-Stock Items (IN202000) form, create two                         non-stock items of the  Labor  type ( 1stLineRate  and                              2ndLineRate ) to represent hours and define the respective rates.                         For details, see  Creating Non-Stock Items: Implementation Activity. On the   ([~/?ScreenId=CR206000|CR206000]) Case Classes (CR206000) form, configure a case                         class that requires a contract and bills cases on a per-activity basis. By using the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT202000|CT202000]) Contract Templates (CT202000) form, create an                         active contract template with scheduled billing. For details, see  To Configure a Contract Template. On the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) Customer Contracts (CT301000) form, create a contract                         based on the contract template configured in Step 3. For details, see  To Configure a Contract. On the  Employees  tab, enter the appropriate                         combinations of earning type, labor item, and employee by using the                              Employee rate matrix  table as a reference. Do the following: Add a row. The  Employee  column of the new row                                 is filled with the  All Employees  value by default. You can                                 change this value by selecting a particular employee from the lookup                                 list. In the  Earning Type  column of the new row                                 select needed earning type. In the  Labor Item  column of the new row                                 select needed labor item. Save your changes. Repeat the previous step for all combinations of earning type, labor item,                         and employee you need.  After the contract is set up, you can proceed with contract activation and recording                 usage by using case activities. To Record Usage by Using Case Activities Activate the contract in the way that suits your needs; now you can proceed                         with the contract fulfillment. For details, see  Contract Setup and Activation. As needed, enter contract usage by using the functionality of the Customer                         Management  module as follows: On the   ([~/?ScreenId=CR306000|CR306000]) Cases (CR306000) form, create a                                 case, specifying the case class that you created during contract                                 configuration (see the previous section) and the applicable                                 customer. Fill in other details at your discretion. On the  Additional Info  tab, assign the                                 contract to the case by using the  Contract                                  box; fill in other details of this tab at your discretion. Save your                                 changes. By using the  Activities  tab of the form, add                                 an activity. For the activity, change the owner if needed, select                                 the  Track Time  check box, and specify the                                 billable time and the earning type. Save and release the activity.                                 For details, see  Case Billing.  The                                     usage transaction is displayed on the  Unbilled                                         Transactions  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT303000|CT303000]) Contract Usage (CT303000) form. The system                                     determines the labor item used to create the usage transaction                                     by using the earning type and the owner of the released                                     activity. Bill the contract according to its schedule. For more information, see  Contract Billing. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="65f3c0de-adca-4521-a0da-71348a8e19d7" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="621d0ba8-f86a-c88d-1bd8-37e2169a4896" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
If the Customer Management feature is disabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) form, you can use the employees' time activities to record contract usage. For this purpose, you may need to set up employee rates that are specific for a contract. Consider the example presented in the following sections of this topic.
==To Configure a Contract with Specific Employee Rates==
Suppose that you offer a contract for annual support and bill customers monthly by employee time activity. You have first-line support engineers, who handle regular cases, and second-line support engineers, who handle more complex problems. The second-line support engineers are John Smith and Jane Kent.{br}

The configuration matrix of employee rates in this example is shown in the following table; when you set up billing by employee time, you can use a similar table for reference.[anchor|#table_yvl_fck_14]
===Employee Rate Matrix===
{| class="checklist" | width="100%" 
|- 
!width="33%" ! Earning Type
!width="33%" ! Labor Item
!width="33%" ! Employee
|- 
| Regular Hours (RG)
| 1stLineRate
| All Employees
|- 
| Regular Hours (RG)
| 2ndLineRate
| Jane Kent
|- 
| Regular Hours (RG)
| 2ndLineRate
| John Smith
|}{br}

To set up employee rates for the contract described above, you would perform the following steps:{br}

[anchor|#ol_xxx_ftj_1n]
#By using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\IN_20_20_00|Non-Stock Items] ([~/?ScreenId=IN202000|IN202000]) form, create two non-stock items of the ''Labor'' type (''1stLineRate'' and ''2ndLineRate'') to represent hours and define their respective rates. For details, see [HelpRoot_InvMgmt\Entity_OrderMgmt_Non_Stock_Items_Implem_Activity|Creating Non-Stock Items: Implementation Activity].
#By using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_20_20_00|Contract Templates] ([~/?ScreenId=CT202000|CT202000]) form, create an active contract template with scheduled billing. For details, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__HOW_Configure_Contract_Template|To Configure a Contract Template].
#On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_10_00|Customer Contracts] ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) form, create a contract based on the contract template configured in Step 2. For details, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__HOW_Prepare_Contract|To Configure a Contract].
#On the '''Employees''' tab, enter the appropriate combinations of earning type, labor item, and employee by using the ''Employee rate matrix'' table as a reference. Do the following:
##Add a row. The '''Employee''' column of the new row is filled with the ''All Employees'' value by default. You can change this value by selecting a particular employee.
##In the '''Earning Type''' column of the new row, select the needed earning type.
##In the '''Labor Item''' column of the new row, select the needed labor item.
##Save your changes.
#Repeat the previous step for all needed combinations of earning type, labor item, and employee. 
{br}

After the contract is set up, you can proceed with contract activation and usage recording by using case activities.
==To Record Usage by Using Time Activities==
[anchor|#ol_lsd_fgx_cr]
#Activate the contract in the way that suits your needs. For details, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__CON_Contract_Signing|Contract Setup and Activation].
#As needed during contract fulfillment, enter contract usage by using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_70_00|Employee Time Activities] ([~/?ScreenId=EP307000|EP307000]) form as follows:
##In the '''Employee''' box, select the employee for which you want to add an activity.
##By using the table toolbar, add an activity (row) to the table. The system inserts all default values for the row. You can change the default values, if needed.
##In the '''Contract''' column of the new row, select the contract to which you want to link the activity. 
##In the '''Time Spent''' column of the row, specify the time the employee spent on this activity.
##In the '''Billable''' column of the row, select the check box, and in the '''Billable Time''' column, specify the time for which you will bill the customer.
##In the '''Description''' column of the row, add a brief description, which will be used as the transaction description.
##Clear the check box in the '''Hold''' column of the row, and save the activity.
##On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_50_70_20|Release Time Activities] ([~/?ScreenId=EP507020|EP507020]) form, release the time activity.
##:The usage transaction is displayed on the '''Unbilled Transactions''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_30_00|Contract Usage] ([~/?ScreenId=CT303000|CT303000]) form. The system determines the labor item used to create the usage transaction by using the earning type and the owner of the released activity.
#Bill the contract according to its schedule. For more information, see [HelpRoot_ContractManagement\AR__con_Contract_Billing|Contract Billing].
]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[To Set Up Billing by Employee Time Activities If the Customer Management feature is disabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features                 (CS100000) form, you can use the employees' time activities to record contract                 usage. For this purpose, you may need to set up employee rates that are specific for                 a contract. Consider the example presented in the following sections of this                 topic. To Configure a Contract with Specific Employee Rates Suppose that you offer a contract for annual support and bill customers monthly by                 employee time activity. You have first-line support engineers, who handle regular                 cases, and second-line support engineers, who handle more complex problems. The                 second-line support engineers are John Smith and Jane Kent. The configuration matrix of employee rates in this example is shown in the following                 table; when you set up billing by employee time, you can use a similar table for                     reference. Employee Rate Matrix Earning Type Labor Item Employee Regular Hours (RG) 1stLineRate All Employees Regular Hours (RG) 2ndLineRate Jane Kent Regular Hours (RG) 2ndLineRate John Smith To set up employee rates for the contract described above, you would perform the                 following steps: By using the   ([~/?ScreenId=IN202000|IN202000]) Non-Stock Items (IN202000) form, create two                         non-stock items of the  Labor  type ( 1stLineRate  and                              2ndLineRate ) to represent hours and define their respective                         rates. For details, see  Creating Non-Stock Items: Implementation Activity. By using the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT202000|CT202000]) Contract Templates (CT202000) form, create an                         active contract template with scheduled billing. For details, see  To Configure a Contract Template. On the   ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000]) Customer Contracts (CT301000) form, create a contract                         based on the contract template configured in Step 2. For details, see  To Configure a Contract. On the  Employees  tab, enter the appropriate                         combinations of earning type, labor item, and employee by using the                              Employee rate matrix  table as a reference. Do the following: Add a row. The  Employee  column of the new row                                 is filled with the  All Employees  value by default. You can                                 change this value by selecting a particular employee. In the  Earning Type  column of the new row,                                 select the needed earning type. In the  Labor Item  column of the new row,                                 select the needed labor item. Save your changes. Repeat the previous step for all needed combinations of earning type, labor                         item, and employee.  After the contract is set up, you can proceed with contract activation and usage                 recording by using case activities. To Record Usage by Using Time Activities Activate the contract in the way that suits your needs. For details, see                              Contract Setup and Activation. As needed during contract fulfillment, enter contract usage by using the                               ([~/?ScreenId=EP307000|EP307000]) Employee Time Activities (EP307000) form as follows: In the  Employee  box, select the employee for                                 which you want to add an activity. By using the table toolbar, add an activity (row) to the table. The                                 system inserts all default values for the row. You can change the                                 default values, if needed. In the  Contract  column of the new row, select                                 the contract to which you want to link the activity.  In the  Time Spent  column of the row, specify                                 the time the employee spent on this activity. In the  Billable  column of the row, select the                                 check box, and in the  Billable Time  column,                                 specify the time for which you will bill the customer. In the  Description  column of the row, add a                                 brief description, which will be used as the transaction                                 description. Clear the check box in the  Hold  column of the                                 row, and save the activity. On the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP507020|EP507020]) Release Time Activities (EP507020) form, release                                 the time activity. The usage transaction is displayed on the                                          Unbilled Transactions  tab of the                                           ([~/?ScreenId=CT303000|CT303000]) Contract Usage (CT303000) form. The                                     system determines the labor item used to create the usage                                     transaction by using the earning type and the owner of the                                     released activity. Bill the contract according to its schedule. For more information, see  Contract Billing. ]]></column>
		</row>
	</rows>
</data>