<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<data>
	<table name="WikiRevision">
		<col name="CompanyID" type="Int" default="Zero" />
		<col name="PageID" type="UniqueIdentifier" />
		<col name="Language" type="VarChar(50)" />
		<col name="PageRevisionID" type="Int" />
		<col name="Content" type="NVarChar(MAX)" />
		<col name="ContentHtml" type="NVarChar(MAX)" nullable="true" />
		<col name="PlainText" type="NVarChar(MAX)" />
		<col name="ApprovalByID" type="UniqueIdentifier" nullable="true" />
		<col name="ApprovalDateTime" type="DateTime" nullable="true" />
		<col name="CreatedByID" type="UniqueIdentifier" />
		<col name="CreatedDateTime" type="DateTime" />
		<col name="CompanyMask" type="VarBinary(32)" default="CompanyMaskReadOnly" />
		<col name="UID" type="UniqueIdentifier" />
		<col name="RecordSourceID" type="SmallInt" nullable="true" />
	</table>
	<rows>
		<row PageID="c592236a-31ab-4e32-afed-45bbc7b1a0cd" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="b0c16ae2-4b51-739e-a630-0b22e881cabc" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
The payroll functionality of Acumatica ERP is used to set up, enter, and maintain employee payroll records and transactions.{br}

You also can use the payroll forms to complete the following tasks:[anchor|#ul_khp_v3q_zv]
*Set up employee payroll classes, which create default settings that can speed data entry of new employee records because the payroll information is grouped according to common factors, such as pay groups and work locations.
*Create batches for processing multiple employees at a time (a typical pay run process) or easily create one-time checks to handle special circumstances. Data from the Acumatica ERP time entry system could be automatically brought into payroll, along with sales commission data, if required. 
*Use predefined inquiries and reports to view current and historical payroll information and pay activity for one employee or a selected group of employees.
*For direct deposits, automatically create the ACH file for the transfer of funds directly to employee bank accounts.
*Post General Ledger activity allocated in many possible ways.
*Automatically generate tax and deduction liability invoices to the accounts payable, and payment information to the cash management forms for bank reconciliation.
]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Overview of the Payroll Process The payroll functionality of  Acumatica ERP is used to set up, enter, and maintain employee payroll records and transactions. You also can use the payroll forms to complete the following tasks: Set up employee payroll classes, which create default settings that can speed data entry         of new employee records because the payroll information is grouped according to common         factors, such as pay groups and work locations. Create batches for processing multiple employees at a time (a typical pay run process) or         easily create one-time checks to handle special circumstances. Data from the  Acumatica ERP time entry system could be automatically brought into payroll, along with sales         commission data, if required.  Use predefined inquiries and reports to view current and historical payroll information         and pay activity for one employee or a selected group of employees. For direct deposits, automatically create the ACH file for the transfer of funds directly         to employee bank accounts. Post General Ledger activity allocated in many possible ways. Automatically generate tax and deduction liability invoices to the accounts payable, and         payment information to the cash management forms for bank reconciliation. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="ca13ce27-0b83-4b7a-9552-f59c43fada97" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" Content="&#xA;In this chapter, you can find information on setting up and maintaining the configuration of the payroll functionality.&#xA;==In This Chapter==[anchor|#ul_ubp_qgn_dw]&#xA;*[HelpRoot_Payroll\PR__CNF_Prep|Prerequisites and Preparation]&#xA;*[HelpRoot_Payroll\PR__CNF_Flow|Configuration Flow]&#xA;" PlainText="Configuring Payroll In this chapter, you can find information on setting up and maintaining the configuration of    the payroll functionality. In This Chapter Prerequisites and PreparationConfiguration Flow" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="3acdd7d5-6316-525b-9490-766f9fe2bf56" RecordSourceID="22377" />
		<row PageID="56b86c64-ee64-4ebe-99c2-23d2b7f2f2f0" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="d18ce8b0-62fe-d5d6-f5bf-3a63de7991fa" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
This topic covers the prerequisites and preparatory steps that must be completed before you begin configuring the payroll functionality.
==Prerequisites and Dependencies==[anchor|#ol_tjd_13n_dw]
#The license for Acumatica ERP should include the ''Payroll'' feature, and the feature should be enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) form. For details, see [HelpRoot_Implement\config_SA_Prep_Instance_for_Implem_GeneralInfo|Preparing Instance: General Information].
#The initial system configuration must be completed and the General Ledger functionality must be configured before you implement payroll. The payroll functionality can be tightly integrated with other Acumatica ERP functional areas, including general ledger, accounts payable, organization structure, and time and expenses. These areas do not require any change in their configuration when payroll is implemented; however, the functionality to be integrated with payroll should be implemented before payroll. (Enabling time tracking is not needed.)

==Preparation==
You should start the implementation of the payroll functionality by collecting and analyzing the necessary information. Perform the following steps before you actually configure; these steps do not need to be done in the listed order. [anchor|#table_rlm_qln_dw]
{| class="checklist" | width="100%" 
|- 
!width="20%" ! Item
!width="80%" ! Description
|- 
| '''Define GL accounts'''
| 
Because payroll uses GL accounts and subaccounts for payroll-related transactions, define the necessary expense and liability accounts and subaccounts and determine which of these accounts will be used by default for records of the following:[anchor|#_257d0c76-9b62-4680-9034-9077b57d4255]
*''Earnings'': An expense account is used to record the earnings.
*''Deductions'': A liability account is used to record the deduction from employee paycheck.
*''Benefits'': An expense account is used to record the benefit to employee paycheck and a liability account to off-set the benefit expense account.
*''Taxes'': An expense account is used to record the taxes and a liability account to off-set the tax expense account.

Review the existing chart of accounts and add missing accounts (if needed) by using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_20_25_00|Chart of Accounts] ([~/?ScreenId=GL202500|GL202500]) form.
|- 
| '''Define payment methods and cash accounts'''
| 
Define which payment methods are to be used to generate paychecks for the employee. Mark these payment methods as available for use in payroll, by selecting the '''Use in PR''' check box in the Summary area of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CA_20_40_00|Payment Methods] ([~/?ScreenId=CA204000|CA204000]) form.{br}

For each payment method define a cash account to be used to generate paychecks for the employee. Mark these cash accounts as available for use in payroll, by selecting the '''Use in PR''' check box on the '''Allowed Cash Accounts''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CA_20_40_00|Payment Methods] ([~/?ScreenId=CA204000|CA204000]) form.{br}

A special export scenario, ''Export PR Payment to ACH Balanced'', was created to handle specific requirement for Payroll direct deposit.
|- 
| '''Configure vendors'''
| Define and configure vendors you will need while working with payroll, such as tax agencies, benefit providers and unions. For details on vendor configuration, see [HelpRoot_Financials\Vendor_GeneralInfo|Vendors: General Information].
|- 
| '''Design numbering sequences'''
| Design the numbering sequences to be used to numerate documents generated by payroll. We recommend using naming conventions in numbering sequences to differentiate payroll documents from other documents generated in the system. For details on creating numbering sequences, see [HelpRoot_Administration\CS__con_Multiple_Numbering_Sequences|Numbering Sequence Usage].
|- 
| '''Design roles'''
| 
Design the roles you need for users who will work with the Payroll forms. We recommend configuring the following security roles: [anchor|#ul_ddb_bpn_dw]
*''PR Clerk'': Payroll clerk. This role gives the user the ability to process payroll on a recurring basis and to print reports and view inquiries; it does not grant access to change setup and configuration information in the Payroll forms. 
*''PR Manager'': Payroll manager. This role gives the user access rights to all payroll functionality.

For details on configuring user roles, see [HelpRoot_Administration\User_Roles_GeneralInfo|User Roles: General Information].
|}]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Prerequisites and Preparation This topic covers the prerequisites and preparatory steps that must be completed before you    begin configuring the payroll functionality. Prerequisites and Dependencies The license for  Acumatica ERP      should include the  Payroll  feature, and the feature should be enabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features (CS100000) form. For details, see  Preparing Instance: General Information. The initial system configuration must be completed and the General Ledger functionality must      be configured before you implement payroll. The payroll functionality can be tightly integrated      with other  Acumatica ERP      functional areas, including general ledger, accounts payable, organization structure, and time      and expenses. These areas do not require any change in their configuration when payroll is      implemented; however, the functionality to be integrated with payroll should be implemented      before payroll. (Enabling time tracking is not needed.) Preparation You should start the implementation of the payroll functionality by collecting and analyzing     the necessary information. Perform the following steps before you actually configure; these     steps do not need to be done in the listed order.  Item Description Define GL accounts Because payroll uses GL accounts and subaccounts for payroll-related transactions, define          the necessary expense and liability accounts and subaccounts and determine which of these          accounts will be used by default for records of the following: Earnings : An expense account is used to record the earnings. Deductions : A liability account is used to record the deduction from employee           paycheck. Benefits : An expense account is used to record the benefit to employee paycheck           and a liability account to off-set the benefit expense account. Taxes : An expense account is used to record the taxes and a liability account to           off-set the tax expense account. Review the existing chart of accounts and add missing accounts (if needed) by using the             ([~/?ScreenId=GL202500|GL202500]) Chart of Accounts (GL202500) form. Define payment methods and cash accounts Define which payment methods are to be used to generate paychecks for the employee. Mark          these payment methods as available for use in payroll, by selecting the  Use in           PR  check box in the Summary area of the   ([~/?ScreenId=CA204000|CA204000]) Payment Methods          (CA204000) form. For each payment method define a cash account to be used to generate paychecks for the          employee. Mark these cash accounts as available for use in payroll, by selecting the            Use in PR  check box on the  Allowed Cash           Accounts  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=CA204000|CA204000]) Payment Methods (CA204000) form. A special export scenario,  Export PR Payment to ACH Balanced , was created to          handle specific requirement for Payroll direct deposit. Configure vendors Define and configure vendors you will need while working with payroll, such as tax         agencies, benefit providers and unions. For details on vendor configuration, see  Vendors: General Information. Design numbering sequences Design the numbering sequences to be used to numerate documents generated by payroll.         We recommend using naming conventions in numbering sequences to differentiate payroll         documents from other documents generated in the system. For details on creating numbering         sequences, see  Numbering Sequence Usage. Design roles Design the roles you need for users who will work with the Payroll forms. We recommend          configuring the following security roles:  PR Clerk : Payroll clerk. This role gives the user the ability to process payroll           on a recurring basis and to print reports and view inquiries; it does not grant access to           change setup and configuration information in the Payroll forms.  PR Manager : Payroll manager. This role gives the user access rights to all           payroll functionality. For details on configuring user roles, see  User Roles: General Information. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="0fd6ab26-24a8-4fc4-9979-cd5d13b31562" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="e710526b-9642-1209-82c0-9927faf5c97c" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
This topic provides a summary of the tasks you complete to configure the payroll functionality in Acumatica ERP.[anchor|#table_tf2_zjg_1w]
{| class="checklist" | width="100%" 
|- 
!width="5%" ! No.
!width="23%" ! Action
!width="71%" ! Description
|- 
| '''1'''
|  '''Configure the structure of the organization'''
| 
On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_15_00|Departments] ([~/?ScreenId=EP201500|EP201500]) and [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_10_00|Positions] ([~/?ScreenId=EP201000|EP201000]) forms, make sure that departments and positions are properly configured for your organization.{br}

On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_15_00|Companies] ([~/?ScreenId=CS101500|CS101500]) form, configure the company-level data that will appear on government forms such as W-2 and ACA forms. Specify if the taxes are filed by branches or not.{br}

If the taxes are filed by branches, on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_20_00|Branches] ([~/?ScreenId=CS102000|CS102000]) form, configure the company-level data that will appear on government forms such as W-2 and ACA forms.
|- 
| '''2'''
|  '''Set up the work calendar'''
| 
Use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_20_90_00|Work Calendar] ([~/?ScreenId=CS209000|CS209000]) form to set up the work calendar.{br}

On the '''Calendar Settings''' tab, specify the number of work hours per day. Indicate any unpaid break time during the work day, so that if your company has a 9-hour work day with an hour off for lunch, the system calculates 8 paid hours.{br}

On the '''Exceptions''' tab, specify holidays, to define when holiday pay must be paid to employees who work instead of regular pay.
|- 
| '''3'''
|  '''Specify your preferences for the Payroll module'''
| 
Use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_10_10_00|Payroll Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=PR101000|PR101000]) form to configure the general settings of payroll.{br}

On the '''General Info''' tab, specify the following settings:[anchor|#_474fa4c3-f6eb-4099-8757-125dbae89ec8]
*In the '''Numbering Settings''' section, select the numbering sequences you created on the preparation stage.
*In the '''Posting and Retention Settings''' section, specify default source of GL accounts, subaccount masks (if any), and other posting settings.
*Fill in the rest of the check boxes as appropriate for your requirements.

On the '''Transaction Date Exceptions''' tab, review the list holidays, add missing exception dates, if any. The system uses the list to define when bank holidays are happening to shift transaction date when creating pay periods.
|- 
| '''4'''
|  '''Set up work locations'''
| 
On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_10_10_40|Work Locations] ([~/?ScreenId=PR101040|PR101040]) form, for each location where work is to be performed, enter all the address information through the postal code. {br}

For details, see [HelpRoot_Payroll\config_Payroll_Work_Locations_Mapref|Configuring Work Locations].
|- 
| '''5'''
|  '''Set up tax codes'''
| 
Use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_20_80_00|Tax Maintenance] ([~/?ScreenId=PR208000|PR208000]) form to set up all of the tax codes you need. {br}

On the '''Tax Codes''' tab of the same form, for each tax, specify vendor (tax agency), default attribute settings, and general ledger accounts.{br}

Note that the attributes may be different depending on the state.{br}

On the '''Company Tax Settings''' tab, select the different settings linked to the taxes at the company level.{br}

For details, see [HelpRoot_Payroll\config_Payroll_Taxes_Mapref|Configuring Taxes].
|- 
| '''6'''
|  '''Set up earning types'''
| 
Use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_10_20_00|Earning Type Codes] ([~/?ScreenId=PR102000|PR102000]) form to set up earning types. {br}

Earning types are the ways in which you can pay an employee. For the predefined earning types, make sure that the settings are specified the way you want them in your organization. Also, if you want a particular earning type to be always assigned to a specific project, you can set it up on this form.{br}

For more information, see [HelpRoot_Payroll\config_Payroll_Earning_Types_Mapref|Configuring Earning Types].
|- 
| '''7'''
|  '''Specify earning type preferences for the Payroll module'''
| 
Use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_10_10_00|Payroll Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=PR101000|PR101000]) form to configure earning type preferences.{br}

On the '''General Info''' tab, in the '''Miscellaneous Settings''' section, you will be able to define the different earning codes used for the creation of the payroll batches when using quick pay process. {br}

Regular earning type for quick pay will only display the earning type code with the Salary category. The holidays earning type for quick pay will only display earning type code with the Time Off category and the commission earning type will only display earning code with the Amount-Based category. {br}

Select the ''Enable Piecework as an Earning Type'' check box, if you plan to use piecework earning types.
|- 
| '''8'''
|  '''Set up deduction and benefit codes'''
| 
On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_10_10_60|Deduction and Benefit Codes] ([~/?ScreenId=PR101060|PR101060]) form, set up your deduction and benefit codes.{br}

You can set up each deduction or benefit code to be only a deduction, only a benefit, or both a deduction and a benefit. Also, you can specify if it is subject to all taxes, no taxes, or specific taxes, in which case you need to add the taxes that it is subject to.{br}

For health care related benefits, you will be able to set up the information related to the ACA reporting to populate the information on the '''ACA Reporting''' tab.{br}

You will also need to create one benefit code flagged as Workers’ Compensation for each state your company is operating in and assign the rate for each code on the '''Worker’s Compensation''' tab.{br}

For details, see [HelpRoot_Payroll\config_Payroll_Deductions_Benefits_Mapref|Configuring Deductions and Benefits].
|- 
| '''9'''
|  '''Set up unions'''
| Use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_20_97_00|Union Locals] ([~/?ScreenId=PR209700|PR209700]) form to configure the different unions the employees are part of. Different earning rates can be applied to different rank inside a union and the specific benefits and deductions can be added on this form (they will be added to the paycheck)
|- 
| '''10'''
|  '''Set up certified projects (Construction Only)'''
| Use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_20_99_00|Certified Projects] ([~/?ScreenId=PR209900|PR209900]) form to set up the payroll related information for government linked projects. Different earning rates can be applied to different types of labor, specific benefits and deductions can be added and fringe benefit rate specified on this form (they will be added to the paycheck).
|- 
| '''11'''
|  '''Configure overtime rules'''
| 
Use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_10_40_00|Overtime Rules] ([~/?ScreenId=PR104000|PR104000]) form to set up overtime rules.{br}

To use this functionality, create earning types with the ''Overtime'' option selected in the '''Earning Type Category''' box on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_10_20_00|Earning Type Codes] ([~/?ScreenId=PR102000|PR102000]). For such earning types you can configure a list of overtime rules to be applied to an employee pay check.
|- 
| '''12'''
|  '''Set up pay groups,pay calendars, and pay periods'''
| 
Use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_20_50_00|Pay Groups] ([~/?ScreenId=PR205000|PR205000]) form to set up pay groups. {br}

A pay group reflects a group of people that get paid in the same frequency.{br}

For each pay group click the '''Calendar''' button on the form toolbar, which navigates to the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_20_60_00|Payroll Calendar] ([~/?ScreenId=PR206000|PR206000]) form. By using this form, you define pay period frequency and pay dates.{br}

For a pay group for which a calendar has been configured generate pay periods on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_20_10_00|Pay Periods] ([~/?ScreenId=PR201000|PR201000]) form.
|- 
| '''13'''
|  '''Set up PTO banks'''
| 
Use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_20_40_00|PTO Banks] ([~/?ScreenId=PR204000|PR204000]) form to define various PTO banks (accrual plans) for your employees.{br}

For more information, see [HelpRoot_Payroll\config_Payroll_PTO_Banks_Mapref|Configuring Paid Time Off].
|- 
| '''14'''
|  '''Set up employee classes'''
| 
Use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_20_20_00|Employee Class] ([~/?ScreenId=PR202000|PR202000]) form to set up payroll classes.{br}

By using employee classes, you can specify certain information as the default settings for employees, including the employee type, pay group, location, union, and paid time off. This information can be overridden at the employee level later. Every change made at this level will propagate to the employee level if the '''Use class default value''' check box is selected on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_20_30_00|Employee Payroll Settings] ([~/?ScreenId=PR203000|PR203000]) form.
|- 
| '''15'''
|  '''Set up employees'''
| 
Use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_30_00|Employees] ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000]) form to set up your employees. Acumatica ERP includes this general-purpose employee maintenance form to record basic setup information about employees for use in a number of different areas, such as Projects, Customer Management, and Time and Expenses. Payroll also uses this basic information, and then adds its own additional required information that is needed for processing payroll-specific transactions. {br}

Because of this, all employees must first be set up in the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_30_00|Employees] form; you need to fill in the general information (especially the employee’s address for tax purposes), the work calendar (to calculate the number of hours worked by the employee during a week and put the labor item to default in the payroll transactions), the employment history (including the employee’s current position and hire date; some validations will be run to prevent the user from paying an employee before start date or after end date), and the GL accounts that are required.
|- 
| '''16'''
|  '''Specify employee payroll settings'''
| On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_20_30_00|Employee Payroll Settings] ([~/?ScreenId=PR203000|PR203000]) form, you will be able to create new payroll employee. When creating a new payroll employee, the system will bring up each employee that was created on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_30_00|Employees] form and that are not yet payroll employee and add payroll data upon selection. Specify the following settings:[anchor|#ul_cb2_rnm_1w]
*On the '''General Info''' tab, if you need to change the defaults that were set up for the employee class, clear the '''Use class default value''' check box next to each box you need to change and then make your change.
*Once you are done setting up the other default settings, click '''Get Tax Codes'''. The tax engine will look at the employee address and get the tax location code that pertains to the location of the employee. Next, click '''View Tax List''' to display a list of taxes that may be applicable for this employee based on the employee’s tax location code. If a tax code has not been added for a particular tax, click '''Add Tax Code''' on the table toolbar. Then you can select the check box to the left of each applicable tax, and click '''Assign Selected Taxes to Employee''' to automatically set up the selected taxes for this employee. All the taxes from the home address and the work address of the employee should be added to the record. The tax engine will calculate the appropriate tax according to the tax settings.
*On the '''Tax Settings''' tab enter the social security number for the employee as well as all the items that pertain to your employee taxes.
*On the '''Taxes''' tab, make sure that all taxes that apply to this employee have been set up (home taxes and work location taxes). If you select a tax on the top panel, the system displays the attributes that belong to that tax on the bottom panel. Fill in the items that apply.
*On the '''Compensation''' tab, add the earning types that will be used as the normal earnings (wages) that apply to your employee. Select the pay rate, such as hourly or annual (or miscellaneous for Piecework). Also, you should enter a start date for each earning type. If you enter an earning type with the same code, you’ll also have to specify an end date for the previous rate.
*On the '''Deductions and Benefits''' tab, enter those items that apply to the employee that you are setting up. You can change the default settings if you clear the '''Use Deduction Defaults''' or '''Use Contribution Defaults''' check box.
*On the '''Paid Time Off''' tab, review the settings that have been copied from the employee class. You can change the default settings if you clear the corresponding '''Use PTO Banks from Employee Class''' check box.
*On the '''Payment Settings''' tab, specify a payment method and a cash account and enter the direct deposit information for the employee. Employees can distribute their pay into an unlimited number of bank accounts.
*On the '''GL Accounts''' tab, specify general lender accounts to be used for this employee.

|}]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Configuration Flow This topic provides a summary of the tasks you complete to configure the payroll functionality     in  Acumatica ERP. No. Action Description 1 Configure the structure of the organization On the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP201500|EP201500]) Departments (EP201500) and   ([~/?ScreenId=EP201000|EP201000]) Positions          (EP201000) forms, make sure that departments and positions are properly configured for your          organization. On the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS101500|CS101500]) Companies (CS101500) form, configure the company-level data          that will appear on government forms such as W-2 and ACA forms. Specify if the taxes are          filed by branches or not. If the taxes are filed by branches, on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS102000|CS102000]) Branches (CS102000)          form, configure the company-level data that will appear on government forms such as W-2 and          ACA forms. 2 Set up the work calendar Use the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS209000|CS209000]) Work Calendar (CS209000) form to set up the work calendar. On the  Calendar Settings  tab, specify the number of work hours per          day. Indicate any unpaid break time during the work day, so that if your company has a          9-hour work day with an hour off for lunch, the system calculates 8 paid hours. On the  Exceptions  tab, specify holidays, to define when holiday          pay must be paid to employees who work instead of regular pay. 3 Specify your preferences for the Payroll module Use the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR101000|PR101000]) Payroll Preferences (PR101000) form to configure the general settings          of payroll. On the  General Info  tab, specify the following settings: In the  Numbering Settings  section, select the numbering           sequences you created on the preparation stage. In the  Posting and Retention Settings  section, specify default           source of GL accounts, subaccount masks (if any), and other posting settings. Fill in the rest of the check boxes as appropriate for your requirements. On the  Transaction Date Exceptions  tab, review the list holidays,          add missing exception dates, if any. The system uses the list to define when bank holidays          are happening to shift transaction date when creating pay periods. 4 Set up work locations On the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR101040|PR101040]) Work Locations (PR101040) form, for each location where work is          to be performed, enter all the address information through the postal code.  For details, see  Configuring Work Locations. 5 Set up tax codes Use the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR208000|PR208000]) Tax Maintenance (PR208000) form to set up all of the tax codes          you need.  On the  Tax Codes  tab of the same form, for each tax, specify          vendor (tax agency), default attribute settings, and general ledger accounts. Note that the attributes may be different depending on the state. On the  Company Tax Settings  tab, select the different settings          linked to the taxes at the company level. For details, see  Configuring Taxes. 6 Set up earning types Use the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR102000|PR102000]) Earning Type Codes (PR102000) form to set up earning types.  Earning types are the ways in which you can pay an employee. For the predefined earning          types, make sure that the settings are specified the way you want them in your          organization. Also, if you want a particular earning type to be always assigned to a          specific project, you can set it up on this form. For more information, see  Configuring Earning Types. 7 Specify earning type preferences for the Payroll module Use the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR101000|PR101000]) Payroll Preferences (PR101000) form to configure earning type          preferences. On the  General Info  tab, in the  Miscellaneous           Settings  section, you will be able to define the different earning codes used          for the creation of the payroll batches when using quick pay process.  Regular earning type for quick pay will only display the earning type code with the          Salary category. The holidays earning type for quick pay will only display earning type          code with the Time Off category and the commission earning type will only display earning          code with the Amount-Based category.  Select the  Enable Piecework as an Earning Type  check box, if you plan to use          piecework earning types. 8 Set up deduction and benefit codes On the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR101060|PR101060]) Deduction and Benefit Codes (PR101060) form, set up your deduction and benefit          codes. You can set up each deduction or benefit code to be only a deduction, only a benefit, or          both a deduction and a benefit. Also, you can specify if it is subject to all taxes, no          taxes, or specific taxes, in which case you need to add the taxes that it is subject          to. For health care related benefits, you will be able to set up the information related to          the ACA reporting to populate the information on the  ACA Reporting           tab. You will also need to create one benefit code flagged as Workers’ Compensation for each          state your company is operating in and assign the rate for each code on the            Worker’s Compensation  tab. For details, see  Configuring Deductions and Benefits. 9 Set up unions Use the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR209700|PR209700]) Union Locals (PR209700) form to configure the different         unions the employees are part of. Different earning rates can be applied to different rank         inside a union and the specific benefits and deductions can be added on this form (they will         be added to the paycheck) 10 Set up certified projects (Construction Only) Use the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR209900|PR209900]) Certified Projects (PR209900) form to set up the payroll related         information for government linked projects. Different earning rates can be applied to         different types of labor, specific benefits and deductions can be added and fringe benefit         rate specified on this form (they will be added to the paycheck). 11 Configure overtime rules Use the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR104000|PR104000]) Overtime Rules (PR104000) form to set up overtime rules. To use this functionality, create earning types with the  Overtime  option selected          in the  Earning Type Category  box on the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR102000|PR102000]) Earning Type Codes (PR102000). For such earning types you can configure a list of          overtime rules to be applied to an employee pay check. 12 Set up pay groups,pay calendars, and pay periods Use the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR205000|PR205000]) Pay Groups (PR205000) form to set up pay groups.  A pay group reflects a group of people that get paid in the same frequency. For each pay group click the  Calendar  button on the form toolbar,          which navigates to the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR206000|PR206000]) Payroll Calendar (PR206000) form. By using this form,          you define pay period frequency and pay dates. For a pay group for which a calendar has been configured generate pay periods on the             ([~/?ScreenId=PR201000|PR201000]) Pay Periods (PR201000) form. 13 Set up PTO banks Use the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR204000|PR204000]) PTO Banks (PR204000) form to define various PTO banks          (accrual plans) for your employees. For more information, see  Configuring Paid Time Off. 14 Set up employee classes Use the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR202000|PR202000]) Employee Class (PR202000) form to set up payroll classes. By using employee classes, you can specify certain information as the default settings          for employees, including the employee type, pay group, location, union, and paid time off.          This information can be overridden at the employee level later. Every change made at this          level will propagate to the employee level if the  Use class default           value  check box is selected on the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR203000|PR203000]) Employee Payroll Settings (PR203000)          form. 15 Set up employees Use the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000]) Employees (EP203000) form to set up your employees.  Acumatica ERP includes this general-purpose employee maintenance form to record basic setup          information about employees for use in a number of different areas, such as Projects,          Customer Management, and Time and Expenses. Payroll also uses this basic information, and          then adds its own additional required information that is needed for processing          payroll-specific transactions.  Because of this, all employees must first be set up in the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000]) Employees form; you need to fill in the general information (especially the employee’s address for          tax purposes), the work calendar (to calculate the number of hours worked by the employee          during a week and put the labor item to default in the payroll transactions), the          employment history (including the employee’s current position and hire date; some          validations will be run to prevent the user from paying an employee before start date or          after end date), and the GL accounts that are required. 16 Specify employee payroll settings On the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR203000|PR203000]) Employee Payroll Settings (PR203000) form, you will be able to create new         payroll employee. When creating a new payroll employee, the system will bring up each         employee that was created on the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000]) Employees form and that are not yet         payroll employee and add payroll data upon selection. Specify the following settings: On the  General Info  tab, if you need to change the defaults that           were set up for the employee class, clear the  Use class default            value  check box next to each box you need to change and then make your           change. Once you are done setting up the other default settings, click  Get Tax            Codes . The tax engine will look at the employee address and get the tax           location code that pertains to the location of the employee. Next, click  View            Tax List  to display a list of taxes that may be applicable for this employee           based on the employee’s tax location code. If a tax code has not been added for a           particular tax, click  Add Tax Code  on the table toolbar. Then you           can select the check box to the left of each applicable tax, and click  Assign            Selected Taxes to Employee  to automatically set up the selected taxes for           this employee. All the taxes from the home address and the work address of the employee           should be added to the record. The tax engine will calculate the appropriate tax according           to the tax settings. On the  Tax Settings  tab enter the social security number for the           employee as well as all the items that pertain to your employee taxes. On the  Taxes  tab, make sure that all taxes that apply to this           employee have been set up (home taxes and work location taxes). If you select a tax on the           top panel, the system displays the attributes that belong to that tax on the bottom panel.           Fill in the items that apply. On the  Compensation  tab, add the earning types that will be used           as the normal earnings (wages) that apply to your employee. Select the pay rate, such as           hourly or annual (or miscellaneous for Piecework). Also, you should enter a start date for           each earning type. If you enter an earning type with the same code, you’ll also have to           specify an end date for the previous rate. On the  Deductions and Benefits  tab, enter those items that apply           to the employee that you are setting up. You can change the default settings if you clear           the  Use Deduction Defaults  or  Use Contribution            Defaults  check box. On the  Paid Time Off  tab, review the settings that have been           copied from the employee class. You can change the default settings if you clear the           corresponding  Use PTO Banks from Employee Class  check box. On the  Payment Settings  tab, specify a payment method and a cash           account and enter the direct deposit information for the employee. Employees can           distribute their pay into an unlimited number of bank accounts. On the  GL Accounts  tab, specify general lender accounts to be           used for this employee. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="972f8477-552f-4864-aee9-1361dcdde7da" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" Content="&#xA;In this chapter, you will learn how you can create work locations for a company." PlainText="Configuring Work Locations In this chapter, you will learn how you can create work locations for a company. " ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="5c53bb9b-7b74-cb09-a766-457aea799288" RecordSourceID="22377" />
		<row PageID="fe9918f1-bf06-4b74-8a82-b94e7c9fe89b" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="4b74742a-8ab0-3aef-3eb1-92690b74889a" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
A work location includes an address and other information pertaining to a physical location where work is performed. This may be a business location of the employer, or it may be a job site where work is being carried out. Work locations are used in the calculation of state and local taxes. All work locations where taxes may need to be withheld need to be set up, and the work associated with them needs to be tracked in payroll.{br}{TOC}
==Learning Objectives==
In this chapter, you will learn how to create a work location.
==Applicable Scenarios==
You configure work locations if your company has business in multiple states and you need to calculate state and local taxes for those locations.
==Configuration of Work Locations==
You create and edit work locations on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_10_10_40|Work Locations] ([~/?ScreenId=PR101040|PR101040]) form. For each location, you specify an address, including the postal code, which the system will use for the calculation of state and local taxes.{br}

If a work location shares the address of a branch, you can select that branch in the '''Use Address from Branch ID''' box, and the address boxes in the '''Main Address''' section will be automatically populated with the information from the branch record. In this case, if the branch address changes, the work location address will also change automatically.{br}

You can specify multiple work locations for an employee class in the '''Work Locations''' table on '''Payroll Settings''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_20_20_00|Employee Class] ([~/?ScreenId=PR202000|PR202000]) form. Only the work locations that are specified in the table will be available in an employee's paychecks and adjustments and in the related payroll batches if the '''Use Class Default Value''' check box is selected for the employee on the '''General Info''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_20_30_00|Employee Payroll Settings] ([~/?ScreenId=PR203000|PR203000]) form. You can mark one work location as the default for the system to use it on transaction entry if no specific work location is specified.]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Work Locations: General Information A work location includes an address and other information pertaining to a physical location         where work is performed. This may be a business location of the employer, or it may be a job         site where work is being carried out. Work locations are used in the calculation of state         and local taxes. All work locations where taxes may need to be withheld need to be set up,         and the work associated with them needs to be tracked in payroll. Learning Objectives In this chapter, you will learn how to create a work location. Applicable Scenarios You configure work locations if your company has business in multiple states and you need to         calculate state and local taxes for those locations. Configuration of Work Locations You create and edit work locations on the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR101040|PR101040]) Work Locations (PR101040) form. For     each location, you specify an address, including the postal code, which the system will use for     the calculation of state and local taxes. If a work location shares the address of a branch, you can select that branch in the       Use Address from Branch ID  box, and the address boxes in the       Main Address  section will be automatically populated with the     information from the branch record. In this case, if the branch address changes, the work     location address will also change automatically. You can specify multiple work locations for an employee class in the  Work      Locations  table on  Payroll Settings  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR202000|PR202000]) Employee Class (PR202000) form. Only the work locations that are specified in the     table will be available in an employee's paychecks and adjustments and in the related payroll     batches if the  Use Class Default Value  check box is selected for the     employee on the  General Info  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR203000|PR203000]) Employee Payroll Settings (PR203000) form. You can mark one work location as the     default for the system to use it on transaction entry if no specific work location is     specified. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="68593b1c-0bd2-4f51-9613-54e34f363766" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="48623e6c-5adb-c389-642b-8be1bb0c3bb9" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
In the following implementation activity, you will learn how to create a work location.[anchor|#_f3336550-f83a-41f6-a45d-070039b38623]((({S:Danger}The following activity is based on the ''U100'' dataset. If you are using another dataset, or if any system settings have been changed in ''U100'', these changes can affect the workflow of the activity and the results of the processing. To avoid any issues, restore the ''U100'' dataset to its initial state.
)))
==Story==
Suppose that the SweetLife company needs to keep track of the work associated with each of its branches. Acting as an administrator, you need to create three work locations, each corresponding to a different branch of SweetLife Fruits & Jams.
==Process Overview==
You create a work location on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_10_10_40|Work Locations] ([~/?ScreenId=PR101040|PR101040]) form. You select a branch to be used as the source of the address information for the work location.
==System Preparation==
Before you start creating a work location, sign in to a company with the ''U100'' dataset preloaded as a system administrator with the ''admin'' login.
==Step: Creating a Work Location==
To create a work location, do the following:[anchor|#_fa742785-635f-4638-890f-918dff014a89]
#Open the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_10_10_40|Work Locations] ([~/?ScreenId=PR101040|PR101040]) form.[anchor|#_780b2915-31df-4bf2-a260-2a5167b27051]
#On the form toolbar, click '''Add New Record'''.
#Specify the following settings:
#*'''Location ID''': <tt>HEADOFFICE</tt>
#*'''Location Name''': <tt>Head office</tt>
#*'''Use Address from Branch ID''': ''HEADOFFICE''
#Leave the '''Active''' check box selected.[anchor|#_5fde0c87-5801-4ec2-8d2b-8af5cbd08190]
#On the form toolbar, click '''Save'''.
]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Work Locations: Implementation Activity In the following implementation activity, you will learn how to create a work                 location. The following activity is             based on the  U100  dataset. If you are using another dataset, or if any system             settings have been changed in  U100 , these changes can affect the workflow of the             activity and the results of the processing. To avoid any issues, restore the  U100              dataset to its initial state. Story Suppose that the SweetLife company needs to keep track of the work associated with                 each of its branches. Acting as an administrator, you need to create three work                 locations, each corresponding to a different branch of SweetLife Fruits &                 Jams. Process Overview You create a work location on the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR101040|PR101040]) Work Locations (PR101040) form.                 You select a branch to be used as the source of the address information for the work                 location. System Preparation Before you start creating a work location, sign in to a company with the  U100                  dataset preloaded as a system administrator with the  admin  login. Step: Creating a Work Location To create a work location, do the following: Open the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR101040|PR101040]) Work Locations (PR101040) form. On              the form toolbar, click  Add New Record . Specify the following settings: Location ID :                              HEADOFFICE Location Name :  Head                             office Use Address from Branch ID :                              HEADOFFICE Leave the  Active  check box selected. On the form toolbar, click  Save . ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="d78a1034-fcaa-4299-8453-49495b66ea4b" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" Content="&#xA;This chapter contains information about how you can set up automatic creation of all necessary taxes that are assigned to payroll employees based on their resident addresses and work locations." PlainText="Configuring Taxes This chapter contains information about how you can set up automatic creation of all necessary     taxes that are assigned to payroll employees based on their resident addresses and work     locations. " ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="797ca553-c0a8-7de8-12b2-ec7cee90c4a3" RecordSourceID="22377" />
		<row PageID="a62bb501-be3a-46ec-a8f1-2928d23349fd" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="722d87a2-159d-b843-9153-ba3958517251" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
Each payroll-related tax (whether it is of the employee withholding type or the employer type) is represented by a payroll tax code. The tax code describes the type of tax, the jurisdiction it is associated with, the tax agency that receives the tax payments, and the specific tax location information necessary for the calculation of the tax by the Symmetry Tax Engine software. Many taxes require additional detailed information, as mandated by the specific government entity, and these details are entered and maintained through attributes associated with the specific tax code.{br}{TOC}
==Learning Objectives==
In this chapter, you will learn how to create payroll-related taxes and assign the appropriate taxes to employees based on their work location or address.
==Applicable Scenarios==
You configure payroll-related taxes if you want to process payroll documents with state withholding taxes and employer taxes calculated because the system will prevent you from calculating a paycheck if the relevant taxes are not assigned to the employee. 
==Setting Up Taxes==
By clicking '''Update Taxes''' on the form toolbar of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_20_80_00|Tax Maintenance] ([~/?ScreenId=PR208000|PR208000]) form, you download the latest tax details from the Tax Symmetry engine, and then the system creates tax codes related to all employee addresses and work locations stored in the system. As a result, the '''Tax Codes''' tab on that form becomes populated with data. You need to perform this operation during the initial configuration of taxes in the system and then each time new tax information becomes available in the Tax Symmetry engine—you will see a warning on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_30_20_00|Pay Checks and Adjustments] ([~/?ScreenId=PR302000|PR302000]) and [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_30_10_00|Payroll Batches] ([~/?ScreenId=PR301000|PR301000]) forms if tax information needs to be updated in the system.{br}

On the '''Tax Codes''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_20_80_00|Tax Maintenance] form, all available taxes are listed in the table. In the row of each tax code whose settings need to be updated or reviewed, a warning or an error icon is displayed, depending on whether the setting is marked as required. The settings of the selected tax code are displayed in the '''Tax Settings''' table. By clicking '''View Tax Details''' on the table toolbar, you can open the '''Tax Details''' dialog box, which displays the details of the selected tax, such as the government-issued identification code for the employer and information from the tax engine.{br}

On the '''Company Tax Settings''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_20_80_00|Tax Maintenance] form, you can review and edit details for various employee attributes used for taxation. The list of attributes is loaded from the Tax Symmetry engine and updated when you click '''Update Taxes''' on the form toolbar. {br}

After the taxes have been created and reviewed, you can click '''Assign Taxes to Employees''' on the form toolbar. As a result, the system assigns the relevant taxes to all employees based on their work locations and resident addresses, which are specified on the '''General Info''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_20_30_00|Employee Payroll Settings] ([~/?ScreenId=PR203000|PR203000]) form. (For more information about work locations, see [HelpRoot_Payroll\config_Payroll_Work_Locations_GeneralInfo|Work Locations: General Information].){br}

To assign taxes to an individual employee, you need to click the '''Import Taxes''' button on the '''Taxes''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_20_30_00|Employee Payroll Settings] form. As a result, the system fills in the table in the left pane of the tab with the relevant taxes based on the work locations and the address specified for the employee.]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Taxes: General Information Each payroll-related tax (whether it is of the employee withholding type or the employer type)     is represented by a payroll tax code. The tax code describes the type of tax, the jurisdiction     it is associated with, the tax agency that receives the tax payments, and the specific tax     location information necessary for the calculation of the tax by the Symmetry Tax Engine     software. Many taxes require additional detailed information, as mandated by the specific     government entity, and these details are entered and maintained through attributes associated     with the specific tax code. Learning Objectives In this chapter, you will learn how to create payroll-related taxes and assign the appropriate     taxes to employees based on their work location or address. Applicable Scenarios You configure payroll-related taxes if you want to process payroll documents with state         withholding taxes and employer taxes calculated because the system will prevent you from         calculating a paycheck if the relevant taxes are not assigned to the employee.  Setting Up Taxes By clicking  Update Taxes  on the form toolbar of the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR208000|PR208000]) Tax Maintenance (PR208000) form, you download the latest tax details from the Tax     Symmetry engine, and then the system creates tax codes related to all employee addresses and     work locations stored in the system. As a result, the  Tax Codes  tab on     that form becomes populated with data. You need to perform this operation during the initial     configuration of taxes in the system and then each time new tax information becomes available in     the Tax Symmetry engine—you will see a warning on the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR302000|PR302000]) Pay Checks and Adjustments (PR302000)     and   ([~/?ScreenId=PR301000|PR301000]) Payroll Batches (PR301000) forms if tax information needs to be updated in     the system. On the  Tax Codes  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR208000|PR208000]) Tax Maintenance form, all     available taxes are listed in the table. In the row of each tax code whose settings need to be     updated or reviewed, a warning or an error icon is displayed, depending on whether the setting     is marked as required. The settings of the selected tax code are displayed in the  Tax      Settings  table. By clicking  View Tax Details  on the table     toolbar, you can open the  Tax Details  dialog box, which displays the     details of the selected tax, such as the government-issued identification code for the employer     and information from the tax engine. On the  Company Tax Settings  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR208000|PR208000]) Tax Maintenance     form, you can review and edit details for various employee attributes used for taxation. The     list of attributes is loaded from the Tax Symmetry engine and updated when you click       Update Taxes  on the form toolbar.  After the taxes have been created and reviewed, you can click  Assign Taxes to      Employees  on the form toolbar. As a result, the system assigns the relevant taxes     to all employees based on their work locations and resident addresses, which are specified on     the  General Info  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR203000|PR203000]) Employee Payroll Settings (PR203000)     form. (For more information about work locations, see  Work Locations: General Information.) To assign taxes to an individual employee, you need to click the  Import      Taxes  button on the  Taxes  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR203000|PR203000]) Employee Payroll Settings form. As a result, the system fills in the table in the     left pane of the tab with the relevant taxes based on the work locations and the address     specified for the employee. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="a3afb805-da3f-4f8c-afb0-9f037b94295b" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" Content="&#xA;This chapter contains information about earning type codes used by the payroll functionality." PlainText="Configuring Earning Types This chapter contains information about earning type codes used by the payroll     functionality. " ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="3ee2e81b-696d-7f48-1702-752af538a137" RecordSourceID="22377" />
		<row PageID="63c4ba03-9cf7-4215-8654-5145856a9c8d" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="9b2f13b8-4064-e4f5-c196-f56bcff6de2b" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
In payroll, an earning type code determines the type of earning an employee is paid during the pay period.{br}{TOC}
==Learning Objectives==
In this chapter, you will learn how to create and set up earning type codes in payroll.
==Applicable Scenarios==
You configure earning type codes to be able to record hours and earnings information for employees.
==Categories of Earning Types==
The system recognizes the following categories of earning types:[anchor|#_b53cba53-3a0a-40d0-9f38-cc1aac99197e]
*''Salary'': An earning type of this category is processed as a normal earning. These earning types are available on the '''Compensation''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_20_30_00|Employee Payroll Settings] ([~/?ScreenId=PR203000|PR203000]) form. Also, the regular hours on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_10_10_00|Payroll Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=PR101000|PR101000]) form display only earning types of this category.
*''Overtime'': The system processes an earning type of this category as an overtime. For an overtime earning type, you need to specify a multiplier by which an employee&rsquo;s regular pay rate is to be multiplied to determine the final pay rate, and the earning type to be used as the source of the regular pay rate.
*''Amount Based'': Earning types of this category are amount-based. That is, if such an earning type is specified for a record on the '''Earning Details''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_30_20_00|Pay Checks and Adjustments] ([~/?ScreenId=PR302000|PR302000]) form, the '''Hours''' and '''Rate''' columns are non-editable for that record and you need to specify an amount in the '''Amount''' column.
*:Only an amount-based earning type may be selected in the '''Commission Earning Type''' box on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_10_10_00|Payroll Preferences] form.
*''Piecework'': An earning type of this category is processed as a piecework. That is, if such an earning type is selected for a record on the '''Earning Details''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_30_20_00|Pay Checks and Adjustments] form, the '''Unit''' and '''Unit Type''' columns become available for the record and the system calculates earned amount by multiplying the rate by the number of units instead of hours. 
*:If an employee has been assigned a piecework earning type on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_20_30_00|Employee Payroll Settings] form and you add such an employee to a payroll batch on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_30_10_00|Payroll Batches] ([~/?ScreenId=PR301000|PR301000]) form, you can specify the number of units and their type in the table of the '''Earning Details''' dialog box.
*:This type of earnings is not included in overtime calculation. 
*''Time Off'': Earning types of this category are processed as time off. Only these earning types are available on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_20_40_00|PTO Banks] ([~/?ScreenId=PR204000|PR204000]) form for a disbursing earning. Also, the holidays settings on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_10_10_00|Payroll Preferences] form display earning type codes only of this category.

You can create earning types by using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_10_20_00|Earning Type Codes] ([~/?ScreenId=PR102000|PR102000]) form. Earning types of the ''Piecework'' category can be created only if the '''Enable Piecework as an Earning Type''' check box is selected on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_10_10_00|Payroll Preferences] form.
==Predefined Earning Types==
 By default, the following earning types are available in the system:[anchor|#_931b6306-e915-49ce-91ef-a2aa582d9737]
*''Regular Hours (RG)'': Standard working hours that are paid based on the standard employee rate.
*''Overtime (OT)'': Overtime working hours that are paid based on the standard rate multiplied by the value of the overtime multiplier.
*''Public Holidays (HL)'': Non-working hours of public holidays, which are non-payable. You can use this earning type to indicate that certain days included in the paycheck are public holidays when no work is done.
*''Vacations (VL)'': Non-working hours of vacations, which are also non-payable. You can use this earning type to indicate that the employee is not working due to vacation.

==Earning Type Settings==
 For an earning type code, you can define the following settings:[anchor|#_df9172b0-880a-472d-b504-79b5a90896c4]
*Whether the hours linked with the earning type code are considered for PTO calculation
*Whether the earning type is to appear in Box 12 of the W- 2 report and which code it will use
*The method used to determine the list of applicable taxes
*A project and project task to be associated with the earning type code by default
* GL accounts to be used to record transactions linked with the earning type code

Only earning types marked as ''Active'' can be used in the calculation of a paycheck.]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Earning Type Codes: General Information In payroll, an earning type code determines the type of earning an employee is paid during the     pay period. Learning Objectives In this chapter, you will learn how to create and set up earning type codes in payroll. Applicable Scenarios You configure earning type codes to be able to record hours and earnings information for     employees. Categories of Earning Types The system recognizes the following categories of earning types: Salary : An earning type of this category is processed as a normal earning. These      earning types are available on the  Compensation  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR203000|PR203000]) Employee Payroll Settings (PR203000) form. Also, the regular hours on the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR101000|PR101000]) Payroll Preferences (PR101000) form display only earning types of this category. Overtime : The system processes an earning type of this category as an overtime. For      an overtime earning type, you need to specify a multiplier by which an employee's regular pay      rate is to be multiplied to determine the final pay rate, and the earning type to be used as      the source of the regular pay rate. Amount Based : Earning types of this category are amount-based. That is, if such an      earning type is specified for a record on the  Earning Details  tab of the         ([~/?ScreenId=PR302000|PR302000]) Pay Checks and Adjustments (PR302000) form, the  Hours  and        Rate  columns are non-editable for that record and you need to specify      an amount in the  Amount  column. Only an amount-based earning type may       be selected in the  Commission Earning Type  box on the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR101000|PR101000]) Payroll Preferences form. Piecework : An earning type of this category is processed as a piecework. That is, if      such an earning type is selected for a record on the  Earning Details  tab      of the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR302000|PR302000]) Pay Checks and Adjustments form, the  Unit  and        Unit Type  columns become available for the record and the system      calculates earned amount by multiplying the rate by the number of units instead of hours.  If       an employee has been assigned a piecework earning type on the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR203000|PR203000]) Employee Payroll Settings       form and you add such an employee to a payroll batch on the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR301000|PR301000]) Payroll Batches       (PR301000) form, you can specify the number of units and their type in the table of the         Earning Details  dialog box. This type of earnings is not       included in overtime calculation.  Time Off : Earning types of this category are processed as time off. Only these      earning types are available on the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR204000|PR204000]) PTO Banks (PR204000) form for a      disbursing earning. Also, the holidays settings on the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR101000|PR101000]) Payroll Preferences form      display earning type codes only of this category. You can create earning types by using the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR102000|PR102000]) Earning Type Codes (PR102000) form.     Earning types of the  Piecework  category can be created only if the  Enable      Piecework as an Earning Type  check box is selected on the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR101000|PR101000]) Payroll Preferences form. Predefined Earning Types  By default, the following earning types are available in the system: Regular Hours (RG) : Standard working hours that are paid based on the standard      employee rate. Overtime (OT) : Overtime working hours that are paid based on the standard rate      multiplied by the value of the overtime multiplier. Public Holidays (HL) : Non-working hours of public holidays, which are non-payable.      You can use this earning type to indicate that certain days included in the paycheck are public      holidays when no work is done. Vacations (VL) : Non-working hours of vacations, which are also non-payable. You can      use this earning type to indicate that the employee is not working due to vacation. Earning Type Settings  For an earning type code, you can define the following settings: Whether the hours linked with the earning type code are considered for PTO calculation Whether the earning type is to appear in Box 12 of the W- 2 report and which code it will      use The method used to determine the list of applicable taxes A project and project task to be associated with the earning type code by default  GL accounts to be used to record transactions linked with the earning type code Only earning types marked as  Active  can be used in the calculation of a paycheck. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="f7dd0084-dbe4-41ca-a00b-293511708082" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" Content="&#xA;This chapter contains information about deduction and benefit codes." PlainText="Configuring Deductions and Benefits This chapter contains information about deduction and benefit codes. " ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="73ac5a71-4876-8179-022a-9bac8402a145" RecordSourceID="22377" />
		<row PageID="1e1030ef-99f5-4c8a-b48f-a9ad9d9f573e" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="3862c59d-5abe-a8fd-7dd1-b592de0503ad" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
A deduction code reduces the employee net pay and a benefit code increases the cost of payroll for the company. In Acumatica ERP, there is no actual difference between deduction and benefit codes for payroll calculation purposes—both may include an employee (deduction) and an employer (contribution) component, both may involve complex calculation methods, and both may or may not be subject to various taxes.{br}{TOC}
==Learning Objectives==
In this chapter, you will learn how to do the following:[anchor|#ul_dmx_2lv_pr]
*Create deduction and benefit codes
*Specify whether the created code is an employee deduction, an employer contribution, or both
*Specify a source entity with which the code can be used
*Specify how deductions or benefits should be calculated
*Specify what earning types may be used in the calculation of deductions and benefits
*Specify which payroll items may increase or decrease the applicable wage, if applicable

==Applicable Scenarios==
You configure deduction and benefit codes if you need to calculate employee deductions and employer contributions to employee wages.
==Creation of a Deduction and Benefit Code==
You can create and edit deduction and benefit codes by using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_10_10_60|Deduction and Benefit Codes] ([~/?ScreenId=PR101060|PR101060]) form. For each code, you need to specify in the '''Contribution Type''' box whether it should be calculated as an employee deduction, an employer contribution, or both.{br}

You can also specify a vendor for a deduction and benefit code. This vendor is to be owed the liability resulting from the deduction or benefit and will be used for an AP liability bill.
==Calculation of Deductions and Benefits==
Depending on the contribution type specified for the deduction and benefit code, on the '''Employee Deduction Settings''' or '''Employer Contribution Settings''' tab (or on both tabs) of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_10_10_60|Deduction and Benefit Codes] form, you can select one of the following options in the '''Calculation Method''' box:[anchor|#_3e3e9d79-0821-4bf2-a8ad-3994354442de]
*''Fixed Amount'': The deduction uses the amount specified in the '''Amount''' box on the same tab. The amount is added in each pay period.
*''Percent of Gross'': The deduction is calculated by multiplying the gross wages (the total of all earning types that contribute to gross wages) by the percentage specified in the '''Percent''' box on the same tab. 
*''Percent of Custom'': The deduction is calculated as a percentage of the applicable wage. For the calculation, the system uses the percent specified in the '''Percent''' box on this tab and the information specified on the '''Applicable Wage''' tab of this form where you can define which payroll items may increase or decrease the applicable wage.
*:This option is available only if the '''Affects Tax Calculation''' check box in the Summary area of the form is cleared.
*''Percent of Net'': The deduction is calculated by multiplying the net wages (the total of all earning types that contribute to net wages) by the percentage specified in the '''Percent''' box on the same tab. 
*''Amount per Hour'': The deduction is calculated by multiplying the total hours for all earning types (typically hours, but could be piecework, miles, or another unit) by the amount specified in the '''Amount''' box on the same tab.

In the '''Applicable Earnings''' box on these tabs, you can specify what earning types can be used in the calculation of employee deductions or employer contributions based on the categories of those earning types. The category of each earning type code is specified in the Summary area of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_10_20_00|Earning Type Codes] ([~/?ScreenId=PR102000|PR102000]) form. [anchor|#_35762ab6-0a10-43e3-a858-54796681531a]
*''Total Earnings'': Earning types of the ''Salary'', ''Overtime'', and ''Time Off'' categories can be used in the calculation. This option appears in the drop-down list only if the ''Percent of Gross'', ''Percent of Custom'', or ''Amount per Hour'' calculation method is specified on the tab.
*''Regular Earnings'': Only ''Salary'' earnings can be used for the calculation. This option appears in the drop-down list only if the ''Percent of Gross'' or ''Amount per Hour'' calculation method is specified on the tab.
*''Regular and OT Earnings'': Earning types of the ''Salary'' and ''Overtime'' categories can be used in the calculation. This option appears in the drop-down list only if the ''Percent of Gross'' or ''Amount per Hour'' calculation method is specified on the tab.
*''Straight Time Earnings'': Earning types of the ''Salary'' and ''Overtime'' categories can be used in the calculation. This option appears in the drop-down list only if the ''Percent of Gross'' or ''Percent of Custom'' calculation method is specified on the tab.

==Deduction and Benefit Code Source==
Each deduction and benefit code can be associated with only one source: employee settings, certified projects, unions, or workers’ compensation codes. You can select a source in the '''Associated With''' box on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_10_10_60|Deduction and Benefit Codes] form.{br}

With this capability, correct YTD, QTD, and MTD amounts of deductions and benefits associated with a particular union or certified project can be calculated for reports.{br}

For an existing deduction and benefit code, you cannot modify the '''Associated With''' option specified for the code if the code is already associated with an entity or payment.
==Reporting==
In the '''Reporting Type''' box on the '''Employee Deduction Settings''' and '''Employer Contribution Settings''' tabs of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_10_10_60|Deduction and Benefit Codes] form, you can specify if the contribution is to appear in Box 12 of the W-2 report and which code it will use. If the contribution should not appear in Box 12 of the W-2 report, you need to select the ''0-Normal'' option.
==Taxes==
If you select the '''Affects Tax Calculation''' check box, the '''Tax Settings''' tab becomes available on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_10_10_60|Deduction and Benefit Codes] form. You can use that tab to determine which taxes this code is subject to.
==ACA Information==
You can mark a deduction and benefit code as containing ACA information by selecting the '''ACA Applicable''' check box in the Summary area of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_10_10_60|Deduction and Benefit Codes] form. As a result, the '''ACA Information''' tab will appear on the form where you can specify information needed for ACA reporting.]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Deduction and Benefit Codes: General Information A deduction code reduces the employee net pay and a benefit code increases the cost of payroll     for the company. In  Acumatica ERP,     there is no actual difference between deduction and benefit codes for payroll calculation     purposes—both may include an employee (deduction) and an employer (contribution)     component, both may involve complex calculation methods, and both may or may not be subject to     various taxes. Learning Objectives In this chapter, you will learn how to do the following: Create deduction and benefit codes Specify whether the created code is an employee deduction, an employer contribution, or      both Specify a source entity with which the code can be used Specify how deductions or benefits should be calculated Specify what earning types may be used in the calculation of deductions and benefits Specify which payroll items may increase or decrease the applicable wage, if applicable Applicable Scenarios You configure deduction and benefit codes if you need to calculate employee deductions and     employer contributions to employee wages. Creation of a Deduction and Benefit Code You can create and edit deduction and benefit codes by using the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR101060|PR101060]) Deduction and Benefit Codes (PR101060) form. For each code, you need to specify in     the  Contribution Type  box whether it should be calculated as an employee     deduction, an employer contribution, or both. You can also specify a vendor for a deduction and benefit code. This vendor is to be owed the     liability resulting from the deduction or benefit and will be used for an AP liability bill. Calculation of Deductions and Benefits Depending on the contribution type specified for the deduction and benefit code, on the       Employee Deduction Settings  or  Employer Contribution      Settings  tab (or on both tabs) of the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR101060|PR101060]) Deduction and Benefit Codes     form, you can select one of the following options in the  Calculation      Method  box: Fixed Amount : The deduction uses the amount specified in the        Amount  box on the same tab. The amount is added in each pay      period. Percent of Gross : The deduction is calculated by multiplying the gross wages (the      total of all earning types that contribute to gross wages) by the percentage specified in the        Percent  box on the same tab.  Percent of Custom : The deduction is calculated as a percentage of the applicable      wage. For the calculation, the system uses the percent specified in the        Percent  box on this tab and the information specified on the        Applicable Wage  tab of this form where you can define which payroll      items may increase or decrease the applicable wage. This option is available only if the         Affects Tax Calculation  check box in the Summary area of the form is       cleared. Percent of Net : The deduction is calculated by multiplying the net wages (the total      of all earning types that contribute to net wages) by the percentage specified in the        Percent  box on the same tab.  Amount per Hour : The deduction is calculated by multiplying the total hours for all      earning types (typically hours, but could be piecework, miles, or another unit) by the amount      specified in the  Amount  box on the same tab. In the  Applicable Earnings  box on these tabs, you can specify what     earning types can be used in the calculation of employee deductions or employer contributions     based on the categories of those earning types. The category of each earning type code is     specified in the Summary area of the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR102000|PR102000]) Earning Type Codes (PR102000)     form.  Total Earnings : Earning types of the  Salary ,  Overtime , and  Time       Off  categories can be used in the calculation. This option appears in the drop-down list      only if the  Percent of Gross ,  Percent of Custom , or  Amount per Hour       calculation method is specified on the tab. Regular Earnings : Only  Salary  earnings can be used for the calculation. This      option appears in the drop-down list only if the  Percent of Gross  or  Amount per       Hour  calculation method is specified on the tab. Regular and OT Earnings : Earning types of the  Salary  and  Overtime       categories can be used in the calculation. This option appears in the drop-down list only if      the  Percent of Gross  or  Amount per Hour  calculation method is specified on the      tab. Straight Time Earnings : Earning types of the  Salary  and  Overtime       categories can be used in the calculation. This option appears in the drop-down list only if      the  Percent of Gross  or  Percent of Custom  calculation method is specified on the      tab. Deduction and Benefit Code Source Each deduction and benefit code can be associated with only one source: employee settings,     certified projects, unions, or workers’ compensation codes. You can select a source in the       Associated With  box on the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR101060|PR101060]) Deduction and Benefit Codes     form. With this capability, correct YTD, QTD, and MTD amounts of deductions and benefits associated     with a particular union or certified project can be calculated for reports. For an existing deduction and benefit code, you cannot modify the  Associated      With  option specified for the code if the code is already associated with an entity     or payment. Reporting In the  Reporting Type  box on the  Employee Deduction      Settings  and  Employer Contribution Settings  tabs of the        ([~/?ScreenId=PR101060|PR101060]) Deduction and Benefit Codes form, you can specify if the contribution is to     appear in Box 12 of the W-2 report and which code it will use. If the contribution should not     appear in Box 12 of the W-2 report, you need to select the  0-Normal  option. Taxes If you select the  Affects Tax Calculation  check box, the  Tax      Settings  tab becomes available on the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR101060|PR101060]) Deduction and Benefit Codes     form. You can use that tab to determine which taxes this code is subject to. ACA Information You can mark a deduction and benefit code as containing ACA information by selecting the       ACA Applicable  check box in the Summary area of the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR101060|PR101060]) Deduction and Benefit Codes form. As a result, the  ACA      Information  tab will appear on the form where you can specify information needed     for ACA reporting. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="ef6223b8-660e-4f22-bb2a-a44b7175d9ff" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" Content="&#xA;The topics of this chapter describe how you can configure paid time off banks for employees." PlainText="Configuring Paid Time Off The topics of this chapter describe how you can configure paid time off banks for     employees. " ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="51b18b5c-2088-8f8d-6786-4c6a80e0c1f5" RecordSourceID="22377" />
		<row PageID="83a73e05-59e3-4ed2-960a-fa5a660f99f9" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="ed8e0ffb-8d34-3544-6189-fc3a48b75f65" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
Many companies permit employees to accrue hours or days of paid time off (PTO) as they work, to use for sick or vacation leave. In Acumatica ERP, you can define various PTO accrual plans (PTO banks) for your employees.{br}{TOC}
==Learning Objectives==
In this chapter, you will learn how to create PTO banks and link them with individual employees.
==Applicable Scenarios==
You configure PTO banks if you want to be able to accrue hours that employees may use for paid time off.
==PTO Banks==
On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_20_40_00|PTO Banks] ([~/?ScreenId=PR204000|PR204000]) form, you can create PTO banks, which then can be assigned to individual employees through the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_20_20_00|Employee Class] ([~/?ScreenId=PR202000|PR202000]) and [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_20_30_00|Employee Payroll Settings] ([~/?ScreenId=PR203000|PR203000]) forms.{br}

PTO banks accrue hours from earnings that have the '''Accrue Time Off''' check box selected on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_10_20_00|Earning Type Codes] ([~/?ScreenId=PR102000|PR102000]) form. For each PTO bank, you need to specify an accrual rate and a unique disbursing earning type. You also can establish an accrual limit for a PTO bank—that is, the maximum number of hours that can be accrued for that bank. {br}

You can decide whether you want to allow negative balances in paychecks, choose how you want to use carryover hours, and specify the start date individually for each PTO bank used by an employee in the employee payroll settings.{br}

You can mark a PTO bank as active or inactive. Inactive PTO banks stop accruing hours, but you still can use hours from those banks.{br}

PTO banks are updated during a paycheck release.]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Paid Time Off: General Information Many companies permit employees to accrue hours or days of paid time off (PTO) as they work,     to use for sick or vacation leave. In  Acumatica ERP,     you can define various PTO accrual plans (PTO banks) for your employees. Learning Objectives In this chapter, you will learn how to create PTO banks and link them with individual     employees. Applicable Scenarios You configure PTO banks if you want to be able to accrue hours that employees may use for paid     time off. PTO Banks On the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR204000|PR204000]) PTO Banks (PR204000) form, you can create PTO banks, which then     can be assigned to individual employees through the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR202000|PR202000]) Employee Class (PR202000)     and   ([~/?ScreenId=PR203000|PR203000]) Employee Payroll Settings (PR203000) forms. PTO banks accrue hours from earnings that have the  Accrue Time Off      check box selected on the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR102000|PR102000]) Earning Type Codes (PR102000) form. For each PTO bank,     you need to specify an accrual rate and a unique disbursing earning type. You also can establish     an accrual limit for a PTO bank—that is, the maximum number of hours that can be accrued for     that bank.  You can decide whether you want to allow negative balances in paychecks, choose how you want     to use carryover hours, and specify the start date individually for each PTO bank used by an     employee in the employee payroll settings. You can mark a PTO bank as active or inactive. Inactive PTO banks stop accruing hours, but you     still can use hours from those banks. PTO banks are updated during a paycheck release. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="0479383d-5255-4ab6-a6bf-aec17c1907c4" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" Content="&#xA;This chapter describes how payroll is calculated and how payments are processed with the Payroll functionality.&#xA;==In This Chapter==[anchor|#ul_nbv_zsn_dw]&#xA;*[HelpRoot_Payroll\PR__con_Pay_Checks_Adjustments|Paychecks and Adjustments]&#xA;*[HelpRoot_Payroll\PR_CON_Payroll_Batches|Payroll Batches]&#xA;*[HelpRoot_Payroll\PR__con_Liability_Payment|Payroll Liability Payment]&#xA;" PlainText="Managing Payroll Processes This chapter describes how payroll is calculated and how payments are processed with the    Payroll functionality. In This Chapter Paychecks and AdjustmentsPayroll BatchesPayroll Liability Payment" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="128428d5-c051-8120-5eb9-d41758333d46" RecordSourceID="22377" />
		<row PageID="4a41a0ad-32a2-4979-b751-f22ea32488a3" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="8934e2e2-9974-2b47-3ad2-79c9e2a8443f" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
You can review and modify the details of each individual paycheck on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_30_20_00|Pay Checks and Adjustments] ([~/?ScreenId=PR302000|PR302000]) form. Depending on the selected type of the payment and its current status, you can use the form for a number of different purposes, all related to the maintenance of paycheck information, as described below.{br}

You will only be able to create one ''regular'' and one ''special'' type of paycheck for an employee during a specific pay period, but you’ll be able to create as many adjustment and special documents as needed. If you open a pay period that already has a paycheck, the system will redirect you either to the paycheck or to the payroll batch if the batch is not released yet (you can remove the paycheck from the batch to create one manually for the selected pay period).{br}

For each pay period, the system will automatically calculate and fetch the right pay rate. If the employee has been assigned a yearly salary, the system will use the number of hours per week and the number of weeks worked during the year to calculate an hourly rate. If the rate is hourly, no calculation is done.{br}

Once this rate is calculated, it will be compared to rates set for the certified project if the employee worked on a certified project or to rates set for a union if the employee is part of a union. The system will select the highest rate it could find an apply it to the hours linked with the union or the project.{br}

Also, you can use this form to review and process direct deposits. The settings on this form are used for both printed checks and direct deposits; depending on the payment method selected, the system will default from the option set up on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_20_30_00|Employee Payroll Settings].{br}{TOC}
==Calculation Logic==
You can use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_30_20_00|Pay Checks and Adjustments] form for reviewing or modifying the details associated with a particular employee’s paycheck before it is printed or released. After changes are made, you need to click '''Actions''' > '''Calculate''' on the form toolbar. {br}

If some paycheck was created for a prior pay period, the system will prevent you from calculating the paycheck and force you to release the previous one. It ensures that the YTD, QTD and MTD information are always up to date.{br}

The calculation process will launch the overtime rules validation and create new earning lines if some rules were triggered. It will then, calculate the deduction and benefit amounts to apply to the paycheck. It will make sure the package from the unions and certified projects are applied if configured. Afterward, it will call the web service to fetch the right rate to apply to the employee taxes. Finally, it will accrue the paid time off and disburse it if an earning linked to a bank was entered in the earning details.{br}

Calculation is not automatic after each change because each time you need to invoke the '''Calculate''' action, and frequent recalculations by the tax calculation engine could slow the system down. But the system will make sure that you recalculate the paycheck every time it is needed.
==Pay Checks and Adjustments==
The [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_30_20_00|Pay Checks and Adjustments] form may also be used to make any necessary adjustments. You can also use the form to enter employee beginning balances, typically by entering one check per employee per month or per quarter. You can enter negative amounts on the form, which may result in a negative net check if you select the ''Adjustment'' option in the '''Type''' box.{br}

You can enter the data on the '''Earnings and Hours''' tab and then click '''Actions''' > '''Calculate''' on the form toolbar to have the system populate the '''Deductions''' and '''Taxes''' tabs. You can then override any or all amounts in order to make the net check come out as you need it to.{br}

For taxes, you need to make sure the amount entered in the tax is equal to the amount entered in the tax details and tax split when using the labor item or earning type as the source of the expense accounts or if you assign the labor burden to the project (the source of the expense accounts can be specified on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_10_10_00|Payroll Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=PR101000|PR101000]) form).
==Voiding of Paychecks==
The [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_30_20_00|Pay Checks and Adjustments] form may be used to void any check in the system. You can void a check once it has been released; but as soon as you create the liabilities generated from a paycheck, you will not be able to void the paycheck.{br}

When you click '''Actions''' > '''Void''' on the form toolbar, all payroll information—such as gross pay, taxable wages, taxes, deductions, benefits, and sick time and PTO accrual—is automatically updated.{br}

Upon release of the voided check record, GL posting amounts are automatically generated into a GL batch. For GL accounts and amounts, the system uses the activity previously generated for the check, reversing all amounts, rather than using the current system configuration, because the configuration may have changed since the check was originally released.{br}

The system marks the original check as being voided and keeps a record of the voided-check activity.{br}

In most cases, a voided payroll check needs to be immediately replaced by a new check that is either identical to (in the case of a lost check) the original check or very similar to (in the case of a check that contained some mistake) it. ]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Paychecks and Adjustments You can review and modify the details of each individual paycheck on the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR302000|PR302000]) Pay Checks and Adjustments (PR302000) form. Depending on the selected type of the payment and     its current status, you can use the form for a number of different purposes, all related to the     maintenance of paycheck information, as described below. You will only be able to create one  regular  and one  special  type of paycheck for     an employee during a specific pay period, but you’ll be able to create as many adjustment and     special documents as needed. If you open a pay period that already has a paycheck, the system     will redirect you either to the paycheck or to the payroll batch if the batch is not released     yet (you can remove the paycheck from the batch to create one manually for the selected pay     period). For each pay period, the system will automatically calculate and fetch the right pay rate. If     the employee has been assigned a yearly salary, the system will use the number of hours per week     and the number of weeks worked during the year to calculate an hourly rate. If the rate is     hourly, no calculation is done. Once this rate is calculated, it will be compared to rates set for the certified project if     the employee worked on a certified project or to rates set for a union if the employee is part     of a union. The system will select the highest rate it could find an apply it to the hours     linked with the union or the project. Also, you can use this form to review and process direct deposits. The settings on this form     are used for both printed checks and direct deposits; depending on the payment method selected,     the system will default from the option set up on the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR203000|PR203000]) Employee Payroll Settings. Calculation Logic You can use the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR302000|PR302000]) Pay Checks and Adjustments form for reviewing or modifying the details     associated with a particular employee’s paycheck before it is printed or released. After changes     are made, you need to click  Actions Calculate  on the form toolbar.  If some paycheck was created for a prior pay period, the system will prevent you from     calculating the paycheck and force you to release the previous one. It ensures that the YTD, QTD     and MTD information are always up to date. The calculation process will launch the overtime rules validation and create new earning lines     if some rules were triggered. It will then, calculate the deduction and benefit amounts to apply     to the paycheck. It will make sure the package from the unions and certified projects are     applied if configured. Afterward, it will call the web service to fetch the right rate to apply     to the employee taxes. Finally, it will accrue the paid time off and disburse it if an earning     linked to a bank was entered in the earning details. Calculation is not automatic after each change because each time you need to invoke the       Calculate  action, and frequent recalculations by the tax calculation     engine could slow the system down. But the system will make sure that you recalculate the     paycheck every time it is needed. Pay Checks and Adjustments The   ([~/?ScreenId=PR302000|PR302000]) Pay Checks and Adjustments form may also be used to make any necessary adjustments.     You can also use the form to enter employee beginning balances, typically by entering one check     per employee per month or per quarter. You can enter negative amounts on the form, which may     result in a negative net check if you select the  Adjustment  option in the       Type  box. You can enter the data on the  Earnings and Hours  tab and then click  Actions Calculate  on the form toolbar to have the system populate the       Deductions  and  Taxes  tabs. You can then override     any or all amounts in order to make the net check come out as you need it to. For taxes, you need to make sure the amount entered in the tax is equal to the amount entered     in the tax details and tax split when using the labor item or earning type as the source of the     expense accounts or if you assign the labor burden to the project (the source of the expense     accounts can be specified on the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR101000|PR101000]) Payroll Preferences (PR101000) form). Voiding of Paychecks The   ([~/?ScreenId=PR302000|PR302000]) Pay Checks and Adjustments form may be used to void any check in the system. You can     void a check once it has been released; but as soon as you create the liabilities generated from     a paycheck, you will not be able to void the paycheck. When you click  Actions Void  on the form toolbar, all payroll information—such as gross pay, taxable     wages, taxes, deductions, benefits, and sick time and PTO accrual—is automatically     updated. Upon release of the voided check record, GL posting amounts are automatically generated into a     GL batch. For GL accounts and amounts, the system uses the activity previously generated for the     check, reversing all amounts, rather than using the current system configuration, because the     configuration may have changed since the check was originally released. The system marks the original check as being voided and keeps a record of the voided-check     activity. In most cases, a voided payroll check needs to be immediately replaced by a new check that is     either identical to (in the case of a lost check) the original check or very similar to (in the     case of a check that contained some mistake) it.  ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="79530282-9da9-45bb-9c1b-2411b0bbb30a" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="52183b72-c916-18ea-0851-a7424a5d67f5" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
Typically, employees are not paid on an individual basis but based on membership of a group. You will divide your workforce in pay groups that will have the same schedule of pay period (weekly, biweekly, monthly). By using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_30_10_00|Payroll Batches] ([~/?ScreenId=PR301000|PR301000]) form, you can create paychecks for a specific pay group.{br}

First, you select the type of batch you want to create (regular, special or adjustment), specify a pay group and pay period. Note that you won’t be able to select employees that are not part of the pay group during the pay period selected. If an employee already has a regular paycheck for the pay period selected, the system will display a warning and you won’t be able to select this employee for the pay run. For special type, no restrictions apply.
==Adding Employees==
On the '''Document Details''' tab, you add employees by clicking the '''Add Employee''' button on the table toolbar. In the '''Add Employee''' dialog box you can do one of the following:[anchor|#_4c6aaf3d-d767-426f-8d72-573e24b13e57]
*Use the ''Quick Pay'' functionality which will bring hours using the calendar assigned to the employee by selecting the '''Pre-Populate with Employee Defaults (Quick Pay)''' check box. To populate the earning code, the system uses the settings specified on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_10_10_00|Payroll Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=PR101000|PR101000]) form.
*Import the time from the released time activities entered for the employee bringing all the details linked to them by selecting the '''Time Activities (will override defaults as applicable)''' check box.
*Import the unpaid commission by selecting the '''Sales Commissions''' check box. It will create an amount-based earning line for each employee having unpaid commissions. The check box is available if the ''Commissions'' feature is enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) form.

You can review and modify earning details for each employee by clicking the '''Earning Details''' button on the table toolbar. {br}

You’ll now have the gross pay calculated for each employee. But you might want to exclude a specific deductions or benefits or to prevent the system from using an overtime rule for a specific batch of employees. By navigating to the '''Deductions and Benefits''' and '''Overtime Rules''' tabs, you will be able to deactivate specific item just for this payroll batch.{br}

Upon the release of the batch, the system will create a paycheck for each employee selected and you will be able to process them as normal paycheck. You will still need to calculate the paychecks to apply the taxes, deductions and benefits, print the paycheck and then release it.]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Payroll Batches Typically, employees are not paid on an individual basis but based on membership of a group.     You will divide your workforce in pay groups that will have the same schedule of pay period     (weekly, biweekly, monthly). By using the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR301000|PR301000]) Payroll Batches (PR301000) form, you     can create paychecks for a specific pay group. First, you select the type of batch you want to create (regular, special or adjustment),         specify a pay group and pay period. Note that you won’t be able to select employees that are         not part of the pay group during the pay period selected. If an employee already has a         regular paycheck for the pay period selected, the system will display a warning and you         won’t be able to select this employee for the pay run. For special type, no restrictions         apply. Adding Employees On the  Document Details  tab, you add employees by clicking the            Add Employee  button on the table toolbar. In the  Add           Employee  dialog box you can do one of the following: Use the  Quick Pay  functionality which will bring hours using the calendar assigned to           the employee by selecting the  Pre-Populate with Employee Defaults (Quick             Pay)  check box. To populate the earning code, the system uses the settings           specified on the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR101000|PR101000]) Payroll Preferences (PR101000) form. Import the time from the released time activities entered for the employee bringing all the           details linked to them by selecting the  Time Activities (will override defaults             as applicable)  check box. Import the unpaid commission by selecting the  Sales Commissions            check box. It will create an amount-based earning line for each employee having unpaid           commissions. The check box is available if the  Commissions  feature is enabled on           the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features (CS100000) form. You can review and modify earning details for each employee by clicking the  Earning      Details  button on the table toolbar.  You’ll now have the gross pay calculated for each employee. But you might want to exclude a         specific deductions or benefits or to prevent the system from using an overtime rule for a         specific batch of employees. By navigating to the  Deductions and           Benefits  and  Overtime Rules  tabs, you will be able to         deactivate specific item just for this payroll batch. Upon the release of the batch, the system will create a paycheck for each employee selected         and you will be able to process them as normal paycheck. You will still need to calculate         the paychecks to apply the taxes, deductions and benefits, print the paycheck and then         release it. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="0cd397a6-4e55-4519-8dac-a0dc96ed21be" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="1a7693b7-1250-e54a-c855-c1f60ff4da15" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
Using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_50_10_00|Process Payroll Documents] ([~/?ScreenId=PR501000|PR501000]) form you can apply all the possible actions from the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_30_20_00|Pay Checks and Adjustments] ([~/?ScreenId=PR302000|PR302000]) form to multiple documents. When you select an action, the system filters the list of documents and displays only those documents to which the operation can be applied.{br}

The following operations are available:[anchor|#_748c4932-0d43-4949-af76-f7c55ac63f71]
*'''Put on Hold''': Using this action you can put on hold documents with the ''Needs Calculation'' or ''Pending Print'' status.
*'''Remove from Hold''': With this action you can clear the '''Hold''' check box for the selected documents with the ''Hold'' status.
*'''Calculate''': You use this action to initiate the calculation process for the documents with the ''Needs Calculation'' status.
*'''Release''': Using this action you can release documents with the ''Printed/Paid'' status.
*'''Void''': You use this action to void documents with the ''Released'' status.
]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Processing of Payroll Documents Using the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR501000|PR501000]) Process Payroll Documents (PR501000) form you can apply all the                 possible actions from the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR302000|PR302000]) Pay Checks and Adjustments (PR302000) form to                 multiple documents. When you select an action, the system filters the list of                 documents and displays only those documents to which the operation can be                 applied. The following operations are available: Put on Hold : Using this action you can put on hold documents with the                          Needs Calculation  or  Pending Print  status. Remove from Hold : With this action you can clear the                          Hold  check box for the selected documents with the                          Hold  status. Calculate : You use this action to initiate the calculation process for                     the documents with the  Needs Calculation  status. Release : Using this action you can release documents with the                          Printed/Paid  status. Void : You use this action to void documents with the  Released                      status. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="ef3e0bb6-d173-41bc-b50b-8e37f4cf5a4c" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="21004fd7-c971-ed85-5843-332a798954ab" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
You use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_50_50_00|Print Check] ([~/?ScreenId=PR505000|PR505000]) form for mass processing of the documents with the ''Pending Print'' status. That is, print checks generated during payroll batches preparation or generate the ACH file. To put on hold documents with this status, you should use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_50_10_00|Process Payroll Documents].{br}

First, you select a payment method and corresponding cash account, the system displays the list of relevant documents. If you process multiple checks at once, the system generates a single printable version with all the paychecks and displays it for your review and printing. {br}

If you process multiple direct deposit paychecks, the system generates a single batch and redirects you to the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_30_50_00|Direct Deposit Batch] ([~/?ScreenId=PR305000|PR305000]) form for further processing.{br}

The system will automatically send the user to the right following page (either the report or the direct deposit batch screen)]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Check Printing You use the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR505000|PR505000]) Print Check (PR505000) form for mass processing of the         documents with the  Pending Print  status. That is, print checks generated during         payroll batches preparation or generate the ACH file. To put on hold documents with this         status, you should use the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR501000|PR501000]) Process Payroll Documents. First, you select a payment method and corresponding cash account, the system displays the         list of relevant documents. If you process multiple checks at once, the system generates a         single printable version with all the paychecks and displays it for your review and         printing.  If you process multiple direct deposit paychecks, the system generates a single batch and         redirects you to the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR305000|PR305000]) Direct Deposit Batch (PR305000) form for further         processing. The system will automatically send the user to the right following page (either the report         or the direct deposit batch screen) ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="7d51d2df-75fb-43e0-a0ba-2ad9fed79dcc" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="11d70615-8fc1-f814-6c2d-4c90e6e2dcb3" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
The pay run process generates payroll liability records in accordance with the setup of each specific deduction, benefit, and tax in the system. On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PR_50_30_00|Create Liabilities Bill] ([~/?ScreenId=PR503000|PR503000]) form, you can translate these liability records into accounts payable bills so that they can be paid through standard accounts payable processes.{br}

You use the form to filter and select liability records, so you can determine which payroll liability activities need to be converted into AP bills. The boxes in the selection area of the form are used to determine which records to select for processing. Only liability records and amounts not previously processed are included in the table. Once a record is processed, it disappears from the list of available records.{br}

If you click the '''Process''' or '''Process All''' button on the form toolbar, the system creates an AP bill for each selected liability or for all listed records, respectively. If the '''Single Line Per Invoice''' check box is selected, the system will create one bill for each record. Otherwise it will group the bills for each vendor. You can also create bills for zero amount records by selecting the '''Create zero amount lines on bill''' check box.]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Payroll Liability Payment The pay run process generates payroll liability records in accordance with the setup of each    specific deduction, benefit, and tax in the system. On the   ([~/?ScreenId=PR503000|PR503000]) Create Liabilities Bill    (PR503000) form, you can translate these liability records into accounts payable bills so that    they can be paid through standard accounts payable processes. You use the form to filter and select liability records, so you can determine which payroll    liability activities need to be converted into AP bills. The boxes in the selection area of the    form are used to determine which records to select for processing. Only liability records and    amounts not previously processed are included in the table. Once a record is processed, it    disappears from the list of available records. If you click the  Process  or  Process All  button on    the form toolbar, the system creates an AP bill for each selected liability or for all listed    records, respectively. If the  Single Line Per Invoice  check box is selected, the system    will create one bill for each record. Otherwise it will group the bills for each vendor. You can    also create bills for zero amount records by selecting the  Create zero amount lines on     bill  check box. ]]></column>
		</row>
	</rows>
</data>