<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<data>
	<table name="WikiRevision">
		<col name="CompanyID" type="Int" default="Zero" />
		<col name="PageID" type="UniqueIdentifier" />
		<col name="Language" type="VarChar(50)" />
		<col name="PageRevisionID" type="Int" />
		<col name="Content" type="NVarChar(MAX)" />
		<col name="ContentHtml" type="NVarChar(MAX)" nullable="true" />
		<col name="PlainText" type="NVarChar(MAX)" />
		<col name="ApprovalByID" type="UniqueIdentifier" nullable="true" />
		<col name="ApprovalDateTime" type="DateTime" nullable="true" />
		<col name="CreatedByID" type="UniqueIdentifier" />
		<col name="CreatedDateTime" type="DateTime" />
		<col name="CompanyMask" type="VarBinary(32)" default="CompanyMaskReadOnly" />
		<col name="UID" type="UniqueIdentifier" />
		<col name="RecordSourceID" type="SmallInt" nullable="true" />
	</table>
	<rows>
		<row PageID="11f78806-453f-48b0-9b60-ccb7e87b7ba7" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="4c9040b4-c789-d252-6249-1319ce7a0f78" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
You close an active financial period in the cash management subledger to prevent transactions from being posted to this period, and to be able to close this financial period in the general ledger. To close a financial period in the cash management subledger, you need to perform the steps described in this guide.{br}{TOC}[anchor|#_76497371-3c1c-40b5-8e27-24c44b037c6d]
==1. Release Any Unreleased Cash Management Documents==((({S:Hint}If you do not have unreleased Cash Management transactions, skip this step.
)))
You use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CA_50_20_00|Release Cash Transactions] ([~/?ScreenId=CA502000|CA502000]) form to release multiple cash transactions, as the following screenshot shows. On this form, you select the needed cash transactions and click '''Release''', or you click '''Release All''' if you want to release all listed cash transactions. For details, see [HelpRoot_Financials\CA__HOW_To_Release_Multiple_CashTransactions|To Release Multiple Cash Transactions].[anchor|#_5df53d59-ed52-4f15-9eab-ec9c7fd4b3ce][anchor|#_78e03e06-65f9-4e7c-bccb-f063f3ba7dd6][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Closing_Period_in_CA_Step1.png|popup|450px]((({S:Hint}You can also release any individual cash entry on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CA_30_40_00|Transactions] ([~/?ScreenId=CA304000|CA304000]) form and an individual funds transfer on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CA_30_10_00|Funds Transfers] ([~/?ScreenId=CA301000|CA301000]) form.
)))[anchor|#_e542b5a5-b69a-42d6-944a-a1cb4aa26d6a]
==2. Optional: Reclassify Unknown Payments==
If you have unknown payments in the system, you use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CA_50_65_00|Reclassify Payments] ([~/?ScreenId=CA506500|CA506500]) form to reclassify them. To do so, you select the entry type related to unknown payments, specify the customer or the vendor and the module of the document for each unknown payment, and process these payments. The system generates payments from the formerly unknown payments. To review and release the generated document, you click the payment in the table and click the '''View Resulting Document''' button. You release the generated document by clicking '''Release''' on the form, which opens, as shown in the screenshot below. [anchor|#_ff147e66-899f-4ac3-930d-f188ce0cff9e][anchor|#_75c8a6d4-7a2a-4edd-88b5-76269fbb1fbd][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Closing_Period_in_CA_Step3.png|popup|450px]
For details on releasing a single payment or multiple payments, see [HelpRoot_Financials\AR__how_Releasing_Customer_Payments|To Release a Payment Document] and [HelpRoot_Financials\AR__how_Releasing_Multiple_Invoices_or_Memos|To Release Multiple AR Documents]. For details on releasing multiple Accounts Payable documents, see [HelpRoot_Financials\AP__how_Releasing_Bills_and_Adjustments|To Release Multiple Accounts Payable Documents].[anchor|#_696338b2-fb9d-43ec-9438-4f4504338617]
==3. Reconcile Bank Statements==
For details on this step, see the [HelpRoot_QG_Financials\QG__Reconciling_Bank_Statements|Reconciling Bank Statements] Quick Guide.[anchor|#_b5442750-b7eb-45cb-950f-1c0fabfc6daa]
==4. Close the Period==
Once all the previous steps have been performed, you close the needed financial period on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CA_50_60_00|Close Financial Periods] ([~/?ScreenId=CA506000|CA506000]) form. To do so, if the ''Centralized Period Management'' feature is disabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) form, you select the company in which you want to close the financial period. (If the feature is enabled, the periods will be closed in all the companies within the tenant.) You then select ''Close'' in the '''Action''' box, specify the financial year, select the period that you want to close, and click '''Process''' on the form toolbar. (See the following screenshot.)[anchor|#_49b6bbdb-6f6f-4c4b-a870-5ce2d690897b][anchor|#_76c37834-f817-48de-9a55-21b63a5c5063][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Closing_Period_in_CA_Step4.png|popup|350px]
For details, see [HelpRoot_Financials\CA__HOW_To_Close_Financial_Periods_in_CA|To Close Financial Periods in Cash Management].((({S:Hint}You may need to reopen a period if it has been closed by mistake. To do this, select ''Reopen'' in the '''Action''' box, specify the financial year, select the period that you want to close, and click '''Process''' on the form toolbar. For details, see [HelpRoot_Financials\CA__HOW_To_Reopen_Financial_Periods_in_CA|To Reopen a Financial Period in Cash Management].
)))
==Related Articles==
*[HelpRoot_Financials\CA__CON_CashEntry_Processing|Cash Entry Processing]
*[HelpRoot_Financials\CA__CON_FundTransfersProcessing|Funds Transfer Processing]
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\AR_30_20_00|Payments and Applications] ([~/?ScreenId=AR302000|AR302000])
*[HelpRoot_Financials\CA__con_Reclassification_of_Payments|Reclassification of Unknown Payments]
*[HelpRoot_Financials\CA__CON_ReclassifiedJournalTrans|Reclassification Results]
*[HelpRoot_Financials\CA__CON_ReconcilingTransactions|Reconciliation Process]
*[HelpRoot_Financials\CA__HOW_PerformReconciliation|To Perform Reconciliation]
*[HelpRoot_Financials\AR__how_Releasing_Customer_Payments|To Release a Payment Document]
*[HelpRoot_Financials\AR__how_Releasing_Multiple_Invoices_or_Memos|To Release Multiple AR Documents]
*[HelpRoot_Financials\CA__HOW_To_Release_Multiple_CashTransactions|To Release Multiple Cash Transactions]
*[HelpRoot_Financials\CA__MNG_Closing_Financial_Periods|Closing Financial Periods in Cash Management]
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_20_00|Checks and Payments] ([~/?ScreenId=AP302000|AP302000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\CA_50_60_00|Close Financial Periods] ([~/?ScreenId=CA506000|CA506000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\CA_30_10_00|Funds Transfers] ([~/?ScreenId=CA301000|CA301000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\CA_50_65_00|Reclassify Payments] ([~/?ScreenId=CA506500|CA506500])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\CA_50_20_00|Release Cash Transactions] ([~/?ScreenId=CA502000|CA502000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\CA_30_40_00|Transactions] ([~/?ScreenId=CA304000|CA304000])]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Closing a Financial Period in the Cash Management Subledger You close an active financial period in the cash management subledger to prevent                 transactions from being posted to this period, and to be able to close this                 financial period in the general ledger. To close a financial period in the cash                 management subledger, you need to perform the steps described in this guide. 1. Release Any Unreleased Cash Management Documents If you do not have unreleased Cash Management transactions, skip this step. You use the   ([~/?ScreenId=CA502000|CA502000]) Release Cash Transactions (CA502000) form to release                 multiple cash transactions, as the following screenshot shows. On this form, you                 select the needed cash transactions and click  Release , or you                 click  Release All  if you want to release all listed cash                 transactions. For details, see  To Release Multiple Cash Transactions. You can also release any individual cash entry on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CA304000|CA304000]) Transactions (CA304000) form and an individual                 funds transfer on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CA301000|CA301000]) Funds Transfers (CA301000)                 form. 2. Optional: Reclassify Unknown Payments If you have unknown payments in the system, you use the   ([~/?ScreenId=CA506500|CA506500]) Reclassify Payments (CA506500) form to reclassify them. To                 do so, you select the entry type related to unknown payments, specify the customer                 or the vendor and the module of the document for each unknown payment, and process                 these payments. The system generates payments from the formerly unknown payments. To                 review and release the generated document, you click the payment in the table and                 click the  View Resulting Document  button. You release the                 generated document by clicking  Release  on the form, which                 opens, as shown in the screenshot below.                  For details on releasing a single payment or multiple payments, see  To Release a Payment Document and  To Release Multiple AR Documents. For                 details on releasing multiple Accounts Payable documents, see  To Release Multiple Accounts Payable Documents. 3. Reconcile Bank Statements For details on this step, see the  Reconciling Bank Statements                 Quick Guide. 4. Close the Period Once all the previous steps have been performed, you close the needed financial                 period on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CA506000|CA506000]) Close Financial Periods (CA506000) form. To do                 so, if the  Centralized Period Management  feature is disabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features (CS100000) form, you select the company                 in which you want to close the financial period. (If the feature is enabled, the                 periods will be closed in all the companies within the tenant.) You then select                      Close  in the  Action  box, specify the financial                 year, select the period that you want to close, and click                      Process  on the form toolbar. (See the following                 screenshot.) For details, see  To Close Financial Periods in Cash Management. You may need to reopen a period if it has been closed by mistake. To do this,                 select  Reopen  in the  Action  box, specify the financial                 year, select the period that you want to close, and click                      Process  on the form toolbar. For details, see  To Reopen a Financial Period in Cash Management.  ([~/?ScreenId=AR302000|AR302000])  ([~/?ScreenId=AP302000|AP302000])  ([~/?ScreenId=CA506000|CA506000])  ([~/?ScreenId=CA301000|CA301000])  ([~/?ScreenId=CA506500|CA506500])  ([~/?ScreenId=CA502000|CA502000])  ([~/?ScreenId=CA304000|CA304000]) ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="9fe3197a-6230-4cc6-8d17-2e6a992d7f75" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="c6b6c544-ddb2-bd2c-3a5d-3930244b2a50" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[After all the needed transactions have been posted to a financial period and all figures have been verified, you can close the financial period in the accounts receivable subledger. This prevents users from posting new transactions to this period and gives you the ability to close this financial period in the general ledger. To close a financial period in the accounts receivable subledger, you perform the steps described in this guide.{br}{TOC}
==1. Generate Recurring Transactions==((({S:Hint}If you do not use scheduling for recurring documents, you should skip this step. 
)))
To generate the recurring batch, you specify the last date of the period in the '''Execution Date''' box and when to stop the execution, and then run the schedule on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AR_50_40_00|Generate Recurring Transactions] ([~/?ScreenId=AR504000|AR504000]) form, as the following screenshot shows.[anchor|#_9424bae0-8da1-4a72-b856-1c6ea1c3519e][anchor|#_e373440a-066b-492f-aebe-cfeb5da756c1][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Closing_Period_in_AR_Step1.png|popup|450px]
For details, see [HelpRoot_Financials\AR__how_Generating_Recurring_Invoices|To Generate Recurring Documents].{br}

The system generates recurring documents, which you release on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AR_50_10_00|Release AR Documents] ([~/?ScreenId=AR501000|AR501000]) form. For details, see [HelpRoot_Financials\AR__how_Releasing_Multiple_Invoices_or_Memos|To Release Multiple AR Documents].
==2. Auto-Apply Payments==((({S:Hint}If you do not auto-apply payments in your business process, you should skip this step.
)))
If the period to be closed includes customer payments and prepayments to be applied automatically to open invoices, debit memos, or overdue charges, you initiate the process of payment auto-application on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AR_50_60_00|Auto-Apply Payments] ([~/?ScreenId=AR506000|AR506000]) form. You specify the application date, set the batch to be released after the process is finished, select the statement cycle, and click '''Process''' (see the following screenshot).[anchor|#_b789149c-e888-46e4-9407-227dda20369a][anchor|#_5530274d-1f17-44e7-a5e5-e6b258b9b7dd][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Closing_Period_in_AR_Step2.png|popup|450px]
For details, see [HelpRoot_Financials\AR__how_Auto-Applying_Customer_Payments|To Apply a Payment Document Automatically].
==3. Generate VAT Credit Memos==((({S:Hint}If you do not use VATs for which the '''Reduce Taxable Amount on Early Payments''' cash discount option is selected on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\TX_20_50_00|Taxes] ([~/?ScreenId=TX205000|TX205000]) form, you should skip this step.
)))
On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AR_50_45_00|Generate VAT Credit Memos] ([~/?ScreenId=AR504500|AR504500]) form, you generate VAT credit memos for the documents for which the full payment has been made within the cash discount period. To do so, you specify the last date of the period and branch for which you want to generate credit memos, select the documents loaded to the table and click '''Process''', as the following screenshot shows.[anchor|#_b99cd2ed-b93e-4d0e-86fb-d74a05dc461f][anchor|#_8bf48339-129e-4c45-92a3-ba959a598271][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Closing_Period_in_AR_Step3.png|popup|450px]
If the '''Automatically Release Credit Memos''' check box is selected on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AR_10_10_00|Accounts Receivable Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=AR101000|AR101000]) form, the adjusting credit memos have been automatically applied to the invoices and closed. If this check box is cleared, you release the credit memos on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AR_50_10_00|Release AR Documents] ([~/?ScreenId=AR501000|AR501000]) form.
==4. Generate Overdue Charges==((({S:Hint}Depending on your company credit management policy, this step can be skipped.
)))
Before you close the financial period in the accounts receivable subledger, you find documents that are subject to overdue charges for the period to be closed, calculate the amounts of overdue charges, and create appropriate documents for the charges. To perform this step, you open the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AR_50_70_00|Calculate Overdue Charges] ([~/?ScreenId=AR507000|AR507000]) form, select the last date of the financial period (the one you want to close), and the statement cycle, and click '''Calculate''' (see the following screenshot). After the system has found the applicable overdue documents and calculated the charges, you generate the overdue charge documents by selecting all of the documents in the table and clicking '''Process''', or by clicking '''Process All'''.[anchor|#_93cdb57e-96fb-4dea-a397-edf23c3071f1][anchor|#_15daf139-28f4-4f7e-8177-3549ae20ecc8][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Closing_Period_in_AR_Step4.png|popup|450px]
For detailed instructions, see [HelpRoot_Financials\AR__how_Calculating_Overdue_Charges|To Calculate Overdue Charges].{br}

As a result of processing, the system generates Accounts Receivable documents of the ''Overdue Charge'' type with the ''Balanced'' or ''On Hold'' status, depending on whether the '''Hold Documents on Entry''' check box is selected on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AR_10_10_00|Accounts Receivable Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=AR101000|AR101000]) form. You then further process the generated documents by using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AR_30_10_00|Invoices and Memos] ([~/?ScreenId=AR301000|AR301000]) form.
==5. Prepare Dunning Letters==((({S:Hint}This step is required if you need to produce dunning letters to remind your customers about overdue documents (whether or not you charge your customers for preparing and sending the letters).
)))
You prepare dunning letters for customers that have unpaid and overdue invoices on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AR_52_10_00|Prepare Dunning Letters] ([~/?ScreenId=AR521000|AR521000]) form. To do so, you specify the date of the financial period to be specified on the generated letters, select the customers for which you want to generate letters, and click '''Process''', as the following screenshot shows.[anchor|#_e25739c7-6f38-49d7-856f-0ea8e007b14a][anchor|#_10de313f-cd0f-4ef7-85ec-43fd96e83a19][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Closing_Period_in_AR_Step5_1.png|popup|450px]
Depending on the settings of the particular customers, you may also need to print or email the dunning letters. You print the dunning letters, email them, or indicate if they should not be printed or emailed on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AR_52_20_00|Print/Release Dunning Letters] ([~/?ScreenId=AR522000|AR522000]) form by selecting the appropriate action and processing the needed letters (see the following screenshot).[anchor|#_e4eb5ff1-5a4f-4bdf-b458-d38e70178fde][anchor|#_c3bb829a-75de-41fb-9243-b3a9a4010dfd][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Closing_Period_in_AR_Step5_2.png|popup|450px]
If the '''Automatically Release Dunning Letters''' check box is cleared on the '''Dunning Letters''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AR_10_10_00|Accounts Receivable Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=AR101000|AR101000]) form, you also release the generated dunning letters on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AR_52_20_00|Print/Release Dunning Letters] form. {br}

When the dunning letters have been released, the system generates invoices with the fees for customers if the fees have been configured in the system. If the '''Automatically Release Dunning Fee Documents''' check box is cleared on the '''Dunning Letters''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AR_10_10_00|Accounts Receivable Preferences] form, the invoices are created with the ''Balanced'' status. You can adjust the fee amount, if needed, and release each invoice on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AR_30_10_00|Invoices and Memos] ([~/?ScreenId=AR301000|AR301000]) form.
==6. Release Any Unreleased Accounts Receivable Documents==
You check whether you have unreleased documents to be posted to the period to be closed on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AR_50_10_00|Release AR Documents] ([~/?ScreenId=AR501000|AR501000]) form, and release the unreleased documents, as shown below.[anchor|#_744a9b52-567b-40de-939d-bb3e4688df4a][anchor|#_7f74c9c8-bcb9-4f0d-8a8f-e30ab47a4fbb][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Closing_Period_in_AR_Step6.png|popup|450px]
For details, see [HelpRoot_Financials\AR__how_Releasing_Multiple_Invoices_or_Memos|To Release Multiple AR Documents].
==7. Revalue Customers&rsquo; Accounts Receivable Accounts Maintained in a Foreign Currency. ==((({S:Hint} If you do not have customers&rsquo; accounts maintained in a foreign currency, skip this step.
)))
On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CM_50_50_00|Revalue AR Accounts] ([~/?ScreenId=CM505000|CM505000]) form, you perform revaluation of customers' Accounts Receivable accounts maintained in a foreign currency. You select the period you want to close, the foreign currency of the accounts to be revalued, and specify a description of the revaluation, as the screenshot below shows. {br}

The system generates a revaluation batch and opens it on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_30_10_00|Journal Transactions] ([~/?ScreenId=GL301000|GL301000]) form, as shown in the lower part of the screenshot.((({S:Hint}Because the revaluation batch is auto-reversing, the next period should be activated on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_20_10_00|Master Financial Calendar] ([~/?ScreenId=GL201000|GL201000]) form, so that the reversing batch can be posted to the next period after the period has been closed.
)))[anchor|#_471f8b78-7385-4fa0-8549-e93e9cc6865b][anchor|#_1c027ef4-da6a-4d68-88b5-51ef19923c03][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Closing_Period_in_AR_Step7.png|popup|450px]
==8. Reconcile Accounts Receivable and General Ledger Accounts ==
To perform reconciliation, for each Accounts Receivable account used in Accounts Receivable documents of the period to be closed, you have to compare the total balance of open documents with the balance of the account according to the transactions posted to the General Ledger. The balances must be equal.{br}

To do this, on the [HelpRoot_ReportReference\AR_63_20_00|AR Balance by GL Account] ([~/?ScreenId=AR632000|AR632000]) report form, you select the ''Account Summary'' report format option, the necessary branch, and the financial period. (See the following screenshot, which shows the report form and the generated report.)[anchor|#_fa2f6128-f82c-4118-a400-c7ef60a685c5][anchor|#_26d0af0a-685c-42eb-a847-df2a6e8ea513][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Closing_Period_in_AR_Step8_1.png|popup|450px]
On the [HelpRoot_ReportReference\GL_63_25_00|Trial Balance Detailed] ([~/?ScreenId=GL632500|GL632500]) report form, you select the branch, the ledger, and the financial period. (See the following screenshot, which shows the report form and the generated report.)[anchor|#_0a9dcf4f-d788-46c9-99e9-a07c6cd98d16][anchor|#_42e2011f-bfd6-4cb5-97d0-6d15e235b9a2][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Closing_Period_in_AR_Step8_2.png|popup|450px]
Compare the balances of the Accounts Receivable accounts in both reports. If the balances are equal, the balances are reconciled.((({S:Hint}During the reconciliation, you might find a discrepancy between the total balance of open Accounts Receivable documents by General Ledger account and the balance of this account according to the trial balance. The discrepancy could be caused by transactions being posted to the Accounts Receivable account directly from the general ledger without a document being processed in the accounts receivable subledger. Another possible cause of a discrepancy is the presence of unposted batches generated from Accounts Receivable documents. To review the batches that have been released but not yet posted, you can use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_50_20_00|Post Transactions] ([~/?ScreenId=GL502000|GL502000]) form.
)))
==9. Prepare Statements==((({S:Hint}You perform this step if the generation of statements must be performed on or before the last day of the financial period.
)))
You prepare statements for statement cycles on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AR_50_30_00|Prepare Statements] ([~/?ScreenId=AR503000|AR503000]) form. To prepare a statement, you select the date on which you need to prepare statements and the cycle or cycles for which you want to generate statements; on the form toolbar, you click '''Process''' (see the following screenshot).[anchor|#_28d3d0f4-280c-45c1-aa5b-7ce5058794c0][anchor|#_00d30ab8-8214-47c7-ac58-8f25e3285b55][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Closing_Period_in_AR_Step9.png|popup|450px]
 For detailed instructions, see [HelpRoot_Financials\AR__how_Preparing_Customer_Statements|To Prepare Customer Statements].{br}

Once a statement has been generated, it is saved in the statement history of the customer in its state at the moment it was generated (or regenerated).{br}

You then print a generated statement on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AR_50_35_00|Print Statements] ([~/?ScreenId=AR503500|AR503500]) form if the '''Print Statements''' check box is selected for this customer on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AR_30_30_00|Customers] ([~/?ScreenId=AR303000|AR303000]) form. For details on how to print statements, see [HelpRoot_Financials\AR__how_Printing_or_Emailing_Customer_Statements|To Print Customer Statements or Send Them by Email].
==10. Optional: Calculate Commissions and Close the Commission Period==
If you pay commissions to salespersons who work with customers, you can prepare salespersons&rsquo; commissions for the needed commission period that coincides with the financial period to be closed. To do this, on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AR_50_55_00|Calculate Commissions] ([~/?ScreenId=AR505500|AR505500]) form, you select the financial period to be closed and then click '''Process All''' on the form toolbar. (See the screenshot below.) {br}

After the system has calculated the commissions, you click '''Review Commission Period''' on the form toolbar. The [HelpRoot_FormReference\AR_50_65_00|Close Commission Period] ([~/?ScreenId=AR506500|AR506500]) form is opened for the commission period you are closing, as shown in the lower part of the following screenshot. To close the period, on the form toolbar, you click '''Actions''' > '''Close Period'''. [anchor|#_b4da4a96-8db2-4ccf-aa6e-72cff322cd0a][anchor|#_63810ea3-ecef-4037-bfbe-476e8c525163][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Closing_Period_in_AR_Step10.png|popup|450px]
For details, see [HelpRoot_Financials\AR__how_Preparing_Commissions|To Prepare Commissions].[anchor|#_d36adba0-e760-485c-89b4-ae74b4fee5e9]
==11. Close the Period in the Accounts Receivable Subledger==
Once the required steps have been performed, you close the needed financial period on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AR_50_90_00|Close Financial Periods] ([~/?ScreenId=AR509000|AR509000]) form. To do so, if the ''Centralized Period Management'' feature is disabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) form, you select the company in which you want to close the financial period. (If the feature is enabled, the periods will be closed in all the companies within the tenant.) You then select ''Close'' in the '''Action''' box, specify the financial year, select the period that you want to close, and click '''Process''' on the form toolbar. (See the following screenshot.)[anchor|#_70a099a0-93fc-43b3-8ed8-f4b433fac6ef][anchor|#_0221215e-445f-42b2-94e5-d1a0a80a099f][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Closing_Period_in_AR_Step11.png|popup|400px]
For details, see [HelpRoot_Financials\AR__HOW_To_Close_Financial_Period_in_AR|To Close Financial Periods in Accounts Receivable].((({S:Hint}You may need to reopen a period if it was closed by mistake. To do this, select ''Reopen'' in the '''Action''' box, specify the financial year, select the period that you want to close, and click '''Process''' on the form toolbar. For details, see [HelpRoot_Financials\AR__HOW_To_Reopen_Financial_Period_in_AR|To Reopen a Financial Period in Accounts Receivable].
)))
==Related Articles==
*[HelpRoot_Financials\CM__con_Overview_of_Revaluations|Accounts Receivable Revaluations]
*[HelpRoot_QG_Financials\QG__Closing_Financial_Period_in_GL_Module|Closing a Financial Period in the General Ledger]
*[HelpRoot_Financials\AR__con_Commission_Calculation|Commission Configuration and Calculation]
*[HelpRoot_Financials\AR__CON_InvoiceReleasing|Invoice Releasing]
*[HelpRoot_Financials\AR__CON_PaymentRelease|Release of Payments]
*[HelpRoot_Financials\AR__con_Recurring_Invoices|Schedules for Recurring Documents]]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Closing a Financial Period in the Accounts Receivable Subledger After all the needed transactions have been posted to a financial       period and all figures have been verified, you can close the financial period in the accounts       receivable subledger. This prevents users from posting new transactions to this period and       gives you the ability to close this financial period in the general ledger. To close a       financial period in the accounts receivable subledger, you perform the steps described in this       guide. 1. Generate Recurring Transactions If you do not use scheduling for recurring documents, you should skip this step.  To generate the recurring batch, you specify the last date of the period in the            Execution Date  box and when to stop the execution, and then run the         schedule on the   ([~/?ScreenId=AR504000|AR504000]) Generate Recurring Transactions (AR504000) form, as the         following screenshot shows. For details, see  To Generate Recurring Documents. The system generates recurring documents, which you release on the   ([~/?ScreenId=AR501000|AR501000]) Release AR Documents (AR501000) form. For details, see  To Release Multiple AR Documents. 2. Auto-Apply Payments If you do not auto-apply payments in your business process, you should skip this         step. If the period to be closed includes customer payments and prepayments to be applied         automatically to open invoices, debit memos, or overdue charges, you initiate the process of         payment auto-application on the   ([~/?ScreenId=AR506000|AR506000]) Auto-Apply Payments (AR506000)         form. You specify the application date, set the batch to be released after the process is         finished, select the statement cycle, and click  Process  (see the         following screenshot). For details, see  To Apply a Payment Document Automatically. 3. Generate VAT Credit Memos If you do not use VATs for which the  Reduce Taxable Amount on Early           Payments  cash discount option is selected on the   ([~/?ScreenId=TX205000|TX205000]) Taxes (TX205000) form, you should skip this         step. On the   ([~/?ScreenId=AR504500|AR504500]) Generate VAT Credit Memos (AR504500) form, you generate VAT         credit memos for the documents for which the full payment has been made within the cash         discount period. To do so, you specify the last date of the period and branch for which you         want to generate credit memos, select the documents loaded to the table and click            Process , as the following screenshot shows. If the  Automatically Release Credit Memos  check box is selected on         the   ([~/?ScreenId=AR101000|AR101000]) Accounts Receivable Preferences (AR101000) form, the adjusting credit         memos have been automatically applied to the invoices and closed. If this check box is         cleared, you release the credit memos on the   ([~/?ScreenId=AR501000|AR501000]) Release AR Documents         (AR501000) form. 4. Generate Overdue Charges Depending on your company credit management policy, this step can be skipped. Before you close the financial period in the accounts receivable subledger, you find         documents that are subject to overdue charges for the period to be closed, calculate the         amounts of overdue charges, and create appropriate documents for the charges. To perform         this step, you open the   ([~/?ScreenId=AR507000|AR507000]) Calculate Overdue Charges (AR507000) form, select         the last date of the financial period (the one you want to close), and the statement cycle,         and click  Calculate  (see the following screenshot). After the system         has found the applicable overdue documents and calculated the charges, you generate the         overdue charge documents by selecting all of the documents in the table and clicking            Process , or by clicking  Process All . For detailed instructions, see  To Calculate Overdue Charges. As a result of processing, the system generates Accounts Receivable documents of the            Overdue Charge  type with the  Balanced  or  On Hold  status, depending on         whether the  Hold Documents on Entry  check box is selected on the             ([~/?ScreenId=AR101000|AR101000]) Accounts Receivable Preferences (AR101000) form. You then further process         the generated documents by using the   ([~/?ScreenId=AR301000|AR301000]) Invoices and Memos         (AR301000) form. 5. Prepare Dunning Letters This step is required if you need to produce dunning letters to remind your customers         about overdue documents (whether or not you charge your customers for preparing and sending         the letters). You prepare dunning letters for customers that have unpaid and overdue invoices on the             ([~/?ScreenId=AR521000|AR521000]) Prepare Dunning Letters (AR521000) form. To do so, you specify the         date of the financial period to be specified on the generated letters, select the customers         for which you want to generate letters, and click  Process , as the         following screenshot shows. Depending on the settings of the particular customers, you may also need to print or email         the dunning letters. You print the dunning letters, email them, or indicate if they should         not be printed or emailed on the   ([~/?ScreenId=AR522000|AR522000]) Print/Release Dunning Letters (AR522000)         form by selecting the appropriate action and processing the needed letters (see the         following screenshot). If the  Automatically Release Dunning Letters  check box is cleared on         the  Dunning Letters  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=AR101000|AR101000]) Accounts Receivable Preferences (AR101000) form, you also release the generated         dunning letters on the   ([~/?ScreenId=AR522000|AR522000]) Print/Release Dunning Letters form.  When the dunning letters have been released, the system generates invoices with the fees         for customers if the fees have been configured in the system. If the            Automatically Release Dunning Fee Documents  check box is cleared on         the  Dunning Letters  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=AR101000|AR101000]) Accounts Receivable Preferences form, the invoices are created with the            Balanced  status. You can adjust the fee amount, if needed, and release each invoice         on the   ([~/?ScreenId=AR301000|AR301000]) Invoices and Memos (AR301000) form. 6. Release Any Unreleased Accounts Receivable Documents You check whether you have unreleased documents to be posted to the period to be closed on         the   ([~/?ScreenId=AR501000|AR501000]) Release AR Documents (AR501000) form, and release the         unreleased documents, as shown below. For details, see  To Release Multiple AR Documents. 7. Revalue Customers' Accounts Receivable Accounts Maintained in a Foreign Currency.   If you do not have customers' accounts maintained in a foreign currency, skip this         step. On the   ([~/?ScreenId=CM505000|CM505000]) Revalue AR Accounts (CM505000) form, you perform         revaluation of customers' Accounts Receivable accounts maintained in a foreign currency. You         select the period you want to close, the foreign currency of the accounts to be revalued,         and specify a description of the revaluation, as the screenshot below shows.  The system generates a revaluation batch and opens it on the   ([~/?ScreenId=GL301000|GL301000]) Journal Transactions (GL301000) form, as shown in the lower part of         the screenshot. Because the revaluation batch is auto-reversing, the next period should be activated on         the   ([~/?ScreenId=GL201000|GL201000]) Master Financial Calendar (GL201000) form, so that the reversing         batch can be posted to the next period after the period has been closed. 8. Reconcile Accounts Receivable and General Ledger Accounts  To perform reconciliation, for each Accounts Receivable account used in Accounts Receivable         documents of the period to be closed, you have to compare the total balance of open         documents with the balance of the account according to the transactions posted to the         General Ledger. The balances must be equal. To do this, on the   ([~/?ScreenId=AR632000|AR632000]) AR Balance by GL Account (AR632000) report form,         you select the  Account Summary  report format option, the necessary branch, and the         financial period. (See the following screenshot, which shows the report form and the         generated report.) On the   ([~/?ScreenId=GL632500|GL632500]) Trial Balance Detailed (GL632500) report form, you select         the branch, the ledger, and the financial period. (See the following screenshot, which shows         the report form and the generated report.) Compare the balances of the Accounts Receivable accounts in both reports. If the balances         are equal, the balances are reconciled. During the reconciliation, you might find a discrepancy between the total balance of         open Accounts Receivable documents by General Ledger account and the balance of this account         according to the trial balance. The discrepancy could be caused by transactions being posted         to the Accounts Receivable account directly from the general ledger without a document being         processed in the accounts receivable subledger. Another possible cause of a discrepancy is         the presence of unposted batches generated from Accounts Receivable documents. To review the         batches that have been released but not yet posted, you can use the   ([~/?ScreenId=GL502000|GL502000]) Post Transactions (GL502000) form. 9. Prepare Statements You perform this step if the generation of statements must be performed on or before the         last day of the financial period. You prepare statements for statement cycles on the   ([~/?ScreenId=AR503000|AR503000]) Prepare Statements (AR503000) form. To prepare a statement, you         select the date on which you need to prepare statements and the cycle or cycles for which         you want to generate statements; on the form toolbar, you click            Process  (see the following screenshot).  For detailed instructions, see  To Prepare Customer Statements. Once a statement has been generated, it is saved in the statement history of the customer         in its state at the moment it was generated (or regenerated). You then print a generated statement on the   ([~/?ScreenId=AR503500|AR503500]) Print Statements         (AR503500) form if the  Print Statements  check box is selected for         this customer on the   ([~/?ScreenId=AR303000|AR303000]) Customers (AR303000) form. For         details on how to print statements, see  To Print Customer Statements or Send Them by Email. 10. Optional: Calculate Commissions and Close the Commission Period If you pay commissions to salespersons who work with customers, you can prepare         salespersons' commissions for the needed commission period that coincides with the financial         period to be closed. To do this, on the   ([~/?ScreenId=AR505500|AR505500]) Calculate Commissions         (AR505500) form, you select the financial period to be closed and then click            Process All  on the form toolbar. (See the screenshot below.)  After the system has calculated the commissions, you click  Review Commission           Period  on the form toolbar. The   ([~/?ScreenId=AR506500|AR506500]) Close Commission Period         (AR506500) form is opened for the commission period you are closing, as shown in the         lower part of the following screenshot. To close the period, on the form toolbar, you click  Actions Close Period .  For details, see  To Prepare Commissions. 11. Close the Period in the Accounts Receivable Subledger Once the required steps have been performed, you close the needed financial period on the             ([~/?ScreenId=AR509000|AR509000]) Close Financial Periods (AR509000) form. To do so, if the            Centralized Period Management  feature is disabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features (CS100000) form, you select the company in which         you want to close the financial period. (If the feature is enabled, the periods will be         closed in all the companies within the tenant.) You then select  Close  in the            Action  box, specify the financial year, select the period that you         want to close, and click  Process  on the form toolbar. (See the         following screenshot.) For details, see  To Close Financial Periods in Accounts Receivable. You may need to reopen a period if it was closed by mistake. To do this, select            Reopen  in the  Action  box, specify the financial year, select         the period that you want to close, and click  Process  on the form         toolbar. For details, see  To Reopen a Financial Period in Accounts Receivable. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="091b4593-3dc3-47ca-9964-e3c23e3d4670" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="2a2e17f7-0973-df47-5421-fb14af8a734a" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[After all the needed transactions have been posted to a financial period and all figures have been verified, you can close the financial period in the accounts payable subledger. This prevents users from posting new transactions to this period and gives you the ability to close this financial period in the general ledger. To close a financial period in the accounts payable subledger, you perform the steps described in this guide.{br}{TOC}
==1. Generate Recurring Transactions==((({S:Hint}If you do not use scheduling for recurring documents, you should skip this step. 
)))
To generate the recurring document, you specify the last date of the period in the '''Execution Date''' box and when to stop the execution, and then run the schedule on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_50_40_00|Generate Recurring Transactions] ([~/?ScreenId=AP504000|AP504000]) form, as the following screenshot shows.[anchor|#_45dfe112-2ee2-4bd7-b9a5-c894c4c1063c][anchor|#_7565fdc7-8358-4e3d-90f6-4d5486b9211d][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Closing_Period_in_AP_Step1.png|popup|450px]
For details, see [HelpRoot_Financials\AP__how_Generating_Recurring_Bills|To Generate Recurring Documents].{br}

The system generates recurring documents, which you release on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_50_10_00|Release AP Documents] ([~/?ScreenId=AP501000|AP501000]) form. For details, see [HelpRoot_Financials\AP__how_Releasing_Bills_and_Adjustments|To Release Multiple Accounts Payable Documents].
==2. Generate VAT Debit Adjustments==((({S:Hint}If you do not use VAT for which the '''Reduce Taxable Amount on Early Payments''' cash discount option is selected on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\TX_20_50_00|Taxes] ([~/?ScreenId=TX205000|TX205000]) form, skip this step.
)))
On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_50_45_00|Generate VAT Debit Adjustments] ([~/?ScreenId=AP504500|AP504500]) form, you generate VAT debit adjustments for the documents for which the full payment has been made within the cash discount period. To do so, you specify date of the period end and branch for which you want to generate debit adjustments, select the documents loaded to the table and click '''Process''', as the following screenshot shows.[anchor|#_b99cd2ed-b93e-4d0e-86fb-d74a05dc461f][anchor|#_9799889a-a8bd-4678-9065-832639f6e67e][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Closing_Period_in_AP_Step2_3.png|popup|400px]
The adjusting debit adjustments have been automatically applied to the bills and closed.
==3. Release Any Unreleased Accounts Payable Documents==
You check if you have unreleased documents by selecting the period to be closed, clicking '''Run Report''' on the [HelpRoot_ReportReference\AP_61_07_00|AP Edit] ([~/?ScreenId=AP610700|AP610700]) form, and reviewing the report, as the following screenshot shows.[anchor|#_5d010263-b00b-46d2-9f58-239cdf453b54][anchor|#_a5838c35-50c4-43c6-af5f-0d8da4fd88d8][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Closing_Period_in_AP_Step3_1.png|popup|450px]((({S:Hint}If you do not have unreleased Accounts Payable documents, proceed to the next step.
)))
You release payments to be posted within the period to be closed on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_50_52_00|Release Payments] ([~/?ScreenId=AP505200|AP505200]) form. For details, see [HelpRoot_Financials\AP__how_Releasing_AP_Checks|To Release Accounts Payable Checks]. {br}

You release other Accounts Payable documents to be posted within the period to be closed on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_50_10_00|Release AP Documents] ([~/?ScreenId=AP501000|AP501000]) form. For details, see [HelpRoot_Financials\AP__how_Releasing_Bills_and_Adjustments|To Release Multiple Accounts Payable Documents].
==4. Revalue Vendors&rsquo; Accounts Payable Accounts Maintained in a Foreign Currency==((({S:Hint} If you do not have vendors&rsquo; accounts maintained in a foreign currency, skip this step.
)))
On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CM_50_40_00|Revalue AP Accounts] ([~/?ScreenId=CM504000|CM504000]) form, you perform revaluation of vendors' Accounts Payable accounts maintained in a foreign currency. You select the period you want to close, the foreign currency of the accounts to revalue, and specify a description of the revaluation, as the screenshot below shows. {br}

The system generates a revaluation batch and opens it on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_30_10_00|Journal Transactions] ([~/?ScreenId=GL301000|GL301000]) form, as shown in the lower part of the screenshot.((({S:Hint}Because the revaluation batch is auto-reversing, the next period should be activated on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_20_10_00|Master Financial Calendar] ([~/?ScreenId=GL201000|GL201000]) form, so that the reversing batch can be posted to the next period after the period has been closed.
)))[anchor|#_88af6697-d2ea-44bd-b044-d48889e8df3d][anchor|#_cd13e5e8-3ab2-48fe-91d7-c488ccc31621][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Closing_Period_in_AP_Step3.png|popup|450px]
==5. Reconcile Accounts Payable Accounts with General Ledger Accounts==
To perform reconciliation, for each Accounts Payable account used in Accounts Payable documents of the period to be closed, you have to compare the total balance of open documents with the balance of the account according to the transactions posted to the General Ledger. The balances must be equal.{br}

To do this, on the [HelpRoot_ReportReference\AP_63_20_00|AP Balance by GL Account] ([~/?ScreenId=AP632000|AP632000]) report form, you select the ''Account Summary'' report format option, the necessary branch, and the financial period. (See the following screenshot, which shows the report form and the generated report.)[anchor|#_1ab6aeb6-7e10-464e-a4ed-94a9a710391e][anchor|#_f178aae1-9301-47fe-98a4-0f72c9abd266][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Closing_Period_in_AP_Step4_1.png|popup|450px]
On the [HelpRoot_ReportReference\GL_63_25_00|Trial Balance Detailed] ([~/?ScreenId=GL632500|GL632500]) report form, you select the branch, the ledger, and the financial period. (See the following screenshot, which shows the report form and the generated report.)[anchor|#_80d40ccb-2bd7-46ad-a4e0-10e5b7eee221][anchor|#_9bf84c65-2fb7-451e-b78c-25715b5c7036][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Closing_Period_in_AP_Step4_2.png|popup|450px]
Compare the balances of the Accounts Payable accounts in both reports. If the balances are equal, the balances are reconciled.((({S:Hint}During the reconciliation, you might find a discrepancy between the total balance of open Accounts Payable documents by General Ledger account and the balance of this account according to the trial balance. The discrepancy could be caused by transactions being posted to the Accounts Payable account directly from the general ledger without a document being processed in the accounts payable subledger. Another possible cause of the discrepancy is the presence of unposted batches generated from Accounts Payable documents. To review the batches that have been released but not yet posted, you can use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_50_20_00|Post Transactions] ([~/?ScreenId=GL502000|GL502000]) form.
)))[anchor|#_d36adba0-e760-485c-89b4-ae74b4fee5e9]
==6. Close the Period in the Accounts Payable Subledger==
Once all the previous steps have been performed, you close the needed financial period on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_50_60_00|Close Financial Periods] ([~/?ScreenId=AP506000|AP506000]) form. To do so, if the ''Centralized Period Management'' feature is disabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) form, you select the company in which you want to close the financial period. (If the feature is enabled, the periods will be closed in all the companies within the tenant.) You then select ''Close'' in the '''Action''' box, specify the financial year, select the period that you want to close, and click '''Process''' on the form toolbar. (See the following screenshot.)[anchor|#_5eec471b-6582-4879-9462-e565b3ee9fd0][anchor|#_47becb71-c86b-4680-a274-3254a6fa891e][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Closing_Period_in_AP_Step5.png|popup|350px]
For instructions, see [HelpRoot_Financials\AP__how_Closing_a_Financial_Period_in_AP|To Close Financial Periods in Accounts Payable].((({S:Hint}You may need to reopen a period if it has been closed by mistake. To do this, select ''Reopen'' in the '''Action''' box, specify the financial year, select the period that you want to close, and click '''Process''' on the form toolbar. For details, see [HelpRoot_Financials\AP__how_Reopening_a_Financial_Period_in_AP|To Reopen a Financial Period in Accounts Payable].
)))
==Related Articles==
*[HelpRoot_Financials\CM__con_Overview_of_Revaluations|Accounts Receivable Revaluations]
*[HelpRoot_QG_Financials\QG__Closing_Financial_Period_in_GL_Module|Closing a Financial Period in the General Ledger]
*[HelpRoot_Financials\GL__con_Period-End_Closing_Procedures|Closing Periods]
*[HelpRoot_Financials\AP__con_Recurring_Bills|Schedules for Recurring Documents]]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Closing a Financial Period in the Accounts Payable Subledger After all the needed transactions have been posted to a             financial period and all figures have been verified, you can close the financial period             in the accounts payable subledger. This prevents users from posting new transactions to             this period and gives you the ability to close this financial period in the general             ledger. To close a financial period in the accounts payable subledger, you perform the             steps described in this guide. 1. Generate Recurring Transactions If you do not use scheduling for recurring documents, you should skip this step.  To generate the recurring document, you specify the last date of the period in the                      Execution Date  box and when to stop the execution, and                 then run the schedule on the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP504000|AP504000]) Generate Recurring Transactions                 (AP504000) form, as the following screenshot shows. For details, see  To Generate Recurring Documents. The system generates recurring documents, which you release on the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP501000|AP501000]) Release AP Documents (AP501000) form. For details, see                      To Release Multiple Accounts Payable Documents. 2. Generate VAT Debit Adjustments If you do not use VAT for which the  Reduce Taxable Amount on Early Payments  cash discount option is selected on the   ([~/?ScreenId=TX205000|TX205000]) Taxes (TX205000) form, skip this step. On the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP504500|AP504500]) Generate VAT Debit Adjustments (AP504500) form, you generate VAT debit                 adjustments for the documents for which the full payment has been made within the                 cash discount period. To do so, you specify date of the period end and branch for                 which you want to generate debit adjustments, select the documents loaded to the                 table and click  Process , as the following screenshot                 shows. The adjusting debit adjustments have been automatically applied to the bills and closed. 3. Release Any Unreleased Accounts Payable Documents You check if you have unreleased documents by selecting the period to be closed,                 clicking  Run Report  on the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP610700|AP610700]) AP Edit (AP610700) form, and reviewing the                 report, as the following screenshot shows. If you do not have unreleased Accounts Payable documents, proceed to the next                 step. You release payments to be posted within the period to be closed on the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP505200|AP505200]) Release Payments (AP505200) form. For details, see                      To Release Accounts Payable Checks.  You release other Accounts Payable documents to be posted within the period to be                 closed on the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP501000|AP501000]) Release AP Documents (AP501000) form. For                 details, see  To Release Multiple Accounts Payable Documents. 4. Revalue Vendors' Accounts Payable Accounts Maintained in a Foreign                 Currency  If you do not have vendors' accounts maintained in a foreign currency, skip this                 step. On the   ([~/?ScreenId=CM504000|CM504000]) Revalue AP Accounts (CM504000) form, you perform                 revaluation of vendors' Accounts Payable accounts maintained in a foreign currency.                 You select the period you want to close, the foreign currency of the accounts to                 revalue, and specify a description of the revaluation, as the screenshot below                 shows.  The system generates a revaluation batch and opens it on the   ([~/?ScreenId=GL301000|GL301000]) Journal Transactions (GL301000) form, as shown in the lower                 part of the screenshot. Because the revaluation batch is auto-reversing, the next period should be                 activated on the   ([~/?ScreenId=GL201000|GL201000]) Master Financial Calendar (GL201000) form, so                 that the reversing batch can be posted to the next period after the period has been                 closed. 5. Reconcile Accounts Payable Accounts with General Ledger Accounts To perform reconciliation, for each Accounts Payable account used in Accounts Payable                 documents of the period to be closed, you have to compare the total balance of open                 documents with the balance of the account according to the transactions posted to                 the General Ledger. The balances must be equal. To do this, on the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP632000|AP632000]) AP Balance by GL Account (AP632000) report                 form, you select the  Account Summary  report format option, the necessary                 branch, and the financial period. (See the following screenshot, which shows the                 report form and the generated report.) On the   ([~/?ScreenId=GL632500|GL632500]) Trial Balance Detailed (GL632500) report form, you                 select the branch, the ledger, and the financial period. (See the following                 screenshot, which shows the report form and the generated report.) Compare the balances of the Accounts Payable accounts in both reports. If the                 balances are equal, the balances are reconciled. During the reconciliation, you might find a discrepancy between the total balance                 of open Accounts Payable documents by General Ledger account and the balance of this                 account according to the trial balance. The discrepancy could be caused by                 transactions being posted to the Accounts Payable account directly from the general                 ledger without a document being processed in the accounts payable subledger. Another                 possible cause of the discrepancy is the presence of unposted batches generated from                 Accounts Payable documents. To review the batches that have been released but not                 yet posted, you can use the   ([~/?ScreenId=GL502000|GL502000]) Post Transactions (GL502000)                 form. 6. Close the Period in the Accounts Payable Subledger Once all the previous steps have been performed, you close the needed financial                 period on the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP506000|AP506000]) Close Financial Periods (AP506000) form. To do                 so, if the  Centralized Period Management  feature is disabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features (CS100000) form, you select the company                 in which you want to close the financial period. (If the feature is enabled, the                 periods will be closed in all the companies within the tenant.) You then select                      Close  in the  Action  box, specify the financial                 year, select the period that you want to close, and click                      Process  on the form toolbar. (See the following                 screenshot.) For instructions, see  To Close Financial Periods in Accounts Payable. You may need to reopen a period if it has been closed by mistake. To do this,                 select  Reopen  in the  Action  box, specify the financial                 year, select the period that you want to close, and click                      Process  on the form toolbar. For details, see  To Reopen a Financial Period in Accounts Payable. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="fce35d0b-a014-4903-a849-31884e1e8a6c" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="2aee91a9-a876-246d-0210-3bf892fa9995" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
You close an open financial period in the fixed assets subledger to prevent transactions from being posted to this period, and to be able to close this financial period in the general ledger. To close a financial period in the fixed assets subledger, you need to perform the steps described in this guide.{br}{TOC}[anchor|#section_old_s11_mz]
==1. Make Sure That All Needed Transactions Have Been Converted to Fixed Assets==
For the period to be closed, you need to ensure that all needed transactions that have been posted to the FA Accrual account have been converted to fixed assets. To check this, generate the [HelpRoot_ReportReference\FA_62_00_10|Unreconciled Transactions for Period] ([~/?ScreenId=FA620010|FA620010]) report. The report shows any transactions posted within the selected period range that have not been converted to fixed assets.{br}

[anchor|#image_j3l_5jk_sz][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Closing_Period_in_FA_Step1.png|450px]{br}

On this screenshot, the [HelpRoot_ReportReference\FA_62_00_10|Unreconciled Transactions for Period] report shows an AP transaction that had been posted to the Accrued Purchases - Fixed Assets account but has not been converted to an asset. [anchor|#section_g4m_dsp_mz]
==2. Convert Any Purchases to Assets ==
((({S:Hint}If you do not have purchases that need to be converted to assets, skip this step.
))){br}

You convert the purchased item to an asset on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\FA_50_45_00|Convert Purchases to Assets] ([~/?ScreenId=FA504500|FA504500]) form, as the screenshot below shows. {br}

[anchor|#fig_mrb_bqp_mz][anchor|#image_wlv_clk_sz][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Closing_Period_in_FA_Step2.png|450px]{br}

For details, see [HelpRoot_Financials\FA__how_Converting_Purchases_to_Assets|To Convert Items to Fixed Assets].[anchor|#section_w5z_fsp_mz]
==3. Release Any Unreleased FA Transactions ==
((({S:Hint}If you do not have unreleased FA transactions, skip this step.
))){br}

You release an individual fixed asset transaction by using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\FA_30_10_00|Fixed Asset Transactions] ([~/?ScreenId=FA301000|FA301000]) form, as the following screenshot shows. On this form, click the reference number of the unreleased document, and on the document entry form that opens, release the document.{br}

[anchor|#fig_w3q_4qp_mz][anchor|#image_gcl_3lk_sz][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Closing_Period_in_FA_Step3.png|450px]{br}

If you have many unreleased documents, you can instead use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\FA_50_30_00|Release FA Transactions] ([~/?ScreenId=FA503000|FA503000]) form, on which you can process multiple transactions simultaneously.{br}

For details, see [HelpRoot_Financials\FA__how_Release_Transactions|To Release a Fixed Asset Transaction] and [HelpRoot_Financials\FA__how_Relase_Multiple_Transactions|To Release Fixed Asset Transactions].[anchor|#section_j5q_lc1_mz]
==4. Depreciate Fixed Assets in the Period to Be Closed==
In this step, you depreciate the fixed assets that should be depreciated in the needed period before closing this period.{br}

On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\FA_50_20_00|Calculate Depreciation] ([~/?ScreenId=FA502000|FA502000]) form, depreciate the fixed assets that the system loads to the table when you specify the needed period. {br}

[anchor|#image_hqm_4kk_sz][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Closing_Period_in_FA_Step4.png|450px]{br}

For details, see [HelpRoot_Financials\FA__con_Depreciation_of_Fixed_Assets|Depreciation of Fixed Assets] and [HelpRoot_Financials\FA__how_Depreciate_assets|To Depreciate an Asset].[anchor|#section_akf_4c1_mz]
==5. Reconcile Fixed Assets with GL Account Balances==
For the period that you need to close, compare the balances of the Fixed Assets and Accumulated Depreciation accounts by using the [HelpRoot_ReportReference\FA_64_30_00|FA Balance by GL Account] ([~/?ScreenId=FA643000|FA643000]) report and the [HelpRoot_ReportReference\GL_63_25_00|Trial Balance Detailed] ([~/?ScreenId=GL632500|GL632500]) report.{br}

[anchor|#image_gpx_wkk_sz][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Closing_Period_in_FA_Step5.png|450px]{br}

Both reports should show the same balances for each Fixed Assets account and Accumulated Depreciation account (and the corresponding subaccounts, if you use them), which means that the balances are reconciled for the needed period.[anchor|#section_ejm_qc1_mz]
==6. Close the Financial Period==
Once all the previous steps have been performed, you can close the needed financial period on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\FA_50_90_00|Close Financial Periods] ([~/?ScreenId=FA509000|FA509000]) form. To do so, if the ''Centralized Period Management'' feature is disabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) form, you select the company in which you want to close the financial period. (If the feature is enabled, the periods will be closed in all the companies within the tenant.) You then select ''Close'' in the '''Action''' box, specify the financial year, select the period that you want to close, and click '''Process''' on the form toolbar. (See the following screenshot.){br}

[anchor|#image_hmq_rkk_sz][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Closing_Period_in_FA_Step6.png|popup|400px]{br}

For the closed period, new assets cannot be acquired, existing assets cannot be disposed of, and depreciation cannot be calculated, even if the '''Restrict Access to Closed Periods''' check box is cleared on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_10_20_00|General Ledger Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=GL102000|GL102000]) form. For details on closing a period, see [HelpRoot_Financials\FA__HOW_To_Close_Financial_Period_in_FA|To Close Financial Periods in Fixed Assets].((({S:Hint}You may need to reopen a period if it has been closed by mistake. To do this, select ''Reopen'' in the '''Action''' box, specify the financial year, select the period that you want to close, and click '''Process''' on the form toolbar. For details, see [HelpRoot_Financials\FA__HOW_To_Reopen_Financial_Period_in_FA|To Reopen a Financial Period in Fixed Assets].
)))
==Related Articles==
*[HelpRoot_Financials\FA__con_Fixed_Asset_Creation|Fixed Asset Entry]
*[HelpRoot_Financials\FA__con_Manual_Creation_of_Fixed_Asset_Transaction|Fixed Asset Adjustment Transactions]
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\FA_50_45_00|Convert Purchases to Assets] ([~/?ScreenId=FA504500|FA504500])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\FA_30_30_00|Fixed Assets] ([~/?ScreenId=FA303000|FA303000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\FA_50_30_00|Release FA Transactions] ([~/?ScreenId=FA503000|FA503000])
*[HelpRoot_Financials\FA__WW_Routines|Daily Routines]]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Closing a Financial Period in the Fixed Assets Subledger You close an open financial period in the fixed assets subledger to prevent                 transactions from being posted to this period, and to be able to close this                 financial period in the general ledger. To close a financial period in the fixed                 assets subledger, you need to perform the steps described in this guide. 1. Make Sure That All Needed Transactions Have Been Converted to Fixed                 Assets For the period to be closed, you need to ensure that all needed transactions that                 have been posted to the FA Accrual account have been converted to fixed assets. To                 check this, generate the   ([~/?ScreenId=FA620010|FA620010]) Unreconciled Transactions for Period (FA620010)                 report. The report shows any transactions posted within the selected period range                 that have not been converted to fixed assets. On this screenshot, the   ([~/?ScreenId=FA620010|FA620010]) Unreconciled Transactions for Period report shows an                 AP transaction that had been posted to the Accrued Purchases - Fixed Assets account                 but has not been converted to an asset.  2. Convert Any Purchases to Assets  If you do not have purchases that need to be converted to assets, skip this                     step. You convert the purchased item to an asset on the   ([~/?ScreenId=FA504500|FA504500]) Convert Purchases to Assets (FA504500) form, as the screenshot                 below shows.  For details, see  To Convert Items to Fixed Assets. 3. Release Any Unreleased FA Transactions  If you do not have unreleased FA transactions, skip this step. You release an individual fixed asset transaction by using the   ([~/?ScreenId=FA301000|FA301000]) Fixed Asset Transactions (FA301000) form, as the following                 screenshot shows. On this form, click the reference number of the unreleased                 document, and on the document entry form that opens, release the document. If you have many unreleased documents, you can instead use the   ([~/?ScreenId=FA503000|FA503000]) Release FA Transactions (FA503000) form, on which you can                 process multiple transactions simultaneously. For details, see  To Release a Fixed Asset Transaction and                      To Release Fixed Asset Transactions. 4. Depreciate Fixed Assets in the Period to Be Closed In this step, you depreciate the fixed assets that should be depreciated in the                 needed period before closing this period. On the   ([~/?ScreenId=FA502000|FA502000]) Calculate Depreciation (FA502000) form, depreciate                 the fixed assets that the system loads to the table when you specify the needed                 period.  For details, see  Depreciation of Fixed Assets and  To Depreciate an Asset. 5. Reconcile Fixed Assets with GL Account Balances For the period that you need to close, compare the balances of the Fixed Assets and                 Accumulated Depreciation accounts by using the   ([~/?ScreenId=FA643000|FA643000]) FA Balance by GL Account (FA643000) report and the   ([~/?ScreenId=GL632500|GL632500]) Trial Balance Detailed (GL632500) report. Both reports should show the same balances for each Fixed Assets account and                 Accumulated Depreciation account (and the corresponding subaccounts, if you use                 them), which means that the balances are reconciled for the needed period. 6. Close the Financial Period Once all the previous steps have been performed, you can close the needed financial                 period on the   ([~/?ScreenId=FA509000|FA509000]) Close Financial Periods (FA509000) form. To do                 so, if the  Centralized Period Management  feature is disabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features (CS100000) form, you select the company                 in which you want to close the financial period. (If the feature is enabled, the                 periods will be closed in all the companies within the tenant.) You then select                      Close  in the  Action  box, specify the financial                 year, select the period that you want to close, and click                      Process  on the form toolbar. (See the following                 screenshot.) For the closed period, new assets cannot be acquired, existing assets cannot be                 disposed of, and depreciation cannot be calculated, even if the  Restrict                     Access to Closed Periods  check box is cleared on the   ([~/?ScreenId=GL102000|GL102000]) General Ledger Preferences (GL102000) form. For details on closing a                 period, see  To Close Financial Periods in Fixed Assets. You may need to reopen a period if it has been closed by mistake. To do this,                 select  Reopen  in the  Action  box, specify the financial                 year, select the period that you want to close, and click                      Process  on the form toolbar. For details, see  To Reopen a Financial Period in Fixed Assets.  ([~/?ScreenId=FA504500|FA504500])  ([~/?ScreenId=FA303000|FA303000])  ([~/?ScreenId=FA503000|FA503000]) ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="87f05154-79d2-40da-99f0-e9395bf495eb" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="1f8b1651-8022-d2b7-ad04-6a5e545df462" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[After all the needed transactions have been posted to a financial period and all figures have been verified, you can close the financial period in the system to prevent users from posting new transactions to this period. To close a financial period in the general ledger, you perform the steps described in this guide.{br}{TOC}[anchor|#_7cf0ef42-0ab7-46f4-b527-ec9b9deb748c]
==1. Optional: Close the Period in the Subledgers==((({S:Hint}Depending on your company&rsquo;s policy, you can skip this step and close the periods in the subledgers and the general ledger at the same time.
)))
A financial period can be closed in the general ledger after if it has been closed in all of the following subledgers that are activated in your system: Accounts Payable, Accounts Receivable, Cash Management, Inventory, and Fixed Assets, or at the same time with the closing it in the general ledger. To check whether the needed period is closed in the subledgers, you open the [HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_50_30_00|Manage Financial Periods] ([~/?ScreenId=GL503000|GL503000]) form and select ''Close'' in the '''Action''' box. For the closed periods, the appropriate check boxes are selected (as shown in the following screenshot).[anchor|#_2f097071-4f96-4059-a38b-3c81726c83db][anchor|#_61094cba-72b8-4aa5-896c-54d0767d09f0][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Closing_Period_in_GL_Step1.png|popup|450px]
If a check box in any column is cleared, this period is open in the respective subledger. [anchor|#_9ec2dc96-bc99-425f-b42f-95ea2b63a43e]
==2. Generate and Post Recurring Transactions==((({S:Hint}If you do not use scheduling for recurring documents, you should skip this step. 
)))
To generate the recurring batch, you specify the last date of the period and when to stop the execution, and then run the schedule on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_50_40_00|Generate Recurring Transactions] ([~/?ScreenId=GL504000|GL504000]) form, as the following screenshot shows.[anchor|#_a8c8ad00-0b6f-4f05-a22f-92b80ab38e03][anchor|#_4381ff64-dc0c-4cb4-b562-86c961e2576a][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Closing_Period_in_GL_Step3.png|popup|450px]
For details, see [HelpRoot_Financials\GL__how_Generating_Recurring_Transactions|To Generate Recurring Transactions for Schedules].{br}

The system generates recurring batches. You release them on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_50_10_00|Release Transactions] ([~/?ScreenId=GL501000|GL501000]) form. If the '''Automatically Post on Release''' check box is selected on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_10_20_00|General Ledger Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=GL102000|GL102000]) form, the system posts the transactions when they are released. If this check box is cleared, you post the transactions on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_50_20_00|Post Transactions] ([~/?ScreenId=GL502000|GL502000]) form. For details, see [HelpRoot_Financials\GL__how_Releasing_Multiple_Batches|To Release Multiple Batches] and [HelpRoot_Financials\GL__how_Posting_Batches|To Post Batches].
==3. Release Any Unreleased General Ledger Transactions ==
On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_50_10_00|Release Transactions] ([~/?ScreenId=GL501000|GL501000]) form, you check whether you have unreleased transactions for the period to be closed. If you have any unreleased transactions, you release them by selecting the necessary transactions and clicking '''Release''' or clicking '''Release All''' on the form toolbar, as the screenshot below shows. [anchor|#_1e14dcfb-9c57-4660-a8f5-f4929be0bcbd][anchor|#_7e857164-4cf4-4383-b5f4-1f0d33ea76fd][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Closing_Period_in_GL_Step2.png|popup|450px]
For details, see [HelpRoot_Financials\GL__how_Releasing_Multiple_Batches|To Release Multiple Batches].{br}

 If the '''Automatically Post on Release''' check box is selected on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_10_20_00|General Ledger Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=GL102000|GL102000]) form, the system posts the transactions on release. If this check box is cleared, you post them as described in the following step.
==4. Release and Post Any Unposted General Ledger Transactions ==
On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_50_20_00|Post Transactions] ([~/?ScreenId=GL502000|GL502000]) form, you check whether you have unposted transactions for the period to be closed. If you have any unposted transactions, you post them by selecting the necessary transactions and clicking '''Post''' or clicking '''Post All''' on the form toolbar, as the screenshot below shows. [anchor|#_3988311a-a010-4b4e-ae06-d704521fef13][anchor|#_2d293866-8dcb-476d-b466-e6f63c186071][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Closing_Period_in_GL_Step3_1.png|popup|450px]
For details, see [HelpRoot_Financials\GL__how_Posting_Batches|To Post Batches].[anchor|#_4513ce34-01c7-43ed-8c7d-8d1428ec5f11]
==5. Revalue General Ledger Accounts Denominated in a Foreign Currency ==
On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CM_50_60_00|Revalue GL Accounts] ([~/?ScreenId=CM506000|CM506000]) form, you perform revaluation for accounts denominated in a foreign currency. You select the period you want to close, the foreign currency associated with the accounts, and specify a description of the revaluation transaction, as the screenshot below shows. ((({S:Hint}The revaluation rate types have to be specified for the denominated accounts on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_20_25_00|Chart of Accounts] ([~/?ScreenId=GL202500|GL202500]) form. If the revaluation rate type has not been specified for a particular account, for revaluation of this account, the system uses the default rate specified in the '''GL Revaluation Rate Type''' box of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CM_10_10_00|Currency Management Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=CM101000|CM101000]) form.
))){br}

The system generates a revaluation batch and opens it on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_30_10_00|Journal Transactions] ([~/?ScreenId=GL301000|GL301000]) form, as shown in the lower part of the screenshot.[anchor|#_61dc2548-5046-4c75-864e-8917c64e489a][anchor|#_9e0096d3-7e68-4c1c-b8fe-0b8e870df4c0][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Closing_Period_in_GL_Step5_1.png|popup|450px]
==6. Review the Account Balances and the List of Transactions, and Reclassify Transactions==
Before closing the financial period, you prepare and review the account balances by using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_40_10_00|Account Summary] ([~/?ScreenId=GL401000|GL401000]) form. On the form, you select the appropriate branch, the ledger, and the financial period to be closed, as the following screenshot shows.[anchor|#_74836e9d-3ec8-4347-855b-a530561999cd][anchor|#_0495b35c-5819-454f-b0d4-81f662bb5157][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Closing_Period_in_GL_Step6_4.png|popup|450px]
To get the list of transactions for a specified account, you use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_40_40_00|Account Details] ([~/?ScreenId=GL404000|GL404000]) form. On the form, you select the appropriate branch, the ledger, the financial period to be closed (in the '''From Period''' and '''To Period''' boxes), and the account.[anchor|#_346be811-afe2-483a-ac5a-e67bd3ace054][anchor|#_3959c668-6728-48a6-8d5c-2b51d6c1599d][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Closing_Period_in_GL_Step6_5.png|popup|450px]
When you review the list of transactions on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_40_40_00|Account Details] form, if you notice that an amount has been posted to the wrong General Ledger account, subaccount, or branch by mistake, you can reclassify any General Ledger transactions. To do this, you select the transactions to be reclassified and click '''Reclassify''' on the form toolbar. (See the screenshot below.) The system navigates to the [HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_50_60_00|Reclassify Transactions] ([~/?ScreenId=GL506000|GL506000]) form, also shown in the following screenshot, where you specify the parameters to be changed (branch, account, or subaccount). [anchor|#_2a26720c-8021-4038-a180-13cacebe65f6][anchor|#_14f41f21-faae-479b-a39f-4531261ef185][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Closing_Period_in_GL_Step6_6.png|popup|450px]
When you click '''Process''' on the form toolbar, the system processes your changes and creates the reclassification batch. You release this batch on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_30_10_00|Journal Transactions] ([~/?ScreenId=GL301000|GL301000]) form, as the following screenshot shows, before you close the financial period in which the transaction is dated.[anchor|#_54587acd-f9d8-4cc1-86b5-29bb84e6ee0b][anchor|#_b93ec223-cf60-4820-af5e-9e71a3a927ab][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Closing_Period_in_GL_Step6_7.png|popup|450px]
For detailed instructions, see [HelpRoot_Financials\GL__how_To_Reclassify_GL_Batch|To Reclassify General Ledger Transactions].[anchor|#_b5c5b8df-bd82-459f-b35b-f5770ec82852]
==7. Optional: Run Allocations==
If amounts that have been accumulated on some of accounts and subaccounts during the period need to be distributed between different accounts and subaccounts based on the previously configured allocation rules, you use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_50_45_00|Run Allocations] ([~/?ScreenId=GL504500|GL504500]) form. On this form, you specify the last date of the period in the '''Allocation Date''' box, select the allocation rules to be run, and click '''Process''' (see the following screenshot).[anchor|#_3dcda42c-264e-4f79-839f-398749f7338e][anchor|#_01f65979-a8b2-4a5f-9baf-ed5c36d55c7c][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Closing_Period_in_GL_Step8.png|popup|450px]
After you have run the allocation process, the system generates batches of the ''Allocation'' type on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_30_10_00|Journal Transactions] ([~/?ScreenId=GL301000|GL301000]) form. To finish the allocation (and then close the period), you have to release and post the generated transactions.[anchor|#_d36adba0-e760-485c-89b4-ae74b4fee5e9]
==8. Close the Period in the General Ledger==
On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_50_30_00|Manage Financial Periods] ([~/?ScreenId=GL503000|GL503000]) form, close the needed financial period. To do so, if the ''Centralized Period Management'' feature is disabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) form, you select the company in which you want to close the financial period. (If the feature is enabled, the periods will be closed in all the companies within the tenant.) You then select ''Close'' in the '''Action''' box, specify the financial year, select the period that you want to close, and click '''Process''' on the form toolbar. (See the following screenshot.)[anchor|#_1144d89b-7e26-4232-a714-155e1694f9d0][anchor|#_61d5d7a0-50e8-413f-8d62-4525f4404b32][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Closing_Period_in_GL_Step9.png|popup|400px]
If the period you are closing has not been closed in the subledgers, when you click '''Process''', the system displays a message that the selected period will be closed in all the subledgers too. Click '''OK''' to confirm the operation.{br}

For details, see [HelpRoot_Financials\GL__HOW_To_Close_Period|To Close Financial Periods].((({S:Hint}You may need to reopen a period if it has been closed by mistake. To do this, select ''Reopen'' in the '''Action''' box, specify the financial year, select the period that you want to close, and click '''Process''' on the form toolbar. For details, see [HelpRoot_Financials\GL__HOW_To_Reopen_Financial_Periods|To Reopen Financial Periods].
)))
==Related Articles==
*[HelpRoot_QG_Financials\QG__Closing_Financial_Period_in_AP_Module|Closing a Financial Period in the Accounts Payable Subledger]
*[HelpRoot_QG_Financials\QG__Closing_Financial_Period_in_AR_Module|Closing a Financial Period in the Accounts Receivable Subledger]
*[HelpRoot_QG_Financials\QG__Closing_Financial_Period_in_CA_Module|Closing a Financial Period in the Cash Management Subledger]
*[HelpRoot_QG_Financials\QG__Closing_Financial_Period_in_FA_Module|Closing a Financial Period in the Fixed Assets Subledger]
*[HelpRoot_Financials\GL__con_Period-End_Closing_Procedures|Closing Periods]
*[HelpRoot_Financials\GL__CON_Period_Closing_Prerequisites|Year-End Closing]
*[HelpRoot_Financials\GL__HOW_To_Close_Period|To Close Financial Periods]
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_50_30_00|Manage Financial Periods] ([~/?ScreenId=GL503000|GL503000])]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Closing a Financial Period in the General Ledger After all the needed transactions have been posted to a             financial period and all figures have been verified, you can close the financial period             in the system to prevent users from posting new transactions to this period. To close a             financial period in the general ledger, you perform the steps described in this             guide. 1. Optional: Close the Period in the Subledgers Depending on your company's policy, you can skip this step and close the periods                 in the subledgers and the general ledger at the same time. A financial period can be closed in the general ledger after if it has been closed in                 all of the following subledgers that are activated in your system: Accounts Payable,                 Accounts Receivable, Cash Management, Inventory, and Fixed Assets, or at the same                 time with the closing it in the general ledger. To check whether the needed period                 is closed in the subledgers, you open the   ([~/?ScreenId=GL503000|GL503000]) Manage Financial Periods (GL503000) form and select  Close  in the  Action  box.                 For the closed periods, the appropriate check boxes are selected (as shown in the                 following screenshot). If a check box in any column is cleared, this period is open in the respective                 subledger.  2. Generate and Post Recurring Transactions If you do not use scheduling for recurring documents, you should skip this step.  To generate the recurring batch, you specify the last date of the period and when to                 stop the execution, and then run the schedule on the   ([~/?ScreenId=GL504000|GL504000]) Generate Recurring Transactions (GL504000) form, as the following                 screenshot shows. For details, see  To Generate Recurring Transactions for Schedules. The system generates recurring batches. You release them on the   ([~/?ScreenId=GL501000|GL501000]) Release Transactions (GL501000) form. If the                      Automatically Post on Release  check box is selected on                 the   ([~/?ScreenId=GL102000|GL102000]) General Ledger Preferences (GL102000) form, the system posts                 the transactions when they are released. If this check box is cleared, you post the                 transactions on the   ([~/?ScreenId=GL502000|GL502000]) Post Transactions (GL502000) form.                 For details, see  To Release Multiple Batches                 and  To Post Batches. 3. Release Any Unreleased General Ledger Transactions  On the   ([~/?ScreenId=GL501000|GL501000]) Release Transactions (GL501000) form, you check                 whether you have unreleased transactions for the period to be closed. If you have                 any unreleased transactions, you release them by selecting the necessary                 transactions and clicking  Release  or clicking  Release                     All  on the form toolbar, as the screenshot below shows.  For details, see  To Release Multiple Batches.  If the  Automatically Post on Release  check box is selected on                 the   ([~/?ScreenId=GL102000|GL102000]) General Ledger Preferences (GL102000) form, the system posts                 the transactions on release. If this check box is cleared, you post them as                 described in the following step. 4. Release and Post Any Unposted General Ledger Transactions  On the   ([~/?ScreenId=GL502000|GL502000]) Post Transactions (GL502000) form, you check                 whether you have unposted transactions for the period to be closed. If you have any                 unposted transactions, you post them by selecting the necessary transactions and                 clicking  Post  or clicking  Post All  on the form                 toolbar, as the screenshot below shows.  For details, see  To Post Batches. 5. Revalue General Ledger Accounts Denominated in a Foreign Currency  On the   ([~/?ScreenId=CM506000|CM506000]) Revalue GL Accounts (CM506000) form, you perform                 revaluation for accounts denominated in a foreign currency. You select the period                 you want to close, the foreign currency associated with the accounts, and specify a                 description of the revaluation transaction, as the screenshot below shows.  The                     revaluation rate types have to be specified for the denominated accounts on the                           ([~/?ScreenId=GL202500|GL202500]) Chart of Accounts (GL202500) form. If the                     revaluation rate type has not been specified for a particular account, for                     revaluation of this account, the system uses the default rate specified in the                          GL Revaluation Rate Type  box of the   ([~/?ScreenId=CM101000|CM101000]) Currency Management Preferences (CM101000) form. The system generates a revaluation batch and opens it on the   ([~/?ScreenId=GL301000|GL301000]) Journal Transactions (GL301000) form, as shown in the lower                 part of the screenshot. 6. Review the Account Balances and the List of Transactions, and Reclassify                 Transactions Before closing the financial period, you prepare and review the account balances by                 using the   ([~/?ScreenId=GL401000|GL401000]) Account Summary (GL401000) form. On the                 form, you select the appropriate branch, the ledger, and the financial period to be                 closed, as the following screenshot shows. To get the list of transactions for a specified account, you use the   ([~/?ScreenId=GL404000|GL404000]) Account Details (GL404000) form. On the form, you                 select the appropriate branch, the ledger, the financial period to be closed (in the                      From Period  and  To Period  boxes),                 and the account. When you review the list of transactions on the   ([~/?ScreenId=GL404000|GL404000]) Account Details form, if you notice that an amount has                 been posted to the wrong General Ledger account, subaccount, or branch by mistake,                 you can reclassify any General Ledger transactions. To do this, you select the                 transactions to be reclassified and click  Reclassify  on the                 form toolbar. (See the screenshot below.) The system navigates to the   ([~/?ScreenId=GL506000|GL506000]) Reclassify Transactions (GL506000) form, also shown in the                 following screenshot, where you specify the parameters to be changed (branch,                 account, or subaccount).  When you click  Process  on the form toolbar, the system                 processes your changes and creates the reclassification batch. You release this                 batch on the   ([~/?ScreenId=GL301000|GL301000]) Journal Transactions (GL301000) form, as the                 following screenshot shows, before you close the financial period in which the                 transaction is dated. For detailed instructions, see  To Reclassify General Ledger Transactions. 7. Optional: Run Allocations If amounts that have been accumulated on some of accounts and subaccounts during the                 period need to be distributed between different accounts and subaccounts based on                 the previously configured allocation rules, you use the   ([~/?ScreenId=GL504500|GL504500]) Run Allocations (GL504500) form. On this form, you                 specify the last date of the period in the  Allocation Date                  box, select the allocation rules to be run, and click  Process                  (see the following screenshot). After you have run the allocation process, the system generates batches of the                      Allocation  type on the   ([~/?ScreenId=GL301000|GL301000]) Journal Transactions                 (GL301000) form. To finish the allocation (and then close the period), you have                 to release and post the generated transactions. 8. Close the Period in the General Ledger On the   ([~/?ScreenId=GL503000|GL503000]) Manage Financial Periods (GL503000) form, close the needed                 financial period. To do so, if the  Centralized Period Management  feature is                 disabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features (CS100000) form, you                 select the company in which you want to close the financial period. (If the feature                 is enabled, the periods will be closed in all the companies within the tenant.) You                 then select  Close  in the  Action  box, specify the                 financial year, select the period that you want to close, and click                      Process  on the form toolbar. (See the following                 screenshot.) If the period you are closing has not been closed in the subledgers, when you click                      Process , the system displays a message that the selected                 period will be closed in all the subledgers too. Click  OK  to                 confirm the operation. For details, see  To Close Financial Periods. You may need to reopen a period if it has been closed by mistake. To do this,                 select  Reopen  in the  Action  box, specify the financial                 year, select the period that you want to close, and click                      Process  on the form toolbar. For details, see  To Reopen Financial Periods.  ([~/?ScreenId=GL503000|GL503000]) ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="4422bbca-8086-454b-8f88-740467a221b3" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="4554f52d-2e86-a5cb-b58e-1752b872d9e7" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
In Acumatica ERP, for reporting purposes, you may need to restate account balances from the base currency (or a foreign currency) to any foreign currency configured for use in the system—that is, perform a translation from one currency to another.{br}

To prepare the translation, you need to perform the steps described in this guide.{br}{TOC}
==Before You Proceed==
[anchor|#_6e0ff39a-22a1-4f47-a832-3afe0416be87]
*Make sure that the ''Translation of Financial Statements'' feature is enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) form.
*Ensure that a ledger of the ''Reporting'' type has been created for translations on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_20_15_00|Ledgers] ([~/?ScreenId=GL201500|GL201500]) form and that the currency to which you need to translate account balances is assigned to the ledger. For details on how to create a ''Reporting'' ledger, see [HelpRoot_Financials\GL__HOW_To_Add_Reporting_Ledger|To Add a Reporting Ledger].
*Make sure that the necessary currency rate types for translation have been created in the system on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CM_20_10_00|Currency Rate Types] ([~/?ScreenId=CM201000|CM201000]) form. For instructions on creating a rate type, see [HelpRoot_Financials\CM__how_To_Create_Rate_Type|To Create a Rate Type].
*Be sure that the necessary accounts (and subaccounts, if they are used in your system) are specified for the currency you are planning to translate account balances to in the '''Translation Gain and Loss Accounts''' section of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CM_20_20_00|Currencies] ([~/?ScreenId=CM202000|CM202000]) form.
*If you are performing a translation for the second period defined in the system or any later period, make sure that the translations for the previous periods have been completed.
[anchor|#_e54315f8-1277-431f-9627-82aef1d98532]
==1. Configure a Translation Definition==
((({S:Hint}If a translation definition that meets your requirements has already been configured, you can skip this step.
))){br}

To perform a translation in the system, you create a translation definition on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CM_20_30_00|Translation Definition] ([~/?ScreenId=CM203000|CM203000]) form. On this form, you define the source and destination ledgers, the accounts to be translated, and the rules to be used for translation. (For an example of a configured translation, see the screenshot below.) For details, see [HelpRoot_Financials\CM__HOW_To_Configure_Translation_Definition|To Configure a Translation Definition].{br}

((({S:Warn} In this guide, you will see sample settings that are needed for translation. These sample settings are presented to illustrate the process of configuring translations. In your system, you have to configure the translation based on the legal requirements and business requirements of your company.
)))[anchor|#_465d52f0-962e-42b0-9d99-b6d611f36114][anchor|#_7d34f916-1319-47a6-b78d-af36043cf38a][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Translating_to_FX_Step1.png|popup|450px]
((({S:Hint}[anchor|#_0d34797d-15db-4736-9131-725350f67333]
*The ''YTD Net Income'' account should not be included in the translation definition, because the balance of this account is calculated based on the translated balances of income and expense accounts.
*On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CM_10_10_00|Currency Management Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=CM101000|CM101000]) form, in the '''Default Translation ID''' box, you can specify the translation definition that will be used by default.
)))[anchor|#_92be7e9e-a233-408c-9513-b4fc588fb230]
==2. Define the Currency Rates That Are Effective on the Date of Translation==
On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CM_30_10_00|Currency Rates] ([~/?ScreenId=CM301000|CM301000]) form, you need to define the currency rates from the currency of the account to be converted to the reporting currency that will be effective on the date of translation. In the screenshot below, you can see the defined currency rates that can be used for translations of different types from the United States dollar (USD) to the euro (EUR); these rates have been effective since April 30, 2017.[anchor|#_a7570d34-3e4c-4b68-b090-53947153b69a][anchor|#_0efb1049-b6fc-40e5-a316-e1dfd95869b2][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Translating_to_FX_Step2.png|popup|450px]
((({S:Hint}Even if you had EUR-to-USD rates of the needed rate types entered into the system that were effective on the date of translation, the system would not use the reciprocal EUR-to-USD rate for performing translations from USD to EUR. To perform the translation, you always have to first define the currency rates from the currency of the account to be converted to reporting currency.
))){br}

For details on how to define currency rates, see [HelpRoot_Financials\CM__how_To_Add_Currency_Rate|To Add a Currency Rate].[anchor|#_bb1acaa1-dddd-45e0-860e-ceb09f68ee5f]
==3. Prepare the Translation==
On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CM_50_10_00|Prepare Translation] ([~/?ScreenId=CM501000|CM501000]) form, you prepare the translation by specifying the financial period for which the translation will be performed and the translation definition to be used for translation (in the '''Translation ID''' box), as shown in the following screenshot.{br}

After you have specified the necessary information, you click '''Create Translation''' on the form toolbar to create a translation worksheet in the system. The [HelpRoot_FormReference\CM_30_40_00|Translation Worksheets] ([~/?ScreenId=CM304000|CM304000]) form opens with the translation worksheet the system has created.[anchor|#_0cc1933c-86d0-43a4-a9b5-6fd50a0713e1][anchor|#_2469f07e-a355-429f-9400-54f79b8d88d1][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Translating_to_FX_Step3.png|popup|450px]
For details, see [HelpRoot_Financials\CM__HOW_To_Translate_Financial_Statements|To Translate Financial Statements].[anchor|#_49b32860-e6cf-41a3-bd8f-9f9bb6b2862f]
==4. Review and Release the Translation Worksheet==
You review the prepared translation worksheet on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CM_30_40_00|Translation Worksheets] ([~/?ScreenId=CM304000|CM304000]) form (see the screenshot below). The system has translated the account balances by using the exchange rates of the appropriate type and the rules of translation specified in the translation definition. The '''Source Amount''' column shows the amount to be translated: the PTD balance for the accounts translated with the ''PTD Balance'' method, and the ending balance for the period for the accounts translated with the ''YTD Balance'' method. The '''Translated Amount''' column shows the result of the translation of the source amount with the specified currency rate and translation method.{br}

If you need to, you can modify the amounts in the '''Transaction Debit Amount''' and '''Transaction Credit Amount''' columns—that is, the amounts that will be posted to the reporting ledger. Also, if the translation worksheet is incorrect, you can delete it before release and prepare it again (after the exchange rates and the amounts in the source ledger have been corrected).{br}

After you are sure that everything is correct, you release the translation worksheet by clicking '''Release''' on the form toolbar (also shown in the following screenshot).[anchor|#_fcca46d5-64db-4459-bdd3-a2cba2b09295][anchor|#_9f189895-3f68-40c3-b956-583d3cd1d811][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Translating_to_FX_Step4.png|popup|450px]
The system creates a translation batch, which number you can see in the '''Translation Batch Num.''' box.[anchor|#_a5ff3e59-b06d-4ce4-a1cb-aa7c2a70efa6]
==5. Post the Batch That Was Generated in the General Ledger Module==
((({S:Hint}If the '''Automatically Post to GL on Release''' check box is selected on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CM_10_10_00|Currency Management Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=CM101000|CM101000]) form, the batch has been posted automatically to the General Ledger module when it was released and you can skip this step.
))){br}

To post the batch, you use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_50_20_00|Post Transactions] ([~/?ScreenId=GL502000|GL502000]) form. After you post the batch, the system changes its status to ''Posted'', as shown in the following screenshot. For details, see [HelpRoot_Financials\GL__how_Posting_Batches|To Post Batches].[anchor|#_b0e2a385-c916-424c-9c3c-cfc84cc30f00][anchor|#_e160b266-d30c-4edc-ac77-2902681721e6][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Translating_to_FX_Step5_2.png|popup|450px][anchor|#_ff1a4a52-6c13-42fc-8de5-002fcf35fa3a][anchor|#_47008177-e217-4cc9-89d2-75ab6dc62228]
==6. Review the Account Balances in the Reporting Ledger==
The destination reporting ledger now contains account balances translated to the foreign currency, and you can use it for preparing financial statements and other reports in this currency for the period for which the translation has been performed. {br}

You review the translated account balances for the ledger and period by using [HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_40_10_00|Account Summary] ([~/?ScreenId=GL401000|GL401000]) form, shown in the following screenshot.[anchor|#_39134da8-e2e6-4c58-9890-b4180ec48a29][anchor|#_6a3c4e0e-4241-402f-b82c-f5163411aa8b][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Translating_to_FX_Step6.png|popup|450px]
==Related Articles==
*[HelpRoot_Financials\CM__con_Creation_of_Translation_Definitions|Creation of Translation Definitions]
*[HelpRoot_Financials\CM__con_Multiple_Currency_Rates|Entry of Currency Rates]
*[HelpRoot_Financials\CM__con_Overview_of_Translations|Translation Processing Workflow]
*[HelpRoot_Financials\CM__con_Currency_Rate_Type_Setup|Currency Rate Type Creation]
*[HelpRoot_Financials\CM__how_To_Add_Currency_Rate|To Add a Currency Rate]
*[HelpRoot_Financials\GL__HOW_To_Add_Reporting_Ledger|To Add a Reporting Ledger]
*[HelpRoot_Financials\CM__HOW_To_Configure_Translation_Definition|To Configure a Translation Definition]
*[HelpRoot_Financials\CM__how_To_Create_Rate_Type|To Create a Rate Type]
*[HelpRoot_Financials\GL__how_Posting_Batches|To Post Batches]
*[HelpRoot_Financials\CM__HOW_To_Translate_Financial_Statements|To Translate Financial Statements]
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_40_10_00|Account Summary] ([~/?ScreenId=GL401000|GL401000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\CM_20_10_00|Currency Rate Types] ([~/?ScreenId=CM201000|CM201000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\CM_30_10_00|Currency Rates] ([~/?ScreenId=CM301000|CM301000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\CM_20_20_00|Currencies] ([~/?ScreenId=CM202000|CM202000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_30_10_00|Journal Transactions] ([~/?ScreenId=GL301000|GL301000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_20_15_00|Ledgers] ([~/?ScreenId=GL201500|GL201500])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_50_20_00|Post Transactions] ([~/?ScreenId=GL502000|GL502000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\CM_50_10_00|Prepare Translation] ([~/?ScreenId=CM501000|CM501000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\CM_30_40_00|Translation Worksheets] ([~/?ScreenId=CM304000|CM304000])]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Translating from One Currency to Another In  Acumatica ERP, for reporting purposes, you may need to restate account balances from the base                 currency (or a foreign currency) to any foreign currency configured for use in the                 system—that is, perform a translation from one currency to another. To prepare the translation, you need to perform the steps described in this                 guide. Before You Proceed Make sure that the  Translation of Financial Statements  feature is                         enabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features (CS100000)                         form. Ensure that a ledger of the  Reporting  type has been created for                         translations on the   ([~/?ScreenId=GL201500|GL201500]) Ledgers                         (GL201500) form and that the currency to which you need to translate                         account balances is assigned to the ledger. For details on how to create a                              Reporting  ledger, see  To Add a Reporting Ledger. Make sure that the necessary currency rate types for translation have been                         created in the system on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CM201000|CM201000]) Currency Rate Types                         (CM201000) form. For instructions on creating a rate type, see  To Create a Rate Type. Be sure that the necessary accounts (and subaccounts, if they are used in                         your system) are specified for the currency you are planning to translate                         account balances to in the  Translation Gain and Loss                             Accounts  section of the   ([~/?ScreenId=CM202000|CM202000]) Currencies (CM202000) form. If you are performing a translation for the second period defined in the                         system or any later period, make sure that the translations for the previous                         periods have been completed. 1. Configure a Translation Definition If a translation definition that meets your requirements has already been                     configured, you can skip this step. To perform a translation in the system, you create a translation definition on the                       ([~/?ScreenId=CM203000|CM203000]) Translation Definition (CM203000) form. On this form,                 you define the source and destination ledgers, the accounts to be translated, and                 the rules to be used for translation. (For an example of a configured translation,                 see the screenshot below.) For details, see  To Configure a Translation Definition.  In this guide, you will see sample settings that are needed                     for translation. These sample settings are presented to illustrate the process                     of configuring translations. In your system, you have to configure the                     translation based on the legal requirements and business requirements of your                     company. The  YTD Net Income  account should not be included in the                             translation definition, because the balance of this account is                             calculated based on the translated balances of income and expense                             accounts. On the   ([~/?ScreenId=CM101000|CM101000]) Currency Management Preferences (CM101000) form,                             in the  Default Translation ID  box, you can                             specify the translation definition that will be used by default. 2. Define the Currency Rates That Are Effective on the Date of                 Translation On the   ([~/?ScreenId=CM301000|CM301000]) Currency Rates (CM301000) form, you need to                 define the currency rates from the currency of the account to be converted to the                 reporting currency that will be effective on the date of translation. In the                 screenshot below, you can see the defined currency rates that can be used for                 translations of different types from the United States dollar (USD) to the euro                 (EUR); these rates have been effective since April 30, 2017. Even if you had EUR-to-USD rates of the needed rate types entered into the                     system that were effective on the date of translation, the system would not use                     the reciprocal EUR-to-USD rate for performing translations from USD to EUR. To                     perform the translation, you always have to first define the currency rates from                     the currency of the account to be converted to reporting currency. For details on how to define currency rates, see  To Add a Currency Rate. 3. Prepare the Translation On the   ([~/?ScreenId=CM501000|CM501000]) Prepare Translation (CM501000) form, you prepare                 the translation by specifying the financial period for which the translation will be                 performed and the translation definition to be used for translation (in the                      Translation ID  box), as shown in the following                 screenshot. After you have specified the necessary information, you click  Create                     Translation  on the form toolbar to create a translation worksheet in                 the system. The   ([~/?ScreenId=CM304000|CM304000]) Translation Worksheets (CM304000) form                 opens with the translation worksheet the system has created. For details, see  To Translate Financial Statements. 4. Review and Release the Translation Worksheet You review the prepared translation worksheet on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CM304000|CM304000]) Translation Worksheets (CM304000) form (see the screenshot                 below). The system has translated the account balances by using the exchange rates                 of the appropriate type and the rules of translation specified in the translation                 definition. The  Source Amount  column shows the amount to be                 translated: the PTD balance for the accounts translated with the  PTD Balance                  method, and the ending balance for the period for the accounts translated with the                      YTD Balance  method. The  Translated Amount  column                 shows the result of the translation of the source amount with the specified currency                 rate and translation method. If you need to, you can modify the amounts in the  Transaction Debit                     Amount  and  Transaction Credit Amount                  columns—that is, the amounts that will be posted to the reporting ledger.                 Also, if the translation worksheet is incorrect, you can delete it before release                 and prepare it again (after the exchange rates and the amounts in the source ledger                 have been corrected). After you are sure that everything is correct, you release the translation worksheet                 by clicking  Release  on the form toolbar (also shown in the                 following screenshot). The system creates a translation batch, which number you can see in the                      Translation Batch Num.  box. 5. Post the Batch That Was Generated in the General Ledger Module If the  Automatically Post to GL on Release  check box is                     selected on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CM101000|CM101000]) Currency Management Preferences (CM101000) form,                     the batch has been posted automatically to the General Ledger module when it was                     released and you can skip this step. To                 post the batch, you use the   ([~/?ScreenId=GL502000|GL502000]) Post Transactions                 (GL502000) form. After you post the batch, the system changes its status to                      Posted , as shown in the following screenshot. For details, see  To Post Batches. 6. Review the Account Balances in the                 Reporting Ledger The destination reporting ledger now contains account balances translated to the                 foreign currency, and you can use it for preparing financial statements and other                 reports in this currency for the period for which the translation has been                 performed.  You review the translated account balances for the ledger and period by using   ([~/?ScreenId=GL401000|GL401000]) Account Summary (GL401000) form, shown in the                 following screenshot.  ([~/?ScreenId=GL401000|GL401000])  ([~/?ScreenId=CM201000|CM201000])  ([~/?ScreenId=CM301000|CM301000])  ([~/?ScreenId=CM202000|CM202000])  ([~/?ScreenId=GL301000|GL301000])  ([~/?ScreenId=GL201500|GL201500])  ([~/?ScreenId=GL502000|GL502000])  ([~/?ScreenId=CM501000|CM501000])  ([~/?ScreenId=CM304000|CM304000]) ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="053ba27f-be94-4bf4-bb41-09e9eb0a56b7" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="1c2ffe49-9a3a-750d-481c-55e0d1982be3" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[You perform a bank reconciliation to find discrepancies between account balances tracked by your company and a bank, locate any errors, and make needed corrections or adjustments. To reconcile bank statements, you need to perform the steps described in this guide.{br}{TOC}[anchor|#_53ceba4b-4340-456d-b4ea-141d86873170]
==1. Configure the Cash Account for Uploading Bank Statements==((({S:Hint}You need to configure a cash account only when you perform the reconciliation for a first time. If you have already configured the cash account for bank statement upload, you can skip this step.
)))
To configure a cash account to upload a bank statement to it, you have to specify the identifier of the account in the bank statement and specify the bank statement upload settings for the Cash Management module. You specify the bank account number in the '''External Ref. Number''' box, and the application service that reads the data being imported in the '''Statement Import Service''' box on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CA_20_20_00|Cash Accounts] ([~/?ScreenId=CA202000|CA202000]) form, as shown in the following screenshot.((({S:Hint}In this guide, a bank statement is uploaded from a file of the OFX format. For OFX files, PX.Objects.CA.OFXStatementReader is the service for importing bank statements, and the bank account number is specified in &lt;ACCTID&gt; in the file.
)))[anchor|#_fcc2ef86-c8d4-4195-b5d3-e31099070454][anchor|#_96f17850-b011-4da2-95b8-ff5b17550c46][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Reconciling_Bank_Statements_Step1_1.png|popup|450px]
On the '''Bank Statement Settings''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CA_10_10_00|Cash Management Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=CA101000|CA101000]) form, to import statements to one cash account, you select the '''Import Bank statement to Single Cash Account''' check box, as shown in the screenshot below.[anchor|#_61fd0b48-dc49-4497-8bb6-911e804400b9][anchor|#_80c2fe7a-61ef-4bb1-8bf4-7ce47e7d5a0c][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Reconciling_Bank_Statements_Step1_2.png|popup|350px]((({S:Hint}In this guide, one statement is imported for a single cash account. If you import statements for multiple cash accounts from one file, you need to clear the '''Import Bank Statement to Single Cash Account''' check box and specify the '''Statement Import Service''' setting on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CA_10_10_00|Cash Management Preferences] form.
)))[anchor|#_8c55b862-d4ac-4a51-bd15-0a4f3b93cfdb]
==2. Upload the Bank Statement==((({S:Hint}We recommend that you perform Steps 2 through 4 every day.
)))
You upload a bank statement by clicking '''Upload File''' on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CA_30_65_00|Import Bank Transactions] ([~/?ScreenId=CA306500|CA306500]) form, and selecting a file to be uploaded in the '''Statement File Upload''' dialog box, as the following screenshot shows. After you click '''Upload''' in the dialog box, the system uploads the transactions from the file to the bank statement in the system. For the first imported bank statement, if the file format doesn&rsquo;t provide the beginning balance in bank statements, you specify the beginning balance of the statement in the '''Beginning Balance''' box.((({S:Hint} In each subsequent statement, the system uses as the beginning balance the ending balance of the previous bank statement.
)))[anchor|#_a378a238-9234-49cf-b2fb-c9d37c1a7a50][anchor|#_db5aef16-0dad-4f75-bf3f-180520df3fa8][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Reconciling_Bank_Statements_Step2.png|popup|450px]
For details, see [HelpRoot_Financials\CA__HOW_ImportBankSatement_OFX|To Import a Bank Statement in OFX, QBO, and QFX Formats] and [HelpRoot_Financials\CA__how_to_Import_Statement|To Import a Bank Statement in Excel].[anchor|#_bb180b23-aecd-4ba3-b542-ef052dda3e79]
==3. Match the Bank Transactions to the Existing Documents or Transactions in the System==
You match transactions for the account to which the bank statement is uploaded on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CA_30_60_00|Process Bank Transactions] ([~/?ScreenId=CA306000|CA306000]) form. The left pane displays the not-yet-processed transactions imported from bank statements; you need to review these transactions. The tabs on the right pane show the possible matches for bank transactions. By clicking '''Auto-Match''' on the form toolbar, you run the auto-matching process for the bank transactions so the system searches for possible matching payments and for documents to which the payment could apply, as shown in the following screenshot.[anchor|#_97dbbf9f-a52b-4110-8c6e-423499fdc05f][anchor|#_ef4609f1-7ce5-4a0c-82ae-b89f03e571bf][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Reconciling_Bank_Statements_Step3.png|popup|450px]
For details, see [HelpRoot_Financials\CA__How_to_Match_Transactions_I|To Match Transactions].[anchor|#_8ed194ec-e642-4adc-93e6-2dd5b5ecd9d0]
==4. Specify Details of Documents in the System Based on the Bank Transactions==
On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CA_30_60_00|Process Bank Transactions] ([~/?ScreenId=CA306000|CA306000]) form, for the bank transactions that have no matches to any transaction that exists in the system, you can specify details of documents that will be created during processing of transactions. To do so, you select a transaction that is marked as not matched (as shown in the left pane below), and create a document on the '''Create Payment''' tab (as shown in the right pane below). [anchor|#_0b8e26eb-5328-44fe-9ffa-60924e4f5ecf][anchor|#_dc8563fc-8509-47f3-8091-f29112551d5f][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Reconciling_Bank_Statements_Step4.png|popup|450px][anchor|#_5e4a2e02-3c3f-4d3e-aa42-4d40c3e46ae0]
==5. Process Bank Transactions==
You initiate the processing of transactions on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CA_30_60_00|Process Bank Transactions] ([~/?ScreenId=CA306000|CA306000]) form, as shown in the following screenshot.[anchor|#_556b87dd-4f14-4eb1-ac97-9fa8aa5c2945][anchor|#_eb6e2061-d5a2-4635-b5e6-939b7f5ea579][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Reconciling_Bank_Statements_Step5.png|popup|450px]
The system creates the documents and transactions based on the bank transactions for which you have specified the information, releases them, and selects the read-only '''Cleared''' check box for every created document and transaction.((({S:Hint}You cannot revert or change results related to creation of new payments.
)))
You can see the transactions of the bank statement that have been processed on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CA_30_65_00|Import Bank Transactions] ([~/?ScreenId=CA306500|CA306500]) form, as shown in the following screenshot. The '''Processed''' check box is selected for the transactions that were processed.[anchor|#_f4e63fad-06c4-423b-8ca2-914ad2389925][anchor|#_c7fdbdf6-47a3-4a67-967e-c1abf81b8d14][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Reconciling_Bank_Statements_Step5_2.png|popup|450px][anchor|#_5c7645b1-c1d5-4fe6-aca7-796c2d33eddc]
==6. Prepare the Reconciliation Statement for the Bank Statement Period==((({S:Hint}You perform this step at the end of each financial period.
)))
You prepare a reconciliation statement on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CA_30_20_00|Reconciliation Statements] ([~/?ScreenId=CA302000|CA302000]) form. You specify the cash account for bank statement, the reconciliation date, and the statement balance. In the table, you then select the '''Reconciled '''check box for the transactions that have the '''Cleared '''check box selected, as the following screenshot shows. Finally, you click '''Release''' to release the bank statement.[anchor|#_a5777a31-1834-4ea1-81fd-fb135554b9f6][anchor|#_30a9c79f-f7b3-4e3b-bfb1-67c5c2e35d9e][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Reconciling_Bank_Statements_Step6.png|popup|450px]
For details, see [HelpRoot_Financials\CA__HOW_PerformReconciliation|To Perform Reconciliation].
==Related Articles==
*[HelpRoot_Financials\CA__CON_BatchPaymentsMatching|Batch Payment Matching]
*[HelpRoot_Financials\CA__CON_ReconcilingTransactions|Reconciliation Process]
*[HelpRoot_Financials\CA__CON_BankTran_MatchingSettings|Transaction Matching Settings]
*[HelpRoot_Financials\CA__HOW_ImportBankSatement_OFX|To Import a Bank Statement in OFX, QBO, and QFX Formats]
*[HelpRoot_Financials\CA__how_to_Import_Statement|To Import a Bank Statement in Excel]
*[HelpRoot_Financials\CA__HOW_PerformReconciliation|To Perform Reconciliation]
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\CA_20_20_00|Cash Accounts] ([~/?ScreenId=CA202000|CA202000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\CA_10_10_00|Cash Management Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=CA101000|CA101000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\CA_30_65_00|Import Bank Transactions] ([~/?ScreenId=CA306500|CA306500])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\CA_30_60_00|Process Bank Transactions] ([~/?ScreenId=CA306000|CA306000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\CA_30_20_00|Reconciliation Statements] ([~/?ScreenId=CA302000|CA302000])]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Reconciling Bank Statements You perform a bank reconciliation to find discrepancies             between account balances tracked by your company and a bank, locate any errors, and make             needed corrections or adjustments. To reconcile bank statements, you need to perform the             steps described in this guide. 1. Configure the Cash Account for Uploading Bank Statements You need to configure a cash account only when you perform the reconciliation for                 a first time. If you have already configured the cash account for bank statement                 upload, you can skip this step. To configure a cash account to upload a bank statement to it, you have to specify the                 identifier of the account in the bank statement and specify the bank statement                 upload settings for the Cash Management module. You specify the bank account number                  in the  External Ref.                     Number  box, and the application service that reads the data being                 imported in the  Statement Import Service  box on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CA202000|CA202000]) Cash Accounts (CA202000) form, as shown in the                 following screenshot. In this guide, a bank statement is uploaded from a file of the OFX format. For OFX                 files, PX.Objects.CA.OFXStatementReader is the service for importing bank                 statements, and the bank account number is specified in <ACCTID> in the                 file. On the  Bank Statement Settings  tab of the    ([~/?ScreenId=CA101000|CA101000]) Cash Management Preferences (CA101000) form, to import statements                 to one cash account, you select the  Import Bank statement to Single Cash                     Account  check box, as shown in the screenshot below. In this guide, one statement is imported for a single cash account. If you import                 statements for multiple cash accounts from one file, you need to clear the                      Import Bank Statement to Single Cash Account  check box                 and specify the  Statement Import Service  setting on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CA101000|CA101000]) Cash Management Preferences form. 2. Upload the Bank Statement We recommend that you perform Steps 2 through 4 every day. You upload a bank statement by clicking  Upload File  on the                       ([~/?ScreenId=CA306500|CA306500]) Import Bank Transactions (CA306500) form, and selecting a                 file to be uploaded in the  Statement File Upload  dialog box,                 as the following screenshot shows. After you click  Upload  in                 the dialog box, the system uploads the transactions from the file to the bank                 statement in the system. For the first imported bank statement, if the file format                 doesn't provide the beginning balance in bank statements, you specify the beginning                 balance of the statement in the  Beginning Balance  box.  In each subsequent statement, the system uses as the beginning balance the ending                 balance of the previous bank statement. For details, see  To Import a Bank Statement in OFX, QBO, and QFX Formats and                      To Import a Bank Statement in Excel. 3. Match the Bank Transactions to the Existing Documents or Transactions in the                 System You match transactions for the account to which the bank statement is uploaded on the                       ([~/?ScreenId=CA306000|CA306000]) Process Bank Transactions (CA306000) form. The left pane                 displays the not-yet-processed transactions imported from bank statements; you need                 to review these transactions. The tabs on the right pane show the possible matches                 for bank transactions. By clicking  Auto-Match  on the form                 toolbar, you run the auto-matching process for the bank transactions so the system                 searches for possible matching payments and for documents to which the payment could                 apply, as shown in the following screenshot. For details, see  To Match Transactions. 4. Specify Details of Documents in the System Based on the Bank                 Transactions On the   ([~/?ScreenId=CA306000|CA306000]) Process Bank Transactions (CA306000) form, for the bank                 transactions that have no matches to any transaction that exists in the system, you                 can specify details of documents that will be created during processing of                 transactions. To do so, you select a transaction that is marked as not matched (as                 shown in the left pane below), and create a document on the  Create                     Payment  tab (as shown in the right pane below).                  5. Process Bank Transactions You initiate the processing of transactions on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CA306000|CA306000]) Process Bank Transactions (CA306000) form, as shown in the                 following screenshot. The system creates the documents and transactions based on the bank transactions for                 which you have specified the information, releases them, and selects the read-only                      Cleared  check box for every created document and                 transaction. You cannot revert or change results related to creation of new payments. You can see the transactions of the bank statement that have been processed on the                       ([~/?ScreenId=CA306500|CA306500]) Import Bank Transactions (CA306500) form, as shown in the                 following screenshot. The  Processed  check box is selected for                 the transactions that were processed. 6. Prepare the Reconciliation Statement for the Bank Statement Period You perform this step at the end of each financial period. You prepare a reconciliation statement on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CA302000|CA302000]) Reconciliation Statements (CA302000) form. You specify the cash                 account for bank statement, the reconciliation date, and the statement balance. In                 the table, you then select the  Reconciled  check box for the                 transactions that have the  Cleared  check box selected, as the                 following screenshot shows. Finally, you click  Release  to                 release the bank statement. For details, see  To Perform Reconciliation.  ([~/?ScreenId=CA202000|CA202000])  ([~/?ScreenId=CA101000|CA101000])  ([~/?ScreenId=CA306500|CA306500])  ([~/?ScreenId=CA306000|CA306000])  ([~/?ScreenId=CA302000|CA302000]) ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="bb07e030-3686-4f39-b648-27d025b33a55" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="23fd6ce1-9c4d-2882-8fd9-1ff5b1b84d65" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
In Acumatica ERP, you can prepare a tax report for a particular tax agency. To prepare this tax report for an open or closed reporting period, you perform the steps described in this guide.{br}{TOC}
==Before You Proceed==
Before you start preparing a tax report for a needed tax agency, make sure that:[anchor|#ul_tyv_yzp_41b]
*The required tax agency has been configured on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_30_00|Vendors] ([~/?ScreenId=AP303000|AP303000]) form.
*The required tax report has been configured in the system.
*All required taxes (that is, those to be reported on) have been created in the system with the tax agency specified on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\TX_20_50_00|Taxes] ([~/?ScreenId=TX205000|TX205000]) form.
*All taxable documents related to the period being closed have been entered and released.
*If this report is being prepared for the first period in a particular year, the period type is correctly specified on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\TX_20_70_00|Tax Periods] ([~/?ScreenId=TX207000|TX207000]) form..

==1. Prepare a Tax Report for the Tax Agency==
You prepare a tax report somewhat differently depending on whether you are preparing a revision for a closed reporting period or preparing the first tax report for an open reporting period.[anchor|#ul_tzx_4qq_41b]
*If you need to prepare a revision for a closed reporting period for which at least one tax report has already been prepared, you use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\TX_50_10_00|Prepare Tax Report] ([~/?ScreenId=TX501000|TX501000]) form, shown in the bottom part of the following screenshot. On the form, you select a tax agency and the closed tax period for which you want to prepare the new revision, and click '''Prepare Tax Report''' on the form toolbar.
*:((({S:Hint}You can prepare a tax report for a closed tax period if the '''Update Closed Tax Periods''' check box is selected for the tax agency on the '''Tax Agency Settings''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_30_00|Vendors] ([~/?ScreenId=AP303000|AP303000]) form.
)))[anchor|#_5f915216-8fcf-4ac3-9560-464e473e536b][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Preparing_Tax_Report_Step_2_1.png|popup|450px]
*:For details, see [HelpRoot_Financials\TX__how_To_Prepare_a_Tax_Report_for_Closed_Reporting_Period|To Prepare a Tax Report for a Closed Reporting Period].
*You prepare a tax report for an open reporting period on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\TX_50_10_00|Prepare Tax Report] form as well. You select a tax agency and the tax period for which you want to prepare the tax report, and click '''Prepare Tax Report''' on the form toolbar. (See the following screenshot.)[anchor|#_ca893d9e-bf4f-4d9d-89f5-dc9303625b28][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Preparing_Tax_Report_Step_2_2.png|popup|450px]
*:For details, see [HelpRoot_Financials\TX__how_To_Prepare_a_Tax_Report|To Prepare a Tax Report for an Open Reporting Period].

==2. Optional: Adjust the Amounts in the Tax Report==
If you need to adjust the tax and taxable amounts included in the prepared tax report, you can create a tax adjustment document manually by using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\TX_30_10_00|Tax Adjustments] ([~/?ScreenId=TX301000|TX301000]) form, as shown in the following screenshot. To do so, you select the type of the adjustment, tax agency, tax period, and date. You also tax details for the tax adjustment. When you release the adjustment by clicking '''Release''' on the form toolbar, the system releases a batch corresponding to the adjustment in the General Ledger, which you can view on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_30_10_00|Journal Transactions] ([~/?ScreenId=GL301000|GL301000]) form (see the bottom part of the following screenshot).[anchor|#_9bd8d9f4-e710-49de-a05f-0f13ae43787a][anchor|#_68b2dfc2-c6c3-4cc4-9c6a-0a1b7127cc9d][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Preparing_Tax_Report_Step_3.png|popup|450px]
For details, see [HelpRoot_Financials\TX__how_To_Create_a_Tax_Adjustment_Documnet|To Create a Tax Adjustment Document].
==3. Optional: Void the Tax Report==
You can void the tax report if any of the following is true:[anchor|#_1de725dc-bd57-45d7-a2d7-aee164e79852]
*You have discovered that new transactions have been posted to the tax period for which the tax report is prepared.
*The report structure requires modifications.
*The first tax period of the year is of the wrong type.
{br}

You void a prepared tax report by using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\TX_50_20_00|Release Tax Report] ([~/?ScreenId=TX502000|TX502000]) form, as the following screenshot shows.[anchor|#_ed714cc4-2a78-40a4-b6b5-06b87a5d00c4][anchor|#_e217c540-f3f7-446a-bf1c-b27afb56f727][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Preparing_Tax_Report_Step_4.png|popup|450px]((({S:Hint}You can then prepare another tax report for the tax period.
)))
For details, see [HelpRoot_Financials\TX__con_Operations_With_Tax_Report|Operations with Tax Reports].
==4. Release the Tax Report==
You release the tax report on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\TX_50_20_00|Release Tax Report] ([~/?ScreenId=TX502000|TX502000]) form (see the following screenshot) by selecting the branch, tax period, and tax agency, and then clicking '''Release''' on the form toolbar.[anchor|#_ae8d6ed8-1ed2-49e1-9790-4e5e5adb38a4][anchor|#_a6da5137-107c-4587-afcd-d6a259a80406][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Preparing_Tax_Report_Step_5.png|popup|450px]
For details, see [HelpRoot_Financials\TX__how_To_Release_a_Tax_Report|To Release a Tax Report].{br}

After you release the report, the system closes the tax period, as you can see on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\TX_20_70_00|Tax Periods] ([~/?ScreenId=TX207000|TX207000]) form (shown in the following screenshot) when you specify the applicable branch, tax agency, and tax year.[anchor|#_9917c0ad-187f-49f5-aa1a-3ea3bc926cbe][anchor|#_3b9f72e0-f34e-4e99-8126-22730bed935f][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Preparing_Tax_Report_Step_5_2.png|popup|450px]
You can view the details of the released tax report on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\TX_50_20_10|Tax Report Details] ([~/?ScreenId=TX502010|TX502010]) form, as the following screenshot shows.[anchor|#_2ac71c39-3575-4973-89e9-0e4ab777a3d2][anchor|#_b738d8f8-2d8a-44a4-9d77-26c9ce8946ea][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Preparing_Tax_Report_Step_5_1.png|popup|450px]
==Related Articles==
*[HelpRoot_Financials\TX__con_Tax_Report_Configuration_and_Setup|Tax Report Configuration]
*[HelpRoot_Financials\TX__con_Tax_Report_Preparation|Tax Report Preparation]
*[HelpRoot_Financials\TX__con_Operations_With_Tax_Report|Operations with Tax Reports]
*[HelpRoot_Financials\TX__con_Tax_Report_Release|Tax Report Release]
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\TX_20_50_00|Taxes] ([~/?ScreenId=TX205000|TX205000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\TX_20_52_00|Reporting Groups] ([~/?ScreenId=TX205200|TX205200])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\TX_20_51_00|Reporting Settings] ([~/?ScreenId=TX205100|TX205100])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\TX_50_20_00|Release Tax Report] ([~/?ScreenId=TX502000|TX502000])]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Preparing a Tax Report for a Tax Agency In  Acumatica ERP, you can prepare a tax report for a particular tax agency. To prepare this tax                 report for an open or closed reporting period, you perform the steps described in                 this guide. Before You Proceed Before you start preparing a tax report for a needed tax agency, make sure that: The required tax agency has been configured on the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP303000|AP303000]) Vendors (AP303000) form. The required tax report has been configured in the system. All required taxes (that is, those to be reported on) have been created in                         the system with the tax agency specified on the   ([~/?ScreenId=TX205000|TX205000]) Taxes (TX205000) form. All taxable documents related to the period being closed have been entered                         and released. If this report is being prepared for the first period in a particular year,                         the period type is correctly specified on the   ([~/?ScreenId=TX207000|TX207000]) Tax Periods (TX207000) form.. 1. Prepare a Tax Report for the Tax Agency You prepare a tax report somewhat differently depending on whether you are preparing                 a revision for a closed reporting period or preparing the first tax report for an                 open reporting period. If you need to prepare a revision for a closed reporting period for which at                     least one tax report has already been prepared, you use the   ([~/?ScreenId=TX501000|TX501000]) Prepare Tax Report (TX501000) form, shown in the                     bottom part of the following screenshot. On the form, you select a tax agency                     and the closed tax period for which you want to prepare the new revision, and                     click  Prepare Tax Report  on the form toolbar. You                         can prepare a tax report for a closed tax period if the  Update                             Closed Tax Periods  check box is selected for the tax agency                         on the  Tax Agency Settings  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP303000|AP303000]) Vendors (AP303000) form. For details, see  To Prepare a Tax Report for a Closed Reporting Period. You prepare a tax report for an open reporting period on the   ([~/?ScreenId=TX501000|TX501000]) Prepare Tax Report form as well. You select a tax agency                     and the tax period for which you want to prepare the tax report, and click                          Prepare Tax Report  on the form toolbar. (See the                     following screenshot.) For details, see  To Prepare a Tax Report for an Open Reporting Period. 2. Optional: Adjust the Amounts in the Tax Report If you need to adjust the tax and taxable amounts included in the prepared tax                 report, you can create a tax adjustment document manually by using the   ([~/?ScreenId=TX301000|TX301000]) Tax Adjustments (TX301000) form, as shown in the                 following screenshot. To do so, you select the type of the adjustment, tax agency,                 tax period, and date. You also tax details for the tax adjustment. When you release                 the adjustment by clicking  Release  on the form toolbar, the                 system releases a batch corresponding to the adjustment in the General Ledger, which                 you can view on the   ([~/?ScreenId=GL301000|GL301000]) Journal Transactions (GL301000) form                 (see the bottom part of the following screenshot). For details, see  To Create a Tax Adjustment Document. 3. Optional: Void the Tax Report You can void the tax report if any of the following is true: You have discovered that new transactions have been posted to the tax period                         for which the tax report is prepared. The report structure requires modifications. The first tax period of the year is of the wrong type. You void a prepared tax report by using the   ([~/?ScreenId=TX502000|TX502000]) Release Tax Report (TX502000) form, as the following                 screenshot shows. You can then prepare another tax report for the tax period. For details, see  Operations with Tax Reports. 4. Release the Tax Report You release the tax report on the   ([~/?ScreenId=TX502000|TX502000]) Release Tax Report                 (TX502000) form (see the following screenshot) by selecting the branch, tax period,                 and tax agency, and then clicking  Release  on the form                 toolbar. For details, see  To Release a Tax Report. After you release the report, the system closes the tax period, as you can see on the                       ([~/?ScreenId=TX207000|TX207000]) Tax Periods (TX207000) form (shown in the                 following screenshot) when you specify the applicable branch, tax agency, and tax                 year. You can view the details of the released tax report on the   ([~/?ScreenId=TX502010|TX502010]) Tax Report Details (TX502010) form, as the following                 screenshot shows.  ([~/?ScreenId=TX205000|TX205000])  ([~/?ScreenId=TX205200|TX205200])  ([~/?ScreenId=TX205100|TX205100])  ([~/?ScreenId=TX502000|TX502000]) ]]></column>
		</row>
	</rows>
</data>