<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<data>
	<table name="WikiRevision">
		<col name="CompanyID" type="Int" default="Zero" />
		<col name="PageID" type="UniqueIdentifier" />
		<col name="Language" type="VarChar(50)" />
		<col name="PageRevisionID" type="Int" />
		<col name="Content" type="NVarChar(MAX)" />
		<col name="ContentHtml" type="NVarChar(MAX)" nullable="true" />
		<col name="PlainText" type="NVarChar(MAX)" />
		<col name="ApprovalByID" type="UniqueIdentifier" nullable="true" />
		<col name="ApprovalDateTime" type="DateTime" nullable="true" />
		<col name="CreatedByID" type="UniqueIdentifier" />
		<col name="CreatedDateTime" type="DateTime" />
		<col name="CompanyMask" type="VarBinary(32)" default="CompanyMaskReadOnly" />
		<col name="UID" type="UniqueIdentifier" />
		<col name="RecordSourceID" type="SmallInt" nullable="true" />
	</table>
	<rows>
		<row PageID="858838bd-ed2b-4fc9-85d3-823b33645736" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" PlainText="Organization Structure The Organization Structure module lets you create and maintain multiple branches for &#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;points of sale (locations) and separate legal entities within your organization to &#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;ensure better visibility into various layers of financial operations. To match &#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;actual workflows established in your organization, you can create a hierarchical &#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;structure of departments, divisions, and workgroups, even across branches, and set &#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;up automatic assignment of document and workloads.  In This Part Overview of Organization Structure ProcessesMultiple Branch SupportBasic Models for Multi-Branch OrganizationSecurity of Organization BranchesCompany Tree and WorkgroupsManaging Assignment and Approval MapsSupport of Multiple Work CalendarsOrganization Structure Form Reference" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="60461ea2-61df-aca4-9344-35a2a5b88dd5" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
The Organization Structure module lets you create and maintain multiple branches for points of sale (locations) and separate legal entities within your organization to ensure better visibility into various layers of financial operations. To match actual workflows established in your organization, you can create a hierarchical structure of departments, divisions, and workgroups, even across branches, and set up automatic assignment of document and workloads. 
==In This Part==
*[HelpRoot_Organization\OS__OS_Features|Overview of Organization Structure Processes]
*[HelpRoot_Organization\CS__con_Multiple_Branch_Support|Multiple Branch Support]
*[HelpRoot_Organization\CS__con_Basic_Models_for_Multi-Branch_Organization|Basic Models for Multi-Branch Organization]
*[HelpRoot_Organization\CS__con_Branch_Security_Administration|Security of Organization Branches]
*[HelpRoot_Organization\EP__con_Company_Organizational_Chart|Company Tree and Workgroups]
*[HelpRoot_Organization\EP__con_Assignment_Automation|Managing Assignment and Approval Maps]
*[HelpRoot_Organization\EP__con_Multiple_Calendar_Support|Support of Multiple Work Calendars]
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\OS__OS_Form_Reference|Organization Structure Form Reference]
]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="807f8ddc-6bec-4809-8d6b-c6032e002510" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="ef84f361-aabe-f64a-35ef-7f1fc1b2997a" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
In Acumatica ERP, you can configure the structure of your organization as consisting of a single branch or multiple branches with different reporting settings to suit complex reporting requirements and data consolidation needs. {br}

Also, by using the Organization Structure module, your organization can automate work assignments and document assignment for approvals. {br}{TOC}
==Multi-Branch Functionality==
In Acumatica ERP, you can configure the system as a single entity or as a multi-branch organization to match the actual organization&rsquo;s structure. All branches of the organization use the same currency and chart of accounts, and have shared lists of trade partners. You can configure automatic balancing of inter-branch transactions. If the branches operate separately, you can set up user access to specific branches only. For additional information, see the following topics: [anchor|#ul_ufn_2t5_q3]
*[HelpRoot_Organization\CS__con_Multiple_Branch_Support|Multiple Branch Support]
*[HelpRoot_Organization\CS__con_Basic_Models_for_Multi-Branch_Organization|Basic Models for Multi-Branch Organization]
*[HelpRoot_Organization\CS__con_Branch_Security_Administration|Security of Organization Branches]

==Organizational Chart and Assignment Automation==
You can build a company tree, which is a model of your organization&rsquo;s hierarchy that includes branches and departments, as well as temporary or permanent workgroups. The company tree may reflect the administrative hierarchy and include sub-hierarchies of workgroups created within specific branches or departments. The company tree is used for creating assignment rules in approval and assignment maps and for determining the scope of the users who want to view items assigned to them. You can use assignment maps to automatically distribute the work items (such as leads, contacts, opportunities, or cases) to be processed or you can use approval maps to distribute the documents (such as time cards, expense receipts, or orders) to be approved among the workgroups, based on relevant item or document properties. For more information, see the following articles: [anchor|#ul_wdr_qgv_q3]
*[HelpRoot_Organization\EP__con_Company_Organizational_Chart|Company Tree and Workgroups]
*[HelpRoot_Organization\EP__con_Assignment_Automation|Managing Assignment and Approval Maps]

==Other Features and Options==
 Acumatica ERP provides unmatched flexibility for each organization to implement its unique business processes by using the Organization Structure functionality. In addition to the features described above, the Organization Structure functionality offers the following features and options: [anchor|#ul_kgn_2t5_q3]
*You can use departments, employee positions, and information about to whom each employee reports to build any hierarchy to be used in assignment and approval maps.
*Buildings can be assigned to branches and depreciated accordingly in the respective branches.
*Multiple work calendars may be used in the organization to correctly estimate work time and overtime in different branches and on different projects, as described in [HelpRoot_Organization\EP__con_Multiple_Calendar_Support|Support of Multiple Work Calendars].

==Related Articles==
*[HelpRoot_Financials\GL__MNG_Inter-Branch_Transactions|Processing Inter-Branch Transactions]]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Overview of Organization Structure Processes In  Acumatica ERP, you can configure the structure of your organization as consisting of a single 				branch or multiple branches with different reporting settings to suit complex 				reporting requirements and data consolidation needs.  Also, by using the Organization Structure module, your organization can automate work 				assignments and document assignment for approvals.  Multi-Branch Functionality In  Acumatica ERP, you can configure the system as a single entity or as a multi-branch 				organization to match the actual organization's structure. All branches of the 				organization use the same currency and chart of accounts, and have shared lists of 				trade partners. You can configure automatic balancing of inter-branch transactions. 				If the branches operate separately, you can set up user access to specific branches 				only. For additional information, see the following topics:  Multiple Branch SupportBasic Models for Multi-Branch OrganizationSecurity of Organization BranchesOrganizational Chart and Assignment Automation You can build a company tree, which is a model of your organization's hierarchy that includes 				branches and departments, as well as temporary or permanent workgroups. The company 				tree may reflect the administrative hierarchy and include sub-hierarchies of 				workgroups created within specific branches or departments. The company tree is used 				for creating assignment rules in approval and assignment maps and for determining 				the scope of the users who want to view items assigned to them. You can use 				assignment maps to automatically distribute the work items (such as leads, contacts, 				opportunities, or cases) to be processed or you can use approval maps to distribute 				the documents (such as time cards, expense receipts, or orders) to be approved among 				the workgroups, based on relevant item or document properties. For more information, 				see the following articles:  Company Tree and WorkgroupsManaging Assignment and Approval MapsOther Features and Options  Acumatica ERP provides unmatched flexibility for each organization to implement its unique 				business processes by using the Organization Structure functionality. In addition to 				the features described above, the Organization Structure functionality offers the 				following features and options:  You can use departments, employee positions, and information about to whom each employee 					reports to build any hierarchy to be used in assignment and approval maps. Buildings can be assigned to branches and depreciated accordingly in the respective 					branches. Multiple work calendars may be used in the organization to correctly estimate work time and 					overtime in different branches and on different projects, as described in  Support of Multiple Work Calendars. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="f2e2d984-0954-4272-bc92-dee20623fa7d" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" PlainText="Managing Companies and Branches In  Acumatica ERP, a    company represents a legal entity with an independent balance sheet and separate tax reporting.    An organization may consist of one company or multiple companies. A company may have no branches, or it may consist of multiple branches, each being a separate    office or a point of sale. Companies with multiple branches can be configured and maintained in      Acumatica ERP only if the  Multi-Branch Support  feature is enabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features (CS100000) form. On the same form, the  Inter-Branch     Transactions  feature should be enabled if different branches of a company can participate in    one transaction. All branches within a tenant have the same chart of accounts, calendar, and base currency. In This Chapter Companies and BranchesMultiple Branch SupportBasic Models for Multi-Branch OrganizationSecurity of Organization Branches" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="1514e608-aada-a708-2843-1aaecc0c701f" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
In Acumatica ERP, a company represents a legal entity with an independent balance sheet and separate tax reporting. An organization may consist of one company or multiple companies.{br}

A company may have no branches, or it may consist of multiple branches, each being a separate office or a point of sale. Companies with multiple branches can be configured and maintained in Acumatica ERP only if the ''Multi-Branch Support'' feature is enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) form. On the same form, the ''Inter-Branch Transactions'' feature should be enabled if different branches of a company can participate in one transaction.{br}

All branches within a tenant have the same chart of accounts, calendar, and base currency.
==In This Chapter==[anchor|#ul_sbr_ywg_ycb]
*[HelpRoot_Organization\OS__con_Companies|Companies and Branches]
*[HelpRoot_Organization\CS__con_Multiple_Branch_Support|Multiple Branch Support]
*[HelpRoot_Organization\CS__con_Basic_Models_for_Multi-Branch_Organization|Basic Models for Multi-Branch Organization]
*[HelpRoot_Organization\CS__con_Branch_Security_Administration|Security of Organization Branches]
]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="3b262f5c-aaaf-48cd-9f8b-cb3f678afc31" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="ffae8436-ebef-5890-7808-c983c84ab3e5" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
In Acumatica ERP, a user can create new companies or maintain existing companies by using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_15_00|Companies] ([~/?ScreenId=CS101500|CS101500]) form.
==Company Type==
Each company has one of the following types, which is specified in the '''Company Type''' box on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_15_00|Companies] ([~/?ScreenId=CS101500|CS101500]) form:[anchor|#ul_aps_rqs_ncb]
*''Without Branches'': A company with this type cannot have any branches. If the ''Multi-Branch Support'' feature is not enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) form, this option is selected by default and cannot be changed.
*''With Branches Not Requiring Balancing'': A company with this type must have at least one branch. If multiple branches of the company are involved in a transaction, balancing entries are not required. This option is available if the ''Multi-Branch Support'' feature is enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] form.
*''With Branches Requiring Balancing'': A company with this type must have at least one branch. If multiple branches of the company are involved in a transaction, balancing entries are required. This option is available if the ''Multi-Branch Support'' and ''Inter-Branch Transactions'' features are enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] form. 

For details about how Acumatica ERP supports multiple branches for a company, see [HelpRoot_Organization\CS__con_Multiple_Branch_Support|Multiple Branch Support].{br}

After a company has been configured, the company type still can be changed as follows.[anchor|#table_wfc_gph_ycb]
{| class="checklist" | width="100%" 
|- 
!width="33%" ! From
!width="33%" ! To
!width="33%" ! Condition
|- 
| ''Without Branches''
| 
 ''With Branches Not Requiring Balancing''{br}

or{br}

''With Branches Requiring Balancing''
| At any time
|- 
| 
''With Branches Not Requiring Balancing''{br}

or{br}

''With Branches Requiring Balancing''
|  ''Without Branches''
| The company has only one branch or no branches at all.
|- 
| ''With Branches Not Requiring Balancing''
|  ''With Branches Requiring Balancing''
| No transactions have been posted by company branches or the company has only one branch.
|- 
| ''With Branches Requiring Balancing''
|  ''With Branches Not Requiring Balancing''
| No transactions have been posted by company branches or the company has only one branch.
|}
==Company Maintenance==
For a company that has the ''With Branches Not Requiring Balancing'' or ''With Branches Requiring Balancing'' type, the '''Branches''' tab becomes available on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_15_00|Companies] ([~/?ScreenId=CS101500|CS101500]) form. By using this tab, a system administrator can add new branches to the company (if it has any) or delete branches from the list of company branches; when the company has no branches, it can be also deleted.{br}

A company with the ''Without Branches'' type can be deleted if it has no GL history (that is, if no GL transactions are associated with the company) and if no cash accounts, employees, warehouses, and fixed assets are linked to the company.{br}

If a user clears the '''Active''' check box on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_15_00|Companies] form for a company that has branches, all the company branches will be deactivated. However, a branch cannot be deactivated if it is linked to an active warehouse, to an employee with a status other than ''Inactive'', or to a fixed asset with a status other than ''Disposed'' or ''Reversed'', and a company with such a branch also cannot be deactivated.
==Configuration of Access to Company Data==
Access to the data related to a specific branch or to all branches of a company is regulated by an access role.{br}

When an access role is specified for a company in the '''Access Role''' box on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_15_00|Companies] ([~/?ScreenId=CS101500|CS101500]) form, the system prompts whether the access role should be copied to the settings of all branches of the company. When the '''Access Role''' box is cleared for the company, the system prompts whether the access role should be removed from the settings of all branches of the company. If no access role is specified for the company, an individual access role can be specified for each branch of the company on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_20_00|Branches] ([~/?ScreenId=CS102000|CS102000]) from.{br}

A user that has access to at least one of the company branches can select the company in corresponding boxes on data entry forms.{br}

For more information about ways to manage the security of a branch, see [HelpRoot_Organization\CS__con_Branch_Security_Administration|Security of Organization Branches].
==Ledgers==
A company can post transactions to various ledgers, but it can be associated with only one actual ledger.{br}

A user can manage ledgers associated with a company in any of the following ways:[anchor|#ul_chn_th3_ycb]
*Create for a new company a ledger of the ''Actual'' type by clicking '''Create Ledger''' on the form toolbar of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_15_00|Companies] ([~/?ScreenId=CS101500|CS101500]) form
*Review the list of the ledgers associated with the company, add an existing ledger to the list, or remove a ledger from the list by using the '''Ledgers''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_15_00|Companies] form
*Review the list of all ledgers associated with the company of the selected branch by using the '''Ledgers''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_20_00|Branches] ([~/?ScreenId=CS102000|CS102000]) form
*Maintain the list of the companies that are allowed to post to non-actual ledgers by using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_20_15_00|Ledgers] ([~/?ScreenId=GL201500|GL201500]) form

An actual ledger can be detached from a company if the ledger contains no transactions associated with any branch of the company.{br}

For more information about ledgers, see the [HelpRoot_Financials\GL__MNG_Managing_Ledgers|Managing Ledgers] chapter in the Financial Management Guide.
==Tax Reports==
For a company with the ''With Branches Requiring Balancing'' type, the '''File Taxes by Branches''' check box is available on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_15_00|Companies] ([~/?ScreenId=CS101500|CS101500]) form. If the check box is cleared, a tax report includes data related to all branches of the company. If the check box is selected, each branch of the company requires an individual report.{br}

For a company with any other type, tax reports always include company-wide data.
==Logos==
On the '''Logo''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_15_00|Companies] ([~/?ScreenId=CS101500|CS101500]) or [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_20_00|Branches] ([~/?ScreenId=CS102000|CS102000]) form, a user can specify separate images for the logo displayed in the top left corner of Acumatica ERP and for the logo displayed on reports for the selected company or branch.]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Companies and Branches In  Acumatica ERP, a user can create new companies or maintain existing companies by using the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS101500|CS101500]) Companies (CS101500) form. Company Type Each company has one of the following types, which is specified in the  Company Type          box on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS101500|CS101500]) Companies (CS101500) form: Without Branches : A company with this type cannot have any branches. If the              Multi-Branch Support  feature is not enabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features (CS100000) form, this option is selected by default and cannot be changed. With Branches Not Requiring Balancing : A company with this type must have at           least one branch. If multiple branches of the company are involved in a transaction,           balancing entries are not required. This option is available if the  Multi-Branch             Support  feature is enabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features form. With Branches Requiring Balancing : A company with this type must have at least           one branch. If multiple branches of the company are involved in a transaction, balancing           entries are required. This option is available if the  Multi-Branch Support  and              Inter-Branch Transactions  features are enabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features form.   For details about how  Acumatica ERP supports multiple branches for a company, see  Multiple Branch Support. After a company has been configured, the company type still can be changed as follows. From To Condition Without Branches With Branches Not Requiring Balancing or With Branches Requiring Balancing At any time With Branches Not Requiring Balancing or With Branches Requiring Balancing Without Branches The company has only one branch or no branches at all. With Branches Not Requiring Balancing With Branches Requiring Balancing No transactions have been posted by company branches or the company has only                 one branch. With Branches Requiring Balancing With Branches Not Requiring Balancing No transactions have been posted by company branches or the company has only                 one branch. Company Maintenance For a company that has the  With Branches Not Requiring Balancing  or  With Branches           Requiring Balancing  type, the  Branches  tab becomes available on         the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS101500|CS101500]) Companies (CS101500) form. By using this tab, a system         administrator can add new branches to the company (if it has any) or delete branches from         the list of company branches; when the company has no branches, it can be also deleted. A company with the  Without Branches  type can be deleted if it has no GL history         (that is, if no GL transactions are associated with the company) and if no cash accounts,         employees, warehouses, and fixed assets are linked to the company. If a user clears the  Active  check box on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS101500|CS101500]) Companies form         for a company that has branches, all the company branches will be deactivated. However, a         branch cannot be deactivated if it is linked to an active warehouse, to an employee with a         status other than  Inactive , or to a fixed asset with a status other than            Disposed  or  Reversed , and a company with such a branch also cannot be         deactivated. Configuration of Access to Company Data Access to the data related to a specific branch or to all branches of a company is         regulated by an access role. When an access role is specified for a company in the  Access Role          box on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS101500|CS101500]) Companies (CS101500) form, the system prompts whether         the access role should be copied to the settings of all branches of the company. When the            Access Role  box is cleared for the company, the system prompts         whether the access role should be removed from the settings of all branches of the company.         If no access role is specified for the company, an individual access role can be specified         for each branch of the company on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS102000|CS102000]) Branches (CS102000)         from. A user that has access to at least one of the company branches can select the company in         corresponding boxes on data entry forms. For more information about ways to manage the security of a branch, see  Security of Organization Branches. Ledgers A company can post transactions to various ledgers, but it can be associated with only one         actual ledger. A user can manage ledgers associated with a company in any of the following ways: Create for a new company a ledger of the  Actual  type by clicking              Create Ledger  on the form toolbar of the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS101500|CS101500]) Companies (CS101500) form Review the list of the ledgers associated with the company, add an existing ledger to           the list, or remove a ledger from the list by using the  Ledgers  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS101500|CS101500]) Companies form Review the list of all ledgers associated with the company of the selected branch by           using the  Ledgers  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS102000|CS102000]) Branches (CS102000)           form Maintain the list of the companies that are allowed to post to non-actual ledgers by           using the   ([~/?ScreenId=GL201500|GL201500]) Ledgers (GL201500) form An actual ledger can be detached from a company if the ledger contains no transactions         associated with any branch of the company. For more information about ledgers, see the  Managing Ledgers         chapter in the Financial Management Guide. Tax Reports For a company with the  With Branches Requiring Balancing  type, the  File           Taxes by Branches  check box is available on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS101500|CS101500]) Companies (CS101500) form. If the check box is cleared, a tax report includes data related to         all branches of the company. If the check box is selected, each branch of the company         requires an individual report. For a company with any other type, tax reports always include company-wide data. Logos On the  Logo  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS101500|CS101500]) Companies (CS101500) or   ([~/?ScreenId=CS102000|CS102000]) Branches (CS102000) form, a user can specify separate images for the         logo displayed in the top left corner of  Acumatica ERP and for the logo displayed on reports for the selected company or branch. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="633b757d-4d8a-4dde-b7be-4fdb8f2968da" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="ff3e5f83-aa08-1313-bdff-c222327c6c59" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
Sooner or later, small and medium-sized businesses may face the challenges presented by growth. The organization can grow by adding new locations that become branches with some degree of autonomy. {br}

Because most Acumatica ERP customers are small and mid-sized businesses, the multi-branch functionality has been developed for organizations that meet certain requirements: 
*All branches use the same base currency.
*The chart of accounts is shared among branches, or similar charts of accounts used by different branches can be merged into one chart of accounts used by all branches.
*The branches have the same financial year and periods.

Larger organizations with base currencies different in different branches, fiscal years, and periods can configure their subsidiaries as separate organizations with individual company IDs and use the consolidation functionality to be able to report as a single company. For details, see [HelpRoot_Financials\GL__con_GL_Consolidations|General Ledger Consolidation Process]. {br}{TOC}
==Organization as a Structure of Branches==
 Acumatica ERP supports multi-branch functionality and provides several basic models for implementing most typical organization structures. For details, see [HelpRoot_Organization\CS__con_Basic_Models_for_Multi-Branch_Organization|Basic Models for Multi-Branch Organization]. {br}

In Acumatica ERP, an organization has a company account with a company ID. Within a company account, at least one branch is needed to represent the organization itself. If the organization includes more than one branch, organization branches are created within the same company ID. The identifiers for branches (Branch IDs) are based on the ''BIZACCT'' segmented key—that is, they have the same segments as identifiers for organization&rsquo;s customers and vendors. 
==User Access to Branch Data==
Since the branches are created within the same organization, they have some shared data and some branch-specific data. {br}

Each employee (user) is assigned to a specific branch. To restrict user access to branch-specific data, you can configure a branch access role for each branch. Then the branch employees will be able to access the shared data (as their roles allow) and the data specific to their branch. To employees who should have access to other branches too, you must assign the access roles for the branches in the user&rsquo;s scope. For details, see [HelpRoot_Organization\CS__con_Branch_Security_Administration|Security of Organization Branches]. If a user has access to several branches, the user will be able to choose the branch he or she needs by selecting it from the form toolbar on each data entry form.
==Data Shared Between Branches==
Some of the data is unconditionally shared and available in all branches for all users who have access to this data by their roles. {br}

In addition to the financial year and periods, the organization&rsquo;s branches share the following information: 
*The chart of accounts.
*Subaccounts.
*Budget tree, for details, see [HelpRoot_Financials\GL__con_Budgeting_Overview|Budgets Modification].
*Taxes, tax categories, and tax zones.
*Credit terms and overdue charges.
*Statement cycles.
*Customer and vendor classes.
*Customers and vendors. You can specify for some customer and vendor locations a default branch with which they have operations, and this location will be unavailable for selection from other branches.
*Stock and non-stock items. If you need to view inventory by branch, configure the ''INVENTORY'' segmented key appropriately, with a segment designating a branch to which the item belongs, but all items will be visible in the list of available items.
*Lot and serial classes.
*Units of measure and conversion rules.
*Posting classes for inventory.

Company tree and assignment maps should include workgroups that belong to all branches. Approval routes may pass across the entire organization.((({S:Hint}
You can use the functionality of restriction groups to assign specific accounts and subaccounts to a particular branch. For details, see [HelpRoot_Organization\CS__con_Branch_Security_Administration|Security of Organization Branches].
)))
==Branch-Specific Data==
The following entities are assigned to only one of the branches: 
*Cash accounts (each of which is denominated in a specific currency)
*Warehouses
*Employees
*Buildings (a sort of fixed asset)

Do not create a subaccount segment for branches; transactions are marked by the originating branch in other ways. Bills and invoices as well as other documents are associated with the particular branch in which they were created. To make them easily identifiable by branch, you can create branch-specific subsequences for all numbering sequences involved by using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_20_10_10|Numbering Sequences] ([~/?ScreenId=CS201010|CS201010]) form, so that a document originating in a specific branch will have a reference number clearly associated with the branch of origin. {br}

If a user has a branch access role that provides access to only one of the branches, the user will be able to view only the documents related to the respective branch. 
==Data Consolidation==
The multi-branch functionality, as it is implemented in Acumatica ERP, enables complex organizations to view the consolidated data from multiple branches without having to perform any additional operations and in real time. It is easy to configure consolidated replenishment or centralized payment of bill or view consolidated data on reports running them from the headquarters branch. {br}

When a user opens a report or inquiry, the system checks the user&rsquo;s access rights to branches. If a user has access to all branches, this user can view the data of any selected branch or the consolidated data by leaving the '''Branch''' box blank. If a user has access to only one branch, this user will be able to view only the data related to the particular branch even if he or she runs the report that should show the consolidated data. {br}

Replenishment is performed on a branch basis, although you can implement the following scenario: The headquarters has a large warehouse for which you configure automatic replenishment. Warehouses assigned to other branches are replenished through transfers from the headquarters&rsquo; warehouse. Thus, your organization will be able to save on volume discounts. {br}

In your system, bills can be paid by a headquarters branch on behalf of other branches. To do this, assign to authorized personnel the roles that provide access to branches. Then the employees who pay the bills will be able to view the bills from all branches on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_20_00|Checks and Payments] ([~/?ScreenId=AP302000|AP302000]) and [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_50_30_00|Prepare Payments] ([~/?ScreenId=AP503000|AP503000]) forms. The cash accounts from which payments are made should be assigned to the headquarters branch. 
==Related Articles==
*[HelpRoot_Organization\CS__con_Basic_Models_for_Multi-Branch_Organization|Basic Models for Multi-Branch Organization]
*[HelpRoot_Organization\CS__con_Branch_Security_Administration|Security of Organization Branches]
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_20_00|Branches] ([~/?ScreenId=CS102000|CS102000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_20_50_10|Buildings] ([~/?ScreenId=CS205010|CS205010])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_10_10_10|Inter-Branch Account Mapping] ([~/?ScreenId=GL101010|GL101010])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_10_30_20|Restriction Groups by Branch] ([~/?ScreenId=GL103020|GL103020])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_10_30_40|GL Accounts by Branch Access] ([~/?ScreenId=GL103040|GL103040])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_10_30_60|Subaccounts by Branch Access] ([~/?ScreenId=GL103060|GL103060])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_20_00|Checks and Payments] ([~/?ScreenId=AP302000|AP302000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_50_30_00|Prepare Payments] ([~/?ScreenId=AP503000|AP503000])]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Multiple Branch Support Sooner or later, small and medium-sized businesses may face the challenges presented 				by growth. The organization can grow by adding new locations that become branches 				with some degree of autonomy.  Because most  Acumatica ERP customers are small and mid-sized businesses, the multi-branch functionality has 				been developed for organizations that meet certain requirements:  All branches use the same base currency. The chart of accounts is shared among branches, or similar charts of accounts 					used by different branches can be merged into one chart of accounts used by all 					branches. The branches have the same financial year and periods. Larger organizations with base currencies different in different branches, fiscal 				years, and periods can configure their subsidiaries as separate organizations with 				individual company IDs and use the consolidation functionality to be able to report 				as a single company. For details, see  General Ledger Consolidation Process.  Organization as a Structure of Branches  Acumatica ERP supports multi-branch functionality and provides several basic models for 				implementing most typical organization structures. For details, see  Basic Models for Multi-Branch Organization.  In  Acumatica ERP, an organization has a company account with a company ID. Within a company 				account, at least one branch is needed to represent the organization itself. If the 				organization includes more than one branch, organization branches are created within 				the same company ID. The identifiers for branches (Branch IDs) are based on the 					 BIZACCT  segmented key—that is, they have the same segments as 				identifiers for organization's customers and vendors.  User Access to Branch Data Since the branches are created within the same organization, they have some shared 				data and some branch-specific data.  Each employee (user) is assigned to a specific branch. To restrict user access to 				branch-specific data, you can configure a branch access role for each branch. Then 				the branch employees will be able to access the shared data (as their roles allow) 				and the data specific to their branch. To employees who should have access to other 				branches too, you must assign the access roles for the branches in the user's scope. 				For details, see  Security of Organization Branches. If a user has access to several branches, the user will be able 				to choose the branch he or she needs by selecting it from the form toolbar on each 				data entry form. Data Shared Between Branches Some of the data is unconditionally shared and available in all branches for all 				users who have access to this data by their roles.  In addition to the financial year and periods, the organization's branches share the 				following information:  The chart of accounts. Subaccounts. Budget tree, for details, see  Budgets Modification. Taxes, tax categories, and tax zones. Credit terms and overdue charges. Statement cycles. Customer and vendor classes. Customers and vendors. You can specify for some customer and vendor locations a 					default branch with which they have operations, and this location will be 					unavailable for selection from other branches. Stock and non-stock items. If you need to view inventory by branch, configure 					the  INVENTORY  segmented key appropriately, with a segment designating a 					branch to which the item belongs, but all items will be visible in the list of 					available items. Lot and serial classes. Units of measure and conversion rules. Posting classes for inventory. Company tree and assignment maps should include workgroups that belong to all 				branches. Approval routes may pass across the entire organization. You can use the functionality of restriction groups to assign specific accounts 					and subaccounts to a particular branch. For details, see  Security of Organization Branches. Branch-Specific Data The following entities are assigned to only one of the branches:  Cash accounts (each of which is denominated in a specific currency) Warehouses Employees Buildings (a sort of fixed asset) Do not create a subaccount segment for branches; transactions are marked by the originating 				branch in other ways. Bills and invoices as well as other documents are associated 				with the particular branch in which they were created. To make them easily 				identifiable by branch, you can create branch-specific subsequences for all 				numbering sequences involved by using the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS201010|CS201010]) Numbering Sequences (CS201020) form, so that a document originating in a specific 				branch will have a reference number clearly associated with the branch of origin.  If a user has a branch access role that provides access to only one of the branches, 				the user will be able to view only the documents related to the respective branch. 			 Data Consolidation The multi-branch functionality, as it is implemented in  Acumatica ERP, enables complex organizations to view the consolidated data from multiple 				branches without having to perform any additional operations and in real time. It is 				easy to configure consolidated replenishment or centralized payment of bill or view 				consolidated data on reports running them from the headquarters branch.  When a user opens a report or inquiry, the system checks the user's access rights to 				branches. If a user has access to all branches, this user can view the data of any 				selected branch or the consolidated data by leaving the  Branch  box blank. If 				a user has access to only one branch, this user will be able to view only the data 				related to the particular branch even if he or she runs the report that should show 				the consolidated data.  Replenishment is performed on a branch basis, although you can implement the 				following scenario: The headquarters has a large warehouse for which you configure 				automatic replenishment. Warehouses assigned to other branches are replenished 				through transfers from the headquarters' warehouse. Thus, your organization will be 				able to save on volume discounts.  In your system, bills can be paid by a headquarters branch on behalf of other branches. To do 				this, assign to authorized personnel the roles that provide access to branches. Then 				the employees who pay the bills will be able to view the bills from all branches on 				the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP302000|AP302000]) Checks and Payments (AP302000) and   ([~/?ScreenId=AP503000|AP503000]) Prepare Payments (AP503000) forms. The cash accounts 				from which payments are made should be assigned to the headquarters branch.   ([~/?ScreenId=CS102000|CS102000])  ([~/?ScreenId=CS205010|CS205010])  ([~/?ScreenId=GL101010|GL101010])  ([~/?ScreenId=GL103020|GL103020])  ([~/?ScreenId=GL103040|GL103040])  ([~/?ScreenId=GL103060|GL103060])  ([~/?ScreenId=AP302000|AP302000])  ([~/?ScreenId=AP503000|AP503000]) ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="347a4a7a-f2da-4e84-afa6-59e2469304dd" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="140ddb09-0ae8-056d-e930-6b33d5a2a3c0" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
In today’s global environment, an organization may have a hierarchic structure of subsidiaries or branches and complex multi-level reporting requirements. Such an organization may need tools for easy data consolidation, as well as better visibility into various layers of financial operations within the organization. {br}

 Acumatica ERP supports multi-branch functionality and provides multiple basic one-level and two-level models, outlined in the sections below, for implementing the most typical organizational structures. For more complex organizations, such models may be combined to implement any structure. ((({S:Warn}
Choosing the model (or combination of models) that suits your organization best is an important decision that must be made before you start implementing Acumatica ERP. 
))){br}{TOC}
==Model 1: Organization with Centralized Accounting==
 With Model 1, shown in the illustration below, the organization, which is a single legal entity, consists of two branches (or locations), each branch representing a company office. Transactions are posted to these branches.[anchor|#image_gr4_cjx_ph][image:UserGuide/Images/Basic_Models_for_Multi-Branch_Organization_odel1.png|popup|200px]
To implement this model in Acumatica ERP, you have to create an additional branch that will represent the legal entity. You also have to have one posting ledger of the ''Actual'' type.{br}

You need to specify the additional branch as the consolidating branch for the posting ledger by using the '''Consolidation Branch''' column on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_20_15_00|Ledgers] ([~/?ScreenId=GL201500|GL201500]) form. The consolidating branch is used only in Form 1099-MISC and tax reports to represent the legal entity. No transactions are posted to the consolidating branch.{br}

To be able to use automatic generation of inter-branch balancing entries for documents that involve multiple branches, you need to enable the ''Inter-Branch Transactions'' feature on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) form, configure the posting ledger by selecting the check box in the '''Branch Accounting''' column for this ledger on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_20_15_00|Ledgers] ([~/?ScreenId=GL201500|GL201500]) form, and define the inter-branch account mapping by using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_10_10_10|Inter-Branch Account Mapping] ([~/?ScreenId=GL101010|GL101010]) form.{br}

If the '''Branch Accounting''' check box is cleared for the ledger, you still can make transactions between the branches (for example, transfer fixed assets from one branch to another), but the system does not create inter-branch balancing entries. The resulting batch remains unbalanced in each of the smaller branches, but the batch is balanced in the ledger that is assigned to the consolidating branch. In this case, the branches are not independent, and separate balance sheet reports cannot be prepared.
==Model 2: Autonomous Branches==
 In Model 2, illustrated below, the organization has a number of branches with a certain level of autonomy, with each branch being a legal entity. The organization and its branches share most of the vendors and customers but keep some of the trade partners as associated with a specific branch. Each branch keeps records of its own and has an accountant or accounting staff. The profitability of each branch can be equally important. [anchor|#image_ys4_2kx_ph][image:UserGuide/Images/Basic_Models_for_Multi-Branch_Organization_odel2.png|popup|200px]
In Acumatica ERP, autonomous branches may use separate ledgers to post their transactions or they may post their transactions to a single ledger with no branch selected as a consolidation branch. If the branches post their transactions to separate ledgers, the system will generate inter-branch transactions automatically. If the branches use the same ledger, to balance the original inter-branch transactions in each branch, you should select for this ledger a check box in the '''Branch Accounting''' column on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_20_15_00|Ledgers] ([~/?ScreenId=GL201500|GL201500]) form. This allows each branch to file reports as a separate legal entity. {br}

A certain level of independence requires that some of branches have their own General Ledger accounts that cannot be used by another branch. You can use restriction groups to assign selected General Ledger accounts and subaccounts to a specific branch for use by this branch only. 
==Model 3: Autonomous Multi-Location Branches==
 An organization might include a number of related legal entities with complex structures. Each legal entity has its headquarters and locations or smaller branches that are not separate legal entities. In this case, each autonomous multi-location entity keeps its own records and performs all accounting procedures. {br}

In Acumatica ERP, such an organization can be configured as a Model 3, which combines Model 1 and Model 2, functioning within one Company ID. (See the following illustration.) Each autonomous branch has its headquarters and locations (or smaller branches that are not separate legal entities) configured as branches. Each autonomous multi-location branch records its operations to a separate ledger with a ''headquarters'' branch specified as the ''consolidation branch'' for the ledger. [anchor|#image_kvj_4kx_ph][image:UserGuide/Images/Basic_Models_for_Multi-Branch_Organization_odel3.png|popup|400px]
Generally, when transactions occur between any two non-independent branches in one ledger, no inter-branch transactions are generated; however, if they are needed for any reason, you can select a check box in the '''Branch Accounting''' column on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_20_15_00|Ledgers] form for the ledger. {br}

When the inter-branch transactions occur between any branches with different posting ledgers, balancing inter-branch transactions will be generated automatically. You should create inter-branch receivable and payable accounts in each ledger and specify the rules to be used by the system for generating balancing transactions by using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_10_10_10|Inter-Branch Account Mapping] ([~/?ScreenId=GL101010|GL101010]) form.
==Model 4: Multi-National or Just Multi-Currency Organization==
 Small and midsize businesses sooner or later may face the problem of growth. They can grow by mergers or by creating local subsidiaries or branches in new regions or countries. Due to their locations, the organization subsidiaries use different base (functional) currency and should meet different reporting requirements (including non-matching financial years); their customers and vendors are not shared. For historical reasons, the organization subsidiaries may have different structures of accounts and subaccounts. {br}

In Acumatica ERP, such subsidiaries can have separate tenant accounts with different Company IDs. The simplest structure is shown by Model 4, illustrated below. Although technically the parent organization and its subsidiaries may keep their data in the same database, they may have different base currencies, different financial year settings, and separate lists of trade partners. Such subsidiaries even can be hosted on different websites. [anchor|#image_wgt_xkx_ph][image:UserGuide/Images/Basic_Models_for_Multi-Branch_Organization_odel4.png|popup|200px]
 Acumatica ERP provides the consolidation-related functionality to be used by both sides: the parent organization and its subsidiaries. If different base currencies are used by the parent company and its subsidiary, such subsidiaries can translate their balances before they prepare the consolidation data for exporting. For details, see [HelpRoot_Financials\GL__con_GL_Consolidations|General Ledger Consolidation Process] and [HelpRoot_Financials\CM__con_Overview_of_Translations|Translation Processing Workflow]. {br}

If inter-branch transactions take place, they should be eliminated manually during period-end or year-end routine procedures. 
==Related Articles==
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_20_00|Branches] ([~/?ScreenId=CS102000|CS102000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_20_50_10|Buildings] ([~/?ScreenId=CS205010|CS205010])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_10_10_10|Inter-Branch Account Mapping] ([~/?ScreenId=GL101010|GL101010])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_10_30_20|Restriction Groups by Branch] ([~/?ScreenId=GL103020|GL103020])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_10_30_40|GL Accounts by Branch Access] ([~/?ScreenId=GL103040|GL103040])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_10_30_60|Subaccounts by Branch Access] ([~/?ScreenId=GL103060|GL103060])]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Basic Models for Multi-Branch Organization In today’s global environment, an organization may have a hierarchic structure of 				subsidiaries or branches and complex multi-level reporting requirements. Such an 				organization may need tools for easy data consolidation, as well as better 				visibility into various layers of financial operations within the organization.   Acumatica ERP supports multi-branch functionality and provides multiple basic one-level and 				two-level models, outlined in the sections below, for implementing the most typical 				organizational structures. For more complex organizations, such models may be 				combined to implement any structure.  Choosing the model (or combination of models) that suits your organization best 					is an important decision that must be made before you start implementing  Acumatica ERP.  Model 1: Organization with Centralized Accounting  With Model 1, shown in the illustration below, the organization, which is a single 				legal entity, consists of two branches (or locations), each branch representing a 				company office. Transactions are posted to these branches. To implement this model in  Acumatica ERP, you have to create an additional branch that will represent the legal entity. 				You also have to have one posting ledger of the  Actual  type. You need to specify the additional branch as the consolidating branch for the posting 				ledger by using the  Consolidation Branch  column on the   ([~/?ScreenId=GL201500|GL201500]) Ledgers (GL201500) form. The consolidating branch is used 				only in Form 1099-MISC and tax reports to represent the legal entity. No 				transactions are posted to the consolidating branch. To be able to use automatic generation of inter-branch balancing entries for 				documents that involve multiple branches, you need to enable the  Inter-Branch 					Transactions  feature on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features (CS100000) 				form, configure the posting ledger by selecting the check box in the 					 Branch Accounting  column for this ledger on the   ([~/?ScreenId=GL201500|GL201500]) Ledgers (GL201500) form, and define the inter-branch 				account mapping by using the   ([~/?ScreenId=GL101010|GL101010]) Inter-Branch Account Mapping (GL101010) form. If the  Branch Accounting  check box is cleared for the ledger, 				you still can make transactions between the branches (for example, transfer fixed 				assets from one branch to another), but the system does not create inter-branch 				balancing entries. The resulting batch remains unbalanced in each of the smaller 				branches, but the batch is balanced in the ledger that is assigned to the 				consolidating branch. In this case, the branches are not independent, and separate 				balance sheet reports cannot be prepared. Model 2: Autonomous Branches  In Model 2, illustrated below, the organization has a number of branches with a certain level 				of autonomy, with each branch being a legal entity. The organization and its 				branches share most of the vendors and customers but keep some of the trade partners 				as associated with a specific branch. Each branch keeps records of its own and has 				an accountant or accounting staff. The profitability of each branch can be equally 				important.  In  Acumatica ERP, autonomous branches may use separate ledgers to post their transactions or they 				may post their transactions to a single ledger with no branch selected as a 				consolidation branch. If the branches post their transactions to separate ledgers, 				the system will generate inter-branch transactions automatically. If the branches 				use the same ledger, to balance the original inter-branch transactions in each 				branch, you should select for this ledger a check box in the  Branch 					Accounting  column on the   ([~/?ScreenId=GL201500|GL201500]) Ledgers 				(GL201500) form. This allows each branch to file reports as a separate legal 				entity.  A certain level of independence requires that some of branches have their own General Ledger 				accounts that cannot be used by another branch. You can use restriction groups to 				assign selected General Ledger accounts and subaccounts to a specific branch for use 				by this branch only.  Model 3: Autonomous Multi-Location Branches  An organization might include a number of related legal entities with complex 				structures. Each legal entity has its headquarters and locations or smaller branches 				that are not separate legal entities. In this case, each autonomous multi-location 				entity keeps its own records and performs all accounting procedures.  In  Acumatica ERP, such an organization can be configured as a Model 3, which combines Model 1 and 				Model 2, functioning within one Company ID. (See the following illustration.) Each 				autonomous branch has its headquarters and locations (or smaller branches that are 				not separate legal entities) configured as branches. Each autonomous multi-location 				branch records its operations to a separate ledger with a  headquarters  branch 				specified as the  consolidation branch  for the ledger.  Generally, when transactions occur between any two non-independent branches in one ledger, no 				inter-branch transactions are generated; however, if they are needed for any reason, 				you can select a check box in the  Branch Accounting  column on the   ([~/?ScreenId=GL201500|GL201500]) Ledgers form for the ledger.  When the inter-branch transactions occur between any branches with different posting ledgers, 				balancing inter-branch transactions will be generated automatically. You should 				create inter-branch receivable and payable accounts in each ledger and specify the 				rules to be used by the system for generating balancing transactions by using the 					  ([~/?ScreenId=GL101010|GL101010]) Inter-Branch Account Mapping (GL101010) form. Model 4: Multi-National or Just Multi-Currency Organization  Small and midsize businesses sooner or later may face the problem of growth. They can grow by 				mergers or by creating local subsidiaries or branches in new regions or countries. 				Due to their locations, the organization subsidiaries use different base 				(functional) currency and should meet different reporting requirements (including 				non-matching financial years); their customers and vendors are not shared. For 				historical reasons, the organization subsidiaries may have different structures of 				accounts and subaccounts.  In  Acumatica ERP, such subsidiaries can have separate tenant accounts with different Company IDs. 				The simplest structure is shown by Model 4, illustrated below. Although technically 				the parent organization and its subsidiaries may keep their data in the same 				database, they may have different base currencies, different financial year 				settings, and separate lists of trade partners. Such subsidiaries even can be hosted 				on different websites.   Acumatica ERP provides the consolidation-related functionality to be used by both sides: the 				parent organization and its subsidiaries. If different base currencies are used by 				the parent company and its subsidiary, such subsidiaries can translate their 				balances before they prepare the consolidation data for exporting. For details, see 					 General Ledger Consolidation Process and  Translation Processing Workflow.  If inter-branch transactions take place, they should be eliminated manually during 				period-end or year-end routine procedures.   ([~/?ScreenId=CS102000|CS102000])  ([~/?ScreenId=CS205010|CS205010])  ([~/?ScreenId=GL101010|GL101010])  ([~/?ScreenId=GL103020|GL103020])  ([~/?ScreenId=GL103040|GL103040])  ([~/?ScreenId=GL103060|GL103060]) ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="2062b3d5-ce37-4664-aa94-b0bd2340af91" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="3564e791-3c23-a3df-0582-eb60044969da" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
If your organization has multiple branches defined in Acumatica ERP, you may need to control which employees get access to which branches. Because branches share some data, you may also need to control access to the shared data. Acumatica ERP provides user access roles, which you can use to control users&rsquo; access to branches, and restriction groups to limit the visibility of shared data. In this topic, you will read about ways to manage the security of a branch.[anchor|#_89584e23-d572-46cd-bf3f-c622497fba60]((({S:Hint}In Acumatica ERP, you can configure groups with direct and inverse restriction. In this topic, for simplicity, groups with direct restriction are used in examples. You can use inverse restriction groups in the same way as you use direct restriction groups. For details on the types of restriction groups, see [HelpRoot_Administration\SM__con_Types_of_Restriction_Groups|Types of Restriction Groups].
))){br}{TOC}
==Usage Scenarios==
The most common scenarios of managing the security of company branches are the following:[anchor|#_08217f27-34c7-4303-a300-0d4fd0841265]
*Managing user access to branches: If your organization has multiple branches (and you have created multiple branches in Acumatica ERP), you can configure access to branches for employees who work in these branches. For details, see [[#_1f2ffbc2-c39f-4c52-8bd6-f4f0df4872ee|User Access to Branches].
*Managing the visibility of data shared between branches: If you need to make data shared between branches (such as General Ledger accounts and subaccounts) visible only within a particluar branch, you can use restriction groups to resolve this task. For more information, see [[#_3dedf8c4-ef96-4dae-8bdd-0c432e7dfd2d|Visibility of Data Within a Branch].
((({S:Hint}You can create and maintain multiple branches in your Acumatica ERP instance only if the ''Multi-Branch Support'' feature is enabled in your system on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) form (for details, see [HelpRoot_Organization\CS__con_Multiple_Branch_Support|Multiple Branch Support]).
)))[anchor|#_1f2ffbc2-c39f-4c52-8bd6-f4f0df4872ee]
==User Access to Branches==
After multiple branches have been defined in the system, you provide access to the branches for users who will work in the system as follows:[anchor|#_383ec72c-e075-40f9-8a53-a29da73480ba]
#On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\SM_20_10_05|User Roles] ([~/?ScreenId=SM201005|SM201005]) form, you create branch-specific user roles (one role per branch) and assign these roles to user accounts. For details on user roles, see [HelpRoot_Administration\SM__con_Role-Based_Access|Role-Based Access].
#On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_20_00|Branches] ([~/?ScreenId=CS102000|CS102000]) form, you assign the roles to branches as follows: For each branch, in the '''Access Role''' box, you select the user role created for this branch.
((({S:Hint}[anchor|#_c9a89fe3-0895-47c9-8967-65e31cb48723]
*Once a role is assigned to one of the branches, other branches also must have roles assigned. A branch with no role assigned will be inaccessible to any user.
*To allow a user to access multiple branches, assign to him or her the roles for the branches to which the user should have access.
)))
If a user, based on his or her role, has access to a data entry form where this user enters a document and specifies the branch of origin, only the branches to which the user has access are available on the drop-down list. The users who have access to multiple branches can select the specific branch from the '''Branches''' menu on the form&rsquo;s title toolbar and create documents on behalf of the selected branch.{br}

No matter which branch users have access to, users who have access to the following forms, based on their roles, will see and work with all branches (because users configure system objects by using these forms):[anchor|#_10e33060-ec9b-4a30-826c-a3bbf507749b]
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_10_10_10|Inter-Branch Account Mapping] ([~/?ScreenId=GL101010|GL101010])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_20_00|Branches] ([~/?ScreenId=CS102000|CS102000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_20_50_10|Buildings] ([~/?ScreenId=CS205010|CS205010])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_50_00|Assignment and Approval Maps] ([~/?ScreenId=EP205000|EP205000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_40_60|Import Company Tree] ([~/?ScreenId=EP204060|EP204060])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_10_30_20|Restriction Groups by Branch] ([~/?ScreenId=GL103020|GL103020])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_10_30_40|GL Accounts by Branch Access] ([~/?ScreenId=GL103040|GL103040])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_10_30_60|Subaccounts by Branch Access] ([~/?ScreenId=GL103060|GL103060])
[anchor|#_3dedf8c4-ef96-4dae-8bdd-0c432e7dfd2d]
==Visibility of Data Within a Branch==
Branches have some data shared between branches and some data kept as branch-specific (for details, see [HelpRoot_Organization\CS__con_Multiple_Branch_Support|Multiple Branch Support]). You may need to restrict the visibility of data that is shared but may contain sensitive information, such as General Ledger accounts and subaccounts. Acumatica ERP provides restriction groups so you can control which accounts and subaccounts are used with which branch. For details on configuring restriction groups for accounts and subaccounts, see [HelpRoot_Financials\GL__con_Account_and_Subaccount_Security|Account and Subaccount Security].
==Forms for Branch Security==
In the following table, you can find the list of the forms that you can use to manage restriction groups with branches and the tasks that you can resolve by using each form.[anchor|#_82e55af4-0200-434b-858c-0a0a7d9c6451]
===Forms for Branch Security===
{| class="checklist" | width="100%" 
|- 
!width="50%" ! Task
!width="50%" ! Form
|- 
| To initially configure the visibility of accounts by branches
| [HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_10_30_40|GL Accounts by Branch Access] ([~/?ScreenId=GL103040|GL103040])
|- 
| To initially configure the visibility of subaccounts (or subaccount segments) by branches
| [HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_10_30_60|Subaccounts by Branch Access] ([~/?ScreenId=GL103060|GL103060])
|- 
| To change the visibility of system objects by a branch in multiple groups
| [HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_10_30_20|Restriction Groups by Branch] ([~/?ScreenId=GL103020|GL103020])
|}[anchor|#_aeb36c4e-8104-44fa-afdf-f04c69a627db]
For information about how to add or remove objects from a restriction group, see [HelpRoot_Administration\RS__con_Operations_Restriction_Groups|Operations with Restriction Groups].
==Related Articles==
*[HelpRoot_Financials\GL__con_Account_and_Subaccount_Security|Account and Subaccount Security]
*[HelpRoot_Organization\CS__con_Multiple_Branch_Support|Multiple Branch Support]
*[HelpRoot_Administration\SM__con_Types_of_Restriction_Groups|Types of Restriction Groups]
*[HelpRoot_Administration\SM__con_Overview_of_Restriction_Groups|Restriction Groups in Acumatica ERP]
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_55_00|Assignment and Approval Maps] ([~/?ScreenId=EP205500|EP205500])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_20_00|Branches] ([~/?ScreenId=CS102000|CS102000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_20_50_10|Buildings] ([~/?ScreenId=CS205010|CS205010])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_40_61|Company Tree] ([~/?ScreenId=EP204061|EP204061])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_10_30_40|GL Accounts by Branch Access] ([~/?ScreenId=GL103040|GL103040])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_10_10_10|Inter-Branch Account Mapping] ([~/?ScreenId=GL101010|GL101010])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_10_30_20|Restriction Groups by Branch] ([~/?ScreenId=GL103020|GL103020])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\GL_10_30_60|Subaccounts by Branch Access] ([~/?ScreenId=GL103060|GL103060])]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Security of Organization Branches If your organization has multiple branches defined in  Acumatica ERP, you may need to control which employees get access to which branches.                     Because branches share some data, you may also need to control access to the                     shared data.  Acumatica ERP provides user access roles, which you can use to control users' access to                     branches, and restriction groups to limit the visibility of shared data. In this                     topic, you will read about ways to manage the security of a branch. In  Acumatica ERP,             you can configure groups with direct and inverse restriction. In this topic, for             simplicity, groups with direct restriction are used in examples. You can use inverse             restriction groups in the same way as you use direct restriction groups. For details on             the types of restriction groups, see  Types of Restriction Groups. Usage Scenarios The most common scenarios of managing the security of company branches are the                     following: Managing user access to branches: If your organization has multiple branches                         (and you have created multiple branches in  Acumatica ERP), you can configure access to branches for employees who work in these                         branches. For details, see  User Access to Branches User Access to Branches. Managing the visibility of data shared between branches: If you need to make                         data shared between branches (such as General Ledger accounts and                         subaccounts) visible only within a particluar branch, you can use                         restriction groups to resolve this task. For more information, see  Visibility of Data Within a Branch Visibility of Data Within a Branch. You can create and maintain multiple branches in your  Acumatica ERP instance only if the  Multi-Branch Support  feature is enabled in your                     system on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features (CS100000) form                     (for details, see  Multiple Branch Support). User Access to Branches After multiple branches have been defined in the system, you provide access to the branches for users who will work in the system as follows: On the   ([~/?ScreenId=SM201005|SM201005]) User Roles (SM201005) form, you create branch-specific user roles (one role per branch) and assign these roles to user accounts. For details on user roles, see  Role-Based Access. On the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS102000|CS102000]) Branches (CS102000) form, you assign the roles to branches as follows: For each branch, in the  Access Role  box, you select the user role created for this branch. Once a role is assigned to one of the branches, other branches also must have roles assigned. A branch with no role assigned will be inaccessible to any user. To allow a user to access multiple branches, assign to him or her the roles for the branches to which the user should have access. If a user, based on his or her role, has access to a data entry form where this user enters a document and specifies the branch of origin, only the branches to which the user has access are available on the drop-down list. The users who have access to multiple branches can select the specific branch from the  Branches  menu on the form's title toolbar and create documents on behalf of the selected branch. No matter which branch users have access to, users who have access to the following forms, based on their roles, will see and work with all branches (because users configure system objects by using these forms):  ([~/?ScreenId=GL101010|GL101010]) Inter-Branch Account Mapping (GL101010)  ([~/?ScreenId=CS102000|CS102000]) Branches (CS102000)  ([~/?ScreenId=CS205010|CS205010]) Buildings (CS205010)  ([~/?ScreenId=EP205000|EP205000]) Assignment and Approval Maps (EP205000)  ([~/?ScreenId=EP204060|EP204060]) Import Company Tree (EP204060)  ([~/?ScreenId=GL103020|GL103020]) Restriction Groups by Branch (GL103020)  ([~/?ScreenId=GL103040|GL103040]) GL Accounts by Branch Access (GL103040)  ([~/?ScreenId=GL103060|GL103060]) Subaccounts by Branch Access (GL103060) Visibility of Data Within a Branch Branches have some data shared between branches and some data kept as branch-specific (for details, see  Multiple Branch Support). You may need to restrict the visibility of data that is shared but may contain sensitive information, such as General Ledger accounts and subaccounts.  Acumatica ERP provides restriction groups so you can control which accounts and subaccounts are used with which branch. For details on configuring restriction groups for accounts and subaccounts, see  Account and Subaccount Security. Forms for Branch Security In the following table, you can find the list of the forms that you can use to manage restriction groups with branches and the tasks that you can resolve by using each form. Forms for Branch Security Task Form To initially configure the visibility of accounts by branches  ([~/?ScreenId=GL103040|GL103040]) GL Accounts by Branch Access (GL103040) To initially configure the visibility of subaccounts (or subaccount segments) by branches  ([~/?ScreenId=GL103060|GL103060]) Subaccounts by Branch Access (GL103060) To change the visibility of system objects by a branch in multiple groups  ([~/?ScreenId=GL103020|GL103020]) Restriction Groups by Branch (GL103020) For information about how to add or remove objects             from a restriction group, see  Operations with Restriction Groups.  ([~/?ScreenId=EP205500|EP205500])  ([~/?ScreenId=CS102000|CS102000])  ([~/?ScreenId=CS205010|CS205010])  ([~/?ScreenId=EP204061|EP204061])  ([~/?ScreenId=GL103040|GL103040])  ([~/?ScreenId=GL101010|GL101010])  ([~/?ScreenId=GL103020|GL103020])  ([~/?ScreenId=GL103060|GL103060]) ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="8c42a9b2-f05f-46e5-907a-328c0170d6c9" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" Content="&#xA; Acumatica ERP provides you with tools for managing your organization&amp;rsquo;s employees. You can maintain the list of employees, specify employee payroll settings and calculate employee cost, manage all organizational processes in which a particular employee is involved, create a user account associated with an employee and set up its access rights in the system, and include employees in workgroups, approval maps, and assignment maps.&#xA;==In This Section==[anchor|#_c1dfa7ad-d178-4dcb-91d9-da5164c6993c]&#xA;{| class=&quot;checklist invisiblechecklist&quot; | width=&quot;100%&quot; &#xA;|- &#xA;| [anchor|#_9d84cb60-f554-4315-b1cb-47267861488c]&#xA;*[HelpRoot_Organization\OS__con_Employee_Settings|Employee Settings]&#xA;*[HelpRoot_Organization\EP__con_Company_Organizational_Chart|Company Tree and Workgroups]&#xA;*[HelpRoot_Organization\EP__con_Multiple_Calendar_Support|Support of Multiple Work Calendars]&#xA;&#xA;| &#xA;|}" PlainText="Managing Employees  Acumatica ERP     provides you with tools for managing your organization's employees. You can maintain the list of     employees, specify employee payroll settings and calculate employee cost, manage all     organizational processes in which a particular employee is involved, create a user account     associated with an employee and set up its access rights in the system, and include employees in     workgroups, approval maps, and assignment maps. In This Section Employee SettingsCompany Tree and WorkgroupsSupport of Multiple Work Calendars" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="ec996030-f230-4f15-5226-c03850bd3524" RecordSourceID="22377" />
		<row PageID="34b5f777-f645-4352-8b6e-b43333819d2a" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="4fc5943b-7995-6069-bcf6-fb9f8eeca43b" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
In Acumatica ERP, each employee has a personal employee account with the following groups of settings, each of which is described in more detail in the sections below:[anchor|#_c6851c29-c847-4c0d-9466-fd40859559fb]
*[[#_4099905a-64b1-44b7-b105-cf8ea79522dd|Contact information]
*[[#_5cb085b6-ef02-4194-9f71-1ebbc5fae4a4|User account information]
*[[#_8144a063-fe46-421b-bb47-8cb482f07ac2|Employment settings]
*[[#_3618211d-8346-4d1c-9c4c-13ae0dbb94c9|Financial settings]
*[[#_5c864a6a-6724-4fbe-b5cf-3f8f7b9a265a|Approval settings]

On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_20_00|Employee Classes] ([~/?ScreenId=EP202000|EP202000]) form, you can specify default values of some of these settings for an employee class. When you create a new employee on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_30_00|Employees] form, you specify an employee class, and then the system fills in many of the elements on the form with default values provided by the class.{br}{TOC}[anchor|#_4099905a-64b1-44b7-b105-cf8ea79522dd]
==Contact Information==
When you create an employee on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_30_00|Employees] form, a contact record associated with this employee is created automatically. The name, contact information, and address specified on the '''General Info''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_30_00|Employees] form always match those specified for the related contact on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CR_30_20_00|Contacts] ([~/?ScreenId=CR302000|CR302000]) form. If you modify these settings for an employee (or a contact), the changes are immediately reflected for the related contact (or an employee).[anchor|#_5cb085b6-ef02-4194-9f71-1ebbc5fae4a4]
==User Account Information==
An employee may have an associated user account so that the employee can access Acumatica ERP. On the '''User Info''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_30_00|Employees] form, a system administrator can view and edit information about the user account, create a new user account if none exists, activate, enable, disable, or unlock the user account, assign roles to the existing user, and manage the user's password.{br}

For more details about user accounts, see [HelpRoot_Administration\US__con_User_Accounts|User Accounts in Acumatica ERP].[anchor|#_8144a063-fe46-421b-bb47-8cb482f07ac2]
==Employment Settings==
On the '''Employee Settings''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_30_00|Employees] form, you can specify the following settings: [anchor|#_517ba48a-471b-49cb-9932-bd3f4efbd32e]
*The branch with which all transactions related to this employee will be associated
*The calendar that describes the work hours of the employee and the time zone the employee works from (see [HelpRoot_Organization\EP__con_Multiple_Calendar_Support|Support of Multiple Work Calendars] for information about how you can define and maintain multiple calendars in the system)
*The requirement for using time cards for the employee (for details about time cards and time reporting, see [HelpRoot_Organization\EP__con_Time_Sheet_Processing|Time Cards])
*The extent of validation of regular work hours for the employee. The requirements for the hourly rates of the employee are specified on the '''Employee Cost''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_30_00|Employees] form
*The non-stock item of the ''Labor'' type used as a source of expense accounts for transactions associated with projects or contracts. You can use the '''Labor Item Overrides''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_30_00|Employees] form to define the relationship between an earning type and a labor item, which is the source of expense accounts

On the '''Employment History''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_30_00|Employees] form, you can maintain information about the employee's history of employment in the company.[anchor|#_3618211d-8346-4d1c-9c4c-13ae0dbb94c9]
==Financial Settings==
On the '''Financial Settings''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_30_00|Employees] form, you can specify the accounts involved in the recording of employee compensation and payments, the employee's tax zone, and the payment method to be used by default for compensation payments.[anchor|#_5c864a6a-6724-4fbe-b5cf-3f8f7b9a265a]
==Approval Settings==
An employee may be assigned as an approver to approve a document or as an owner to process a record. On the''' Assignment and Approval Maps''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_30_00|Employees] form, you can review the list of all assignment and approval maps in which the employee is involved.{br}

On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_50_30_10|Approvals] ([~/?ScreenId=EP503010|EP503010]) form, an employee can approve or reject the documents of various types that have the ''Pending Approval'' status. Only the following documents are visible to the currently signed-in employee on this form: [anchor|#ul_ivq_b2g_g3]
*Those assigned to the employee.
*Those assigned to other users included in the workgroup to which the employee belongs.
*Escalated documents assigned to users of workgroups that are at lower levels in the company tree but in the node of the employee&rsquo;s workgroup. See [HelpRoot_Organization\EP__con_Company_Organizational_Chart|Company Tree and Workgroups] for details about the company tree.

The [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_50_30_10|Approvals] form is available only if the ''Approval Workflow'' feature is enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) form. If the ''Approval Workflow'' feature is disabled, no approval of documents can be set up, with an exception of expense claims; in this case, the system assigns an expense claim for approval to the employee specified in the '''Reports to''' box on the '''General Info''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_30_00|Employees] ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000]) form for the employee who is claiming the expenses; if the '''Reports to''' box is empty, the claim requires no approval—it is assigned the ''Open'' status, and it can be released immediately after submission. (For more information about the approval of expense claims, see [HelpRoot_Organization\EP__con_Claim_Approval|Expense Claim Approval].){br}

For details about assignment and approval maps, see [HelpRoot_Organization\EP__con_Assignment_Automation|Managing Assignment and Approval Maps].
==Related Articles==
*[HelpRoot_Organization\OS__MNG_Companies_and_Branches|Managing Companies and Branches]
*[HelpRoot_Organization\EP__con_Company_Organizational_Chart|Company Tree and Workgroups]
*[HelpRoot_Organization\EP__con_Multiple_Calendar_Support|Support of Multiple Work Calendars]
*[HelpRoot_Organization\EP__con_Assignment_Automation|Managing Assignment and Approval Maps]
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_20_00|Employee Classes] ([~/?ScreenId=EP202000|EP202000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_30_00|Employees] ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000])]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Employee Settings In  Acumatica ERP,     each employee has a personal employee account with the following groups of settings, each of     which is described in more detail in the sections below: Contact information Contact informationUser account information User account informationEmployment settings Employment settingsFinancial settings Financial settingsApproval settings Approval settingsOn the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP202000|EP202000]) Employee Classes (EP202000) form, you can specify default values of some     of these settings for an employee class. When you create a new employee on the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000]) Employees form, you specify an employee class, and then the system fills in     many of the elements on the form with default values provided by the class. Contact Information When you create an employee on the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000]) Employees form, a contact record     associated with this employee is created automatically. The name, contact information, and     address specified on the  General Info  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000]) Employees form always match those specified for the related contact on the        ([~/?ScreenId=CR302000|CR302000]) Contacts (CR302000) form. If you modify these settings for an employee     (or a contact), the changes are immediately reflected for the related contact (or an     employee). User Account Information An employee may have an associated user account so that the employee can access  Acumatica ERP.     On the  User Info  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000]) Employees form, a     system administrator can view and edit information about the user account,  create a new user     account if none exists, activate, enable, disable, or unlock the user account, assign roles to     the existing user, and manage the user's password. For more details about user accounts, see  User Accounts in Acumatica ERP. Employment Settings On the  Employee Settings  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000]) Employees     form, you can specify the following settings:  The branch with which all transactions related to this employee will be associated The calendar that describes the work hours of the employee and the time zone the employee      works from (see  Support of Multiple Work Calendars for information about how      you can define and maintain multiple calendars in the system) The requirement for using time cards for the employee (for details about time cards and time      reporting, see  Time Cards) The extent of validation of regular work hours for the employee. The requirements for the      hourly rates of the employee are specified on the  Employee Cost  tab of      the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000]) Employees form The non-stock item of the  Labor  type used as a source of expense accounts for      transactions associated with projects or contracts. You can use the  Labor Item       Overrides  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000]) Employees form to define the      relationship between an earning type and a labor item, which is the source of expense      accounts On the  Employment History  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000]) Employees     form, you can maintain information about the employee's history of employment in the     company. Financial Settings On the  Financial Settings  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000]) Employees     form, you can specify the accounts involved in the recording of employee compensation and     payments, the employee's tax zone, and the payment method to be used by default for compensation     payments. Approval Settings An employee may be assigned as an approver to approve a document or as an owner to process a     record. On the  Assignment and Approval Maps  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000]) Employees form, you can review the list of all assignment and approval maps in     which the employee is involved. On the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP503010|EP503010]) Approvals (EP503010) form, an employee can approve or reject the     documents of various types that have the  Pending Approval  status. Only the following     documents are visible to the currently signed-in employee on this form:  Those assigned to the employee. Those assigned to other users included in the workgroup to which the employee belongs. Escalated documents assigned to users of workgroups that are at lower levels in the company      tree but in the node of the employee's workgroup. See  Company Tree and Workgroups for details about the company tree. The   ([~/?ScreenId=EP503010|EP503010]) Approvals form is available only if the  Approval Workflow      feature is enabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features (CS100000) form. If the  Approval      Workflow  feature is disabled, no approval of documents can be set up, with an exception of     expense claims; in this case, the system assigns an expense claim for approval to the employee     specified in the  Reports to  box on the  General      Info  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000]) Employees (EP203000) form for the employee     who is claiming the expenses; if the  Reports to  box is empty, the claim     requires no approval—it is assigned the  Open  status, and it can be released     immediately after submission. (For more information about the approval of expense claims, see       Expense Claim Approval.) For details about assignment and approval maps, see  Managing Assignment and Approval Maps.  ([~/?ScreenId=EP202000|EP202000])  ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000]) ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="32ee0de4-1261-415f-8803-bb9dbcdf7d14" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="eb7a6307-2531-f00b-f59a-d8c468d7c33f" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
In Acumatica ERP, you can build a company tree, which is a model of your organization&rsquo;s hierarchy that includes temporary and permanent workgroups. The company tree may reflect the administrative hierarchy and include sub-hierarchies of workgroups created within specific branches or departments. The company tree is used for creating assignment rules in approval and assignment maps and for determining the scope of the users who want to view items assigned to them.{br}{TOC}
==Company Tree==
You create a company tree by using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_40_61|Company Tree] ([~/?ScreenId=EP204061|EP204061]) form. The company tree serves various purposes in addition to reflecting the administrative structure of your company. The tree doesn't directly include branches, departments, and administrative units within departments, but the tree should include all workgroups that participate in company workflows—for instance, the processing of leads and cases, the resolution of overdue cases, and the approval of various documents, such as time cards, expense claims, and purchase orders. {br}

If your company includes multiple branches, consider whether the workflows are completely contained within branches. If they are, for each company branch, create a separate tree branch that arranges the workgroups involved in this organization branch&rsquo;s workflows. If a workgroup of one of the branches participates in workflows of multiple branches, make sure this workgroup is located one level higher on the company tree than other workgroups. Also, make sure the members of this group have access to all the branches involved. 
==Workgroups and Owners==
A workgroup includes members who are employees of the company. Acumatica ERP places no restrictions on the number of group members or the number of groups a user may belong to. A group may include employees with different positions and from different departments. {br}

An employee may be a member of more than one workgroup if he or she participates in multiple workflows. For example, an employee might approve purchase orders greater than $1000 and all expense claims. On the other hand, a workgroup may include members from different departments if they participate in the same stage of a specific workflow, such as processing cases. Workgroups participating in the same workflow should be organized in a separate branch on the tree. Your company&rsquo;s tree should have a separate branch for assigning each type of document that can be automatically assigned. {br}

One member of the group should be specified as the ''owner''—the user to whom, by default, a new record or document will be assigned once the record or document is assigned to this workgroup. For example, if processing a case involves multiple employees and requires performing research, fixing the product or situation, filling out documents, and performing other activities, the owner can be a team lead who is responsible for the group. If processing a case involves only one person, the workgroup may include only one employee, who will also be its default owner. 
==Workgroups in Assignment and Approval Maps==
In Acumatica ERP, you can set up automatic assignment of the following entities to workgroups and to particular employees:[anchor|#ul_e3y_rhf_bv]
*Records for processing: leads, contacts, opportunities, business accounts, and cases 
*Documents for approval: expense claims, time cards, purchase orders, sales orders, and other documents 

This functionality uses assignment maps; it may also use the company tree that contains all workgroups involved in the assignment processes. You don&rsquo;t necessarily have to create a company tree or, if a company tree has been set up, you don&rsquo;t have to always use workgroups in assignment maps because you can specify particular employees as assignees; however, you can create more efficient assignment rules when using a company tree. For each type of document or record that should be automatically assigned, you create any number of assignment maps that define the rules for such assignment, and then, on the related module&rsquo;s preferences form, you specify which assignment map is to be used during the assignment process; for details, see [HelpRoot_Organization\EP__con_Assignment_Automation|Managing Assignment and Approval Maps]. 
==Related Articles==
*[HelpRoot_CRM\CR__con_Assignment_Rules_for_Cases_and_Leads|Assignment Rules]
*[HelpRoot_Organization\EP__con_Assignment_Automation|Managing Assignment and Approval Maps]
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\SM_20_10_10|Users] ([~/?ScreenId=SM201010|SM201010])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_40_61|Company Tree] ([~/?ScreenId=EP204061|EP204061])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_55_00|Assignment and Approval Maps] ([~/?ScreenId=EP205500|EP205500])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\CR_40_50_00|Cases] ([~/?ScreenId=CR405000|CR405000])]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Company Tree and Workgroups In  Acumatica ERP, you can build a company tree, which is a model of your organization's hierarchy 				that includes temporary and permanent workgroups. The company tree may reflect the 				administrative hierarchy and include sub-hierarchies of workgroups created within 				specific branches or departments. The company tree is used for creating assignment 				rules in approval and assignment maps and for determining the scope of the users who 				want to view items assigned to them. Company Tree You create a company tree by using the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP204061|EP204061]) Company Tree 				(EP204061) form. The company tree serves various purposes in addition to 				reflecting the administrative structure of your company. The tree doesn't directly 				include branches, departments, and administrative units within departments, but the 				tree should include all workgroups that participate in company workflows—for 				instance, the processing of leads and cases, the resolution of overdue cases, and 				the approval of various documents, such as time cards, expense claims, and purchase 				orders.  If your company includes multiple branches, consider whether the workflows are 				completely contained within branches. If they are, for each company branch, create a 				separate tree branch that arranges the workgroups involved in this organization 				branch's workflows. If a workgroup of one of the branches participates in workflows 				of multiple branches, make sure this workgroup is located one level higher on the 				company tree than other workgroups. Also, make sure the members of this group have 				access to all the branches involved.  Workgroups and Owners A workgroup includes members who are employees of the company.  Acumatica ERP places no restrictions on the number of group members or the number of groups a 				user may belong to. A group may include employees with different positions and from 				different departments.  An employee may be a member of more than one workgroup if he or she participates in multiple 				workflows. For example, an employee might approve purchase orders greater than $1000 				and all expense claims. On the other hand, a workgroup may include members from 				different departments if they participate in the same stage of a specific workflow, 				such as processing cases. Workgroups participating in the same workflow should be 				organized in a separate branch on the tree. Your company's tree should have a 				separate branch for assigning each type of document that can be automatically 				assigned.  One member of the group should be specified as the  owner —the user to whom, by 				default, a new record or document will be assigned once the record or document is 				assigned to this workgroup. For example, if processing a case involves multiple 				employees and requires performing research, fixing the product or situation, filling 				out documents, and performing other activities, the owner can be a team lead who is 				responsible for the group. If processing a case involves only one person, the 				workgroup may include only one employee, who will also be its default owner.  Workgroups in Assignment and Approval Maps In  Acumatica ERP, you can set up automatic assignment of the following entities to workgroups and 				to particular employees: Records for processing: leads, contacts, opportunities, business accounts, and 					cases  Documents for approval: expense claims, time cards, purchase orders, sales 					orders, and other documents  This functionality uses assignment maps; it may also use the company tree that 				contains all workgroups involved in the assignment processes. You don't necessarily 				have to create a company tree or, if a company tree has been set up, you don't have 				to always use workgroups in assignment maps because you can specify particular 				employees as assignees; however, you can create more efficient assignment rules when 				using a company tree. For each type of document or record that should be 				automatically assigned, you create any number of assignment maps that define the 				rules for such assignment, and then, on the related module's preferences form, you 				specify which assignment map is to be used during the assignment process; for 				details, see  Managing Assignment and Approval Maps.   ([~/?ScreenId=SM201010|SM201010])  ([~/?ScreenId=EP204061|EP204061])  ([~/?ScreenId=EP205500|EP205500])  ([~/?ScreenId=CR405000|CR405000]) ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="e82218ed-38dc-492c-9b42-f1a2f4f2032c" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="34f3e2a1-838b-43f0-bff7-68f189d8ea8b" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
In Acumatica ERP, you can define and maintain multiple work calendars in the system. Work calendars are used for a variety of purposes, including the following: 
*Labor calculations performed for contracts and projects
*Effective scheduling of events
*Tracking the movement of goods through carriers involved in shipping to and from your company

==Work Calendar Settings==
Work calendars can be defined on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_20_90_00|Work Calendar] ([~/?ScreenId=CS209000|CS209000]) form. For each employee calendar, you can define the week's work days and specify working hours for each day. On the '''Exceptions''' tab, you can define holidays, which preempt work days or shift them to a day when the employee generally does not work, and specify any change in working hours for a particular date. {br}

If the work calendar is used for a carrier rather than an employee, specify on which days goods are moved. 
==Employee Calendars==
On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_30_00|Employees] ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000]) form, you can associate calendars with particular employees, such as salespersons or members of customer service and support workgroups. If a calendar is to be used by others, the employee should mark his or her calendar as public by using the [HelpRoot_GettingStarted\SM_20_30_10|User Profile] ([~/?ScreenId=SM203010|SM203010]) form. {br}

An employee&rsquo;s calendar can also be used for labor calculation if the employee works in customer support or on projects. Work time and overtime are calculated automatically for time cards when the employee reports time spent on a case or a project task, if billable tasks and activities are used for the service contract or project. {br}

To organize work more efficiently, employees who work together should share information about their free and busy times. They can do this in the following ways: 
*In Acumatica ERP, users can export their work calendars, which show their free and busy time, and email the resulting file to involved persons.
*Users can export their calendar data from MS Outlook and import it to Acumatica ERP (in .cvs format). MS Outlook continues to periodically update the .cvs file when changes are made in Outlook. Currently, changes to the work calendar in Acumatica ERP do not update the calendar file exported to MS Outlook.

==Related Articles==
*[HelpRoot_CRM\CR__con_Assignment_Rules_for_Cases_and_Leads|Assignment Rules]
*[HelpRoot_Organization\EP__con_Company_Organizational_Chart|Company Tree and Workgroups]
*[HelpRoot_Financials\AR__con_Contract_Billing|Contract Billing]
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_10_00|Customer Contracts] ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\CT_30_30_00|Contract Usage] ([~/?ScreenId=CT303000|CT303000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_80_00|Equipment Time Card] ([~/?ScreenId=EP308000|EP308000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_30_00|Employees] ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_20_90_00|Work Calendar] ([~/?ScreenId=CS209000|CS209000])
*[HelpRoot_GettingStarted\SM_20_30_10|User Profile] ([~/?ScreenId=SM203010|SM203010])]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Support of Multiple Work Calendars In  Acumatica ERP, you can define and maintain multiple work calendars in the system. Work 				calendars are used for a variety of purposes, including the following:  Labor calculations performed for contracts and projects Effective scheduling of events Tracking the movement of goods through carriers involved in shipping to and from 					your company Work Calendar Settings Work calendars can be defined on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS209000|CS209000]) Work Calendar (CS209000) 				form. For each employee calendar, you can define the week's work days and specify 				working hours for each day. On the  Exceptions  tab, you can define holidays, 				which preempt work days or shift them to a day when the employee generally does not 				work, and specify any change in working hours for a particular date.  If the work calendar is used for a carrier rather than an employee, specify on which days 				goods are moved.  Employee Calendars On the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000]) Employees (EP203000) form, you can associate 				calendars with particular employees, such as salespersons or members of customer 				service and support workgroups. If a calendar is to be used by others, the employee 				should mark his or her calendar as public by using the   ([~/?ScreenId=SM203010|SM203010]) User Profile (SM203010) form.  An employee's calendar can also be used for labor calculation if the employee works in 				customer support or on projects. Work time and overtime are calculated automatically 				for time cards when the employee reports time spent on a case or a project task, if 				billable tasks and activities are used for the service contract or project.  To organize work more efficiently, employees who work together should share 				information about their free and busy times. They can do this in the following ways:  In  Acumatica ERP, users can export their work calendars, which show their free and busy time, 					and email the resulting file to involved persons. Users can export their calendar data from MS Outlook and import it to  Acumatica ERP (in .cvs format). MS Outlook continues to periodically update the .cvs file 					when changes are made in Outlook. Currently, changes to the work calendar in  Acumatica ERP do not update the calendar file exported to MS Outlook.  ([~/?ScreenId=CT301000|CT301000])  ([~/?ScreenId=CT303000|CT303000])  ([~/?ScreenId=EP308000|EP308000])  ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000])  ([~/?ScreenId=CS209000|CS209000])  ([~/?ScreenId=SM203010|SM203010]) ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="81a4c534-9bc8-4e11-9296-70ab5ae76240" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="9850092e-7541-45de-34a3-825f6f4265eb" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
 Acumatica ERP gives you the capability to automatically assign records (such as leads and cases) to employees for processing, to appropriately distribute work. When assigning a record to an employee, the system follows the rules and conditions specified in a previously created assignment map.{br}

Also, if the ''Approval Workflow'' feature is enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) form, you can use approval maps to assign documents (such as cash transactions, expense claims, time cards, and purchase orders) to authorized employees for approval.{br}{TOC}
==Supported Types of Maps==
 Acumatica ERP supports various types of maps that may include any number of steps, rules, and conditions for assigning a record to a qualified employee for processing or for assigning a document to an authorized employee for approval. Each map has a type, which can be one of the following:[anchor|#ul_glb_clf_4z]
*''Assignment Map'': Used for assigning business accounts, cases, contacts, email activities, leads, opportunities, purchase receipts, requests, or requisitions to owners for further processing.
*''Approval Map'': Used for assigning approvers to projects or documents, such as bills and adjustments, employee time cards, equipment time cards, expense claims, expense receipts, projects, purchase orders, requests, requisitions, sales orders, or transactions.
*''Assignment and Approval Map'': Used for either assigning entities to owners or assigning approvers to documents. Maps of this type were created in earlier versions of Acumatica ERP. This type remains supported by the system to avoid data loss.

By using the '''Add Approval Map''' or '''Add Assignment Map''' buttons on the form toolbar of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_55_00|Assignment and Approval Maps] ([~/?ScreenId=EP205500|EP205500]) form, you can start creating an approval or assignment map, which opens on a separate entry form.
==Approval Maps==
You can create a new map of the ''Approval'' type or modify an existing one by using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_50_15|Approval Maps] ([~/?ScreenId=EP205015|EP205015]) form.{br}

An approval map consists of steps and rules. In the '''Steps''' pane, you can create any number of steps, each of which may include any number of rules. Steps may be executed in a sequential, parallel, or sequential-parallel fashion.{br}

For each step, you need to select an action that should be performed if no approver has been assigned in accordance with the rules specified for this step, so the document becomes automatically approved or rejected or the next step (if any) gets executed. Also, you can specify whether a step is to be executed in any case or only if no approvers have been found at all previous steps.{br}

For each rule, you specify conditions, which the system checks for the document, and actions to be performed if the conditions are met. As a result, multiple approvers may be assigned to one document. You can configure a rule so that after one approver approves the document, the system waits until other appointed approvers (if any) also approve the document, executes the next step in the approval map, or marks the document as approved. Also, you can specify for each rule whether an approver would have to enter a comment each time he or she approves or rejects a document of the particular type.{br}

If a condition, step, or rule is no longer required in an approval map, you can temporarily deactivate it by clearing the '''Active''' check box in the settings of that condition, step, or rule on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_50_15|Approval Maps] form. A deactivated step or rule is marked with the '''(Inactive)''' prefix in the '''Steps''' pane.((({S:Hint}If you are creating rules for assigning documents for approval, documents that pass through the rules unassigned are considered in the system to be approved, so you don&rsquo;t necessarily have to create complete conditions. For example, in a small business, all documents with an amount greater than $1000 may need to be approved by the CEO. In this case, you would create rules to assign all documents with an amount that exceeds $1000 to a specific user (the CEO) for approval, while all other documents do not need to be assigned. The rules should be configured to assign only documents that have specific properties.
)))
On the '''Approval Details''' tab of a corresponding document entry form, all approvers assigned to the document are listed, and for each approver, additional information is displayed that helps track which approval map and which step and rule in this map is the reason this approver has been assigned.
==Assignment Maps==
Assignment maps are created and modified on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_50_10|Assignment Maps] ([~/?ScreenId=EP205010|EP205010]) form.{br}

An assignment map may include any number of rules, which are executed sequentially. Similarly to a rule in an approval map, a rule in an assignment map includes conditions and actions to be performed if the conditions are met.{br}

If you use assignment maps to distribute a particular type of record or document—for instance, to assign cases to different owners who will handle them—be sure to create a complete set of conditions so that no record or document of the specific type is left unassigned.{br}

If a condition or rule is no longer required in an assignment map, you can temporarily deactivate it by clearing the '''Active''' check box in the settings of that condition or rule on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_50_10|Assignment Maps] form. A deactivated rule is marked with the '''(Inactive)''' prefix in the '''Rules''' pane.((({S:Hint}If conditions allow the same documents to be assigned to two or more groups, all assignments will be performed in the group that is positioned higher than the other groups in the assignment map, and the documents would never reach the other groups. 
)))
==Map Application==
In Acumatica ERP, you can specify an assignment or approval map for a particular type of record or document by using one of the following forms:[anchor|#ul_thj_p5c_2v]
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_10_10_00|Time and Expenses Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=EP101000|EP101000]) form for expense claims, expense receipts, employee time cards, and equipment time cards
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\CR_10_10_00|Customer Management Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=CR101000|CR101000]) form for leads, contacts, business accounts, opportunities, and cases
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\SO_10_10_00|Sales Orders Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=SO101000|SO101000]) form for sales orders of any type for which the '''Require Approval''' check box selected on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\SO_20_10_00|Order Types] ([~/?ScreenId=SO201000|SO201000]) form
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\PO_10_10_00|Purchase Orders Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=PO101000|PO101000]) form for purchase orders of any type
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\RQ_10_10_00|Purchase Requisitions Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=RQ101000|RQ101000]) form for purchase requests and requisitions
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\CA_10_10_00|Cash Management Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=CA101000|CA101000]) form for cash transactions

Users can assign such records as leads, contacts, business accounts, opportunities, and cases in bulk by using the appropriate mass-processing form, such as [HelpRoot_FormReference\CR_50_30_10|Assign Leads] ([~/?ScreenId=CR503010|CR503010]) or [HelpRoot_FormReference\CR_50_32_10|Assign Cases] ([~/?ScreenId=CR503210|CR503210]).
==Map Execution Issues==
Any issues that occur during the execution of an assignment or approval map are recorded in the Acumatica ERP trace log. You can open the trace log by clicking '''Help''' > '''Trace''' on the form title bar. 
==Document Approval==
The appointed approvers can approve documents by using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_50_30_10|Approvals] ([~/?ScreenId=EP503010|EP503010]) form; only users authorized to approve documents should have access rights to this form. For more details, see [HelpRoot_GettingStarted\CO__con_Centralized_Approvals|Approving Documents].
==Approval Notifications==
In Acumatica ERP, you can set up approval notifications, by which an employee will receive an email notification each time a document requires approval from this employee.{br}

To enable approval notifications for a particular type of document, you need to specify an approval map for this type of document on the appropriate form, which can be one of the following:[anchor|#ul_bpf_nlq_cr]
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_10_10_00|Time and Expenses Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=EP101000|EP101000]) form, '''General Settings''' tab, for expense claims, expense receipts, and time cards
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\SO_10_10_00|Sales Orders Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=SO101000|SO101000]) form, '''Approval''' tab, for different types of sales orders
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\PO_10_10_00|Purchase Orders Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=PO101000|PO101000]) form, '''Approval''' tab, for different types of purchase orders
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\RQ_10_10_00|Purchase Requisitions Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=RQ101000|RQ101000]), '''Approval''' tab, for requests and requisitions
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\CA_10_10_00|Cash Management Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=CA101000|CA101000]) form, '''General Settings''' tab, for cash transactions
{br}

After you specify the approval map, on the same form, you need to specify the notification template that will be used for email notifications. You can create new templates or edit existing ones by using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\SM_20_40_03|Notification Templates] ([~/?ScreenId=SM204003|SM204003]) form.{br}

For cash transactions, sales orders, purchase orders, requests, and requisitions, you also need to select the '''Require Approval''' check box on the preferences form of the respective module; otherwise, the approval stage will be skipped.
==Related Articles==
*[HelpRoot_GettingStarted\CO__con_Centralized_Approvals|Approving Documents]
*[HelpRoot_CRM\CR__con_Assignment_Rules_for_Cases_and_Leads|Assignment Rules]
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_50_15|Approval Maps] ([~/?ScreenId=EP205015|EP205015])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_50_10|Assignment Maps] ([~/?ScreenId=EP205010|EP205010])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_40_61|Company Tree] ([~/?ScreenId=EP204061|EP204061])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\PO_30_10_00|Purchase Orders] ([~/?ScreenId=PO301000|PO301000])]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Managing Assignment and Approval Maps  Acumatica ERP gives you the capability to automatically assign records (such as leads and 				cases) to employees for processing, to appropriately distribute work. When assigning 				a record to an employee, the system follows the rules and conditions specified in a 				previously created assignment map. Also, if the  Approval Workflow  feature is enabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features (CS100000) form, you can use approval maps to 				assign documents (such as cash transactions, expense claims, time cards, and 				purchase orders) to authorized employees for approval. Supported Types of Maps  Acumatica ERP supports various types of maps that may include any number of steps, rules, and 				conditions for assigning a record to a qualified employee for processing or for 				assigning a document to an authorized employee for approval. Each map has a type, 				which can be one of the following: Assignment Map : Used for assigning business accounts, cases, contacts, 					email activities, leads, opportunities, purchase receipts, requests, or 					requisitions to owners for further processing. Approval Map : Used for assigning approvers to projects or documents, such 					as bills and adjustments, employee time cards, equipment time cards, expense 					claims, expense receipts, projects, purchase orders, requests, requisitions, 					sales orders, or transactions. Assignment and Approval Map : Used for either assigning entities to owners or 					assigning approvers to documents. Maps of this type were created in earlier 					versions of  Acumatica ERP. This type remains supported by the system to avoid data loss. By using the  Add Approval Map  or  Add Assignment 					Map  buttons on the form toolbar of the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP205500|EP205500]) Assignment and Approval Maps (EP205500) form, you can start creating an approval or 				assignment map, which opens on a separate entry form. Approval Maps You can create a new map of the  Approval  type or modify an existing one by 				using the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP205015|EP205015]) Approval Maps (EP205015) form. An approval map consists of steps and rules. In the  Steps  pane, you can create any 				number of steps, each of which may include any number of rules. Steps may be 				executed in a sequential, parallel, or sequential-parallel fashion. For each step, you need to select an action that should be performed if no approver has been 				assigned in accordance with the rules specified for this step, so the document 				becomes automatically approved or rejected or the next step (if any) gets executed. 				Also, you can specify whether a step is to be executed in any case or only if no 				approvers have been found at all previous steps. For each rule, you specify conditions, which the system checks for the document, and actions 				to be performed if the conditions are met. As a result, multiple approvers may be 				assigned to one document. You can configure a rule so that after one approver 				approves the document, the system waits until other appointed approvers (if any) 				also approve the document, executes the next step in the approval map, or marks the 				document as approved. Also, you can specify for each rule whether an approver would 				have to enter a comment each time he or she approves or rejects a document of the 				particular type. If a condition, step, or rule is no longer required in an approval map, you can 				temporarily deactivate it by clearing the  Active  check box in 				the settings of that condition, step, or rule on the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP205015|EP205015]) Approval Maps form. A deactivated step or rule is 				marked with the  (Inactive)  prefix in the 					 Steps  pane. If you are creating rules for assigning documents for approval, documents that 				pass through the rules unassigned are considered in the system to be approved, so 				you don't necessarily have to create complete conditions. For example, in a small 				business, all documents with an amount greater than $1000 may need to be approved by 				the CEO. In this case, you would create rules to assign all documents with an amount 				that exceeds $1000 to a specific user (the CEO) for approval, while all other 				documents do not need to be assigned. The rules should be configured to assign only 				documents that have specific properties. On the  Approval Details  tab of a corresponding document entry form, all 				approvers assigned to the document are listed, and for each approver, additional 				information is displayed that helps track which approval map and which step and rule 				in this map is the reason this approver has been assigned. Assignment Maps Assignment maps are created and modified on the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP205010|EP205010]) Assignment Maps 				(EP205010) form. An assignment map may include any number of rules, which are executed sequentially. 				Similarly to a rule in an approval map, a rule in an assignment map includes 				conditions and actions to be performed if the conditions are met. If you use assignment maps to distribute a particular type of record or 				document—for instance, to assign cases to different owners who will handle 				them—be sure to create a complete set of conditions so that no record or 				document of the specific type is left unassigned. If a condition or rule is no longer required in an assignment map, you can 				temporarily deactivate it by clearing the  Active  check box in 				the settings of that condition or rule on the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP205010|EP205010]) Assignment Maps form. A deactivated rule is marked with 				the  (Inactive)  prefix in the  Rules  				pane. If conditions allow the same documents to be assigned to two or more groups, all 				assignments will be performed in the group that is positioned higher than the other 				groups in the assignment map, and the documents would never reach the other groups. 			 Map Application In  Acumatica ERP, you can specify an assignment or approval map for a particular type of record or 				document by using one of the following forms:  ([~/?ScreenId=EP101000|EP101000]) Time and Expenses Preferences (EP101000) form for expense claims, expense 					receipts, employee time cards, and equipment time cards  ([~/?ScreenId=CR101000|CR101000]) Customer Management Preferences (CR101000) form for leads, 					contacts, business accounts, opportunities, and cases  ([~/?ScreenId=SO101000|SO101000]) Sales Orders Preferences (SO101000) form for sales orders of any type for which 					the  Require Approval  check box selected on the   ([~/?ScreenId=SO201000|SO201000]) Order Types (SO201000) form  ([~/?ScreenId=PO101000|PO101000]) Purchase Orders Preferences (PO101000) form for purchase 					orders of any type  ([~/?ScreenId=RQ101000|RQ101000]) Purchase Requisitions Preferences (RQ101000) form for purchase requests and 					requisitions  ([~/?ScreenId=CA101000|CA101000]) Cash Management Preferences (CA101000) form for cash transactions Users can assign such records as leads, contacts, business accounts, opportunities, and cases 				in bulk by using the appropriate mass-processing form, such as   ([~/?ScreenId=CR503010|CR503010]) Assign Leads (CR503010) or   ([~/?ScreenId=CR503210|CR503210]) Assign Cases 				(CR503210). Map Execution Issues Any issues that occur during the execution of an assignment or approval map are 				recorded in the  Acumatica ERP trace log. You can open the trace log by clicking  Help Trace  on the form title bar.  Document Approval The appointed approvers can approve documents by using the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP503010|EP503010]) Approvals (EP503010) form; only users authorized to approve documents 				should have access rights to this form. For more details, see  Approving Documents. Approval Notifications In  Acumatica ERP, you can set up approval notifications, by which an employee will receive an 				email notification each time a document requires approval from this employee. To enable approval notifications for a particular type of document, you need to specify an 				approval map for this type of document on the appropriate form, which can be one of 				the following:  ([~/?ScreenId=EP101000|EP101000]) Time and Expenses Preferences (EP101000) form,  General Settings  						tab, for expense claims, expense receipts, and time cards  ([~/?ScreenId=SO101000|SO101000]) Sales Orders Preferences (SO101000) form,  Approval  tab, for 						different types of sales orders  ([~/?ScreenId=PO101000|PO101000]) Purchase Orders Preferences (PO101000) form, 							 Approval  tab, for different types of purchase orders  ([~/?ScreenId=RQ101000|RQ101000]) Purchase Requisitions Preferences (RQ101000),  Approval  tab, for 						requests and requisitions  ([~/?ScreenId=CA101000|CA101000]) Cash Management Preferences (CA101000) form,  General Settings  						tab, for cash transactions After you specify the approval map, on the same form, you need to specify the notification 				template that will be used for email notifications. You can create new templates or 				edit existing ones by using the   ([~/?ScreenId=SM204003|SM204003]) Notification Templates (SM204003) 				form. For cash transactions, sales orders, purchase orders, requests, and requisitions, you also 				need to select the  Require Approval  check box on the preferences form of the 				respective module; otherwise, the approval stage will be skipped.  ([~/?ScreenId=EP205015|EP205015])  ([~/?ScreenId=EP205010|EP205010])  ([~/?ScreenId=EP204061|EP204061])  ([~/?ScreenId=PO301000|PO301000]) ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="62d8adc3-4fcf-415b-ab31-1d60ff2e294b" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="6666a97a-7e31-ce2b-79bc-d0bee9a30921" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
For a multistage approval process, you configure one approval map in which you define the conditions for each stage of the approval process.
==Workflow of Multistage Approvals==
With multistage approvals, a document is approved by multiple approvers in a fixed order; no reviews occur simultaneously. For example, if in your company all Accounts Payable bills should be initially approved by an accountant, and the bills whose total amount exceeds some threshold must also be approved by the top manager, you can configure a multistage approval process: Once an accountant has approved the bill in the first stage, that bill (if it matches the conditions specified for the second stage) goes to the top manager for final approval.{br}

You configure the multistage approval process by using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_55_00|Assignment and Approval Maps] ([~/?ScreenId=EP205500|EP205500]) form. On the '''Rules''' pane of this form, you add a row for each required approval stage (the '''Seq.''' column specifies the order number of the approval stage). In each row, you should specify the employee responsible for approving AP bills on the selected stage, and the workgroup in which the approver is included. On the '''Conditions''' pane, you specify the criteria that Accounts Payable bills must met to be assigned for approval at each stage. ((({S:Hint}For the multistage approval process, the ''Approval Workgroup ID'' parameter (available in the '''Field Name''' column of the '''Conditions''' pane) must be specified for each approval stage. By using this parameter, the system defines the order of approval stages. You must specify this parameter differently depending on whether you configure an approval process that consists of two stages or three or more stages. For details, see [HelpRoot_Organization\AP__How_To_Configure_Multistage_Approvals|To Create an Approval Map for Multistage Approvals].
)))
Besides the ''Approval Workgroup ID'' parameter, for each approval stage, you define the conditions that the documents should meet to be assigned to the approver of that stage. You can add as many specific conditions as needed (for example, whether the bill amount is above a specific threshold amount).
==Related Articles==
*[HelpRoot_Financials\AP__con_Approval_of_AP_Bills|Accounts Payable Document Approval]
*[HelpRoot_Organization\AP__con_Configuring_Approval_Maps_for_Parallel_Approvals|Configuring Approval Maps for Parallel Approvals]
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_10_10_00|Accounts Payable Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=AP101000|AP101000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_55_00|Assignment and Approval Maps] ([~/?ScreenId=EP205500|EP205500])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_40_61|Company Tree] ([~/?ScreenId=EP204061|EP204061])
*[HelpRoot_GettingStarted\CO__con_Centralized_Approvals|Approving Documents]]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Configuring an Approval Map for Multistage Approvals For a multistage approval process, you configure one approval map in which you define the     conditions for each stage of the approval process. Workflow of Multistage Approvals With multistage approvals, a document is approved by multiple approvers in a fixed order; no     reviews occur simultaneously. For example, if in your company all Accounts Payable bills should     be initially approved by an accountant, and the bills whose total amount exceeds some threshold     must also be approved by the top manager, you can configure a multistage approval process: Once     an accountant has approved the bill in the first stage, that bill (if it matches the conditions     specified for the second stage) goes to the top manager for final approval. You configure the multistage approval process by using the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP205500|EP205500]) Assignment and Approval Maps     (EP205500) form. On the  Rules  pane of this form, you add a row for     each required approval stage (the  Seq.  column specifies the order number     of the approval stage). In each row, you should specify the employee responsible for approving     AP bills on the selected stage, and the workgroup in which the approver is included. On the       Conditions  pane, you specify the criteria that Accounts Payable bills     must met to be assigned for approval at each stage.  For the multistage approval process, the  Approval Workgroup ID  parameter (available     in the  Field Name  column of the  Conditions  pane)     must be specified for each approval stage. By using this parameter, the system defines the order     of approval stages. You must specify this parameter differently depending on whether you     configure an approval process that consists of two stages or three or more stages. For details,     see  To Create an Approval Map for Multistage Approvals. Besides the  Approval Workgroup ID  parameter, for each approval stage, you define the     conditions that the documents should meet to be assigned to the approver of that stage. You can     add as many specific conditions as needed (for example, whether the bill amount is above a     specific threshold amount).  ([~/?ScreenId=AP101000|AP101000])  ([~/?ScreenId=EP205500|EP205500])  ([~/?ScreenId=EP204061|EP204061]) ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="2f453cf7-57a0-4b10-ae4e-d2cd4f402413" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="0d98221f-fdfe-fbbc-5ba9-a50d8b7d3eb9" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
You configure an approval map for a multistage approval process by using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_55_00|Assignment and Approval Maps] ([~/?ScreenId=EP205500|EP205500]) form.
==Before You Proceed==
Ensure that the employees who will approve Accounts Payable documents and these employees&rsquo; workgroups are specified on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_40_61|Company Tree] ([~/?ScreenId=EP204061|EP204061]) form. Review the organization's hierarchy of workgroups and, if needed, add new workgroups that include these employees.
==To Create an Approval Map for Multistage Approval==[anchor|#ol_dbx_lgs_tr]
#On the '''Organization''' tab, click '''Organization Structure'''. In the left pane, navigate to '''Manage''' > '''Assignment and Approval Maps'''.
#On the form toolbar, click '''Add New Record'''.
#In the '''Name''' box, type a name for the new approval map (for example, <tt>AP Bill Approval</tt>).
#In the '''Entity''' box, expand the '''Finance &gt; Accounts Payable &gt; Work area &gt; Enter''' nodes; click '''Bills and Adjustments'''.
#Click '''Save''' on the form toolbar. Notice that the map name is shown now in the '''Map''' box.
#On the '''Rules''' pane (to the right of the tree pane), specify an approver as follows:
##On the pane toolbar, click '''Add Row'''.
##In the '''Type''' column, select ''Assign''.
##In the '''Name''' column, type a description of the approval stage (for example, <tt>Approve by Accountant</tt>).
##In the '''Workgroup''' column, select the workgroup that includes the employee responsible for approving AP documents in the first stage. 
##In the '''Assign to''' column, select the employee to whom the documents will be assigned for approval. This employee will be able to see the list of documents assigned to him or her for approval on the '''My Approvals''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_50_30_10|Approvals] ([~/?ScreenId=EP503010|EP503010]) form.
##:((({S:Hint}Any member of the workgroup selected in the '''Workgroup''' column will also have the ability to approve or reject AP documents.
)))
#Click '''Save''' on the form toolbar. Notice that the stage number, ''1'', has appeared in the '''Seq.''' column.
#On the '''Conditions''' pane, define the conditions to be used for assigning the documents to the approver of the first stage as follows:
##On the toolbar of the '''Conditions''' pane, click '''Add Row'''.
##In the '''Entity''' column, select ''Document''.
##In the '''Field Name''' column, select ''Approval Workgroup ID''.
##In the '''Condition''' column, select ''Is Null''.
##:((({S:Hint}For the first stage of a multistage approval process, you must always specify the ''Approval Workgroup ID'' parameter as ''Is Null''.
)))
##On the toolbar, click '''Add Row''' to add the second row and specify the second condition. 
##:((({S:Hint}The settings recommended for the second row (that is, those in Steps 8.6–8.9) are provided as an example. In this example, all AP documents of the ''Bill'' type will be assigned to the approver of the first stage. 
)))
## In the '''Entity''' column, select ''Document''. 
##In the '''Field Name''' column. select ''Type''.
##In the '''Condition''' column, select ''Equals''.
##In the '''Field Value''' column, type {{INV}}. 
##Add a row for each additional condition you want to add for this stage, and specify the appropriate settings.
#On the '''Rules''' pane, add the second stage of the approval process as follows:
##On the pane toolbar, click '''Add Row'''.
##In the '''Type''' column, select ''Assign''.
##In the '''Name''' column, type a description of the second approval stage (for example, <tt>Approve by CEO</tt>).
##In the '''Workgroup''' column, select the workgroup that includes an employee responsible for approving AP documents on the second stage.
##In the '''Assign to''' column, select the employee to whom the documents will be initially assigned for approval.
#Click '''Save''' on the form toolbar. Notice that the stage number ''2'', has appeared in the '''Seq.''' column.
#To specify the conditions for the second approval stage, click the row with the second rule in the '''Rules''' pane, so that the conditions will apply to that rule.
#On the '''Conditions''' pane, define the conditions to be applied for assigning AP documents for approval in the second stage as follows:
##On the pane toolbar, click '''Add Row'''.
##In the '''Entity''' column, select ''Document''.
##In the '''Field Name''' column, select ''Approval Workgroup ID''.
##In the '''Condition''' column, select ''Is Not Null''. 
##:((({S:Hint}The condition ''Approval Workgroup ID Is Not Null'' must be specified for the second stage of the two-stage approval process.{br}

For an approval process that consists of three and more stages, for the second approval stage and each subsequent stage, you must specify the ''Approval Workgroup ID'' field name as follows. In the '''Condition''' column, you select ''Equals'', and in the '''Field Value''' column, you select the workgroup (by its name) that is specified as an approval workgroup for the previous approval stage (in the '''Workgroup''' column of the '''Rules''' pane). {br}

For example, for the second stage of the three-stage approval process, if the ''Finance'' workgroup has been specified for the first approval stage, you specify ''Approval Workgroup ID '' in the '''Field Name''' column, ''Equals'' in the '''Condition''' column, and ''Finance'' in the '''Field Value''' column. For the third stage, if the ''Supervisors'' workgroup has been specified for the second approval stage, ''Approval Workgroup ID'' in the '''Field Name''' column, ''Equals'' in the '''Condition''' column, and ''Supervisors'' in the '''Field Value''' column.
)))
##Add a new row to specify the next condition for this stage, and repeat as needed. 
#In the '''Rule Type''' box (located above the '''Conditions''' pane), select ''All conditions are true'', so that the documents will be assigned to the approvers only if all the specified conditions are true.
#Click '''Save''' on the form toolbar.

The approval map is configured for a multistage approval process.]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[To Create an Approval Map for Multistage Approvals You configure an approval map for a multistage approval process by using the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP205500|EP205500]) Assignment and Approval Maps (EP205500) form. Before You Proceed Ensure that the employees who will approve Accounts Payable documents and these                 employees' workgroups are specified on the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP204061|EP204061]) Company Tree                 (EP204061) form. Review the organization's hierarchy of workgroups and, if                 needed, add new workgroups that include these employees. To Create an Approval Map for Multistage Approval On the  Organization  tab, click  Organization                         Structure . In the left pane, navigate to  Manage Assignment and Approval Maps . On the form toolbar, click  Add New Record . In the  Name  box, type a name for the new approval map                     (for example,  AP Bill Approval ). In the  Entity  box, expand the  Finance > Accounts Payable > Work area > Enter  nodes; click  Bills and Adjustments . Click  Save  on the form toolbar. Notice that the map name                     is shown now in the  Map  box. On the  Rules  pane (to the right of the tree pane),                     specify an approver as follows: On the pane toolbar, click  Add Row . In the  Type  column, select  Assign . In the  Name  column, type a description of the                             approval stage (for example,  Approve by                                 Accountant ). In the  Workgroup  column, select the workgroup                             that includes the employee responsible for approving AP documents in the                             first stage.  In the  Assign to  column, select the employee to                             whom the documents will be assigned for approval. This employee will be                             able to see the list of documents assigned to him or her for approval on                             the  My Approvals  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP503010|EP503010]) Approvals (EP503010) form. Any member of the                                 workgroup selected in the  Workgroup  column                                 will also have the ability to approve or reject AP                             documents. Click  Save  on the form toolbar. Notice that the stage                     number,  1 , has appeared in the  Seq.  column. On the  Conditions  pane, define the conditions to be used                     for assigning the documents to the approver of the first stage as follows: On the toolbar of the  Conditions  pane, click                                  Add Row . In the  Entity  column, select                              Document . In the  Field Name  column, select  Approval                                 Workgroup ID . In the  Condition  column, select  Is                                 Null . For the first stage of a multistage approval process,                                 you must always specify the  Approval Workgroup ID  parameter                                 as  Is Null . On the toolbar, click  Add Row  to add the second                             row and specify the second condition.  The settings recommended for                                 the second row (that is, those in Steps 8.6–8.9) are provided                                 as an example. In this example, all AP documents of the  Bill                                  type will be assigned to the approver of the first stage.   In the  Entity  column, select  Document .  In the  Field Name  column. select                              Type . In the  Condition  column, select                              Equals . In the  Field Value  column, type                                  INV .  Add a row for each additional condition you want to add for this stage,                             and specify the appropriate settings. On the  Rules  pane, add the second stage of the approval                     process as follows: On the pane toolbar, click  Add Row . In the  Type  column, select  Assign . In the  Name  column, type a description of the                             second approval stage (for example,  Approve by                                 CEO ). In the  Workgroup  column, select the workgroup                             that includes an employee responsible for approving AP documents on the                             second stage. In the  Assign to  column, select the employee to                             whom the documents will be initially assigned for approval. Click  Save  on the form toolbar. Notice that the stage                     number  2 , has appeared in the  Seq.  column. To specify the conditions for the second approval stage, click the row with the                     second rule in the  Rules  pane, so that the conditions                     will apply to that rule. On the  Conditions  pane, define the conditions to be                     applied for assigning AP documents for approval in the second stage as                         follows: On the pane toolbar, click  Add Row . In the  Entity  column, select                              Document . In the  Field Name  column, select  Approval                                 Workgroup ID . In the  Condition  column, select  Is Not                                 Null .  The condition  Approval Workgroup ID Is Not Null  must be                                     specified for the second stage of the two-stage approval                                     process. For an approval process that consists of three and more stages,                                     for the second approval stage and each subsequent stage, you                                     must specify the  Approval Workgroup ID  field name as                                     follows. In the  Condition  column, you                                     select  Equals , and in the  Field                                         Value  column, you select the workgroup (by its                                     name) that is specified as an approval workgroup for the                                     previous approval stage (in the  Workgroup                                      column of the  Rules  pane).  For example, for the second stage of the three-stage approval                                     process, if the  Finance  workgroup has been specified for                                     the first approval stage, you specify  Approval Workgroup ID                                       in the  Field Name  column,                                          Equals  in the  Condition                                      column, and  Finance  in the  Field                                         Value  column. For the third stage, if the                                          Supervisors  workgroup has been specified for the                                     second approval stage,  Approval Workgroup ID  in the                                          Field Name  column,  Equals  in                                     the  Condition  column, and                                          Supervisors  in the  Field Value                                      column. Add a new row to specify the next condition for this stage, and repeat                             as needed.  In the  Rule Type  box (located above the                          Conditions  pane), select  All conditions are                         true , so that the documents will be assigned to the approvers only if                     all the specified conditions are true. Click  Save  on the form toolbar. The approval map is configured for a multistage approval process. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="91c561e3-06a9-49ba-85bd-3fbeb71a6633" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="f15df7d3-6c8c-eb38-a61e-7aac4b0032ee" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
For a parallel approval process, you need to configure multiple approval maps on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_55_00|Assignment and Approval Maps] ([~/?ScreenId=EP205500|EP205500]) form. Each approval map can contain its own conditions that must be met for Accounts Payable documents to be assigned to the specified approvers. 
==Workflow of Parallel Approvals==
Parallel approval means approval of a document by multiple employees in any order or even simultaneously. For example, in small companies, each purchase may need to be approved by an accountant and the CFO independently. In this case, you need to create two separate approval maps on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_55_00|Assignment and Approval Maps] form. In one map, you define the accountant as an approver; in another map, you define the CFO as an approver. You can specify no conditions, so that all AP documents will be independently assigned to the accountant and the CFO for approval; or you can specify the conditions to be used by the system for assigning the appropriate approvers to documents. These conditions can use such document properties as amount, vendor, or branch. {br}

For details on configuring the approval maps for parallel approvals, see [HelpRoot_Organization\AP__How_To_Configure_Parallel_Approvals|To Create Approval Maps for Parallel Approvals].
==Related Articles==
*[HelpRoot_Financials\AP__con_Approval_of_AP_Bills|Accounts Payable Document Approval]
*[HelpRoot_Organization\AP__con_Configuring_Multistage_Approvals|Configuring an Approval Map for Multistage Approvals]
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_10_10_00|Accounts Payable Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=AP101000|AP101000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_55_00|Assignment and Approval Maps] ([~/?ScreenId=EP205500|EP205500])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_40_61|Company Tree] ([~/?ScreenId=EP204061|EP204061])
*[HelpRoot_GettingStarted\CO__con_Centralized_Approvals|Approving Documents]]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Configuring Approval Maps for Parallel Approvals For a parallel approval process, you need to configure multiple approval maps on the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP205500|EP205500]) Assignment and Approval Maps (EP205500) form. Each approval map can contain its own         conditions that must be met for Accounts Payable documents to be assigned to the specified         approvers.  Workflow of Parallel Approvals Parallel approval means approval of a document by multiple employees in any order or even         simultaneously. For example, in small companies, each purchase may need to be approved by an         accountant and the CFO independently. In this case, you need to create two separate approval         maps on the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP205500|EP205500]) Assignment and Approval Maps form. In one map, you define the accountant as         an approver; in another map, you define the CFO as an approver. You can specify no         conditions, so that all AP documents will be independently assigned to the accountant and         the CFO for approval; or you can specify the conditions to be used by the system for         assigning the appropriate approvers to documents. These conditions can use such document         properties as amount, vendor, or branch.  For details on configuring the approval maps for parallel approvals, see  To Create Approval Maps for Parallel Approvals.  ([~/?ScreenId=AP101000|AP101000])  ([~/?ScreenId=EP205500|EP205500])  ([~/?ScreenId=EP204061|EP204061]) ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="bcf2257f-391c-4303-bc9d-326a9512e75e" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="705251f9-b553-e00e-546b-c0569407282d" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
You configure the approval maps for a parallel approval process by using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_55_00|Assignment and Approval Maps] ([~/?ScreenId=EP205500|EP205500]) form.
==Before You Proceed==
Ensure that the employees who will approve Accounts Payable documents and these employees&rsquo; workgroups are specified on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_40_61|Company Tree] ([~/?ScreenId=EP204061|EP204061]) form. Review the organization's hierarchy of workgroups and, if needed, add new workgroups that include these employees. 
==To Create Each Approval Map for Parallel Approvals==[anchor|#ol_ohd_rtc_jr]
#On the '''Organization''' tab, click '''Organization Structure'''. In the left pane, navigate to '''Manage''' > '''Assignment and Approval Maps'''.
#On the form toolbar, click '''Add New Record'''.
#In the '''Name''' box in the Summary area of the form, type a name for the new approval map, such as <tt>Approval by CFO</tt> or <tt>Approval by Financial Director</tt>.
#In the '''Entity''' box, expand the '''Finance &gt; Accounts Payable &gt; Work Area &gt; Enter''' nodes; click '''Bills and Adjustments'''.
#Click '''Save''' on the form toolbar. Notice that the map name is shown now in the '''Map''' box.
#In the '''Rules''' pane (to the right of the tree pane), specify an approver as follows: 
##On the pane toolbar, click '''Add Row'''.
##In the '''Type''' column, select ''Assign''.
##In the '''Name''' column, type a description for the approval rule being specified in this row (for example, <tt>Vendor bills over $5000</tt>).
##Optional: In the '''Workgroup''' column, select the workgroup that includes the employee responsible for reviewing AP documents.
##:((({S:Hint}The members of the specified workgroup will also be able to review and approve AP documents. If you want the documents to be reviewed and approved only by the person specified in the '''Assign to''' column, do not enter a workgroup.
)))
##In the '''Assign to''' column, select the employee responsible for reviewing the AP documents. This employee will be able to see the list of AP documents assigned to him or her for approval on the '''My Approvals''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_50_30_10|Approvals] ([~/?ScreenId=EP503010|EP503010]) form.
#Click '''Save''' on the form toolbar.
#If you need the documents that match some particular criteria to be approved, specify these criteria in the '''Conditions''' table. For example, if only the vendor bills whose total document amount is greater than some specified limit should be approved, you would specify these conditions as follows:
#:((({S:Hint}No conditions should be specified if all Accounts Payable documents should be forwarded to an approver.
)))
##On the pane toolbar, click '''Add Row''' to specify first condition.
##In the '''Entity''' column, select ''Document''.
##In the '''Field Name''' column, select ''Type''.
##In the '''Condition''' column, select ''Equals''.
##In the '''Field Value''' column, enter {{INV}}. 
##:The AP documents of the ''Bill'' type will be forwarded for approval.
##On the pane toolbar, click '''Add Row''' to specify second condition.
##In the '''Entity''' column, select ''Document''.
##In the '''Field Name''' column, select ''Amount''.
##In the '''Condition''' column, select ''Is Greater Than''.
##In the '''Value''' column, type the value that defines the total document amount. 
##:The AP bills whose total amount is greater than the specified value would be assigned for approval. The bills whose total amount is less than or equal to the specified value would not require approval, and would be ready for release once they are saved and taken off hold.
#:((({S:Hint} You can add as many conditions as you need. 
)))
#In the '''Rule Type''' box (located above the '''Conditions''' pane), select ''All conditions are true'', so that the documents will be assigned to an approver only if all the specified conditions are true.
#Click '''Save''' on the form toolbar.

By using the instructions above, you should create an approval map for each additional participant in the approval process.]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[To Create Approval Maps for Parallel Approvals You configure the approval maps for a parallel approval process by using the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP205500|EP205500]) Assignment and Approval Maps (EP205500) form. Before You Proceed Ensure that the employees who will approve Accounts Payable documents and these                 employees' workgroups are specified on the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP204061|EP204061]) Company Tree                 (EP204061) form. Review the organization's hierarchy of workgroups and, if                 needed, add new workgroups that include these employees.  To Create Each Approval Map for Parallel Approvals On the  Organization  tab, click  Organization                         Structure . In the left pane, navigate to  Manage Assignment and Approval Maps . On the form toolbar, click  Add New Record . In the  Name  box in the Summary area of the form, type a                     name for the new approval map, such as  Approval by CFO  or                          Approval by Financial Director . In the  Entity  box, expand the  Finance >                         Accounts Payable > Work Area > Enter  nodes; click                          Bills and Adjustments . Click  Save  on the form toolbar. Notice that the map name                     is shown now in the  Map  box. In the  Rules  pane (to the right of the tree pane),                     specify an approver as follows:  On the pane toolbar, click  Add Row . In the  Type  column, select  Assign . In the  Name  column, type a description for the                             approval rule being specified in this row (for example,                                  Vendor bills over $5000 ). Optional: In the  Workgroup  column, select the                             workgroup that includes the employee responsible for reviewing AP                                 documents. The members of the specified workgroup will also be                                 able to review and approve AP documents. If you want the documents                                 to be reviewed and approved only by the person specified in the                                      Assign to  column, do not enter a                                 workgroup. In the  Assign to  column, select the employee                             responsible for reviewing the AP documents. This employee will be able                             to see the list of AP documents assigned to him or her for approval on                             the  My Approvals  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP503010|EP503010]) Approvals (EP503010) form. Click  Save  on the form toolbar. If you need the documents that match some particular criteria to be approved,                     specify these criteria in the  Conditions  table. For                     example, if only the vendor bills whose total document amount is greater than                     some specified limit should be approved, you would specify these conditions as                         follows: No conditions should be specified if all Accounts Payable                         documents should be forwarded to an approver. On the pane toolbar, click  Add Row  to specify                             first condition. In the  Entity  column, select                              Document . In the  Field Name  column, select                              Type . In the  Condition  column, select                              Equals . In the  Field Value  column, enter                                  INV .  The AP documents of the  Bill  type                                 will be forwarded for approval. On the pane toolbar, click  Add Row  to specify                             second condition. In the  Entity  column, select                              Document . In the  Field Name  column, select                              Amount . In the  Condition  column, select  Is Greater                                 Than . In the  Value  column, type the value that defines                             the total document amount.  The AP bills whose total amount is greater                                 than the specified value would be assigned for approval. The bills                                 whose total amount is less than or equal to the specified value                                 would not require approval, and would be ready for release once they                                 are saved and taken off hold.  You can add as many conditions as you need.  In the  Rule Type  box (located above the                          Conditions  pane), select  All conditions are                         true , so that the documents will be assigned to an approver only if all                     the specified conditions are true. Click  Save  on the form toolbar. By using the instructions above, you should create an approval map for each                 additional participant in the approval process. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="a4843382-5d7d-4975-b544-64d1882d4df8" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" PlainText="Time and Expenses By using the Time and Expenses module, companies can automate time tracking and &#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;management by using time cards and expense claims, as well as use robust approval &#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;procedures for controlling time tracking and reporting. Your company can use the &#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;company tree and assignment maps to specify the hierarchy of workgroups that are &#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;involved in document approval processes and escalation routes and set up rules to &#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;assign work items for processing and documents for approval to the correct users and &#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;workgroups. The Time and Expenses module integrates tightly with Projects, also with Accounts &#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;Payable for reimbursing employee expenses, and with Accounts Receivable, for billing &#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;labor and expenses to customers. In This Part Overview of Time and Expenses ProcessesProcessing Expense ClaimsReporting TimeTime and Expenses Form ReferenceTime and Expenses Reports" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="c3765bd4-952a-c265-2aca-5789fae12ab6" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
By using the Time and Expenses module, companies can automate time tracking and management by using time cards and expense claims, as well as use robust approval procedures for controlling time tracking and reporting. Your company can use the company tree and assignment maps to specify the hierarchy of workgroups that are involved in document approval processes and escalation routes and set up rules to assign work items for processing and documents for approval to the correct users and workgroups.{br}

The Time and Expenses module integrates tightly with Projects, also with Accounts Payable for reimbursing employee expenses, and with Accounts Receivable, for billing labor and expenses to customers.
==In This Part==
*[HelpRoot_Organization\TM__TM_Features|Overview of Time and Expenses Processes]
*[HelpRoot_Organization\EP__con_Claim_Processing|Processing Expense Claims]
*[HelpRoot_Organization\EP__MNG_Time|Reporting Time]
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\TM__TM_Form_Reference|Time and Expenses Form Reference]
*[HelpRoot_ReportReference\EP__EP_Reports|Time and Expenses Reports]
]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="fe7abd56-05a9-404a-b547-63ecff208675" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="68c16961-0061-4e06-485c-c5ec5ab9db23" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
By using Acumatica ERP, your company can automate work assignments and labor calculation for contracts and support services. The Time and Expenses functionality integrates with Accounts Payable, for reimbursing employee expenses, and with Accounts Receivable, for billing labor and expenses to customers. 
==Expense Claim Processing==
Using a web browser, employees can submit expense claims, attaching any scanned receipts and supporting documents. The submitted expense claims are assigned for approval according to predefined assignment rules. Once a claim has been approved, Acumatica ERP creates a bill in Accounts Payable to initiate the reimbursement and generates a customer invoice if expenses were designated as billable to a customer. For more details, see [HelpRoot_Organization\EP__con_Claim_Processing|Processing Expense Claims]. 
==Time Tracking for Customers, Contracts, and Projects==
Regardless of where your employees work from, the time they spend on daily activities is recorded in time cards to track the expenses and billing. Once time cards have been automatically assigned for approval and approved by a supervisor, they generate a customer invoice and update contract usage data if a contract is involved. For more information, see [HelpRoot_Financials\AR__con_Contract_Billing|Contract Billing] and [HelpRoot_Organization\EP__con_Time_Tracking|Time Activities].
==Audit Trail==
 Acumatica ERP provides a complete audit trail of all employee transactions. After a document is approved and released, users cannot delete or cancel it. To correct mistakes, users must enter a correcting or reversing entry. Acumatica ERP keeps the details of all Time and Expenses documents, including information about the user who entered the transaction and the user who modified the record. ]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Overview of Time and Expenses Processes By using  Acumatica ERP, your company can automate work assignments and labor calculation for contracts 				and support services. The Time and Expenses functionality integrates with Accounts 				Payable, for reimbursing employee expenses, and with Accounts Receivable, for 				billing labor and expenses to customers.  Expense Claim Processing Using a web browser, employees can submit expense claims, attaching any scanned 				receipts and supporting documents. The submitted expense claims are assigned for 				approval according to predefined assignment rules. Once a claim has been approved, 					 Acumatica ERP creates a bill in Accounts Payable to initiate the reimbursement and generates a 				customer invoice if expenses were designated as billable to a customer. For more 				details, see  Processing Expense Claims.  Time Tracking for Customers, Contracts, and Projects Regardless of where your employees work from, the time they spend on daily activities is 				recorded in time cards to track the expenses and billing. Once time cards have been 				automatically assigned for approval and approved by a supervisor, they generate a 				customer invoice and update contract usage data if a contract is involved. For more 				information, see  Contract Billing and 					 Time Activities. Audit Trail  Acumatica ERP provides a complete audit trail of all employee transactions. After a document is 				approved and released, users cannot delete or cancel it. To correct mistakes, users 				must enter a correcting or reversing entry.  Acumatica ERP keeps the details of all Time and Expenses documents, including information about 				the user who entered the transaction and the user who modified the record.  ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="599fc24b-4c0a-4138-bbfc-43825b8d7458" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="fae490f8-92fb-055e-5202-70cfe5ea35da" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
By using Acumatica ERP, employees of your company can easily file their claims for reimbursement of expenses, which may include expenditures for travel, accommodations, and freight charges. With Acumatica ERP, expense claims can be prepared, approved, and processed in accordance with the process of claim submission adopted by your company.{br}

Each expense claim is based on expense receipts that an employee enters into the system. A claim can include any number of receipts, each having its own settings. An employee can enter expense receipts on the fly, submit them for approval, and then, at a convenient time (for instance, the end of the month), claim approved receipts in bulk to generate the corresponding expense claims. As soon as a new claim is generated, the system automatically routes it to the authorized person for approval (and adjustment, if needed). Once the claim is approved, it can be released. When an expense claim is released, the system automatically generates a bill to reimburse the expenses to the employee. If the employee incurred the expenses while working on a project for a customer, the system also prepares the records for billing the customer.
==In This Chapter==[anchor|#ul_uln_ttr_rq]
*[HelpRoot_Organization\EP__con_Expense_Receipts|Expense Receipts]
*[HelpRoot_Organization\EP__con_Receipt_Approval|Expense Receipt Approval]
*[HelpRoot_Organization\EP__con_Expense_Claims|Expense Claims]
*[HelpRoot_Organization\EP__con_Claim_Approval|Expense Claim Approval]
*[HelpRoot_Organization\EP__con_Claim_Release|Expense Claim Release]
]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Processing Expense Claims By using  Acumatica ERP, employees of your company can easily file their claims for reimbursement of 				expenses, which may include expenditures for travel, accommodations, and freight 				charges. With  Acumatica ERP, expense claims can be prepared, approved, and processed in accordance with the 				process of claim submission adopted by your company. Each expense claim is based on expense receipts that an employee enters into the system. A 				claim can include any number of receipts, each having its own settings. An employee 				can enter expense receipts on the fly, submit them for approval, and then, at a 				convenient time (for instance, the end of the month), claim approved receipts in 				bulk to generate the corresponding expense claims. As soon as a new claim is 				generated, the system automatically routes it to the authorized person for approval 				(and adjustment, if needed). Once the claim is approved, it can be released. When an 				expense claim is released, the system automatically generates a bill to reimburse 				the expenses to the employee. If the employee incurred the expenses while working on 				a project for a customer, the system also prepares the records for billing the 				customer. In This Chapter Expense ReceiptsExpense Receipt ApprovalExpense ClaimsExpense Claim ApprovalExpense Claim Release]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="09ffefec-2924-41b2-8bf7-cc0631f5bd65" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="e651060e-34d8-60b9-82d7-3df8d8268c8a" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
In Acumatica ERP, an expense receipt is a record reflecting that an employee performed a transaction while working for your organization, thus incurring certain expenses.{br}{TOC}
==Properties of an Expense Receipt==
Each receipt can have the following properties:[anchor|#ul_b1x_fjm_dp]
*The expense non-stock item, which defines the financial accounts, the default tax calculation mode and tax category, and the unit of measure used for the receipt. If a standard cost is specified for the item, it is used as the default unit cost. Suppose, for example, that your company reimburses expenses that the employee incurs while using a personal vehicle for company purposes. In this case, the non-stock item would represent the mileage, and you can specify the standard rate per mile as the standard cost.
*:((({S:Hint}The expense subaccount is combined according to the settings specified on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_10_10_00|Time and Expenses Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=EP101000|EP101000]) form.
)))
*The name of the employee who is claiming the expenses.
*The default tax zone, which is copied from the employee&rsquo;s settings; a user can override the tax zone in a particular receipt. The overridden tax zone value can be saved for future use.
*The total amount of the receipt, the tax amount (if applicable), the employee part (that is, the part of the total amount that will not be paid back to the employee), the tip amount (if applicable), and the claim amount (that is, the amount to be reimbursed to the employee, which is calculated by the following rule: '''Claim Amount''' = '''Amount''' + '''Tax Total''' (if taxes are exclusive) + '''Tip Amount''' – '''Employee Part''').
*The receipt currency, which can be any currency registered in the system. You can configure new currencies by using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CM_20_20_00|Currencies] ([~/?ScreenId=CM202000|CM202000]) form.
*The reference number (optional) specified by the employee, which usually matches the number of the original receipt.
*The project or contract, which should be specified if the employee incurred the expenses while working on a particular project or contract. (In this case, the customer associated with the project or contract is filled in automatically.)
*The customer, which should be specified if the employee incurred the expenses while working for a particular customer.
*The scanned image of the original receipt.
*The tax calculation mode. If the ''Net/Gross Entry Mode'' feature is enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) form, you can select whether the amounts that you enter in the expense receipt are tax-exclusive (net) or tax-inclusive (gross). For more information, see [HelpRoot_Financials\TX__con_VAT_in_Expense_Receipts#section_kkz_qp2_jbb|Tax-Exclusive and Tax-Inclusive Amounts in Expense Receipts].

==Access to Expense Receipts==
By using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_10_10|Expense Receipts] ([~/?ScreenId=EP301010|EP301010]) form, you can enter, view, and edit any of the following expense receipts:[anchor|#ul_mvf_pcb_2p]
*Your own receipts
*Receipts of employees in the workgroups at lower levels in the company tree than your workgroup
*Receipts that require your approval
*Receipts of employees for whom you are an appointed delegate; all delegates of an employee are listed on the '''Delegates''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_30_00|Employees] ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000]) form

Also, you can view expense receipts included in the expense claims that require your approval.{br}

On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_50_30_10|Approvals] ([~/?ScreenId=EP503010|EP503010]) form, which is available if the ''Approval Workflow'' feature is enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) form, you can approve or reject receipts assigned to you, to the members of your workgroup, and to the members of the workgroups at lower levels in the company tree than your workgroup.
==Statuses of an Expense Receipts==
On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_10_10|Expense Receipts] form, you can also view the status of the expense receipt, which reflects its processing stage. Typical statuses for expense receipts might include the following:[anchor|#ul_edq_smd_2y]
*''On Hold'': The receipt is new and has not been submitted for approval yet, or the receipt has been rejected and then put on hold while a user is adjusting it.
*''Open'': The receipt is ready to be added to a claim after it has been approved (if approval is required for the receipt) or after it has been submitted for further processing (if approval is not required).
*''Pending Approval'': The receipt is pending approval.
*''Rejected'': The receipt has been rejected.
*''Released'': The expense claim associated with the receipt has been released.

==Approval of Expense Receipts==
If the ''Approval Workflow'' feature is enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] form, expense receipts that have been entered can be submitted for approval. For details, see [HelpRoot_Organization\EP__con_Receipt_Approval|Expense Receipt Approval].
==Generation of Expense Claims==
Expense receipts with the ''Open'' status can be claimed selectively or all at once to form expense claims. When you claim multiple receipts, they may form multiple claims where receipts will be grouped by their common properties. Receipts that have different employees, branches, or customers are always split into different claims. For details, see [HelpRoot_Organization\EP__HOW_To_Submit_Expense_Receipts|To Generate Expense Claims].{br}

Also, if the '''Allow Mixed Tax Settings in Claims''' check box is selected on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_10_10_00|Time and Expenses Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=EP101000|EP101000]) form, a user can add expense receipts with a different tax zone or tax calculation mode (or both) to one claim. When this expense claim is released, the system generates multiple Accounts Payable bills, each of which contains expense receipts with the same tax zone and tax calculation mode. For more information, see [HelpRoot_Financials\TX__con_VAT_in_Expense_Receipts#section_fhb_sjf_jbb|Expense Receipts with Mixed Tax Settings].
==Related Articles==
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\CM_20_20_00|Currencies] ([~/?ScreenId=CM202000|CM202000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_30_00|Employees] ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_10_10|Expense Receipts] ([~/?ScreenId=EP301010|EP301010])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_10_10_00|Time and Expenses Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=EP101000|EP101000])]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Expense Receipts In  Acumatica ERP,     an expense receipt is a record reflecting that an employee performed a transaction while working     for your organization, thus incurring certain expenses. Properties of an Expense Receipt Each receipt can have the following properties: The expense non-stock item, which defines the financial accounts, the default tax      calculation mode and tax category, and the unit of measure used for the receipt. If a standard      cost is specified for the item, it is used as the default unit cost. Suppose, for example, that      your company reimburses expenses that the employee incurs while using a personal vehicle for      company purposes. In this case, the non-stock item would represent the mileage, and you can      specify the standard rate per mile as the standard cost. The expense subaccount is       combined according to the settings specified on the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP101000|EP101000]) Time and Expenses Preferences       (EP101000) form. The name of the employee who is claiming the expenses. The default tax zone, which is copied from the employee's settings; a user can override the      tax zone in a particular receipt. The overridden tax zone value can be saved for future      use. The total amount of the receipt, the tax amount (if applicable), the employee part (that is,      the part of the total amount that will not be paid back to the employee), the tip amount (if      applicable), and the claim amount (that is, the amount to be reimbursed to the employee, which      is calculated by the following rule:  Claim Amount  =        Amount  +  Tax Total  (if taxes are exclusive) +        Tip Amount  –  Employee Part ). The receipt currency, which can be any currency registered in the system. You can configure      new currencies by using the   ([~/?ScreenId=CM202000|CM202000]) Currencies (CM202000) form. The reference number (optional) specified by the employee, which usually matches the number      of the original receipt. The project or contract, which should be specified if the employee incurred the expenses      while working on a particular project or contract. (In this case, the customer associated with      the project or contract is filled in automatically.) The customer, which should be specified if the employee incurred the expenses while working      for a particular customer. The scanned image of the original receipt. The tax calculation mode. If the  Net/Gross Entry Mode  feature is enabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features (CS100000) form, you can select whether the amounts that you      enter in the expense receipt are tax-exclusive (net) or tax-inclusive (gross). For more      information, see  Tax-Exclusive and Tax-Inclusive Amounts in Expense Receipts. Access to Expense Receipts By using the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP301010|EP301010]) Expense Receipts (EP301010) form, you can enter, view, and     edit any of the following expense receipts: Your own receipts Receipts of employees in the workgroups at lower levels in the company tree than your     workgroup Receipts that require your approval Receipts of employees for whom you are an appointed delegate; all delegates of an employee     are listed on the  Delegates  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000]) Employees     (EP203000) form Also, you can view expense receipts included in the expense claims that require your     approval. On the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP503010|EP503010]) Approvals (EP503010) form, which is available if the       Approval Workflow  feature is enabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features     (CS100000) form, you can approve or reject receipts assigned to you, to the members of your     workgroup, and to the members of the workgroups at lower levels in the company tree than your     workgroup. Statuses of an Expense Receipts On the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP301010|EP301010]) Expense Receipts form, you can also view the status of the expense     receipt, which reflects its processing stage. Typical statuses for expense receipts might     include the following: On Hold : The receipt is new and has not been submitted for approval yet, or the      receipt has been rejected and then put on hold while a user is adjusting it. Open : The receipt is ready to be added to a claim after it has been approved (if      approval is required for the receipt) or after it has been submitted for further processing (if      approval is not required). Pending Approval : The receipt is pending approval. Rejected : The receipt has been rejected. Released : The expense claim associated with the receipt has been released. Approval of Expense Receipts If the  Approval Workflow  feature is enabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features     form, expense receipts that have been entered can be submitted for approval. For details, see       Expense Receipt Approval. Generation of Expense Claims Expense receipts with the  Open  status can be claimed selectively or all at once to form     expense claims. When you claim multiple receipts, they may form multiple claims where receipts     will be grouped by their common properties. Receipts that have different employees, branches, or     customers are always split into different claims. For details, see  To Generate Expense Claims. Also, if the  Allow Mixed Tax Settings in Claims  check box is selected     on the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP101000|EP101000]) Time and Expenses Preferences (EP101000) form, a user can add expense receipts with     a different tax zone or tax calculation mode (or both) to one claim. When this expense claim is     released, the system generates multiple Accounts Payable bills, each of which contains expense     receipts with the same tax zone and tax calculation mode. For more information, see  Expense Receipts with Mixed Tax Settings.  ([~/?ScreenId=CM202000|CM202000])  ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000])  ([~/?ScreenId=EP301010|EP301010])  ([~/?ScreenId=EP101000|EP101000]) ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="4f957efc-c775-4fc7-82aa-f7c33eb5d23c" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="cfbbf7f4-75ce-f082-79b5-f03f1f126f48" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
You can create an expense receipt by using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_10_10|Expense Receipts] ([~/?ScreenId=EP301010|EP301010]) form as a starting point. From there, you can add a new expense receipt on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_10_20|Expense Receipt] ([~/?ScreenId=EP301020|EP301020]) form. On this form, you can create the following expense receipts:[anchor|#ul_inq_x2j_hp]
*Your own receipts
*The receipts of employees in workgroups at lower levels in the company tree than your workgroup
*The receipts of employees for whom you are an appointed delegate; all delegates of a particular employee are listed on the '''Delegates''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_30_00|Employees] ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000]) form

==To Create an Expense Receipt==[anchor|#ol_hk2_lfj_hp]
#On the '''Organization''' tab, click '''Time & Expenses'''. In the left pane, select the '''Work Area''' tab, and then navigate to '''Enter''' > '''Expense Receipts'''.
#On the form toolbar, click '''Add New Record'''.
#:The system navigates to the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_10_20|Expense Receipt] form so that you can enter a new expense receipt.
#In the Summary area, specify the following:
##In the '''Date''' box, select the date when the receipt was issued.
##In the '''Expense Item''' box, select the expense non-stock item, which defines the type of the expense. From the settings of this item, the system copies the financial accounts, the default tax category, the standard cost, and the unit of measure used for the receipt.
##:((({S:Hint}If the ''Net/Gross Entry Mode'' feature is enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) form, the default tax calculation mode is also copied from the settings of the selected expense item.
)))
##In the '''Claimed by''' box, select the employee who is claiming the expenses.
##In the '''Branch''' box, select the branch that will reimburse the expenses to the employee.
#On the '''Receipt Details''' tab, in the '''Expense Details''' section, specify the receipt information as follows:
##In the '''Description''' box, type a brief description of the expenses. In the table on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_10_10|Expense Receipts] ([~/?ScreenId=EP301010|EP301010]) form, this description will be used as a link the user can click to open the current form and view the details of the receipt.
##In the '''Quantity''' box, type the quantity of the expense item that the employee purchased according to the receipt. The quantity is expressed in the unit of measure specified in the '''UOM''' box, which is the unit specified for the selected non-stock item on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\IN_20_20_00|Non-Stock Items] form.
##Optional: In the '''Unit Cost''' box, manually override the default value (if one exists), which is the standard cost specified for a unit of the expense non-stock item, or specify the amount in the '''Amount''' box .
##In the '''Employee Part''' box, type the part of the total amount that will not be reimbursed to the employee (that is, the part for which the employee is responsible). 
##:((({S:Hint}Note: If the amount in the '''Amount''' box includes taxes, the '''Employee Part''' should also be specified with the taxes included.
)))
##In the '''Currency''' box, change the currency to that of the receipt, if necessary. If the currency of the receipt is not yet registered in the system, you can create a new currency by using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CM_20_20_00|Currencies] ([~/?ScreenId=CM202000|CM202000]) form.
##Optional: In the '''Ref. Nbr.''' box, type the number of the original receipt, which can be used for future reference.
##In the '''Project/Contract''' box, select the applicable project or contract if the employee incurred the expenses while working on a particular project or contract.
##In the '''Project Task''' box, select the project task to which the expenses are related.
##Optional: In the '''Expense Claim''' box, select an existing expense claim with which you want to associate the expense receipt.
#Optional: In the '''Tax Info''' section, change any of the default tax settings for the receipt as follows:
##In the '''Tax Zone''' box, specify the tax zone that applies to the expense receipt.
## In the '''Tax Calculation''' box, which is available if the ''Net/Gross Entry Mode'' feature is enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) form, specify whether the entered amounts are tax-inclusive or tax-exclusive.
##In the '''Tax Category''' box, select the tax category for the expense item.
#In the '''Financial Details''' section, specify the information to classify the receipt as follows:
##Select the '''Billable''' check box if a customer should be billed for the expense amount.
##In the '''Customer''' box, select a customer if the employee incurred the expenses while working for a particular customer. If you have already selected a project or contract in the '''Project/Contract''' box, the system automatically filled in the customer and it cannot be changed.
#Optional: In the '''Image''' section, do the following:
##Click '''Browse''' to open the file selection window, and select the image of the original receipt.
##Click '''Upload''' to attach the image file to the expense receipt record.
#Optional: On the '''Tax Details''' tab, correct the tax amounts in the '''Tax Amount''' column.
#On the form toolbar, click '''Save''' to save the expense receipt.
]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[To Create an Expense Receipt You can create an expense receipt by using the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP301010|EP301010]) Expense Receipts                 (EP301010) form as a starting point. From there, you can add a new expense                 receipt on the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP301020|EP301020]) Expense Receipt (EP301020) form. On this form, you                 can create the following expense receipts: Your own receipts The receipts of employees in workgroups at lower levels in the company tree                         than your workgroup The receipts of employees for whom you are an appointed delegate; all                         delegates of a particular employee are listed on the                              Delegates  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000]) Employees (EP203000) form To Create an Expense Receipt On the  Organization  tab, click  Time &                         Expenses . In the left pane, select the  Work                         Area  tab, and then navigate to  Enter Expense Receipts . On the form toolbar, click  Add New Record . The system                         navigates to the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP301020|EP301020]) Expense Receipt form so that you can enter                         a new expense receipt. In the Summary area, specify the following: In the  Date  box, select the date when the receipt                             was issued. In the  Expense Item  box, select the expense                             non-stock item, which defines the type of the expense. From the settings                             of this item, the system copies the financial accounts, the default tax                             category, the standard cost, and the unit of measure used for the                                 receipt. If the  Net/Gross Entry Mode  feature is enabled                                 on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features (CS100000) form, the                                 default tax calculation mode is also copied from the settings of the                                 selected expense item. In the  Claimed by  box, select the employee who is                             claiming the expenses. In the  Branch  box, select the branch that will                             reimburse the expenses to the employee. On the  Receipt Details  tab, in the  Expense                         Details  section, specify the receipt information as follows: In the  Description  box, type a brief description                             of the expenses. In the table on the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP301010|EP301010]) Expense Receipts                             (EP301010) form, this description will be used as a link the user can                             click to open the current form and view the details of the receipt. In the  Quantity  box, type the quantity of the                             expense item that the employee purchased according to the receipt. The                             quantity is expressed in the unit of measure specified in the                                  UOM  box, which is the unit specified for the                             selected non-stock item on the   ([~/?ScreenId=IN202000|IN202000]) Non-Stock Items                             form. Optional: In the  Unit Cost  box, manually override                             the default value (if one exists), which is the standard cost specified                             for a unit of the expense non-stock item, or specify the amount in the                                  Amount  box . In the  Employee Part  box, type the part of the                             total amount that will not be reimbursed to the employee (that is, the                             part for which the employee is responsible).  Note: If the amount                                 in the  Amount  box includes taxes, the                                      Employee Part  should also be specified                                 with the taxes included. In the  Currency  box, change the currency to that                             of the receipt, if necessary. If the currency of the receipt is not yet                             registered in the system, you can create a new currency by using the                                   ([~/?ScreenId=CM202000|CM202000]) Currencies (CM202000) form. Optional: In the  Ref. Nbr.  box, type the number                             of the original receipt, which can be used for future reference. In the  Project/Contract  box, select the                             applicable project or contract if the employee incurred the expenses                             while working on a particular project or contract. In the  Project Task  box, select the project task                             to which the expenses are related. Optional: In the  Expense Claim  box, select an                             existing expense claim with which you want to associate the expense                             receipt. Optional: In the  Tax Info  section, change any of the                     default tax settings for the receipt as follows: In the  Tax Zone  box, specify the tax zone that                             applies to the expense receipt.  In the  Tax Calculation  box, which is available                             if the  Net/Gross Entry Mode  feature is enabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features (CS100000) form, specify whether the                             entered amounts are tax-inclusive or tax-exclusive. In the  Tax Category  box, select the tax category                             for the expense item. In the  Financial Details  section, specify the information                     to classify the receipt as follows: Select the  Billable  check box if a customer                             should be billed for the expense amount. In the  Customer  box, select a customer if the                             employee incurred the expenses while working for a particular customer.                             If you have already selected a project or contract in the                                  Project/Contract  box, the system                             automatically filled in the customer and it cannot be changed. Optional: In the  Image  section, do the following: Click  Browse  to open the file selection window,                             and select the image of the original receipt. Click  Upload  to attach the image file to the                             expense receipt record. Optional: On the  Tax Details  tab, correct the tax amounts                     in the  Tax Amount  column. On the form toolbar, click  Save  to save the expense                     receipt. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="dee5f0ba-d049-4b44-8caa-bdbcaf4b93fd" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="5db84b38-c1d8-2c27-ffd8-99e3e208b860" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
After an expense receipt has been taken off hold and submitted for further processing, it gets the ''Pending Approval'' status and requires approval by an authorized employee only if all of the following conditions are met:[anchor|#ul_qj3_rmk_xx]
*The ''Approval Workflow'' feature is enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) form.
*An approval map is selected for expense receipts in the '''Expense Receipt Approval Map''' box on the '''General Settings''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_10_10_00|Time and Expenses Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=EP101000|EP101000]) form.
*The receipt meets the conditions specified in the approval map.

If any of the above conditions is not met, the receipt is considered by the system as preliminarily approved. (That is, it is assumed that the proper steps needed for approval have not been taken or this receipt does not need to be approved, so approval should be skipped.) As a result, the receipt gets the ''Open'' status and can be claimed. For details, see [HelpRoot_Organization\EP__HOW_To_Submit_Expense_Receipts|To Generate Expense Claims].((({S:Hint}If the ''Approval Workflow'' feature is enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) form, the system allows you to configure the approval of both expense receipts and expense claims; however, the requirement to approve the same expenses twice may involve too much redundancy in effort. For effective processing of expenses, it may be sufficient to configure approval of only one type of expense document. For example, if you want all expenses related to a particular project to be approved by the project manager, you can configure approval of only expense receipts associated with the project. 
)))
==Approval or Rejection of Expense Receipts==
You can approve an individual expense receipt you are viewing by using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_10_20|Expense Receipt] ([~/?ScreenId=EP301020|EP301020]) form. The '''Approve''' or '''Reject''' action can be applied to a receipt assigned to you or to a member of a workgroup at a lower level in the company tree than your workgroup.{br}

Also, receipts can be approved on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_50_30_10|Approvals] ([~/?ScreenId=EP503010|EP503010]) form, which is available only if the ''Approval Workflow'' feature is enabled. If you have access to this form, you can view receipts in accordance with the visibility rules applied to all documents listed on this form (that is, you can view the receipts assigned to you, to the members of your workgroup, and to the members of the workgroups at lower levels in the company tree than your workgroup). You can approve all listed documents at once by clicking '''Approve All''' on the form toolbar, or you can approve only particular documents by selecting those documents and then clicking '''Approve'''.((({S:Hint}Although you can use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_50_30_10|Approvals] form to approve expense receipts assigned to other members of your workgroup, you cannot view the details of these receipts on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_10_10|Expense Receipts] form due to certain restrictions of user access. For more information about user access to expense receipts, see [HelpRoot_Organization\EP__con_Expense_Receipts|Expense Receipts].
)))
If a receipt included in a claim has been rejected or put on hold, it remains associated with the claim. You will not be able to submit this claim for further processing until the rejected receipt is either removed from the claim or approved after any necessary adjustments have been made.{br}

Once a claim is approved, it can be released.]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Expense Receipt Approval After an expense receipt has been taken off hold and submitted for further processing, it gets     the  Pending Approval  status and requires approval by an authorized employee only if all     of the following conditions are met: The  Approval Workflow  feature is enabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features      (CS100000) form. An approval map is selected for expense receipts in the  Expense Receipt Approval       Map  box on the  General Settings  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP101000|EP101000]) Time and Expenses Preferences (EP101000) form. The receipt meets the conditions specified in the approval map. If any of the above conditions is not met, the receipt is considered by the system as     preliminarily approved. (That is, it is assumed that the proper steps needed for approval have     not been taken or this receipt does not need to be approved, so approval should be skipped.) As     a result, the receipt gets the  Open  status and can be claimed. For details, see  To Generate Expense Claims. If the  Approval Workflow  feature is enabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features     (CS100000) form, the system allows you to configure the approval of both expense receipts and     expense claims; however, the requirement to approve the same expenses twice may involve too much     redundancy in effort. For effective processing of expenses, it may be sufficient to configure     approval of only one type of expense document. For example, if you want all expenses related to     a particular project to be approved by the project manager, you can configure approval of only     expense receipts associated with the project.  Approval or Rejection of Expense Receipts You can approve an individual expense receipt you are viewing by using the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP301020|EP301020]) Expense Receipt (EP301020) form. The  Approve  or  Reject  action can be     applied to a receipt assigned to you or to a member of a workgroup at a lower level in the     company tree than your workgroup. Also, receipts can be approved on the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP503010|EP503010]) Approvals (EP503010) form,     which is available only if the  Approval Workflow  feature is enabled. If you have access     to this form, you can view receipts in accordance with the visibility rules applied to all     documents listed on this form (that is, you can view the receipts assigned to you, to the     members of your workgroup, and to the members of the workgroups at lower levels in the company     tree than your workgroup). You can approve all listed documents at once by clicking       Approve All  on the form toolbar, or you can approve only particular     documents by selecting those documents and then clicking  Approve . Although you can use the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP503010|EP503010]) Approvals     form to approve expense receipts assigned to other members of your workgroup, you cannot view     the details of these receipts on the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP301010|EP301010]) Expense Receipts form due to certain     restrictions of user access. For more information about user access to expense receipts, see      Expense Receipts. If a receipt included in a claim has been rejected or put on hold, it remains associated with     the claim. You will not be able to submit this claim for further processing until the rejected     receipt is either removed from the claim or approved after any necessary adjustments have been     made. Once a claim is approved, it can be released. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="3ae6ca5b-d724-49be-bd48-046a1f6fcfc7" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="ca0cd148-dac8-9483-97d6-edeb30e49949" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
After an expense receipt has been taken off hold, it might require approval. You can approve a receipt by using one of the following forms:[anchor|#ul_dss_sdq_hp]
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_10_10|Expense Receipts] ([~/?ScreenId=EP301010|EP301010]): You use this form as a starting point from which you can open each individual expense receipt that you want to approve on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_10_20|Expense Receipt] ([~/?ScreenId=EP301020|EP301020]) form and view its details. By using this method, you can also reject each expense receipt.
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_50_30_10|Approvals] ([~/?ScreenId=EP503010|EP503010]): On this form, you can approve any listed expense receipts. However, on this form, you cannot reject expense receipts.

==To Approve an Individual Expense Receipt==[anchor|#_39436b37-3b93-4521-8242-af6583c7cfc5]
#Open the[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_10_10|Expense Receipts] ([~/?ScreenId=EP301010|EP301010]) form by searching for or navigating to it.
#In the Selection area, clear the '''Employee''' box to see the full list of the expense receipts that you are allowed to access.
#Select the '''Pending Approval''' filter tab.
#Click the link in the '''Description''' column for the expense receipt you want to approve, which brings up the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_10_20|Expense Receipt] form with the details of the receipt.
#If you accept the details of the expense receipt, click '''Actions''' > '''Approve''' on the form toolbar.

==To Approve Multiple Expense Receipts==[anchor|#_77b577eb-07d1-4def-aac3-7923f95a3a0d]
#Open the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_50_30_10|Approvals] ([~/?ScreenId=EP503010|EP503010]) form by searching for or navigating to it.
#Do one of the following:
#*If you want to approve expense receipts assigned to you, select the '''My Approvals''' filter tab.
#*If you want to approve expense receipts assigned to you and to the members of your workgroup, select the '''My Workgroup&rsquo;s Approvals''' filter tab.
#*If you want to approve expense receipts assigned to you, to the members of your workgroup, and to the members of the workgroups at a lower level in the company tree than your workgroup, select the '''All Records''' filter tab.
#Click the header of the '''Type''' column, and configure the filter so that only expense receipts are listed on the tab.
#Do one of the following:
#*To approve only certain expense receipts, in the unlabeled column, select the check boxes for the receipts that you want to approve, and then click '''Approve''' on the form toolbar.
#*To approve all listed expense receipts, click '''Approve All''' on the form toolbar.
]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[To Approve Expense Receipts After an expense receipt has been taken off hold, it might require approval. You can                 approve a receipt by using one of the following forms:  ([~/?ScreenId=EP301010|EP301010]) Expense Receipts (EP301010): You use this form as a                         starting point from which you can open each individual expense receipt that                         you want to approve on the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP301020|EP301020]) Expense Receipt (EP301020)                         form and view its details. By using this method, you can also reject each                         expense receipt.  ([~/?ScreenId=EP503010|EP503010]) Approvals (EP503010): On this form, you can approve                         any listed expense receipts. However, on this form, you cannot reject                         expense receipts. To Approve an Individual Expense Receipt Open the  ([~/?ScreenId=EP301010|EP301010]) Expense Receipts (EP301010) form by searching                 for or navigating to it. In the Selection area, clear the  Employee  box to see the full                 list of the expense receipts that you are allowed to access. Select the  Pending Approval  filter tab. Click the link in the  Description  column for the expense receipt you want to                 approve, which brings up the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP301020|EP301020]) Expense Receipt form with                 the details of the receipt. If you accept the details of the expense receipt, click  Actions Approve  on the form toolbar. To Approve Multiple Expense Receipts Open the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP503010|EP503010]) Approvals (EP503010) form by searching                 for or navigating to it. Do one of the following: If you want to approve expense receipts assigned to you, select the  My                             Approvals  filter tab. If you want to approve expense receipts assigned to you and to the members                         of your workgroup, select the  My Workgroup's Approvals  filter                         tab. If you want to approve expense receipts assigned to you, to the members of                         your workgroup, and to the members of the workgroups at a lower level in the                         company tree than your workgroup, select the  All Records  filter                         tab. Click the header of the  Type  column, and configure the filter                 so that only expense receipts are listed on the tab. Do one of the following: To approve only certain expense receipts, in the unlabeled column, select                         the check boxes for the receipts that you want to approve, and then click                              Approve  on the form toolbar. To approve all listed expense receipts, click  Approve All  on the form                         toolbar. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="bbdc11f6-fabb-4154-8d2d-863ce0d9aee6" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="cff85e32-2c30-26da-6841-627996c2c3eb" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
In Acumatica ERP, an employee can file a claim for the reimbursement of expenses he or she incurred on behalf of the company.
==Access to Expense Claims==
On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_10_30|Expense Claims] ([~/?ScreenId=EP301030|EP301030]) form, you can access any of the following expense claims:[anchor|#ul_xfx_bsm_dp]
*Your claims
*Claims of employees in the workgroups at lower levels in the company tree than your workgroup
*Claims of employees for whom you are an appointed delegate
*Claims that require your approval
*Claims that require approval by employees in the workgroups at lower levels in the company tree than your workgroup
((({S:Hint}For more information about the company tree, see [HelpRoot_Organization\EP__con_Company_Organizational_Chart|Company Tree and Workgroups].
)))
On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_50_10_00|Release Expense Claims] ([~/?ScreenId=EP501000|EP501000]) form, all unreleased claims are listed, but you may not be able to edit or view the details of some claims.{br}

On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_50_30_10|Approvals] ([~/?ScreenId=EP503010|EP503010]) form, you can approve or reject claims assigned to you, to the members of your workgroup, and to the members of the workgroups at lower levels in the company tree than your workgroup.{br}{TOC}
==Filing of an Expense Claim==
You, as an employee, can use one of the following methods of filing an expense claim:[anchor|#ul_e2l_mhh_fx]
*On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_10_10|Expense Receipts] ([~/?ScreenId=EP301010|EP301010]) form, enter expense receipts and submit them for approval (if required). When the receipts are approved, you claim them in bulk to automatically generate the corresponding expense claims. (For details, see [HelpRoot_Organization\EP__HOW_To_Submit_Expense_Receipts|To Generate Expense Claims].)
*By using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_10_30|Expense Claims] ([~/?ScreenId=EP301030|EP301030]) form, create a new claim, and then add any number of receipts to the created claim or add lines directly to the claim by using the table on the '''Expense Claim Details''' tab. You can add receipts to a claim only if it has the ''On Hold'' status.
*:((({S:Hint}If the '''Allow Mixed Tax Settings in Claims''' check box is selected on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_10_10_00|Time and Expenses Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=EP101000|EP101000]) form, expense receipts with different tax zones or tax calculation modes (or both) can be processed within one expense claim. If the check box is cleared, all expense receipts added to one expense claim must have the same tax settings. 
)))

If the '''Hold Expense Claims on Entry''' check box on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_10_10_00|Time and Expenses Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=EP101000|EP101000]) form is selected, all new expense claims have the ''On Hold'' status, indicating that they are drafts that can be adjusted, if necessary. You need to check the details of every claim before submitting it for approval; you can submit an expense claim for approval only if all included receipts have the ''Open'' status. If the '''Hold Expense Claims on Entry''' check box is cleared, each newly created expense claim is automatically submitted for approval and the status of the claim is set to ''Pending Approval'' (if approval is required) or ''Approved'' (if no approval is required).{br}

For expenses that require documentation by your company policy, you can attach to each receipt a scanned receipt or other document that confirms your expenses.
==Properties of an Expense Claim==
In Acumatica ERP, an expense claim has the following properties: [anchor|#ul_pyz_13h_fx]
*The unique reference number, which the system assigns based on the numbering sequence specified for claims on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_10_10_00|Time and Expenses Preferences] form.
*The date when the claim is created; this date determines the post period of the bill generated by the claim release unless a particular post period is specified for the claim in the '''Post to Period''' box on the '''Financial Details''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_10_00|Expense Claim] ([~/?ScreenId=EP301000|EP301000]) form, which is available if the claim has the ''Pending Approval'' or ''Approved'' status.
*The total amount of the claim, which is calculated as the sum of the amounts in the '''Amount in Claim Curr.''' column for all the lines specified for the claim.
*The employee part of the total amount, which is not paid back to the employee in accordance with the company policy.
*The taxable and tax amount for the expense claim. You can review the summary information on applicable taxes on the '''Tax Details''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_10_00|Expense Claim] form, or you can view information for an expense claim line by clicking the link in the '''Tax Amount''' column on the '''Expense Claim Details''' tab.
*The currency in which the claim will be reimbursed to the employee; the claim currency may differ from the currency of the included receipts. By default, the claim currency matches the currency specified as the default for the employee, but it can be changed if currency override is enabled for the employee on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_30_00|Employees] ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000]) form.
*The customer (if applicable), which can also be specified for an individual line. The customer specified in the summary area of the claim is the default customer for claim lines; it can be overridden for each line unless a project is specified for the line and the customer is associated with this project. When the '''Billable''' check box is selected for a particular line, the customer will be billed for the expense in the amount returned to the employee.
*The branch that will reimburse the expenses to the employee. 
*The department of the employee, which can affect who approves the claim. You can set up assignment rules for claim approval whereby claims from different departments may be approved by different persons.
*The tax zone and tax calculation mode. 
*:((({S:Hint}If the ''Net/Gross Entry Mode'' feature is enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) form, you can select whether the amounts in the expense claim are tax-exclusive (net) or tax-inclusive (gross). For more information, see [HelpRoot_Financials\TX__con_VAT_in_Expense_Receipts#section_kkz_qp2_jbb|Tax-Exclusive and Tax-Inclusive Amounts in Expense Receipts].
)))

==Statuses of an Expense Claim==
On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_10_30|Expense Claims] form, you can also view the claim's status, which reflects its processing stage. Typical statuses for expense claims might include the following: [anchor|#ul_dvn_zxg_dp]
*''On Hold'': The claim is a draft and cannot be released.
*''Pending Approval'': The claim is pending approval.
*''Approved'': The claim is either approved or requires no approval.
*''Rejected'': The claim is rejected.
*''Released'': An Accounts Payable bill has been generated based on the claim.

==Related Articles==
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_30_00|Employees] ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_10_30|Expense Claims] ([~/?ScreenId=EP301030|EP301030])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_10_10|Expense Receipts] ([~/?ScreenId=EP301010|EP301010])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_50_10_00|Release Expense Claims] ([~/?ScreenId=EP501000|EP501000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_10_10_00|Time and Expenses Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=EP101000|EP101000])]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Expense Claims In  Acumatica ERP, an employee can file a claim for the reimbursement of expenses he or she incurred on         behalf of the company. Access to Expense Claims On the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP301030|EP301030]) Expense Claims (EP301030) form, you can access any of the         following expense claims: Your claims Claims of employees in the workgroups at lower levels in the company tree than your           workgroup Claims of employees for whom you are an appointed delegate Claims that require your approval Claims that require approval by employees in the workgroups at lower levels in the           company tree than your workgroup For more information about the company tree, see  Company Tree and Workgroups. On the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP501000|EP501000]) Release Expense Claims (EP501000) form, all unreleased claims are         listed, but you may not be able to edit or view the details of some claims. On the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP503010|EP503010]) Approvals (EP503010) form, you can approve or reject claims         assigned to you, to the members of your workgroup, and to the members of the workgroups at         lower levels in the company tree than your workgroup. Filing of an Expense Claim You, as an employee, can use one of the following methods of filing an expense claim: On the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP301010|EP301010]) Expense Receipts (EP301010) form, enter expense receipts and           submit them for approval (if required). When the receipts are approved, you claim them in           bulk to automatically generate the corresponding expense claims. (For details, see  To Generate Expense Claims.) By using the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP301030|EP301030]) Expense Claims (EP301030) form, create a new claim, and           then add any number of receipts to the created claim or add lines directly to the claim by           using the table on the  Expense Claim Details  tab. You can add           receipts to a claim only if it has the  On Hold  status. If the  Allow               Mixed Tax Settings in Claims  check box is selected on the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP101000|EP101000]) Time and Expenses Preferences (EP101000) form, expense receipts with different tax             zones or tax calculation modes (or both) can be processed within one expense claim. If             the check box is cleared, all expense receipts added to one expense claim must have the             same tax settings.  If the  Hold Expense Claims on Entry  check box on the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP101000|EP101000]) Time and Expenses Preferences (EP101000) form is selected, all new expense claims have the            On Hold  status, indicating that they are drafts that can be adjusted, if necessary.         You need to check the details of every claim before submitting it for approval; you can         submit an expense claim for approval only if all included receipts have the  Open          status. If the  Hold Expense Claims on Entry  check box is cleared,         each newly created expense claim is automatically submitted for approval and the status of         the claim is set to  Pending Approval  (if approval is required) or  Approved  (if         no approval is required). For expenses that require documentation by your company policy, you can attach to each         receipt a scanned receipt or other document that confirms your expenses. Properties of an Expense Claim In  Acumatica ERP, an expense claim has the following properties:  The unique reference number, which the system assigns based on the numbering sequence           specified for claims on the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP101000|EP101000]) Time and Expenses Preferences form. The date when the claim is created; this date determines the post period of the bill           generated by the claim release unless a particular post period is specified for the claim           in the  Post to Period  box on the  Financial             Details  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP301000|EP301000]) Expense Claim (EP301000) form, which           is available if the claim has the  Pending Approval  or  Approved  status. The total amount of the claim, which is calculated as the sum of the amounts in the              Amount in Claim Curr.  column for all the lines specified for the           claim. The employee part of the total amount, which is not paid back to the employee in           accordance with the company policy. The taxable and tax amount for the expense claim. You can review the summary information           on applicable taxes on the  Tax Details  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP301000|EP301000]) Expense Claim form, or you can view information for an expense claim line by           clicking the link in the  Tax Amount  column on the              Expense Claim Details  tab. The currency in which the claim will be reimbursed to the employee; the claim currency           may differ from the currency of the included receipts. By default, the claim currency           matches the currency specified as the default for the employee, but it can be changed if           currency override is enabled for the employee on the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000]) Employees           (EP203000) form. The customer (if applicable), which can also be specified for an individual line. The           customer specified in the summary area of the claim is the default customer for claim           lines; it can be overridden for each line unless a project is specified for the line and           the customer is associated with this project. When the  Billable            check box is selected for a particular line, the customer will be billed for the expense           in the amount returned to the employee. The branch that will reimburse the expenses to the employee.  The department of the employee, which can affect who approves the claim. You can set up           assignment rules for claim approval whereby claims from different departments may be           approved by different persons. The tax zone and tax calculation mode.  If the  Net/Gross Entry Mode  feature             is enabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features (CS100000) form, you can select             whether the amounts in the expense claim are tax-exclusive (net) or tax-inclusive             (gross). For more information, see  Tax-Exclusive and Tax-Inclusive Amounts in Expense Receipts. Statuses of an Expense Claim On the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP301030|EP301030]) Expense Claims form, you can also view the claim's status, which         reflects its processing stage. Typical statuses for expense claims might include the         following:  On Hold : The claim is a draft and cannot be released. Pending Approval : The claim is pending approval. Approved : The claim is either approved or requires no approval. Rejected : The claim is rejected. Released : An Accounts Payable bill has been generated based on the claim.  ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000])  ([~/?ScreenId=EP301030|EP301030])  ([~/?ScreenId=EP301010|EP301010])  ([~/?ScreenId=EP501000|EP501000])  ([~/?ScreenId=EP101000|EP101000]) ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="fc7f20f4-8b87-4cbc-a217-a857c28b6cef" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="1de9260a-b034-6aa5-bf74-534bffbd7955" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
You can create an expense claim by using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_10_30|Expense Claims] ([~/?ScreenId=EP301030|EP301030]) form as a starting point. From there, you can add a new claim on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_10_00|Expense Claim] ([~/?ScreenId=EP301000|EP301000]) form. On this form, you can enter the following expense claims:[anchor|#ul_xfx_bsm_dp]
*Your own claims
*The claims of employees in the workgroups at lower levels in the company tree than your workgroup
*The claims of employees for whom you are an appointed delegate; all delegates of a particular employee are listed on the '''Delegates''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_30_00|Employees] ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000]) form

==To Create an Expense Claim==[anchor|#ol_nsz_tyk_hp]
#On the '''Organization''' tab, click '''Time & Expenses'''. In the left pane, select the '''Work Area''' tab, and then navigate to '''Enter''' > '''Expense Claims'''.
#On the form toolbar, click '''Add New Record'''.
#:The system navigates to the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_10_00|Expense Claim] form so that you can enter a new expense claim.
#In the Summary area, specify the claim information as follows:
##In the '''Description''' box, type a brief description of the claim.
##In the '''Claimed by''' box, select the employee who is claiming the expenses.
##In the '''Currency''' box, change the currency if the employee should be reimbursed in a different currency.
##Optional: In the '''Customer''' box, select a customer if the employee incurred the expenses while working for a particular customer. If you add expense claim lines directly on the '''Expense Claim Details''' tab, this customer will be automatically specified for each new line.
#On the form toolbar, click '''Save'''.
#To add expense claim lines, on the '''Expense Claim Details''' tab, do one of the following:
#*If you need to enter a new expense receipt that will be added to the claim, click '''Add New Receipt''' on the table toolbar to open the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_10_20|Expense Receipt] ([~/?ScreenId=EP301020|EP301020]) form, and then enter the expense receipt. For details, see [HelpRoot_Organization\EP__HOW_To_Create_an_Expense_Receipt|'''Add Receipts'''].
#*If you need to add existing expense receipts to the claim, click on the table toolbar to open the '''Add Receipts''' dialog box; select one or more existing receipts, and then click '''Add''' to add them to the claim.
#*If you want to add lines directly to the claim, click on the first empty row in the table and fill in the appropriate columns.
#Optional: If you need to correct the tax or taxable amounts in the expense claim, either edit (on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_10_20|Expense Receipt] form) the individual receipts included in the claim, or click the link in the '''Tax Amount''' column for the needed line on the '''Expense Claim Details''' tab, and modify the amounts in the '''Document Taxes''' dialog box, which opens.
#On the form toolbar, click '''Save'''.
]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[To Create an Expense Claim You can create an expense claim by using the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP301030|EP301030]) Expense Claims                 (EP301030) form as a starting point. From there, you can add a new claim on the                       ([~/?ScreenId=EP301000|EP301000]) Expense Claim (EP301000) form. On this form, you can enter                 the following expense claims: Your own claims The claims of employees in the workgroups at lower levels in the company                         tree than your workgroup The claims of employees for whom you are an appointed delegate; all                         delegates of a particular employee are listed on the                              Delegates  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000]) Employees (EP203000) form To Create an Expense Claim On the  Organization  tab, click  Time &                         Expenses . In the left pane, select the  Work                         Area  tab, and then navigate to  Enter Expense Claims . On the form toolbar, click  Add New Record . The system                         navigates to the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP301000|EP301000]) Expense Claim form so that you can enter                         a new expense claim. In the Summary area, specify the claim information as follows: In the  Description  box, type a brief description                             of the claim. In the  Claimed by  box, select the employee who is                             claiming the expenses. In the  Currency  box, change the currency if the                             employee should be reimbursed in a different currency. Optional: In the  Customer  box, select a customer                             if the employee incurred the expenses while working for a particular                             customer. If you add expense claim lines directly on the                                  Expense Claim Details  tab, this customer will                             be automatically specified for each new line. On the form toolbar, click  Save . To add expense claim lines, on the  Expense Claim Details                      tab, do one of the following: If you need to enter a new expense receipt that will be added to the                             claim, click  Add New Receipt  on the table toolbar                             to open the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP301020|EP301020]) Expense Receipt (EP301020) form, and then                             enter the expense receipt. For details, see  Add                                     Receipts '''Add Receipts'''. If you need to add existing expense receipts to the claim, click on the                             table toolbar to open the  Add Receipts  dialog                             box; select one or more existing receipts, and then click                                  Add  to add them to the claim. If you want to add lines directly to the claim, click on the first empty                             row in the table and fill in the appropriate columns. Optional: If you need to correct the tax or taxable amounts in the expense                     claim, either edit (on the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP301020|EP301020]) Expense Receipt form) the individual                     receipts included in the claim, or click the link in the  Tax                         Amount  column for the needed line on the  Expense                         Claim Details  tab, and modify the amounts in the                          Document Taxes  dialog box, which opens. On the form toolbar, click  Save . ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="ac626a96-cf5d-492c-9126-76084504fefc" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="82dd58f7-5620-88b6-d1f7-9e7821013b1b" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
The system automatically generates expense claims when you claim expense receipts by using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_10_10|Expense Receipts] ([~/?ScreenId=EP301010|EP301010]) form. When you claim multiple receipts, multiple claims may be generated, each including receipts with common properties. The system always generates different claims for receipts that have different employees, branches, or customers.
==To Generate Expense Claims==[anchor|#ol_uxp_drk_hp]
#On the '''Organization''' tab, click '''Time & Expenses'''. In the left pane, select the '''Work Area''' tab, and then navigate to '''Enter''' > '''Expense Receipts'''.
#Select the '''To Be Claimed''' filter tab to view only unclaimed receipts that have the ''Open'' status.
#Do one of the following:
#*To claim only particular expense receipts, in the unlabeled column, select the check boxes for the receipts that you want to claim, and then click '''Claim''' on the form toolbar.
#*To claim all listed expense receipts, click '''Claim All''' on the form toolbar.
]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[To Generate Expense Claims The system automatically generates expense claims when you claim expense receipts by                 using the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP301010|EP301010]) Expense Receipts (EP301010) form. When you claim                 multiple receipts, multiple claims may be generated, each including receipts with                 common properties. The system always generates different claims for receipts that                 have different employees, branches, or customers. To Generate Expense Claims On the  Organization  tab, click  Time & Expenses . In the left                     pane, select the  Work Area  tab, and then navigate to  Enter Expense Receipts . Select the  To Be Claimed  filter tab to view only unclaimed receipts that                     have the  Open  status. Do one of the following: To claim only particular expense receipts, in the unlabeled column,                             select the check boxes for the receipts that you want to claim, and then                             click  Claim  on the form toolbar. To claim all listed expense receipts, click  Claim All  on the form                             toolbar. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="ace4d71a-cfd2-4634-8e92-edad9c2a0f4b" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="67e7cfb4-225e-fbab-1fb4-adb83ecb9ce4" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
After an expense claim has been submitted for further processing, it may be assigned to an authorized employee for approval. (A claim cannot be submitted if it includes any receipt with the ''On Hold'', ''Pending Approval'', or ''Rejected'' status, so you need to be sure no receipts have these statuses before submitting the claim.)((({S:Hint}The functionality of expense claims is available only if the ''Expense Management'' feature is enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) form. 
)))((({S:Hint}If the ''Approval Workflow'' feature is enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] form, the system allows you to configure the approval of both expense receipts and expense claims; however, the requirement to approve the same expenses twice may involve too much redundancy in effort. For effective processing of expenses, it may be sufficient to configure the approval of only one type of expense document. For example, if you want all expenses related to a particular project to be approved by the project manager, you can configure approval of only expense receipts associated with the project. 
)))
==Assignment for Approval==
The system performs assignment for approval automatically in one of the following ways:[anchor|#ul_fvg_4wq_2r]
*If the ''Approval Workflow'' feature is enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) form, the system uses approval maps, which can be created on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_55_00|Assignment and Approval Maps] ([~/?ScreenId=EP205500|EP205500]) form. You can specify the map for claim approval on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_10_10_00|Time and Expenses Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=EP101000|EP101000]) form. However, if no approval map is specified or if a claim does not meet the conditions of the specified map, then the claim requires no approval—it is assigned the ''Open'' status, and it can be released immediately after submission.
*If the ''Approval Workflow'' feature is disabled, the system assigns an expense claim for approval to the employee specified in the '''Reports to''' box on the '''General Info''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_30_00|Employees] ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000]) form for the employee who is claiming the expenses; if the '''Reports to''' box is empty, the claim requires no approval—it is assigned the ''Open'' status, and it can be released immediately after submission.

Once the expense claim is assigned for approval, its status changes to ''Pending Approval''. The claim will not be reassigned to another approver if you enable or disable the ''Approval Workflow'' feature or if you modify the approval map specified for expense claims.
==Approval or Rejection of Expense Claims==
You can approve an individual expense claim you are viewing by using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_10_00|Expense Claim] ([~/?ScreenId=EP301000|EP301000]) form. The '''Approve''' or '''Reject''' action can be applied to a claim assigned to you or to a member of a workgroup at a lower level in the company tree than your workgroup.{br}

Also, claims can be approved on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_50_30_10|Approvals] ([~/?ScreenId=EP503010|EP503010]) form, which is available only if the ''Approval Workflow'' feature is enabled. If you have access to this form, you can view claims in accordance with the visibility rules applied to all documents listed on this form (that is, you can view the claims assigned to you, to the members of your workgroup, and to the members of the workgroups at lower levels in the company tree than your workgroup). You can approve all listed documents at once by clicking '''Approve All''' on the form toolbar, or you can approve only particular document by selecting them and then clicking '''Approve'''.((({S:Hint}Although you can use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_50_30_10|Approvals] form to approve expense claims assigned to other members of your workgroup, you cannot view the details of these claims on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_10_30|Expense Claims] form due to certain restrictions of user access. For more information about user access to expense claims, see [HelpRoot_Organization\EP__con_Expense_Claims|Expense Claims].
)))
Once a claim is approved, it can be released.{br}

If your system is configured for the approval of expense claims and AP bills, when the system generates bills on release of expense claims, it does not assign these bills for approval as it considers these bills to be approved because the expense claims for which these bills were generated have already been approved.
==Related Articles==
*[HelpRoot_Organization\EP__con_Assignment_Automation|Managing Assignment and Approval Maps]
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_50_30_10|Approvals] ([~/?ScreenId=EP503010|EP503010])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_55_00|Assignment and Approval Maps] ([~/?ScreenId=EP205500|EP205500])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_10_30|Expense Claims] ([~/?ScreenId=EP301030|EP301030])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_10_10_00|Time and Expenses Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=EP101000|EP101000])]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Expense Claim Approval After an expense claim has been submitted for further processing, it may be assigned to an     authorized employee for approval. (A claim cannot be submitted if it includes any receipt with     the  On Hold ,  Pending Approval , or  Rejected  status, so you need to be sure     no receipts have these statuses before submitting the claim.) The functionality of expense claims is available only if the  Expense Management      feature is enabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features (CS100000) form.  If the  Approval Workflow  feature is enabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features     form, the system allows you to configure the approval of both expense receipts and expense     claims; however, the requirement to approve the same expenses twice may involve too much     redundancy in effort. For effective processing of expenses, it may be sufficient to configure     the approval of only one type of expense document. For example, if you want all expenses related     to a particular project to be approved by the project manager, you can configure approval of     only expense receipts associated with the project.  Assignment for Approval The system performs assignment for approval automatically in one of the following ways: If the  Approval Workflow  feature is enabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features      (CS100000) form, the system uses approval maps, which can be created on the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP205500|EP205500]) Assignment and Approval Maps (EP205500) form. You can specify the map for claim approval on the         ([~/?ScreenId=EP101000|EP101000]) Time and Expenses Preferences (EP101000) form. However, if no approval map is specified or      if a claim does not meet the conditions of the specified map, then the claim requires no      approval—it is assigned the  Open  status, and it can be released immediately after      submission. If the  Approval Workflow  feature is disabled, the system assigns an expense claim for      approval to the employee specified in the  Reports to  box on the        General Info  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000]) Employees (EP203000) form      for the employee who is claiming the expenses; if the  Reports to  box is      empty, the claim requires no approval—it is assigned the  Open  status, and it can      be released immediately after submission. Once the expense claim is assigned for approval, its status changes to  Pending     Approval . The claim will not be reassigned to another approver if you enable or disable the       Approval Workflow  feature or if you modify the approval map specified for expense     claims. Approval or Rejection of Expense Claims You can approve an individual expense claim you are viewing by using the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP301000|EP301000]) Expense Claim (EP301000) form. The  Approve  or  Reject  action can be     applied to a claim assigned to you or to a member of a workgroup at a lower level in the company     tree than your workgroup. Also, claims can be approved on the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP503010|EP503010]) Approvals (EP503010) form, which is     available only if the  Approval Workflow  feature is enabled. If you have access to this     form, you can view claims in accordance with the visibility rules applied to all documents     listed on this form (that is, you can view the claims assigned to you, to the members of your     workgroup, and to the members of the workgroups at lower levels in the company tree than your     workgroup). You can approve all listed documents at once by clicking  Approve      All  on the form toolbar, or you can approve only particular document by selecting     them and then clicking  Approve . Although you can use the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP503010|EP503010]) Approvals form to approve expense claims     assigned to other members of your workgroup, you cannot view the details of these claims on the        ([~/?ScreenId=EP301030|EP301030]) Expense Claims form due to certain restrictions of user access. For more     information about user access to expense claims, see  Expense Claims. Once a claim is approved, it can be released. If your system is configured for the approval of expense claims and AP bills, when the system     generates bills on release of expense claims, it does not assign these bills for approval as it     considers these bills to be approved because the expense claims for which these bills were     generated have already been approved.  ([~/?ScreenId=EP503010|EP503010])  ([~/?ScreenId=EP205500|EP205500])  ([~/?ScreenId=EP301030|EP301030])  ([~/?ScreenId=EP101000|EP101000]) ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="b7975e48-99ab-480f-9079-feba2f5d013c" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="043bdd95-ea05-14e6-0c9f-3719edf8f89d" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
After an expense claim has been submitted, it might require approval. You can approve a claim by using one of the following forms:[anchor|#ul_dss_sdq_hp]
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_10_30|Expense Claims] ([~/?ScreenId=EP301030|EP301030]): You use this form as a starting point from which you can open each expense claim that you want to approve on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_10_00|Expense Claim] ([~/?ScreenId=EP301000|EP301000]) form and view its details. By using this method, you can also reject each expense claim.
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_50_30_10|Approvals] ([~/?ScreenId=EP503010|EP503010]): On this form, you can approve any listed expense claims. However, on this form, you cannot reject expense claims.

==To Approve an Individual Expense Claim==[anchor|#_f18a7852-e3cb-46aa-8454-434f3bbb4cb4]
#Open the[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_10_30|Expense Claims] ([~/?ScreenId=EP301030|EP301030]) form by searching for or navigating to it.
#In the Selection area, clear the '''Employee''' box to see the full list of the expense claims that you are allowed to access.
#Select the '''Pending Approval''' filter tab.
#Click the link in the '''Reference Nbr.''' column for the expense claim you want to approve, which brings up the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_10_00|Expense Claim] form, where you can view the details of the claim.
#If you accept the details of the expense claim, click '''Actions''' > '''Approve''' on the form toolbar.

==To Approve Multiple Expense Claims==[anchor|#_79a40554-990a-4cd2-ad11-9566553db5d2]
#Open the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_50_30_10|Approvals] ([~/?ScreenId=EP503010|EP503010]) form by searching for or navigating to it.
#Do one of the following:
#*If you want to approve expense claims assigned to you, select the '''My Approvals''' filter tab.
#*If you want to approve expense claims assigned to you and to the members of your workgroup, select the '''My Workgroup&rsquo;s Approvals''' filter tab.
#*If you want to approve expense claims assigned to you, to the members of your workgroup, and to the members of the workgroups at a lower level in the company tree than your workgroup, select the '''All Records''' filter tab.
#Click the header of the '''Type''' column, and configure the filter so that only expense receipts are listed on the tab.
#Do one of the following:
#*To approve only certain expense claims, in the unlabeled column, select the check boxes for the claims that you want to approve, and then click '''Approve''' on the form toolbar.
#*To approve all listed expense claims, click '''Approve All''' on the form toolbar.
]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[To Approve Expense Claims After an expense claim has been submitted, it might require approval. You can approve                 a claim by using one of the following forms:  ([~/?ScreenId=EP301030|EP301030]) Expense Claims (EP301030): You use this form as a                         starting point from which you can open each expense claim that you want to                         approve on the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP301000|EP301000]) Expense Claim (EP301000) form and view                         its details. By using this method, you can also reject each expense                         claim.  ([~/?ScreenId=EP503010|EP503010]) Approvals (EP503010): On this form, you can approve                         any listed expense claims. However, on this form, you cannot reject expense                         claims. To Approve an Individual Expense Claim Open the  ([~/?ScreenId=EP301030|EP301030]) Expense Claims (EP301030) form by searching                 for or navigating to it. In the Selection area, clear the  Employee  box to see the full                 list of the expense claims that you are allowed to access. Select the  Pending Approval  filter tab. Click the link in the  Reference Nbr.  column for the expense claim you want to                 approve, which brings up the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP301000|EP301000]) Expense Claim form,                 where you can view the details of the claim. If you accept the details of the expense claim, click  Actions Approve  on the form toolbar. To Approve Multiple Expense Claims Open the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP503010|EP503010]) Approvals (EP503010) form by searching                 for or navigating to it. Do one of the following: If you want to approve expense claims assigned to you, select the  My                             Approvals  filter tab. If you want to approve expense claims assigned to you and to the members of                         your workgroup, select the  My Workgroup's Approvals  filter tab. If you want to approve expense claims assigned to you, to the members of                         your workgroup, and to the members of the workgroups at a lower level in the                         company tree than your workgroup, select the  All Records  filter                         tab. Click the header of the  Type  column, and configure the filter                 so that only expense receipts are listed on the tab. Do one of the following: To approve only certain expense claims, in the unlabeled column, select the                         check boxes for the claims that you want to approve, and then click                              Approve  on the form toolbar. To approve all listed expense claims, click  Approve All  on the form                         toolbar. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="6ce73848-e7b8-4feb-9402-9e0906b03ae6" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="70ed3997-ce31-5f21-ccf6-6e675ecb7750" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
You can release approved expense claims by using the following methods:[anchor|#ul_tbr_3qq_hp]
*On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_50_10_00|Release Expense Claims] ([~/?ScreenId=EP501000|EP501000]) form, release all listed claims at once by clicking '''Release All''' on the form toolbar, or release only particular claims by selecting the unlabeled check boxes for those claims and then clicking '''Release'''.
*On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_10_30|Expense Claims] ([~/?ScreenId=EP301030|EP301030]) form, select the reference number of the approved expense claim that you want to release, which brings up the claim details. Then you can use the '''Release''' action on the form toolbar to release the claim.

When you release an expense claim, the system generates an Accounts Payable bill to reimburse the employee. If the financial period specified for the claim in the '''Post to Period''' box on the '''Financial Details''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_10_00|Expense Claim] ([~/?ScreenId=EP301000|EP301000]) form is closed in Accounts Payable and posting to closed periods is not allowed, you need to specify an open period to be able to release the expense claim, or an error occurs during the release. The system posts the resulting bill to the selected period, which is also copied to the '''Post Period''' box on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_10_00|Bills and Adjustments] ([~/?ScreenId=AP301000|AP301000]) form for the bill.{br}

If the employee incurred the expenses while working on a project for a customer, you can invoice the customer by using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_50_20_00|Bill Expense Claims] ([~/?ScreenId=EP502000|EP502000]) form. In this case, the system generates an invoice for the customer in the same amount as the bill for employee reimbursement. On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_50_20_00|Bill Expense Claims] form, each record relates to a single customer; thus, all unbilled claim lines marked as billable will be included in one invoice.{br}

The system will automatically release Accounts Payable bills and Accounts Receivable invoices from the Time and Expenses module if the '''Automatically Release AP Documents''' and '''Automatically Release AR Documents''' check boxes, respectively, are selected on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_10_10_00|Time and Expenses Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=EP101000|EP101000]) form. ((({S:Hint}The system automatically releases Accounts Payable bills If the '''Automatically Release AP Documents''' check box is selected on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_10_10_00|Time and Expenses Preferences] form even if the approval workflow functionality is activated for AP documents on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_10_10_00|Accounts Payable Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=AP101000|AP101000]) form (the '''Require Approval''' check box is selected). 
)))
Also, the resulting transactions can be automatically posted to the General Ledger module if the '''Automatically Post on Release''' check box is selected on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AR_10_10_00|Accounts Receivable Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=AR101000|AR101000]) or [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_10_10_00|Accounts Payable Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=AP101000|AP101000]) form.
==Related Articles==
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_10_10_00|Accounts Payable Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=AP101000|AP101000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\AR_10_10_00|Accounts Receivable Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=AR101000|AR101000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_50_20_00|Bill Expense Claims] ([~/?ScreenId=EP502000|EP502000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_10_30|Expense Claims] ([~/?ScreenId=EP301030|EP301030])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_50_10_00|Release Expense Claims] ([~/?ScreenId=EP501000|EP501000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_10_10_00|Time and Expenses Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=EP101000|EP101000])]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Expense Claim Release You can release approved expense claims by using the following methods: On the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP501000|EP501000]) Release Expense Claims (EP501000) form, release all                               listed claims at once by clicking  Release All                                on the form toolbar, or release only particular claims by selecting                               the unlabeled check boxes for those claims and then clicking                                      Release . On the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP301030|EP301030]) Expense Claims (EP301030) form, select the                               reference number of the approved expense claim that you want to                               release, which brings up the claim details. Then you can use the                                      Release  action on the form toolbar to                               release the claim. When you release an expense claim, the system generates an Accounts Payable                         bill to reimburse the employee. If the financial period specified for the                         claim in the  Post to Period  box on the                                Financial Details  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP301000|EP301000]) Expense Claim (EP301000) form is closed in Accounts                         Payable and posting to closed periods is not allowed, you need to specify an                         open period to be able to release the expense claim, or an error occurs                         during the release. The system posts the resulting bill to the selected                         period, which is also copied to the  Post Period  box                         on the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP301000|AP301000]) Bills and Adjustments (AP301000) form for the bill. If the employee incurred the expenses while working on a project for a                         customer, you can invoice the customer by using the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP502000|EP502000]) Bill Expense Claims (EP502000) form. In this case, the system                         generates an invoice for the customer in the same amount as the bill for                         employee reimbursement. On the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP502000|EP502000]) Bill Expense Claims form, each                         record relates to a single customer; thus, all unbilled claim lines marked                         as billable will be included in one invoice. The system will automatically release Accounts Payable bills and Accounts                         Receivable invoices from the Time and Expenses module if the                                Automatically Release AP Documents  and                                Automatically Release AR Documents  check boxes, respectively, are selected on the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP101000|EP101000]) Time and Expenses Preferences                         (EP101000) form.  The system automatically releases Accounts Payable                               bills If the  Automatically Release AP Documents                                check box is selected on the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP101000|EP101000]) Time and Expenses Preferences form even                               if the approval workflow functionality is activated for AP documents                               on the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP101000|AP101000]) Accounts Payable Preferences (AP101000) form (the                                Require Approval  check box is selected).                          Also, the resulting transactions can be automatically posted to the General                         Ledger module if the  Automatically Post on Release                          check box is selected on the   ([~/?ScreenId=AR101000|AR101000]) Accounts Receivable Preferences (AR101000)                         or   ([~/?ScreenId=AP101000|AP101000]) Accounts Payable Preferences (AP101000) form.  ([~/?ScreenId=AP101000|AP101000])  ([~/?ScreenId=AR101000|AR101000])  ([~/?ScreenId=EP502000|EP502000])  ([~/?ScreenId=EP301030|EP301030])  ([~/?ScreenId=EP501000|EP501000])  ([~/?ScreenId=EP101000|EP101000]) ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="b4123559-8d36-4fb1-8e4c-719fdd742917" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="78a990ee-62d7-64cb-78f7-523c60396fd7" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
In Acumatica ERP, you can release expense claims in one of the following ways:[anchor|#ul_u1c_xxd_3p]
*One individual claim at a time: Use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_10_30|Expense Claims] ([~/?ScreenId=EP301030|EP301030]) form as a starting point.
*Multiple claims at once: Use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_50_10_00|Release Expense Claims] ([~/?ScreenId=EP501000|EP501000]) form.
{br}

You can release only the expense claims that have the ''Approved'' status.
==To Release an Individual Expense Claim==[anchor|#ol_k3p_5rq_hp]
#On the '''Organization''' tab, click '''Time & Expenses'''. In the left pane, select the '''Work Area''' tab, and then navigate to '''Enter''' > '''Expense Claims'''.
#Select the '''Approved''' filter tab to view only the claims that have been approved and are ready to be released.
#Locate the expense claim that you want to release, and then click the link in the '''Reference Nbr.''' box, which brings up the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_10_00|Expense Claim] ([~/?ScreenId=EP301000|EP301000]) form, where you can view the details of the claim.
#On the form toolbar, click '''Actions''' > '''Release'''.

==To Release Multiple Expense Claims==[anchor|#ol_nlq_wrq_hp]
#On the '''Organization''' tab, click '''Time & Expenses'''. In the left pane, select the '''Processes''' tab, and then navigate to '''Daily''' > '''Release Expense Claims'''.
#Do one of the following:
#*To release only certain expense claims, in the unlabeled column, select the check boxes for the claims that you want to release, and then click '''Release''' on the form toolbar.
#*To release all listed expense claims, click '''Release All''' on the form toolbar.
]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[To Release Expense Claims In  Acumatica ERP, you can release expense claims in one of the following ways: One individual claim at a time: Use the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP301030|EP301030]) Expense Claims                         (EP301030) form as a starting point. Multiple claims at once: Use the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP501000|EP501000]) Release Expense Claims                         (EP501000) form. You can release only the expense claims that have the  Approved  status. To Release an Individual Expense Claim On the  Organization  tab, click  Time & Expenses . In the left                     pane, select the  Work Area  tab, and then navigate to  Enter Expense Claims . Select the  Approved  filter tab to view only the claims that have been                     approved and are ready to be released. Locate the expense claim that you want to release, and then click the link in                     the  Reference Nbr.  box, which brings up the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP301000|EP301000]) Expense Claim (EP301000) form, where you can view the details of the claim. On the form toolbar, click  Actions Release . To Release Multiple Expense Claims On the  Organization  tab, click  Time & Expenses . In the left                     pane, select the  Processes  tab, and then navigate to  Daily Release Expense Claims . Do one of the following: To release only certain expense claims, in the unlabeled column, select                             the check boxes for the claims that you want to release, and then click                                  Release  on the form toolbar. To release all listed expense claims, click  Release All  on the                             form toolbar. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="33906ce9-340d-42f0-bb63-25d8fe3f88b7" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="ed9e768a-fdd7-7bc6-e038-5307a129d52a" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
 Acumatica ERP provides time reporting capabilities that you can use in the following instances: [anchor|#ul_imk_2mn_gq]
*You want to track the time employees spend on individual activities to facilitate the calculation of costs and prices for particular projects and customer services.
*:Employees can use time activities—that is, activities for which employees must report the time that they have spent on them. To enable time activities in the system, you need to enable the ''Time Reporting on Activity'' feature. For details, see [HelpRoot_Organization\EP__con_Time_Tracking|Time Activities].
*You want to track the time employees spend on various activities each week in order to facilitate payroll calculations.
*:For each employee whose time should be reported, you need to select the '''Time Card is Required''' check box on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_30_00|Employees] ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000]) form. A time card is a weekly report on the time spent by the employee on activities. If the ''Time Reporting on Activity'' feature is enabled for your company, you can report working hours by using time cards in combination with time activities. For more information, see [HelpRoot_Organization\EP__con_Time_Sheet_Processing|Time Cards].

==In This Chapter==[anchor|#ul_sfs_bvr_rq]
*[HelpRoot_Organization\EP__con_Time_Tracking|Time Activities]
*[HelpRoot_Organization\EP__con_Time_Sheet_Processing|Time Cards]
]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Reporting Time  Acumatica ERP provides time reporting capabilities that you can use in the following instances:  You want to track the time employees spend on individual activities to facilitate the           calculation of costs and prices for particular projects and customer services. Employees             can use time activities—that is, activities for which employees must report the time             that they have spent on them. To enable time activities in the system, you need to             enable the  Time Reporting on Activity  feature. For details, see  Time Activities. You want to track the time employees spend on various activities each week in order to           facilitate payroll calculations. For each employee whose time should be reported, you             need to select the  Time Card is Required  check box on the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000]) Employees (EP203000) form. A time card is a weekly report on the             time spent by the employee on activities. If the  Time Reporting on Activity              feature is enabled for your company, you can report working hours by using time cards in             combination with time activities. For more information, see  Time Cards. In This Chapter Time ActivitiesTime Cards]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="188a7551-0227-409b-91d2-059717a304c4" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="7f8a1dc7-2026-ad6d-2985-dcef4f904a88" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
In Acumatica ERP, you can enable a feature that gives employees the ability to report the time that they spend on each time activity.{br}{TOC}
==Enabling Time Reporting==
 To enable time reporting for activities, you need to enable the ''Time Reporting on Activity'' feature on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) form, which makes the '''Track Time''' check box available on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CR_30_60_10|Activity] ([~/?ScreenId=CR306010|CR306010]) form. This check box, when selected, enables a group of elements on the same form which you can use to report the total time spent on the activity. Also, by using this group of elements, you can mark the activity as billable and specify the information required for billing—that is, the amount of billable time and the earning type of the activity (for details, see [HelpRoot_CRM\CR__con_Case_Billing|Case Billing]). {br}

If you want the '''Track Time''' check box to be selected by default for activities of certain types, you need to select the corresponding check boxes in the '''Track Time''' column on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CR_10_20_00|Activity Types] ([~/?ScreenId=CR102000|CR102000]) form. 
==Using Earning Types==
In Acumatica ERP, you have to specify an earning type for each billable activity; the earning type determines how the system calculates the cost of employee labor.{br}

The system recognizes two classes of earning types: those defining standard working hours and those defining overtime. On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_10_20_00|Earning Types] ([~/?ScreenId=EP102000|EP102000]) form, where you can add new earning types and adjust the available ones, you can also specify whether an earning type defines standard working hours or overtime by clearing or selecting the '''Overtime''' check box, respectively. On the same form, you can update the multiplier value for any overtime earning type—the system multiplies the employee rate by the multiplier value when calculating the cost of employee labor. For standard working hours, the multiplier is always ''1''.{br}

 By default, the following earning types are available in the system:
*''Regular Hours (RG)'': Standard working hours whose cost is calculated based on the standard employee rate.
*''Overtime (OT)'': Overtime working hours whose cost is calculated by multiplying the standard rate by the value of the overtime multiplier.
*''Public Holidays (HL)'': Non-working hours of public holidays, which are non-billable. You can use this earning type to indicate that certain days included in the time card are public holidays when no work is done.
*''Vacations (VL)'': Non-working hours of vacations, which are also non-billable. You can use this earning type to indicate that the employee is not working due to vacation.

==Approving Activities==
A time activity can be associated with a project task that has an approver specified. If this is the case, the time activity must be approved before it can be released for billing. Either the project task approver or the project manager can approve the time activity.{br}

You can use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_50_70_10|Approve Time Activities] ([~/?ScreenId=EP507010|EP507010]) form to approve activities that require your approval. If you use time cards, you can approve time activities in groups by approving time card summaries on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_50_70_30|Approve Time Activity Summaries] ([~/?ScreenId=EP507030|EP507030]) form.{br}

When the activities are released, the system tracks costs for specific customers, cases, contracts, or projects and generates the corresponding project transactions or customer invoices.
==Related Articles==
*[HelpRoot_Organization\EP__con_Time_Sheet_Processing|Time Cards]
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_70_00|Employee Time Activities] ([~/?ScreenId=EP307000|EP307000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_40_43_00|Activities] ([~/?ScreenId=EP404300|EP404300])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_50_70_10|Approve Time Activities] ([~/?ScreenId=EP507010|EP507010])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_50_70_30|Approve Time Activity Summaries] ([~/?ScreenId=EP507030|EP507030])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_10_20_00|Earning Types] ([~/?ScreenId=EP102000|EP102000])]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Time Activities In  Acumatica ERP, you can enable a feature that gives employees the ability to report the time 				that they spend on each time activity. Enabling Time Reporting  To enable time reporting for activities, you need to enable the  Time Reporting on 					Activity  feature on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features (CS100000) form, 				which makes the  Track Time  check box available on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CR306010|CR306010]) Activity (CR306010) form. This check box, when selected, 				enables a group of elements on the same form which you can use to report the total 				time spent on the activity. Also, by using this group of elements, you can mark the 				activity as billable and specify the information required for billing—that is, the 				amount of billable time and the earning type of the activity (for details, see  Case Billing).  If you want the  Track Time  check box to be selected by default 				for activities of certain types, you need to select the corresponding check boxes in 				the  Track Time  column on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CR102000|CR102000]) Activity Types (CR102000) 				form.  Using Earning Types In  Acumatica ERP, you have to specify an earning type for each billable activity; the earning type 				determines how the system calculates the cost of employee labor. The system recognizes two classes of earning types: those defining standard working 				hours and those defining overtime. On the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP102000|EP102000]) Earning Types 				(EP102000) form, where you can add new earning types and adjust the available 				ones, you can also specify whether an earning type defines standard working hours or 				overtime by clearing or selecting the  Overtime  check box, 				respectively. On the same form, you can update the multiplier value for any overtime 				earning type—the system multiplies the employee rate by the multiplier value when 				calculating the cost of employee labor. For standard working hours, the multiplier 				is always  1 .  By default, the following earning types are available in the system: Regular Hours (RG) : Standard working hours whose cost is calculated based on the 					standard employee rate. Overtime (OT) : Overtime working hours whose cost is calculated by multiplying the 					standard rate by the value of the overtime multiplier. Public Holidays (HL) : Non-working hours of public holidays, which are non-billable. 					You can use this earning type to indicate that certain days included in the time 					card are public holidays when no work is done. Vacations (VL) : Non-working hours of vacations, which are also non-billable. You can 					use this earning type to indicate that the employee is not working due to 					vacation. Approving Activities A time activity can be associated with a project task that has an approver specified. If this 				is the case, the time activity must be approved before it can be released for 				billing. Either the project task approver or the project manager can approve the 				time activity. You can use the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP507010|EP507010]) Approve Time Activities (EP507010) form to approve activities that 				require your approval. If you use time cards, you can approve time activities in 				groups by approving time card summaries on the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP507030|EP507030]) Approve Time Activity Summaries 				(EP507030) form. When the activities are released, the system tracks costs for specific customers, cases, 				contracts, or projects and generates the corresponding project transactions or 				customer invoices.  ([~/?ScreenId=EP307000|EP307000])  ([~/?ScreenId=EP404300|EP404300])  ([~/?ScreenId=EP507010|EP507010])  ([~/?ScreenId=EP507030|EP507030])  ([~/?ScreenId=EP102000|EP102000]) ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="7bad82ce-b6ea-4b5c-beab-4083eb3e299a" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="5d451ca4-19fe-d53c-e49a-d989351d4063" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
To assist you with efficient billing, calculation of payroll, and estimation of project costs, Acumatica ERP provides the time card functionality. A time card is a weekly report on the time you have spent on each activity.{br}

By using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_50_00|Employee Time Card] ([~/?ScreenId=EP305000|EP305000]) form, employees can enter new time cards or view, edit, or release existing time cards.{br}{TOC}
==Enabling Time Cards==
Time cards are available in Acumatica ERP only if the ''Advanced Financials'' check box is selected on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) form.{br}

By default, employees are not required to fill in time cards. However, if time cards are mandatory in your company, you can make them required on a per-employee basis by selecting the '''Time Card is Required''' check box on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_30_00|Employees] ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000]) form.{br}

Time cards are always generated successively, which means that you cannot generate a successive time card for a particular week if no time card has been generated for the preceding week.((({S:Hint}Suppose that the latest time card was generated for an employee a considerable time ago, and now you want to resume the generation of time cards for this employee, but you don&rsquo;t need any time cards for the intervening time interval. To generate multiple empty time cards for the intervening time interval, you can select the employee on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_30_00|Employees] ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000]) form and then, on the '''Employment History''' tab, click '''Generate Time Cards''' on the table toolbar.
)))
==Accessing Time Cards==
On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_50_00|Employee Time Card] form, you can create, view, or adjust any of the following time cards:[anchor|#ul_mhf_xvd_jx]
*Your time cards
*Time cards of the employees for whom you are an appointed delegate
*Time cards of the employees who report to you
*Time cards assigned to you for approval
*Time cards of employees in the workgroups at lower levels in the company tree than your workgroup

On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_50_30_10|Approvals] ([~/?ScreenId=EP503010|EP503010]) form, you can access the following time cards:[anchor|#ul_rhy_tcy_r3]
*Those assigned to you
*Those assigned to other users in your workgroup
*Those escalated from users in workgroups at a lower level in the company tree but in your workgroup&rsquo;s node
((({S:Hint}For more information about the company tree, see [HelpRoot_Organization\EP__con_Company_Organizational_Chart|Company Tree and Workgroups].
)))
==Processing Time Cards==
As a rule, each time card passes through several stages, which might include preparation, approval, and release. The processing stage of a time card is indicated by its status.
==Preparing Time Cards==
When preparing a time card, an employee reports work time by creating separate detail records for the following types of activities:[anchor|#ul_hmd_z2m_fq]
*Those associated with different projects or project tasks
*Those related to different earning types
*Those that are billable and those that are non-billable 

==Assigning Time Cards for Approval==
Depending on the company policy, time cards may need to be approved by authorized employees before they can be released. The time card approval functionality is available if the ''Approval Workflow'' feature is enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) form.{br}

Time cards are assigned for approval automatically according to the assignment rules that are included in the assignment map, which you create on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_55_00|Assignment and Approval Maps] ([~/?ScreenId=EP205500|EP205500]) form. To apply these rules, you need to specify the created map as the time card approval map by using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_10_10_00|Time and Expenses Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=EP101000|EP101000]) form; if no assignment map has been specified there or if a time card meets none of the specified map's conditions, the time card automatically becomes approved. {br}

The system assigns a time card for approval when the time card is completed and the employee changes its status from ''On Hold'' to ''Open''. For more information, see [HelpRoot_Organization\EP__con_Assignment_Automation|Managing Assignment and Approval Maps].
==Approving Time Cards==
A time card cannot be released until it has been approved (if approval is required). If you are an approver, you can approve time cards in bulk by using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_50_30_10|Approvals] ([~/?ScreenId=EP503010|EP503010]) form, or you can approve time cards one at a time by using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_50_00|Employee Time Card] ([~/?ScreenId=EP305000|EP305000]) form.((({S:Hint}If the ''Time Reporting on Activity'' feature is enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] form, you cannot release a time card unless all the activities included in the time card have been approved (if required). For more information, see [HelpRoot_Organization\EP__con_Time_Tracking|Time Activities].
)))
==Using Corrective Time Cards==
If a released time card doesn&rsquo;t reflect the actual time that the employee spent on activities during the week (for example, if the employee reported 40 hours instead of actual 45 hours), the employee can create a corrective time card by opening the released time card on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_50_00|Employee Time Card] ([~/?ScreenId=EP305000|EP305000]) and clicking '''Actions''' &gt; '''Correct''' on the form toolbar.{br}

The data from the original time card is copied to the corrective time card, which has ''Correction'' in the '''Type''' box and the reference number of the original time card in the '''Orig. Reg. Nbr.''' read-only box. The employee can adjust the data of the corrective time card as needed before submitting it for approval (if required). After that, the original time card, because it has been replaced by the corrective time card, is no longer available on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_40_60_00|Employee Time Cards] ([~/?ScreenId=EP406000|EP406000]) inquiry form.{br}

When the corrective time card is released, new transactions are generated for only the difference in the reported hours on this card as compared to the original time card.{br}

A released corrective time card can also be corrected.((({S:Hint}You can correct equipment time cards in a similar way by using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_80_00|Equipment Time Card] ([~/?ScreenId=EP308000|EP308000]) form.
)))
==Combining Time Cards and Time Activities==
In Acumatica ERP, an employee can report working hours by using time cards in combination with time activities. The reported data from a time activity instantly becomes available in one of the employee&rsquo;s time cards. On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_50_00|Employee Time Card] form, the employee can view details of all time activities associated with a particular time card.{br}

A time card can be approved only if all the activities associated with the time card have been approved. When the time card is released, the associated activities are released automatically. An activity cannot be released on its own if it is associated with a time card.{br}

A project transaction may be created during time card release if any of the activities included in the time card is associated with a project. (Alternatively, the same project transaction may be generated if the activity is associated with a billable case, and the case is billed directly to the customer before the time card is released. For details about direct case billing, see [HelpRoot_CRM\CR__con_Case_Billing|Case Billing].) Such transactions can be used for tracking the project costs. (For more information about project cost tracking, see [HelpRoot_Projects\PM__con_Budget_Tracking|Project Budgets].)
==Using Equipment Time Cards==
By using the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_80_00|Equipment Time Card] ([~/?ScreenId=EP308000|EP308000]) form, employees can enter equipment time cards or update existing ones, which gives them the ability to report the time they spend using particular equipment. The processing of equipment time cards is similar to the processing of employee time cards, including the usage of corrective time cards.{br}

Equipment time cards can be associated with specific projects and project tasks. Also, you can use the approval functionality to make sure that before they are released, equipment time cards are approved by the authorized approvers. You can specify the approval map for equipment time cards on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_10_10_00|Time and Expenses Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=EP101000|EP101000]) form; however, if you have not specified the assignment map or if a time card meets none of the specified map's conditions, the time card automatically becomes approved.
==Related Articles==
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_50_00|Employee Time Card] ([~/?ScreenId=EP305000|EP305000])
*[HelpRoot_Organization\EP__con_Time_Tracking|Time Activities]
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_40_61|Company Tree] ([~/?ScreenId=EP204061|EP204061])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_55_00|Assignment and Approval Maps] ([~/?ScreenId=EP205500|EP205500])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_50_70_10|Approve Time Activities] ([~/?ScreenId=EP507010|EP507010])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_50_50_10|Release Time Cards] ([~/?ScreenId=EP505010|EP505010])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_30_80_00|Equipment Time Card] ([~/?ScreenId=EP308000|EP308000])]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Time Cards To assist you with efficient billing, calculation of payroll, and estimation of 				project costs,  Acumatica ERP provides the time card functionality. A time card is a weekly report on the time 				you have spent on each activity. By using the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP305000|EP305000]) Employee Time Card (EP305000) form, employees can enter 				new time cards or view, edit, or release existing time cards. Enabling Time Cards Time cards are available in  Acumatica ERP only if the  Advanced Financials  check box is selected on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features (CS100000) form. By default, employees are not required to fill in time cards. However, if time cards 				are mandatory in your company, you can make them required on a per-employee basis by 				selecting the  Time Card is Required  check box on the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000]) Employees (EP203000) form. Time cards are always generated successively, which means that you cannot generate a 				successive time card for a particular week if no time card has been generated for 				the preceding week. Suppose that the latest time card was generated for an employee a considerable 				time ago, and now you want to resume the generation of time cards for this employee, 				but you don't need any time cards for the intervening time interval. To generate 				multiple empty time cards for the intervening time interval, you can select the 				employee on the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP203000|EP203000]) Employees (EP203000) form and then, on the 					 Employment History  tab, click  Generate Time 					Cards  on the table toolbar. Accessing Time Cards On the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP305000|EP305000]) Employee Time Card form, you can create, view, or adjust any of 				the following time cards: Your time cards Time cards of the employees for whom you are an appointed delegate Time cards of the employees who report to you Time cards assigned to you for approval Time cards of employees in the workgroups at lower levels in the company tree 					than your workgroup On the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP503010|EP503010]) Approvals (EP503010) form, you can 				access the following time cards: Those assigned to you Those assigned to other users in your workgroup Those escalated from users in workgroups at a lower level in the company tree 					but in your workgroup's node For more information about the company tree, see  Company Tree and Workgroups. Processing Time Cards As a rule, each time card passes through several stages, which might include 				preparation, approval, and release. The processing stage of a time card is indicated 				by its status. Preparing Time Cards When preparing a time card, an employee reports work time by creating separate detail 				records for the following types of activities: Those associated with different projects or project tasks Those related to different earning types Those that are billable and those that are non-billable  Assigning Time Cards for Approval Depending on the company policy, time cards may need to be approved by authorized employees 				before they can be released. The time card approval functionality is available if 				the  Approval Workflow  feature is enabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features (CS100000) form. Time cards are assigned for approval automatically according to the assignment rules 				that are included in the assignment map, which you create on the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP205500|EP205500]) Assignment and Approval Maps (EP205500) form. To apply these 				rules, you need to specify the created map as the time card approval map by using 				the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP101000|EP101000]) Time and Expenses Preferences (EP101000) form; if no 				assignment map has been specified there or if a time card meets none of the 				specified map's conditions, the time card automatically becomes approved.  The system assigns a time card for approval when the time card is completed and the 				employee changes its status from  On Hold  to  Open . For more 				information, see  Managing Assignment and Approval Maps. Approving Time Cards A time card cannot be released until it has been approved (if approval is required). 				If you are an approver, you can approve time cards in bulk by using the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP503010|EP503010]) Approvals (EP503010) form, or you can approve time cards one 				at a time by using the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP305000|EP305000]) Employee Time Card (EP305000) form. If the  Time Reporting on Activity  feature is enabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features form, you cannot release a time card unless all the 				activities included in the time card have been approved (if required). For more 				information, see  Time Activities. Using Corrective Time Cards If a released time card doesn't reflect the actual time that the employee spent on activities 				during the week (for example, if the employee reported 40 hours instead of actual 45 				hours), the employee can create a corrective time card by opening the released time 				card on the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP305000|EP305000]) Employee Time Card (EP305000) and clicking 					 Actions  >  Correct  on the form 				toolbar. The data from the original time card is copied to the corrective time card, which has 					 Correction  in the  Type  box and the reference 				number of the original time card in the  Orig. Reg. Nbr.  				read-only box. The employee can adjust the data of the corrective time card as 				needed before submitting it for approval (if required). After that, the original 				time card, because it has been replaced by the corrective time card, is no longer 				available on the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP406000|EP406000]) Employee Time Cards (EP406000) inquiry form. When the corrective time card is released, new transactions are generated for only 				the difference in the reported hours on this card as compared to the original time 				card. A released corrective time card can also be corrected. You can correct equipment time cards in a similar way by using the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP308000|EP308000]) Equipment Time Card (EP308000) form. Combining Time Cards and Time Activities In  Acumatica ERP, an employee can report working hours by using time cards in combination with 				time activities. The reported data from a time activity instantly becomes available 				in one of the employee's time cards. On the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP305000|EP305000]) Employee Time Card form, 				the employee can view details of all time activities associated with a particular 				time card. A time card can be approved only if all the activities associated with the time card 				have been approved. When the time card is released, the associated activities are 				released automatically. An activity cannot be released on its own if it is 				associated with a time card. A project transaction may be created during time card release if any of the activities 				included in the time card is associated with a project. (Alternatively, the same 				project transaction may be generated if the activity is associated with a billable 				case, and the case is billed directly to the customer before the time card is 				released. For details about direct case billing, see  Case Billing.) Such transactions can be used for tracking 				the project costs. (For more information about project cost tracking, see  Project Budgets.) Using Equipment Time Cards By using the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP308000|EP308000]) Equipment Time Card (EP308000) form, employees can enter equipment 				time cards or update existing ones, which gives them the ability to report the time 				they spend using particular equipment. The processing of equipment time cards is 				similar to the processing of employee time cards, including the usage of corrective 				time cards. Equipment time cards can be associated with specific projects and project tasks. 				Also, you can use the approval functionality to make sure that before they are 				released, equipment time cards are approved by the authorized approvers. You can 				specify the approval map for equipment time cards on the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP101000|EP101000]) Time and Expenses Preferences (EP101000) form; however, if you have not specified 				the assignment map or if a time card meets none of the specified map's conditions, 				the time card automatically becomes approved.  ([~/?ScreenId=EP305000|EP305000])  ([~/?ScreenId=EP204061|EP204061])  ([~/?ScreenId=EP205500|EP205500])  ([~/?ScreenId=EP507010|EP507010])  ([~/?ScreenId=EP505010|EP505010])  ([~/?ScreenId=EP308000|EP308000]) ]]></column>
		</row>
	</rows>
</data>