<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<data>
	<table name="WikiRevision">
		<col name="CompanyID" type="Int" default="Zero" />
		<col name="PageID" type="UniqueIdentifier" />
		<col name="Language" type="VarChar(50)" />
		<col name="PageRevisionID" type="Int" />
		<col name="Content" type="NVarChar(MAX)" />
		<col name="ContentHtml" type="NVarChar(MAX)" nullable="true" />
		<col name="PlainText" type="NVarChar(MAX)" />
		<col name="ApprovalByID" type="UniqueIdentifier" nullable="true" />
		<col name="ApprovalDateTime" type="DateTime" nullable="true" />
		<col name="CreatedByID" type="UniqueIdentifier" />
		<col name="CreatedDateTime" type="DateTime" />
		<col name="CompanyMask" type="VarBinary(32)" default="CompanyMaskReadOnly" />
		<col name="UID" type="UniqueIdentifier" />
		<col name="RecordSourceID" type="SmallInt" nullable="true" />
	</table>
	<rows>
		<row PageID="7c048700-ca24-4c0c-b10d-d694bcd0eb03" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="4b9f283b-4d58-f142-64d3-a9622dcfc56d" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
In Acumatica ERP, you can reserve stock when you enter sales orders so that the items promised to a customer cannot be shipped to another customer. With a sales order of the ''SA'' type (that is, a sales order with allocations), the system allocates the item quantity on the sales order automatically once the sales order is saved.{br}

If you want to allocate the items of an existing regular sales order of the ''SO'' type, or you want to allocate the items of a sales order partially, you need to perform the steps described in this guide.{br}{TOC}[anchor|#section_xwm_511_dy]
==1. Create a Sales Order==
On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\SO_30_10_00|Sales Orders] ([~/?ScreenId=SO301000|SO301000]) form, you create a sales order of the ''SO'' type, and fill in the '''Document Details''' tab with the ordered items.((({S:Hint}You can also allocate the items of an existing ''SO'' sales order with the ''On Hold'' or ''Open'' status.
)))[anchor|#section_fl4_4qr_zz]
==2. Allocate the Quantity of an Item==
On the '''Document Details''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\SO_30_10_00|Sales Orders] ([~/?ScreenId=SO301000|SO301000]) form, you click the line for which you are going to allocate a quantity of the item, and on the table toolbar, you click '''Allocations'''. The '''Allocations''' dialog box opens.[anchor|#fig_y2h_hpg_11b][anchor|#image_cgh_hpg_11b][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Allocating_Items_Step2.png|popup|450px]
In the dialog box, you select the '''Allocated''' check box, and click '''OK''' to close the dialog box. This quantity will be allocated when you save your changes to the sales order.[anchor|#fig_af3_dch_11b][anchor|#image_tg3_dch_11b][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Allocating_Items_Step2b.png|popup|450px]
During the allocation of an item that has an insufficient ''Available'' quantity at the warehouse the item is sold from, the system splits the allocated line in the '''Allocations''' dialog box to allocate all the ''Available'' quantity and leave the remaining quantity unallocated in the second line.[anchor|#fig_onl_qw3_b1b][anchor|#image_mpl_qw3_b1b][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Allocating_Items_Step2c.png|popup|450px][anchor|#section_fz1_rjh_11b]
==3. Optional: Allocate an Item That Is Tracked by Lot or Serial Number==
When an item that is tracked by lot or serial number is allocated, you can select the lot or serial number in the '''Lot/Serial Nbr.''' box of the '''Allocations''' dialog box. Alternatively, you can leave this box blank and select lot or serial number when you process the shipment for the sales order.((({S:Hint}If a lot or serial number has been selected on allocation, when you process the shipment for the sales order, you can change the lot or serial number, if needed.
)))[anchor|#fig_yjp_13h_11b][anchor|#image_llp_13h_11b][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Allocating_Items_Step3.png|popup|450px][anchor|#section_rvj_rjh_11b]
==4. Optional: Allocate an Item at Another Warehouse==
You can also allocate an item at a different warehouse than the one the item is sold from—for example, if the item has no ''Available'' quantity at the warehouse—by changing the warehouse in the '''Alloc. Warehouse''' box of the '''Allocations''' dialog box.((({S:Hint}The quantities allocated at another warehouse need to be transferred to the warehouse the item was sold from before the item is shipped to the customer. For details, see [HelpRoot_OrderMgmt\SO__MNG_TR_Orders|Sale with Transferred Stock Items].
)))[anchor|#fig_h2y_djh_11b][anchor|#image_lfy_djh_11b][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Allocating_Items_Step4.png|popup|450px][anchor|#section_ory_gmh_11b]
==5. Save the Sales Order==
To allocate the items, you save your changes to the sales order.
==Related Articles==
*[HelpRoot_OrderMgmt\SO__con_scn_Sale_with_Shipping|Sale of Stock Items with Shipping]
*[HelpRoot_OrderMgmt\SO__How_Create_Sale_Order_SA|To Create a Sales Order with Allocations (SA)]]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Allocating Items During Sales Order Processing In  Acumatica ERP, you can reserve stock when you enter sales orders so that the items promised to                 a customer cannot be shipped to another customer. With a sales order of the                      SA  type (that is, a sales order with allocations), the system allocates                 the item quantity on the sales order automatically once the sales order is                 saved. If you want to allocate the items of an existing regular sales order of the  SO                  type, or you want to allocate the items of a sales order partially, you need to                 perform the steps described in this guide. 1. Create a Sales Order On the   ([~/?ScreenId=SO301000|SO301000]) Sales Orders (SO301000) form, you create a                 sales order of the  SO  type, and fill in the  Document                     Details  tab with the ordered items. You can also allocate the items of an existing  SO  sales order with the                      On Hold  or  Open  status. 2. Allocate the Quantity of an Item On the  Document Details  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=SO301000|SO301000]) Sales Orders (SO301000) form, you click the line for                 which you are going to allocate a quantity of the item, and on the table toolbar,                 you click  Allocations . The  Allocations                  dialog box opens. In the dialog box, you select the  Allocated  check box, and                 click  OK  to close the dialog box. This quantity will be                 allocated when you save your changes to the sales order. During the allocation of an item that has an insufficient  Available  quantity at                 the warehouse the item is sold from, the system splits the allocated line in the                      Allocations  dialog box to allocate all the                      Available  quantity and leave the remaining quantity unallocated in the                 second line. 3. Optional: Allocate an Item That Is Tracked by Lot or Serial Number When an item that is tracked by lot or serial number is allocated, you can select the                 lot or serial number in the  Lot/Serial Nbr.  box of the                      Allocations  dialog box. Alternatively, you can leave this                 box blank and select lot or serial number when you process the shipment for the                 sales order. If a lot or serial number has been selected on allocation, when you process the                 shipment for the sales order, you can change the lot or serial number, if                 needed. 4. Optional: Allocate an Item at Another Warehouse You can also allocate an item at a different warehouse than the one the item is sold                 from—for example, if the item has no  Available  quantity at the                 warehouse—by changing the warehouse in the  Alloc.                     Warehouse  box of the  Allocations  dialog                 box. The quantities allocated at another warehouse need to be transferred to the                 warehouse the item was sold from before the item is shipped to the customer. For                 details, see  Sale with Transferred Stock Items. 5. Save the Sales Order To allocate the items, you save your changes to the sales order. To Create a Sales Order with Allocations (SA) ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="beb4a189-d545-4bed-b317-8e6b9eaf778e" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="889ec230-973f-e6e3-52c6-a3602610c2ad" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[[anchor|#section_own_yjf_l1b]
In Acumatica ERP, you can fulfill a sales order even if some of the items on the sales order have no ''Available'' quantity at the warehouse. You can allocate these items at a warehouse that differs from the warehouse of the sales order and then transfer the allocated items to fulfill the sales order, as described in this guide.{br}{TOC}[anchor|#section_xwm_511_dy][anchor|#title_tcs_r1c_n1b]
==1. Create a Sales Order==
On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\SO_30_10_00|Sales Orders] ([~/?ScreenId=SO301000|SO301000]) form, you create a sales order of the ''SO'' type and fill in the '''Document Details''' tab with the ordered items.{br}

If some items have no ''Available'' quantity at the warehouse of the sales order line, as shown in the following screenshot with ''LAPTOP12'', you can allocate them at another warehouse.((({S:Hint}You can select ''Ship Complete'' as the '''Shipping Rule''' of each sales order line if you want to ship the sales order only if the full quantity of all the sales order lines is available for shipping at the warehouse specified in the lines. You can predefine each customer&rsquo;s default shipping rule for sales orders on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AR_30_30_00|Customers] ([~/?ScreenId=AR303000|AR303000]) form.
)))[anchor|#fig_y2h_hpg_11b][anchor|#image_cgh_hpg_11b][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__SO_Transfer1.png|popup|450px]
For details, see [HelpRoot_OrderMgmt\SO__How_Create_Sale_Order|To Create a Sales Order (SO)].[anchor|#section_j2v_5tl_l1b][anchor|#title_xw5_r1c_n1b]
==2. Allocate the Unavailable Quantities of the Sales Order Lines==
On the '''Document Details''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\SO_30_10_00|Sales Orders] ([~/?ScreenId=SO301000|SO301000]) form, you allocate the items that have insufficient ''Available'' quantity at the warehouse. In the '''Allocations''' dialog box (as the screenshot below shows), you select the '''Allocated''' check box and an '''Alloc. Warehouse''' that differs from the warehouse of the sales order line and for which the item has a sufficient ''Available'' quantity.{br}

When you save the sales order with the ''Open'' status (that is, with the '''Hold''' check box cleared), the system generates transfer requests for each line of the sales order for which the item has been allocated in a warehouse other than the warehouse selected in the line.[anchor|#fig_mb5_jvc_n1b][anchor|#image_gc5_jvc_n1b][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__SO_Transfer2.png|popup|450px]
For details, see [HelpRoot_OrderMgmt\SO__How_Allocate_Item|To Reserve an Inventory Item for an Order].[anchor|#section_fhy_5tl_l1b][anchor|#title_dyx_r1c_n1b]
==3. Create the Transfer Order==
On the toolbar of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\SO_30_10_00|Sales Orders] ([~/?ScreenId=SO301000|SO301000]) form, you click '''Actions''' > '''Create Transfer Order''' to create transfer orders. On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\SO_50_90_00|Create Transfer Orders] ([~/?ScreenId=SO509000|SO509000]) form, which opens, you process the transfer requests of the sales order (see the following screenshot).((({S:Hint}You can also create transfer orders for multiple sales orders if the '''Order Type''' and '''Order Nbr.''' are cleared on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\SO_50_90_00|Create Transfer Orders] ([~/?ScreenId=SO509000|SO509000]) form.
)))
The system creates a consolidated transfer order, which is a sales order of the ''TR'' type, for each group of transfer requests that have both the same source warehouse ('''From Warehouse''') and the same destination warehouse ('''To Warehouse'''). The date of the created transfer orders is that specified in the '''Creation Date''' box.[anchor|#fig_c2t_xgd_n1b][anchor|#image_qft_xgd_n1b][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__SO_Transfer3.png|popup|450px]((({S:Hint}If you want to ship the transfer order only in full, you can select ''Ship Complete'' as the '''Shipping Rule''' of each transfer order line to avoid a partial shipment. You can predefine each branch&rsquo;s default shipping rule for transfer orders on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_20_00|Branches] ([~/?ScreenId=CS102000|CS102000]) form.
)))
For details, see [HelpRoot_OrderMgmt\SO__How_Create_Transfer_Order|To Create a Transfer Order (TR)].[anchor|#section_hx1_vtl_l1b][anchor|#title_jk1_s1c_n1b]
==4. Create the Shipment for the Transfer Order==
On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\SO_30_10_00|Sales Orders] ([~/?ScreenId=SO301000|SO301000]) form, you create the shipment for each transfer order (that is, sales order of the ''TR'' type) that has been created, as the following screenshot shows.((({S:Hint}You can also create shipments for multiple transfer orders on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\SO_50_10_00|Process Orders] ([~/?ScreenId=SO501000|SO501000]) form by selecting the ''Create Shipment'' action and processing the needed orders.
)))[anchor|#fig_dhc_4zd_n1b][anchor|#image_h3c_4zd_n1b][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__SO_Transfer4.png|popup|450px]
For details, see [HelpRoot_OrderMgmt\SO__How_Create_Shipment|To Create a Shipment for an Order].[anchor|#section_owr_k12_n1b][anchor|#title_xqj_h12_n1b]
==5. Process the Shipment==
On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\SO_30_20_00|Shipments] ([~/?ScreenId=SO302000|SO302000]) form, by selecting the appropriate actions on the form toolbar, you confirm each shipment that has been created and update the inventory to issue the items, as the following screenshot shows.((({S:Hint}You can also process multiple shipments at once on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\SO_50_30_00|Process Shipments] ([~/?ScreenId=SO503000|SO503000]) form.
)))[anchor|#fig_lfv_4zd_n1b][anchor|#image_zgv_4zd_n1b][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__SO_Transfer5.png|popup|450px]
For details, see [HelpRoot_OrderMgmt\SO__How_Confirm_Shipment|To Confirm a Shipment].[anchor|#section_fb2_vtl_l1b][anchor|#title_ozc_s1c_n1b]
==6. Create and Process the Transfer Receipts for the Shipment==
On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PO_30_20_00|Purchase Receipts] ([~/?ScreenId=PO302000|PO302000]) form, you create a receipt of the ''Transfer Receipt'' type, as the screenshot below shows. In the '''Warehouse''' box in the Summary area, you select the warehouse of the sales order, which will receive the transfer order.{br}

You then release the transfer receipt, which causes the inventory receipt to be created. When this inventory receipt is released, the system counts the items that have been transferred to the sales order as available.((({S:Hint}You can also receive multiple transfer orders with one transfer receipt.
)))[anchor|#fig_mbm_1d2_n1b][anchor|#image_adm_1d2_n1b][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__SO_Transfer6.png|popup|450px][anchor|#related-links_mqs_yjf_l1b]
==Related Articles==
*[HelpRoot_OrderMgmt\SO__MNG_TR_Orders|Sale with Transferred Stock Items]
*[HelpRoot_OrderMgmt\SO__con_scn_Sale_with_Transfer|Processing Steps for a Sale with Transfer]]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Fulfilling Sales Orders by Using Transfer Orders In  Acumatica ERP, you can fulfill a sales order even if some of the items on the sales order have                 no  Available  quantity at the warehouse. You can allocate these items at a                 warehouse that differs from the warehouse of the sales order and then transfer the                 allocated items to fulfill the sales order, as described in this guide. 1. Create a Sales Order On the   ([~/?ScreenId=SO301000|SO301000]) Sales Orders (SO301000) form, you create a                 sales order of the  SO  type and fill in the  Document                     Details  tab with the ordered items. If some items have no  Available  quantity at the warehouse of the sales order                 line, as shown in the following screenshot with  LAPTOP12 , you can allocate                 them at another warehouse. You can select  Ship Complete  as the  Shipping Rule  of                 each sales order line if you want to ship the sales order only if the full quantity                 of all the sales order lines is available for shipping at the warehouse specified in                 the lines. You can predefine each customer's default shipping rule for sales orders                 on the   ([~/?ScreenId=AR303000|AR303000]) Customers (AR303000) form. For details, see  To Create a Sales Order (SO). 2. Allocate the Unavailable Quantities of the Sales Order                 Lines On the  Document Details  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=SO301000|SO301000]) Sales Orders (SO301000) form, you allocate the items                 that have insufficient  Available  quantity at the warehouse. In the                      Allocations  dialog box (as the screenshot below shows),                 you select the  Allocated  check box and an  Alloc.                     Warehouse  that differs from the warehouse of the sales order line                 and for which the item has a sufficient  Available  quantity. When you save the sales order with the  Open  status (that is, with the                      Hold  check box cleared), the system generates transfer                 requests for each line of the sales order for which the item has been allocated in a                 warehouse other than the warehouse selected in the line. For details, see  To Reserve an Inventory Item for an Order. 3. Create the Transfer Order On the toolbar of the   ([~/?ScreenId=SO301000|SO301000]) Sales Orders (SO301000) form,                 you click  Actions Create Transfer Order  to create transfer orders. On the   ([~/?ScreenId=SO509000|SO509000]) Create Transfer Orders (SO509000) form, which opens, you process                 the transfer requests of the sales order (see the following screenshot). You can also create transfer orders for multiple sales orders if the                      Order Type  and  Order Nbr.  are                 cleared on the   ([~/?ScreenId=SO509000|SO509000]) Create Transfer Orders (SO509000) form. The system creates a consolidated transfer order, which is a sales order of the                      TR  type, for each group of transfer requests that have both the same                 source warehouse ( From Warehouse ) and the same destination                 warehouse ( To Warehouse ). The date of the created transfer                 orders is that specified in the  Creation Date  box. If you want to ship the transfer order only in full, you can select  Ship                     Complete  as the  Shipping Rule  of each transfer order                 line to avoid a partial shipment. You can predefine each branch's default shipping                 rule for transfer orders on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS102000|CS102000]) Branches                 (CS102000) form. For details, see  To Create a Transfer Order (TR). 4. Create the Shipment for the Transfer Order On the   ([~/?ScreenId=SO301000|SO301000]) Sales Orders (SO301000) form, you create the                 shipment for each transfer order (that is, sales order of the  TR  type) that                 has been created, as the following screenshot shows. You can also create shipments for multiple transfer orders on the   ([~/?ScreenId=SO501000|SO501000]) Process Orders (SO501000) form by selecting the                      Create Shipment  action and processing the needed orders. For details, see  To Create a Shipment for an Order. 5. Process the Shipment On the   ([~/?ScreenId=SO302000|SO302000]) Shipments (SO302000) form, by selecting the                 appropriate actions on the form toolbar, you confirm each shipment that has been                 created and update the inventory to issue the items, as the following screenshot                 shows. You can also process multiple shipments at once on the   ([~/?ScreenId=SO503000|SO503000]) Process Shipments (SO503000) form. For details, see  To Confirm a Shipment. 6. Create and Process the Transfer Receipts for the                 Shipment On the   ([~/?ScreenId=PO302000|PO302000]) Purchase Receipts (PO302000) form, you create a                 receipt of the  Transfer Receipt  type, as the screenshot below shows. In the                      Warehouse  box in the Summary area, you select the                 warehouse of the sales order, which will receive the transfer order. You then release the transfer receipt, which causes the inventory receipt to be                 created. When this inventory receipt is released, the system counts the items that                 have been transferred to the sales order as available. You can also receive multiple transfer orders with one transfer receipt. ]]></column>
		</row>
	</rows>
</data>