<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<data>
	<table name="WikiRevision">
		<col name="CompanyID" type="Int" default="Zero" />
		<col name="PageID" type="UniqueIdentifier" />
		<col name="Language" type="VarChar(50)" />
		<col name="PageRevisionID" type="Int" />
		<col name="Content" type="NVarChar(MAX)" />
		<col name="ContentHtml" type="NVarChar(MAX)" nullable="true" />
		<col name="PlainText" type="NVarChar(MAX)" />
		<col name="ApprovalByID" type="UniqueIdentifier" nullable="true" />
		<col name="ApprovalDateTime" type="DateTime" nullable="true" />
		<col name="CreatedByID" type="UniqueIdentifier" />
		<col name="CreatedDateTime" type="DateTime" />
		<col name="CompanyMask" type="VarBinary(32)" default="CompanyMaskReadOnly" />
		<col name="UID" type="UniqueIdentifier" />
		<col name="RecordSourceID" type="SmallInt" nullable="true" />
	</table>
	<rows>
		<row PageID="7efbb532-490d-47a8-835e-cc94c1231aa1" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="cff78a7e-0ac5-934d-a6e2-a192e231cff6" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
You can install Acumatica ERP locally on a server, as described in this guide.
==Before You Proceed==
Before you install Acumatica ERP, make sure that the server computer and software meet the system requirements, which are specified in [HelpRoot_Install\System_Requirements|System Requirements for Acumatica ERP 2019 R1].
==Steps==
[[#_142d1433-a8c8-447f-88aa-d4face758972|1. Install the Tools on the Server]{br}

[[#_15636f38-ddd1-422e-9bde-2d3b22be8af8|2. Deploy an Instance on the Server]{br}

[[#_ab17ccf0-5578-47ed-8385-a129363b85e2|3. Change the Password for the Default User]{br}

[[#_f3212bbb-90b3-4b6b-97de-9728855ac17b|4. Activate a License for the Instance][anchor|#_142d1433-a8c8-447f-88aa-d4face758972]
==1. Install the Acumatica ERP Tools on the Server==
To install the Acumatica ERP Tools, you run the Acumatica ERP installation package and follow the instructions of the Acumatica ERP Installer wizard. (See the following screenshot.)[anchor|#_05137900-32b9-4b36-aabe-4b7d3450d752][anchor|#_7049124d-62d4-468d-8f58-fe4ce23dcdeb][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Installing_Locally_Step1.png|popup|300px]
For details, see [HelpRoot_Install\Installing_ERP_Configuration_wizard|To Install the Acumatica ERP Tools].[anchor|#_15636f38-ddd1-422e-9bde-2d3b22be8af8]
==2. Deploy an Acumatica ERP Instance on the Server==
You deploy an Acumatica ERP instance by using the Acumatica ERP Configuration                             Wizard, as shown in the following screenshot.[anchor|#_c4832844-f7cc-4cda-992b-4a109e8d1039][anchor|#_a10483c8-e41e-4b48-b604-4217401aa911][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Installing_Locally_Step2.png|popup|300px]
For details, see [HelpRoot_Install\Installing_ERP_Instance|To Deploy an Acumatica ERP Instance].[anchor|#_ab17ccf0-5578-47ed-8385-a129363b85e2]
==3. Change the Password for the Default User==
Every Acumatica ERP instance comes with an active default user account that you use to sign in to the system. After installation, you start working with Acumatica ERP by changing the password for the default user (see the following screenshot). You use the following initial credentials for the default user:[anchor|#_07bd13bb-3da5-4940-ae30-7f12b3eddfff]
*User name: <tt>admin</tt>
*Password: <tt>setup</tt>
[anchor|#_93250d29-9f04-4d7c-8a6a-13a7a134c3a5][anchor|#_7acb0be9-0bc7-4ae1-8166-b79a66061d8a][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Installing_Locally_Step3.png|popup|450px]
For details, see [HelpRoot_Install\Intalling_First_Start|To Change the Password at the First Sign-In].[anchor|#_f3212bbb-90b3-4b6b-97de-9728855ac17b]
==4. Activate a License for the Acumatica ERP Instance==
On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\SM_20_15_10|Activate License] ([~/?ScreenId=SM201510|SM201510]) form, you activate your Acumatica ERP instance by entering a product key. (See the following screenshot.)[anchor|#_4fad1a79-c2d1-43a6-a030-1ca458b7c77d][anchor|#_b23558e6-51a6-41fb-bc8c-d8e440099589][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Installing_Locally_Step4.png|popup|400px]
For details, see [HelpRoot_Install\how__Licensing_ERP|To Activate the License for an Acumatica ERP Instance].
==Related Articles==
*[HelpRoot_Install\Installing_ERP_Locally|Installing Acumatica ERP Locally]
*[HelpRoot_Install\Licensing_Acumatica|Licensing and Activating Acumatica ERP]]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Installing  Acumatica ERP Locally You can install  Acumatica ERP locally on a server, as described in this guide. Before You Proceed Before you install  Acumatica ERP, make sure that the server computer and software meet the system requirements,                 which are specified in  System Requirements for Acumatica ERP 2019 R1. Steps 1. Install the  Tools on the Server 1. Install the Tools on the Server2. Deploy an  Instance on the Server 2. Deploy an Instance on the Server3. Change the Password for the Default User 3. Change the Password for the Default User4. Activate a License for the  Instance 4. Activate a License for the Instance1. Install the  Acumatica ERP Tools on the Server To install the  Acumatica ERP Tools, you run the  Acumatica ERP installation package and follow the instructions of the  Acumatica ERP Installer wizard. (See the following screenshot.) For details, see  To Install the Acumatica ERP Tools. 2. Deploy an  Acumatica ERP Instance on the Server You deploy an  Acumatica ERP instance by using the  Acumatica ERP Configuration                             Wizard, as shown in the following screenshot. For details, see  To Deploy an Acumatica ERP Instance. 3. Change the Password for the Default User Every  Acumatica ERP instance comes with an active default user account that you use to sign in to the                 system. After installation, you start working with  Acumatica ERP by changing the password for the default user (see the following screenshot). You                 use the following initial credentials for the default user: User name:  admin Password:  setup For details, see  To Change the Password at the First Sign-In. 4. Activate a License for the  Acumatica ERP Instance On the   ([~/?ScreenId=SM201510|SM201510]) Activate License (SM201510) form, you activate                 your  Acumatica ERP instance by entering a product key. (See the following screenshot.) For details, see  To Activate the License for an Acumatica ERP Instance. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="c59843e3-084e-4f33-9262-17602a7fae7e" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="6029ebb2-34ae-bdfa-3f1e-957bd9fc6381" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
In addition to deploying an Acumatica ERP instance, you can deploy Acumatica Self-Service                         Portal, where your customers can view all the relevant information about their interactions with your company and perform common activities online. In this guide, you will read about how to deploy Acumatica Self-Service                         Portal.
==Before You Proceed==
Before you start deploying Self-Service Portal, you need to install Acumatica ERP and deploy an instance because its database is used by the portal. For details, see [HelpRoot_Install\Installing_Acumatica|Installing Acumatica ERP].
==Steps==
[[#_3baf824e-9665-4bb6-af15-4394a906855a|1. Deploy a Instance]{br}

[[#_947fb3b1-bc32-48db-aeeb-20057bb92018|2. Optional: Specify the Company Available for Users]{br}

[[#_f76e4233-9014-4e8b-ad14-8ae6f1f4226f|3. Activate a License for][anchor|#_3baf824e-9665-4bb6-af15-4394a906855a]
==1. Deploy a Self-Service Portal Instance==
After you install the Acumatica ERP instance, you use the Acumatica ERP Configuration                             Wizard to deploy the Self-Service Portal instance and connect it to the database used by the Acumatica ERP instance. In the following screenshot, you can see the '''Create Portal''' check box, which you need to select on Step 6 of the Acumatica ERP Configuration                             Wizard.[anchor|#_bb9dc124-e144-4ccf-84c3-ec30057369c1][anchor|#_d08c2118-0bbc-47cb-bcfa-76ed8eb917fe][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Deploying_Portal_Step1.png|popup|300px]
For details, see [HelpRoot_Install\Installing_Portal_Deploying|To Deploy a Self-Service Portal Instance].[anchor|#_947fb3b1-bc32-48db-aeeb-20057bb92018]
==2. Optional: Specify the Company Available for Self-Service Portal Users==
If you use a multi-company Acumatica ERP configuration, after you deploy a Self-Service Portal instance, in the <tt>web.config</tt> file for the portal, you must specify the company that will be available for the Self-Service Portal users. (See the following screenshot.)[anchor|#_c1cdfb8c-3072-4d1a-a54c-66fdd0c44785][anchor|#_ed4a7460-d43a-48c1-bdb6-27d18ddbae2f][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Deploying_Portal_Step2.png|popup|300px]
For details, see [HelpRoot_Install\Installing_Portal_Configuring|To Specify the Tenant Available for Self-Service Portal Users].[anchor|#_f76e4233-9014-4e8b-ad14-8ae6f1f4226f]
==3. Activate a License for Self-Service Portal==
To use Self-Service Portal in production, you need to apply a license. If your license for Acumatica ERP provides you with a capability to launch the portal, you apply the same license on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\SM_20_15_10|Activate License] ([~/?ScreenId=SM201510|SM201510]) form of Self-Service Portal. (See the following screenshot.)[anchor|#_e97c2669-d98c-4816-9678-13d55659f3c9][anchor|#_e051dd2f-f856-48b7-b8fd-3796eab9ea29][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Deploying_Portal_Step3.png|popup|400px]
The instructions for activating the license are the same as those described in [HelpRoot_Install\how__Licensing_ERP|To Activate the License for an Acumatica ERP Instance], except that you perform these steps on Self-Service Portal.
==Related Articles==
*[HelpRoot_Install\Installing_Portal|Setting Up Acumatica Self-Service                         Portal]
*[HelpRoot_Install\Licensing_Acumatica|Licensing and Activating Acumatica ERP]]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Deploying  Acumatica Self-Service                         PortalIn addition to deploying an  Acumatica ERP instance, you can deploy  Acumatica Self-Service                         Portal, where your customers can view all the relevant information about their                 interactions with your company and perform common activities online. In this guide,                 you will read about how to deploy  Acumatica Self-Service                         Portal. Before You Proceed Before you start deploying  Self-Service Portal, you need to install  Acumatica ERP and deploy an instance because its database is used by the portal. For details,                 see  Installing Acumatica ERP. Steps 1. Deploy a  Instance 1. Deploy a Instance2. Optional: Specify the Company Available for  Users 2. Optional: Specify the Company Available for Users3. Activate a License for 3. Activate a License for1. Deploy a  Self-Service Portal Instance After you install the  Acumatica ERP instance, you use the  Acumatica ERP Configuration                             Wizard to deploy the  Self-Service Portal instance and connect it to the database used by the  Acumatica ERP instance. In the following screenshot, you can see the  Create                     Portal  check box, which you need to select on Step 6 of the  Acumatica ERP Configuration                             Wizard. For details, see  To Deploy a Self-Service Portal Instance. 2. Optional: Specify the Company Available for  Self-Service Portal Users If you use a multi-company  Acumatica ERP configuration, after you deploy a  Self-Service Portal instance, in the  web.config  file for the portal, you must                 specify the company that will be available for the  Self-Service Portal users. (See the following screenshot.) For details, see  To Specify the Tenant Available for Self-Service Portal Users. 3. Activate a License for  Self-Service PortalTo use  Self-Service Portal in production, you need to apply a license. If your license for  Acumatica ERP provides you with a capability to launch the portal, you apply the same license                 on the   ([~/?ScreenId=SM201510|SM201510]) Activate License (SM201510) form of  Self-Service Portal. (See the following screenshot.) The instructions for activating the license are the same as those described in  To Activate the License for an Acumatica ERP Instance, except that you perform                 these steps on  Self-Service Portal. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="6937d643-1dfd-4cda-9ae3-551f4895a656" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="d1cd2780-e9ad-071b-6f6a-4cd1adc87ed6" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
You can run Acumatica ERP on Amazon Web Services (AWS). In this case, you use Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) to host the web server and Amazon Relational Database Service (Amazon RDS) to host the databases. In this guide, you will read about installing Acumatica ERP on AWS.
==Before You Begin==
Before you start deploying Acumatica ERP on Amazon Web Services, you should do the following:[anchor|#ul_ngx_3d2_wl]
*Sign up for Amazon Web Services.
*Create a key pair, which you will need to get access to your Amazon EC2 instance.
*Create a security group that will specify your Amazon EC2 instance and that can access your Amazon RDS instance.
*Investigate the system requirements for the server computer and software and be sure they are met: [HelpRoot_Install\System_Requirements|System Requirements for Acumatica ERP 2019 R1].
*Investigate the recommended parameters of virtual machines: [HelpRoot_Install\System_Requirements_PCP_PCS_Licenses|Typical Hardware and Virtual Machine Configurations for PCS and PCP Licenses].

==Steps==
[[#_72ef70c3-380e-44ba-baa6-581939c2b0b4|1. Launch an Amazon EC2 Instance]{br}

[[#_875e6102-f757-4514-9f8b-3fb52e7cbbc2|2. Create a Database Instance on Amazon RDS]{br}

[[#_4da8d128-f128-4da0-bc1a-8d86778ac4c4|3. Deploy on Amazon EC2]{br}

[[#_aee965da-47b1-4b06-85f4-77b138254a23|4. Change the Password for the Default User]{br}

[[#_f9c90abc-09c2-4aa8-92b6-a472cfabaf7b|5. Activate a License for the Instance][anchor|#_72ef70c3-380e-44ba-baa6-581939c2b0b4]
==1. Launch an Amazon EC2 Instance==
You launch your Amazon EC2 instance and secure it by specifying a key pair and a security group. In the following screenshot, you can see the launched instance.[anchor|#_42031039-79a1-4b06-9919-8bd0d57939fa][anchor|#_43e2c678-70f7-4bf8-b7ca-de9058f37416][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Installing_Acumatica_on_AWS_Step1.png|popup|450px]{br}

For details, see [HelpRoot_Install\Installing_Amazon_EC2|To Launch an Amazon EC2 Instance].[anchor|#_875e6102-f757-4514-9f8b-3fb52e7cbbc2]
==2. Create a Database Instance on Amazon RDS==
You create a database instance by using the Amazon RDS console. After the database instance is launched, you copy the DNS name in the '''Endpoint''' box (see the following screenshot) because you will need it during the installation of Acumatica ERP.[anchor|#_f40703e2-2abe-4f91-9fa4-a2e9f5c82220][anchor|#_cb432658-727f-49ca-a4c3-0c81b401d8cb][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Installing_Acumatica_on_AWS_Step2.png|popup|450px]
For details, see [HelpRoot_Install\Installing_Amazon_RDS|To Create a Database Instance on Amazon RDS].[anchor|#_4da8d128-f128-4da0-bc1a-8d86778ac4c4]
==3. Deploy Acumatica ERP on Amazon EC2==
You install Acumatica ERP Tools and deploy application instances on Amazon EC2. In the following screenshot, you can see the Acumatica ERP Installation wizard on an Amazon EC2 virtual machine.[anchor|#_26aee550-d85b-4fda-934d-391a71369439][anchor|#_26319ae9-8acf-43b5-a027-7764e026fb18][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Installing_Acumatica_on_AWS_Step3.png|popup|450px]{br}

For details, see [HelpRoot_Install\Installing_Amazon__ERP|To Deploy Acumatica ERP on Amazon EC2].[anchor|#_aee965da-47b1-4b06-85f4-77b138254a23]
==4. Change the Password for the Default User==
Every Acumatica ERP instance comes with an active default user account that you use to sign in to the system. After installation, you start working with Acumatica ERP by changing the password for the default user. (See the following screenshot.) You use the following initial credentials for the default user:[anchor|#_07bd13bb-3da5-4940-ae30-7f12b3eddfff]
*User name: <tt>admin</tt>
*Password: <tt>setup</tt>
[anchor|#_8739ac4f-2ac2-4089-a8d3-c0dcb3e68d9b][anchor|#_84cdf25f-a9dc-4e14-81d9-6dfc60acdc44][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Installing_Locally_Step3.png|popup|450px]
For details, see [HelpRoot_Install\Intalling_First_Start|To Change the Password at the First Sign-In].[anchor|#_f9c90abc-09c2-4aa8-92b6-a472cfabaf7b]
==5. Activate a License for the Acumatica ERP Instance==
On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\SM_20_15_10|Activate License] ([~/?ScreenId=SM201510|SM201510]) form, you activate your Acumatica ERP instance by entering a product key, as shown in the following screenshot.[anchor|#_3b87f82c-97f9-4759-b636-4c5fd7ad3ff8][anchor|#_e9e0a82d-f153-4d21-a31f-aabeb9a45700][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Installing_Locally_Step4.png|popup|400px]
For details, see [HelpRoot_Install\how__Licensing_ERP|To Activate the License for an Acumatica ERP Instance].
==Related Articles==
*[HelpRoot_Install\Installing_Amazon_AWS_RDS|Installing Acumatica ERP on Amazon Web Services]
*[HelpRoot_Install\Installing_ERP_Locally|Installing Acumatica ERP Locally]
*[HelpRoot_Install\Licensing_Acumatica|Licensing and Activating Acumatica ERP]]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Installing  Acumatica ERP on Amazon Web Services You can run  Acumatica ERP on Amazon Web Services (AWS). In this case, you use Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud                 (Amazon EC2) to host the web server and Amazon Relational Database Service (Amazon                 RDS) to host the databases. In this guide, you will read about installing  Acumatica ERP on AWS. Before You Begin Before you start deploying  Acumatica ERP on Amazon Web Services, you should do the following: Sign up for Amazon Web Services. Create a key pair, which you will need to get access to your Amazon EC2                     instance. Create a security group that will specify your Amazon EC2 instance and that can                     access your Amazon RDS instance. Investigate the system requirements for the server computer and software and be                     sure they are met:  System Requirements for Acumatica ERP 2019 R1. Investigate the recommended parameters of virtual machines:  Typical Hardware and Virtual Machine Configurations for PCS and PCP Licenses. Steps 1. Launch an Amazon EC2 Instance 1. Launch an Amazon EC2 Instance2. Create a Database Instance on Amazon RDS 2. Create a Database Instance on Amazon RDS3. Deploy  on Amazon EC2 3. Deploy on Amazon EC24. Change the Password for the Default User 4. Change the Password for the Default User5. Activate a License for the  Instance 5. Activate a License for the Instance1. Launch an Amazon EC2 Instance You launch your Amazon EC2 instance and secure it by specifying a key pair and a                 security group. In the following screenshot, you can see the launched instance. For details, see  To Launch an Amazon EC2 Instance. 2. Create a Database Instance on Amazon RDS You create a database instance by using the Amazon RDS console. After the database                 instance is launched, you copy the DNS name in the  Endpoint                  box (see the following screenshot) because you will need it during the installation                 of  Acumatica ERP. For details, see  To Create a Database Instance on Amazon RDS. 3. Deploy  Acumatica ERP on Amazon EC2 You install  Acumatica ERP Tools and deploy application instances on Amazon EC2. In the following                 screenshot, you can see the  Acumatica ERP Installation wizard on an Amazon EC2 virtual machine. For details, see  To Deploy Acumatica ERP on Amazon EC2. 4. Change the Password for the Default User Every  Acumatica ERP instance comes with an active default user account that you use to sign in to the                 system. After installation, you start working with  Acumatica ERP by changing the password for the default user. (See the following screenshot.)                 You use the following initial credentials for the default user: User name:  admin Password:  setup For details, see  To Change the Password at the First Sign-In. 5. Activate a License for the  Acumatica ERP Instance On the   ([~/?ScreenId=SM201510|SM201510]) Activate License (SM201510) form, you activate                 your  Acumatica ERP instance by entering a product key, as shown in the following screenshot. For details, see  To Activate the License for an Acumatica ERP Instance. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="6a201344-24db-4b24-b52b-1e744af65500" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="9bc360b4-3a7a-8dbe-771c-4fb191b7ed75" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
You can use the Acumatica ERP web interface to remotely update Acumatica ERP (if it is installed in the private cloud or in the public cloud on Amazon EC2) to a newer version or build, as described in this guide.{br}{TOC}[anchor|#_e6d8ced4-f723-46a0-b6a6-23aeb66ae400]
==Before You Proceed==
We strongly recommend that before you update Acumatica ERP to a newer product version, you do the following:[anchor|#_8d75e6ba-fa54-4dd3-9dce-af4ecf5fb1e7]
*Back up all configuration files and databases used by the application instances.
*If you have created any custom views with the {{SCHEMABINDING}} clause in the Acumatica ERP database, remove them. (You can create these views anew after update.)
*If you have been replicating the Acumatica ERP database, turn off the replication. (Otherwise, the system cannot be updated.)
*If you developed a client application by using the screen-based SOAP API, follow the procedure described in [HelpRoot_Install\Updating__how_Update_API_Using_Wrapper|To Update a Client Application that Uses Screen-Based Web Services] to prevent a failure of your application that can happen because of the UI changes in the system.
*On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\SM_20_50_30|Automation Schedule Statuses] ([~/?ScreenId=SM205030|SM205030]) form, make sure that no processes are scheduled for the update time. If you find any scheduled processes reschedule them so that they start after the update.
*On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\SM_20_35_20|Tenants] ([~/?ScreenId=SM203520|SM203520]) form, click '''Optimize Database''' to check your Acumatica ERP database for orphaned snapshots and delete them if the system finds any orphaned snapshots.
[anchor|#_8b1d99a8-28ad-4222-9716-adea3b3ca93f]
==1. Lock Out the System==
If users might attempt to log in to the system during the time of update, you need to schedule automatic lockout of the system on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\SM_20_35_10|Apply Updates] ([~/?ScreenId=SM203510|SM203510]) form (see the following screenshot). You can specify the lockout time right before the update or several days or hours in advance (according to business processes accepted in your organization).[anchor|#_c2df2428-14dc-4836-949f-4a91c875a7e6][anchor|#_4127af0d-2554-4b12-b420-677557f1f905][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Web_System_Update_Step1_1.png|popup|300px]{br}

When the system is locked out, a message alerting users to the system lockout is displayed on the Welcome screen (as shown in the following screenshot).[anchor|#_61e3e920-a9b9-4736-8711-a7271d58b419][anchor|#_e14c5396-a0ee-4bf4-a8b4-c3432d436c01][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Web_System_Update_Step1_3.png|popup|300px]{br}

For details, see [HelpRoot_Install\Updating__how_Enable_Lockout|To Schedule the System Lockout].[anchor|#_6b5d7623-47cc-46e4-96f8-b4472064bf42]
==2. Validate Customization of Your Acumatica ERP Instance==
If you have published customization projects in your Acumatica ERP instance, validate the compatibility of the currently published customization code with the code of the selected product version (see the following screenshot).[anchor|#_c96395fe-eab8-4bf2-b7a7-9dbfe4195fd4][anchor|#_2dad7c13-60b3-4ec6-893b-1bbaf5730bc7][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Web_System_Update_Step2.png|popup|450px]{br}

For details, see [HelpRoot_Dev_Customization\CG_GL_Upgrading_ValidatingBefore|To Validate the Compatibility of the Published Customization with a New Version Before an Upgrade].[anchor|#_20d4d536-b0ab-4eb3-b6ea-f746567bf70e]
==3. Update Your Acumatica ERP Instance==
On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\SM_20_35_10|Apply Updates] ([~/?ScreenId=SM203510|SM203510]) form, you update your Acumatica ERP instance (as shown in the following screenshot).[anchor|#_cd948235-7aee-4d9b-9b0a-11d5ef81bb51][anchor|#_5bc484c4-4d60-4d32-8652-e8b1b2f6e057][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Web_System_Update_Step3.png|popup|450px]{br}

For details, see [HelpRoot_Install\Upgrading_Using_Web_Interface|To Update Acumatica ERP by Using the Web Interface].[anchor|#_bbb5a380-e1db-41d0-962a-4787aa8a80ee]
==4. Build the Search Indexes==
If you have updated your system from a version that did not include search indexes, on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\SM_20_95_00|Rebuild Full-Text Entity Index] ([~/?ScreenId=SM209500|SM209500]) form, you build the search indexes to accelerate search in Acumatica ERP (see the following screenshot).[anchor|#_40aa62d7-d04d-4dfb-a987-64d3e53b51c7][anchor|#_bbaed987-60bb-4a8a-98cd-41ed27fa6550][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Web_System_Update_Step4.png|popup|450px]{br}

For details, see [HelpRoot_Administration\SM__how_Search_indexes_update|To Build Search Indexes][anchor|#_c00630a2-d82c-47b2-9f2e-f9d35af1152a]
==5. Unlock the System==
If you have locked out the system, on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\SM_20_35_10|Apply Updates] ([~/?ScreenId=SM203510|SM203510]) form, you unlock the system (as shown in the following screenshot).[anchor|#_5f9513b0-e4d4-4f08-b2a4-a01dd95b3532][anchor|#_deefbd99-b219-4304-a536-e27a37593d66][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Web_System_Update_Step5.png|popup|300px]{br}

For details, see [HelpRoot_Install\Updating__how_Disable_Lockout|To Unlock an Acumatica ERP Instance].
==Related Articles==
*[HelpRoot_Install\Upgrading_Acumatica|Updating Acumatica ERP]
*[HelpRoot_Install\Updates__con_Web_Interface|Updating Acumatica ERP by Using the Web Interface]]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Updating  Acumatica ERP by Using the Web Interface You can use the  Acumatica ERP web interface to remotely update  Acumatica ERP (if it is installed in the private cloud or in the public cloud on Amazon EC2) to                 a newer version or build, as described in this guide. Before You Proceed We strongly recommend that before you update  Acumatica ERP              to a newer product version, you do the following: Back up all configuration files and databases used by the application instances. If you have created any custom views with the  SCHEMABINDING                      clause in the  Acumatica ERP database, remove them. (You can create these views anew after update.) If you have been replicating the  Acumatica ERP database, turn off the replication. (Otherwise, the system cannot be                     updated.) If you developed a client application by using the screen-based SOAP API, follow the procedure                     described in  To Update a Client Application that Uses Screen-Based Web Services to                     prevent a failure of your application that can happen because of the UI changes                     in the system. On the   ([~/?ScreenId=SM205030|SM205030]) Automation Schedule Statuses (SM205030) form, make                     sure that no processes are scheduled for the update time. If you find any                     scheduled processes reschedule them so that they start after the update. On the   ([~/?ScreenId=SM203520|SM203520]) Tenants (SM203520) form, click                          Optimize Database  to check your  Acumatica ERP database for orphaned snapshots and delete them if the system finds any                     orphaned snapshots. 1. Lock Out the System If users might attempt to log in to the system during the time of update, you need to                 schedule automatic lockout of the system on the   ([~/?ScreenId=SM203510|SM203510]) Apply Updates (SM203510) form (see the                 following screenshot). You can specify the lockout time right before the update or                 several days or hours in advance (according to business processes accepted in your                     organization). When the system is locked out, a message alerting users to the system lockout is                 displayed on the Welcome screen (as shown in the following screenshot). For details, see  To Schedule the System Lockout. 2. Validate Customization of Your  Acumatica ERP Instance If you have published customization projects in your  Acumatica ERP instance, validate the compatibility of the currently published customization                 code with the code of the selected product version (see the following                     screenshot). For details, see  To Validate the Compatibility of the Published Customization with a New Version Before an Upgrade. 3. Update Your  Acumatica ERP Instance On the   ([~/?ScreenId=SM203510|SM203510]) Apply Updates (SM203510) form,                 you update your  Acumatica ERP instance (as shown in the following screenshot). For details, see  To Update Acumatica ERP by Using the Web Interface. 4. Build the Search Indexes If you have updated your system from a version that did not include search indexes,                 on the   ([~/?ScreenId=SM209500|SM209500]) Rebuild Full-Text Entity Index (SM209500) form, you build                 the search indexes to accelerate search in  Acumatica ERP (see the following screenshot). For details, see  To Build Search Indexes5. Unlock the System If you have locked out the system, on the   ([~/?ScreenId=SM203510|SM203510]) Apply Updates (SM203510) form, you unlock the system (as shown in the                 following screenshot). For details, see  To Unlock an Acumatica ERP Instance. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="227f527e-52ae-4d58-9214-a3ceacd86886" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="10894347-ab45-3204-b32e-1cd132ac2827" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
You can update your Acumatica ERP instance locally on the server where the previous version of the system is installed, as described in this guide.{br}

You perform the update procedure on the server where the previous version of the Acumatica ERP Tools has been installed.((({S:Hint}To run the installation package, you must be signed in to a user account with the ''Administrator'' role on your local computer.
))){br}{TOC}[anchor|#_ebaaa73d-7912-4c17-8826-d7842b29feb5]
==Before You Proceed==
We strongly recommend that before you update Acumatica ERP to a newer product version, you do the following:[anchor|#_692fa28a-83cf-4601-9674-77c62ccf7d06]
*Back up all configuration files and databases used by the application instances.
*If you have created any custom views with the {{SCHEMABINDING}} clause in the Acumatica ERP database, remove them. (You can create these views anew after update.)
*If you have been replicating the Acumatica ERP database, turn off the replication. (Otherwise, the system cannot be updated.)
*If you developed a client application by using the screen-based SOAP API, follow the procedure described in [HelpRoot_Install\Updating__how_Update_API_Using_Wrapper|To Update a Client Application that Uses Screen-Based Web Services] to prevent a failure of your application that can happen because of the UI changes in the system.
*On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\SM_20_50_30|Automation Schedule Statuses] ([~/?ScreenId=SM205030|SM205030]) form, make sure that no processes are scheduled for the update time. If you find any scheduled processes reschedule them so that they start after the update.
*On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\SM_20_35_20|Tenants] ([~/?ScreenId=SM203520|SM203520]) form, click '''Optimize Database''' to check your Acumatica ERP database for orphaned snapshots and delete them if the system finds any orphaned snapshots.
[anchor|#_9a69f9d1-54ee-44b7-8e46-d3a31bfc2333]
==1. Lock Out the System==
If users might attempt to log in to the system during the time of update, you need to schedule automatic lockout of the system on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\SM_20_35_10|Apply Updates] ([~/?ScreenId=SM203510|SM203510]) form (see the following screenshot). You can specify the lockout time right before the update or several days or hours in advance (according to business processes accepted in your organization).[anchor|#_c2df2428-14dc-4836-949f-4a91c875a7e6][anchor|#_4127af0d-2554-4b12-b420-677557f1f905][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Web_System_Update_Step1_1.png|popup|300px]{br}

When the system is locked out, a message alerting users to the system lockout is displayed on the Welcome screen (as shown in the following screenshot).[anchor|#_61e3e920-a9b9-4736-8711-a7271d58b419][anchor|#_e14c5396-a0ee-4bf4-a8b4-c3432d436c01][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Web_System_Update_Step1_3.png|popup|300px]{br}

For details, see [HelpRoot_Install\Updating__how_Enable_Lockout|To Schedule the System Lockout].[anchor|#_79b476ed-feec-4ae9-914a-f0afb2983b44]
==2. Update the Acumatica ERP Tools==
Update the Acumatica ERP Tools by using the installation package file (see the screenshot below).[anchor|#_2fafc528-9060-4f08-ac8e-06b55c559bcc][anchor|#_5203f553-b17a-47ac-96a1-6b529fcf355b][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Local_System_Update_Step2.png|popup|300px]{br}

For details, see [HelpRoot_Install\Upgrading_Configuration_Wizard|To Update the Acumatica ERP Tools].[anchor|#_1ef974f8-96f3-4da3-8036-c5789dfad70d]
==3. Update the Database and the Site of Your Acumatica ERP Instance==
In the Acumatica ERP Configuration Wizard, you start updating the database and the site of your application instance (as shown in the following screenshot).[anchor|#_27ef911f-72ac-4aac-aa4b-a4a59451e789][anchor|#_863cac60-c5d9-45b8-97ff-d45838f402d2][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Local_System_Update_Step3.png|popup|300px]{br}

For details on updating the site and the database, see [HelpRoot_Install\Upgrading_Both_Database_and_Site|To Update the Database and Site of an Acumatica ERP Instance].[anchor|#_7e5f6318-2aaf-41be-a9be-3d27c6b55428]
==4. Build the Search Indexes==
If you have updated your system from a version that did not include search indexes, on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\SM_20_95_00|Rebuild Full-Text Entity Index] ([~/?ScreenId=SM209500|SM209500]) form, you build these search indexes to accelerate search in Acumatica ERP (see the following screenshot).[anchor|#_76b3125c-4414-4cc7-81c5-48cf13430b3c][anchor|#_93270a76-b1fb-45ec-ad95-c0e76e6438c9][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Web_System_Update_Step4.png|popup|300px]{br}

For details, see [HelpRoot_Administration\SM__how_Search_indexes_update|To Build Search Indexes][anchor|#_eab13e04-9584-45c3-8a6d-c08830211311]
==5. Unlock the System==
If you have locked out the system, on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\SM_20_35_10|Apply Updates] ([~/?ScreenId=SM203510|SM203510]) form, you unlock the system (as shown in the following screenshot).[anchor|#_2411241f-042b-4856-9945-35bf4fed606b][anchor|#_6c2bfd7d-9c8b-4c5c-8d9b-a960b00633eb][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Web_System_Update_Step5.png|popup|300px]{br}

For details, see [HelpRoot_Install\Updating__how_Disable_Lockout|To Unlock an Acumatica ERP Instance].
==Related Articles==
*[HelpRoot_Install\Upgrading_Acumatica|Updating Acumatica ERP]
*[HelpRoot_Install\Upgrading_Locally|Updating Acumatica ERP by Using the Configuration Wizard]]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Updating  Acumatica ERP by Using the Configuration Wizard You can update your  Acumatica ERP instance locally on the server where the previous version of the system is                 installed, as described in this guide. You perform the update procedure on the server where the previous version of the  Acumatica ERP Tools has been installed. To run the installation package, you must be signed in to a user account with the                      Administrator  role on your local computer. Before You Proceed We strongly recommend that before you update  Acumatica ERP              to a newer product version, you do the following: Back up all configuration files and databases used by the application instances. If you have created any custom views with the  SCHEMABINDING                      clause in the  Acumatica ERP database, remove them. (You can create these views anew after update.) If you have been replicating the  Acumatica ERP database, turn off the replication. (Otherwise, the system cannot be                     updated.) If you developed a client application by using the screen-based SOAP API, follow the procedure                     described in  To Update a Client Application that Uses Screen-Based Web Services to                     prevent a failure of your application that can happen because of the UI changes                     in the system. On the   ([~/?ScreenId=SM205030|SM205030]) Automation Schedule Statuses (SM205030) form, make                     sure that no processes are scheduled for the update time. If you find any                     scheduled processes reschedule them so that they start after the update. On the   ([~/?ScreenId=SM203520|SM203520]) Tenants (SM203520) form, click                          Optimize Database  to check your  Acumatica ERP database for orphaned snapshots and delete them if the system finds any                     orphaned snapshots. 1. Lock Out the System If users might attempt to log in to the system during the time of update, you need to                 schedule automatic lockout of the system on the   ([~/?ScreenId=SM203510|SM203510]) Apply Updates (SM203510) form (see the                 following screenshot). You can specify the lockout time right before the update or                 several days or hours in advance (according to business processes accepted in your                     organization). When the system is locked out, a message alerting users to the system lockout is                 displayed on the Welcome screen (as shown in the following screenshot). For details, see  To Schedule the System Lockout. 2. Update the  Acumatica ERP Tools Update the  Acumatica ERP Tools by using the installation package file (see the screenshot below). For details, see  To Update the Acumatica ERP Tools. 3. Update the Database and the Site of Your  Acumatica ERP Instance In the  Acumatica ERP Configuration Wizard, you start updating the database and the site of your                 application instance (as shown in the following screenshot). For details on updating the site and the database, see  To Update the Database and Site of an Acumatica ERP Instance. 4. Build the Search Indexes If you have updated your system from a version that did not include search indexes,                 on the   ([~/?ScreenId=SM209500|SM209500]) Rebuild Full-Text Entity Index (SM209500) form, you build                 these search indexes to accelerate search in  Acumatica ERP (see the following screenshot). For details, see  To Build Search Indexes5. Unlock the System If you have locked out the system, on the   ([~/?ScreenId=SM203510|SM203510]) Apply Updates (SM203510) form, you unlock the system (as shown in the                 following screenshot). For details, see  To Unlock an Acumatica ERP Instance. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="117034df-eab8-4f8e-8d66-eea8b5808352" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="463754a7-0430-81c8-16ae-4bcea596f3b3" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
You can update your Acumatica ERP Service on Windows Azure with a new installation package on the Windows Azure portal, as described in this guide.{br}{TOC}[anchor|#_94b158ac-2a00-45eb-9186-a5aa801aeedc]
==1. Download the Service Package File==
On the [http://partner.acumatica.com/|Partner Portal], you download the service package file (<tt>.cspkg</tt>) of the Acumatica ERP version to which you want to update your Acumatica ERP Service (see the following screenshot).[anchor|#_cd28d3fa-88ea-40cc-8b1c-28c009b72f52][anchor|#_e3da5fb4-99e1-4d13-a639-ab748119306a][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Azure_System_Update_Step1.png|popup|450px]{br}

For details, see [HelpRoot_Install\Deploying_on_Azure__Config_Package|To Download the Configuration Package].[anchor|#_6ab334a2-31a4-443d-898e-71b3a1ac385a]
==2. Download the Configuration File of Your Acumatica ERP Service==
You download the configuration file (<tt>.cscfg</tt>) of your Acumatica ERP Service from the Windows Azure portal (see the following screenshot).[anchor|#_d002cbc5-51aa-4466-aef2-f9d82b2e40dc][anchor|#_5751fa83-b373-4217-bae2-626901321665][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Azure_System_Update_Step2.png|popup|450px]{br}

For details, see [HelpRoot_Install\Upgrading_on_Azure_how_Download_Config_File|To Download the Acumatica ERP Service Configuration File].[anchor|#_5b8ef28c-8baf-4990-b681-2f5e0584ff19]
==3. Lock Out the System==
If users might attempt to log in to the system during the time of update, you need to schedule automatic lockout of the system on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\SM_20_35_10|Apply Updates] ([~/?ScreenId=SM203510|SM203510]) form (see the following screenshot). You can specify the lockout time right before the update or several days or hours in advance (according to business processes accepted in your organization).[anchor|#_133e2a0f-b89a-40a4-957e-d1de7b0d209b][anchor|#_434ce2d8-c3a5-40d6-88c7-20b17cc34998][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Web_System_Update_Step1_1.png|popup|300px]{br}

When the system is locked out, a message alerting users to the system lockout is displayed on the Welcome screen (as shown in the following screenshot).[anchor|#_61e3e920-a9b9-4736-8711-a7271d58b419][anchor|#_e14c5396-a0ee-4bf4-a8b4-c3432d436c01][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Web_System_Update_Step1_3.png|popup|300px]{br}

For details, see [HelpRoot_Install\Updating__how_Enable_Lockout|To Schedule the System Lockout].[anchor|#_d32a41b2-59f6-4730-bcf9-0eb9e0f5dca3]
==4. Update Your Acumatica ERP Service on Windows Azure==
On the Windows Azure portal, you update your Acumatica ERP Service (see the following screenshot).[anchor|#_6826b424-0732-4007-8aa3-9d1ea299af49][anchor|#_d0e69a3a-2586-4e4d-b9da-a4258650ad9f][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Azure_System_Update_Step4.png|popup|450px]{br}

For details, see [HelpRoot_Install\Upgrading_on_Azure_how_Update_Service|To Update Your Acumatica ERP Service on Windows Azure].[anchor|#_4dd827eb-ad16-4914-8b45-e99f100ada2a]
==5. Build the Search Indexes==
If you have updated your system from a version that did not include search indexes, on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\SM_20_95_00|Rebuild Full-Text Entity Index] ([~/?ScreenId=SM209500|SM209500]) form in Acumatica ERP, you build these search indexes to accelerate search (see the following screenshot).[anchor|#_14d64a33-66fe-4609-bf76-8b2c4d4dbeb5][anchor|#_05d01ad5-05b1-400d-8c3a-7c19ce35d5a4][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Web_System_Update_Step4.png|popup|450px]{br}

For details, see [HelpRoot_Administration\SM__how_Search_indexes_update|To Build Search Indexes].[anchor|#_17124caa-c8a8-41a6-a4df-6669da5c08cb]
==6. Unlock the System==
If you have locked out the system, on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\SM_20_35_10|Apply Updates] ([~/?ScreenId=SM203510|SM203510]) form, you unlock the system (as shown in the following screenshot).[anchor|#_994201d9-1735-4dfd-88e3-f27554db53e9][anchor|#_7be1c167-c339-4af3-a071-645f01be5298][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Web_System_Update_Step5.png|popup|300px]{br}

For details, see [HelpRoot_Install\Updating__how_Disable_Lockout|To Unlock an Acumatica ERP Instance].
==Related Articles==
*[HelpRoot_Install\Upgrading_Acumatica|Updating Acumatica ERP]
*[HelpRoot_Install\Upgrading_on_Azure|Updating Your Acumatica ERP Service on Windows Azure]]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Updating Your  Acumatica ERP Service on Windows Azure You can update your  Acumatica ERP Service on Windows Azure with a new installation package on the Windows Azure portal, as                 described in this guide. 1. Download the Service Package File On the  Partner Portal Partner Portal, you download the service package file                     ( .cspkg ) of the  Acumatica ERP version to which you want to update your  Acumatica ERP Service (see the following screenshot). For details, see  To Download the Configuration Package. 2. Download the Configuration File of Your  Acumatica ERP ServiceYou download the configuration file ( .cscfg ) of your  Acumatica ERP Service from the Windows Azure portal (see the following screenshot). For details, see  To Download the Acumatica ERP Service Configuration File. 3. Lock Out the System If users might attempt to log in to the system during the time of update, you need to                 schedule automatic lockout of the system on the   ([~/?ScreenId=SM203510|SM203510]) Apply Updates (SM203510) form (see the                 following screenshot). You can specify the lockout time right before the update or                 several days or hours in advance (according to business processes accepted in your                     organization). When the system is locked out, a message alerting users to the system lockout is                 displayed on the Welcome screen (as shown in the following screenshot). For details, see  To Schedule the System Lockout. 4. Update Your  Acumatica ERP Service on Windows Azure On the Windows Azure portal, you update your  Acumatica ERP Service (see the following screenshot). For details, see  To Update Your Acumatica ERP Service on Windows Azure. 5. Build the Search Indexes If you have updated your system from a version that did not include search indexes,                 on the   ([~/?ScreenId=SM209500|SM209500]) Rebuild Full-Text Entity Index (SM209500) form in  Acumatica ERP, you build these search indexes to accelerate search (see the following                     screenshot). For details, see  To Build Search Indexes. 6. Unlock the System If you have locked out the system, on the   ([~/?ScreenId=SM203510|SM203510]) Apply Updates (SM203510) form, you unlock the system (as shown in the                 following screenshot). For details, see  To Unlock an Acumatica ERP Instance. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="7d266a46-5ac0-43ff-9d34-34b4374fdf29" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="d880bb7f-392b-5a45-117e-13186d373a66" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
To access Acumatica ERP, users must pass authentication to confirm their identity. Then users pass authorization to determine their access rights to system resources, such as suites, modules, and forms. Users can access only the resources they are allowed to use and perform only the actions they are authorized to based on their access rights. In this guide, you will read how to initially configure security for user accounts stored in Acumatica ERP.
==Before You Proceed==
You first apply all customizations to your Acumatica ERP instance if the customizations contain newly created forms. You will need to configure access rights to these forms along with standard forms.
==Steps==
[[#_3bfd6836-917b-4ca0-8310-60eb8b2a7edf|1. Create User Roles]{br}

[[#_656bf942-2147-4b26-965d-5c4edd41e4ce|2. Set Up Access Rights for User Roles]{br}

[[#_78ae03bb-f26d-4923-a1f4-45b2e7be9400|3. Create User Accounts and Assign User Roles][anchor|#_3bfd6836-917b-4ca0-8310-60eb8b2a7edf]
==1. Create User Roles==
You create user roles on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\SM_20_10_05|User Roles] ([~/?ScreenId=SM201005|SM201005]) form, shown in the following screenshot, based on the responsibilities of your organization's employees who will work with Acumatica ERP.[anchor|#_19b62e5a-ab84-4907-b43b-4dcafeb09ec8][anchor|#_f708be22-ede4-4e6a-bb5f-6b66cbbdfd79][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Configuring_User_Security_Step1.png|popup|400px]
For details, see [HelpRoot_Administration\SM__con_Role-Based_Access|Role-Based Access].[anchor|#_656bf942-2147-4b26-965d-5c4edd41e4ce]
==2. Set Up Access Rights for User Roles==
On the [HelpRoot_ReportReference\SM_65_15_00|Access Rights by Role] ([~/?ScreenId=SM651500|SM651500]) form, shown in the following screenshot, you set up access rights for user roles to Acumatica ERP resources, depending on the tasks performed by users with these user roles.[anchor|#_660a3b93-4765-46f0-9742-627b3b74facb][anchor|#_a9c9a75b-1a6f-463a-b9d8-3bfc8637579f][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Configuring_User_Security_Step2.png|popup|400px]
For details, see [HelpRoot_Administration\US__how_Access_Rights_by_Role_Configuration|To Configure Access Rights for a Selected User Role].[anchor|#_78ae03bb-f26d-4923-a1f4-45b2e7be9400]
==3. Create User Accounts and Assign User Roles==
On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\SM_20_10_10|Users] ([~/?ScreenId=SM201010|SM201010]) form, which the following screenshot shows, you create accounts for all users of your Acumatica ERP instance and assign roles, which you have created in Step 1, to these users.[anchor|#_80d89634-8751-4d2f-ad03-fe2750e1fea7][anchor|#_ce7e1944-31be-4b34-b9a2-ef1c4fbdd6c6][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Configuring_User_Security_Step3.png|popup|450px]
For details, see [HelpRoot_Administration\US__how_Create_User_Account|To Create a Local User Account].
==Related Articles==
*[HelpRoot_Administration\US__con_User_Accounts|User Accounts in Acumatica ERP]
*[HelpRoot_Administration\US__con_Access_Rights|User Access Rights]
*[HelpRoot_Administration\SM__con_Role-Based_Access|Role-Based Access]
*[HelpRoot_Administration\SM__con_Roles_and_Access_Rights|Levels of Access Rights]]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Configuring User Security To access  Acumatica ERP, users must pass authentication to confirm their identity. Then users pass                 authorization to determine their access rights to system resources, such as suites,                 modules, and forms. Users can access only the resources they are allowed to use and                 perform only the actions they are authorized to based on their access rights. In                 this guide, you will read how to initially configure security for user accounts                 stored in  Acumatica ERP. Before You Proceed You first apply all customizations to your  Acumatica ERP instance if the customizations contain newly created forms. You will need to                 configure access rights to these forms along with standard forms. Steps 1. Create User Roles 1. Create User Roles2. Set Up Access Rights for User Roles 2. Set Up Access Rights for User Roles3. Create User Accounts and Assign User Roles 3. Create User Accounts and Assign User Roles1. Create User Roles You create user roles on the   ([~/?ScreenId=SM201005|SM201005]) User Roles                 (SM201005) form, shown in the following screenshot,  based on the                 responsibilities of your organization's employees who will work with  Acumatica ERP. For details, see  Role-Based Access. 2. Set Up Access Rights for User Roles On the   ([~/?ScreenId=SM651500|SM651500]) Access Rights by Role (SM651500) form, shown in the                 following screenshot, you set up access rights for user roles to  Acumatica ERP resources, depending on the tasks performed by users with these user roles. For details, see  To Configure Access Rights for a Selected User Role. 3. Create User Accounts and Assign User Roles On the   ([~/?ScreenId=SM201010|SM201010]) Users (SM201010) form, which the                 following screenshot shows, you create accounts for all users of your  Acumatica ERP instance and assign roles, which you have created in Step 1, to these users. For details, see  To Create a Local User Account. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="f812f476-f83c-4a5d-8034-d44ac2f24c98" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="66de1c22-beca-ca2e-71bb-f5a25ca42bd0" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
You configure the sending of push notifications to mobile devices about changes to an entity by using the monitoring business events functionality of Acumatica ERP.{br}

This guide explains how to configure the sending of push notifications to an employee who has been specified as the owner of an opportunity, whether the opportunity is new or its owner has been changed.{br}{TOC}
==Before You Proceed==
Make sure that the ability of the system to send push notifications is turned on for the mobile devices of the users who are supposed to receive the notifications. For details, see ''Management of User Accounts'' in [HelpRoot_Administration\US__con_User_Accounts|User Accounts in Acumatica ERP].
==1. Determine the Generic Inquiry to Be Used for Monitoring==
You use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\SM_20_80_00|Generic Inquiry] ([~/?ScreenId=SM208000|SM208000]) form to create and modify inquiries. You can create a new generic inquiry based on the {{PX.Objects.CR.CROpportunity}} table or use an existing one that retrieves the following data fields for the {{CROpportunity}} object:[anchor|#_c3ad233b-b904-43c2-9da9-22bfee7a9c28]
*{{OpportunityID}}
*{{OwnerID}}
*{{NoteID}}
*{{Subject}}
*{{Amount}}
*{{Status}}

You fill in the settings in the Summary area of the form ('''Inquiry Title''', '''Site Map Title''', and '''Site Map Location''') at your discretion.{br}

For details on configuring a generic inquiry, see [HelpRoot_ReportingTools\RP__how_tools_GI_DesigningGI|To Design a Generic Inquiry].
==2. Configure a Business Event==
To monitor changes to the user identifier for the opportunity owner, you create a business event on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\SM_30_20_50|Business Events] ([~/?ScreenId=SM302050|SM302050]) form, as described in [HelpRoot_Administration\AI__how_Business_Event_by_Record_Change|To Monitor Changes of the Business Process Data], using the generic inquiry that you have configured in the first step. The trigger conditions for the business event are a new record (the ''Record Inserted'' operation) or changed {{OwnerID}} field in the {{CROpportunity}} table (the ''Field Changed'' operation); see the screenshot below.[anchor|#_8d42e433-b321-48ab-8df7-151c0537f655][anchor|#_f2a3f8e3-f814-4bf3-933d-9fc71e5b8f3d][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG_Admin_BusinessEvent.png|popup|Business event to monitor changes in opportunity owner|450px]
==3. Configure a Push Notification==
The easiest way to create a push notification that is sent to mobile devices for a business event is to do so while you are creating the event on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\SM_30_20_50|Business Events] ([~/?ScreenId=SM302050|SM302050]) form: On the table toolbar of the '''Subscribers''' tab, you click '''Create Subscriber''' > '''Mobile Notification'''. This causes the system to open the [HelpRoot_FormReference\SM_20_40_04|Mobile Notifications] form with the correct value (the identifier of the generic inquiry you have configured in the first step) selected in the '''Screen''' box.{br}

You fill in the settings of the mobile notification template by using the data fields from the inquiry; see the screenshot below.[anchor|#_2ba00a48-5cd9-45cb-9ced-f9fd83f318f1][anchor|#_02993383-1b84-4b98-8d66-d6dd95ee9c1c][image:QuickGuides/Images/QG__Admin_PushNotification.png|popup|A mobile notification template to notify a user about change of an opportunity owner|450px]
==4. Test the Monitoring of the Change of an Opportunity Owner==
Once the push notification is configured and the business event is activated, each employee that is specified as an owner of an opportunity will receive the push notification about this event. To test the monitoring you have set up, you create a new opportunity and make sure that the assigned user receives the configured push notification; similarly change the owner of an existing opportunity and make sure the user receives the notification.{br}

The system saves information each time it processes the business event, which you can view on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\SM_50_20_30|Business Event History] ([~/?ScreenId=SM502030|SM502030]) form; you can also open this form by clicking the '''View History''' button on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\SM_30_20_50|Business Events] ([~/?ScreenId=SM302050|SM302050]) form. If something went wrong, you can find all the information you for troubleshooting in the processing history.
==Related Articles==
*[HelpRoot_Administration\AI__con_Event_Monitoring|Monitoring and Managing Events]
*[HelpRoot_ReportingTools\RP__how_tools_GI_DesigningGI|To Design a Generic Inquiry]
*[HelpRoot_Administration\AI__how_Business_Event_by_Record_Change|To Monitor Changes of the Business Process Data]
*[HelpRoot_Administration\US__con_User_Accounts|User Accounts in Acumatica ERP]]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Sending Push Notifications About Opportunities Assigned You configure the sending of push notifications to mobile devices about changes to an entity     by using the monitoring business events functionality of  Acumatica ERP. This guide explains how to configure the sending of push notifications to an employee who has     been specified as the owner of an opportunity, whether the opportunity is new or its owner has     been changed. Before You Proceed Make sure that the ability of the system to send push notifications is turned on for the     mobile devices of the users who are supposed to receive the notifications. For details, see       Management of User Accounts  in  User Accounts in Acumatica ERP. 1. Determine the Generic Inquiry to Be Used for Monitoring You use the   ([~/?ScreenId=SM208000|SM208000]) Generic Inquiry (SM208000) form to create and modify     inquiries. You can create a new generic inquiry based on the       PX.Objects.CR.CROpportunity  table or use an existing one that retrieves the     following data fields for the  CROpportunity  object: OpportunityID OwnerID NoteID Subject Amount Status You fill in the settings in the Summary area of the form ( Inquiry     Title ,  Site Map Title , and  Site Map      Location ) at your discretion. For details on configuring a generic inquiry, see  To Design a Generic Inquiry. 2. Configure a Business Event To monitor changes to the user identifier for the opportunity owner, you create a business     event on the   ([~/?ScreenId=SM302050|SM302050]) Business Events (SM302050) form, as described in  To Monitor Changes of the Business Process Data, using the generic inquiry     that you have configured in the first step. The trigger conditions for the business event are a     new record (the  Record Inserted  operation) or changed   OwnerID  field in     the  CROpportunity  table (the  Field Changed  operation); see the     screenshot below. Business event to monitor changes in opportunity owner 3. Configure a Push Notification The easiest way to create a push notification that is sent to mobile devices for a business     event is to do so while you are creating the event on the   ([~/?ScreenId=SM302050|SM302050]) Business Events (SM302050) form: On the table toolbar of the       Subscribers  tab, you click  Create Subscriber Mobile Notification . This causes the system to open the   ([~/?ScreenId=SM204004|SM204004]) Mobile Notifications     form with the correct value (the identifier of the generic inquiry you have configured in the     first step) selected in the  Screen  box. You fill in the settings of the mobile notification template by using the data fields from the     inquiry; see the screenshot below. A mobile notification template to notify a user about change of an opportunity      owner 4. Test the Monitoring of the Change of an Opportunity Owner Once the push notification is configured and the business event is activated, each employee     that is specified as an owner of an opportunity will receive the push notification about this     event. To test the monitoring you have set up, you create a new opportunity and make sure that     the assigned user receives the configured push notification; similarly change the owner of an     existing opportunity and make sure the user receives the notification. The system saves information each time it processes the business event, which you can view on     the   ([~/?ScreenId=SM502030|SM502030]) Business Event History (SM502030) form; you can also open this form by     clicking the  View History  button on the   ([~/?ScreenId=SM302050|SM302050]) Business Events (SM302050) form. If something went wrong, you can find     all the information you for troubleshooting in the processing history. ]]></column>
		</row>
	</rows>
</data>