<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<data>
	<table name="WikiRevision">
		<col name="CompanyID" type="Int" default="Zero" />
		<col name="PageID" type="UniqueIdentifier" />
		<col name="Language" type="VarChar(50)" />
		<col name="PageRevisionID" type="Int" />
		<col name="Content" type="NVarChar(MAX)" />
		<col name="ContentHtml" type="NVarChar(MAX)" nullable="true" />
		<col name="PlainText" type="NVarChar(MAX)" />
		<col name="ApprovalByID" type="UniqueIdentifier" nullable="true" />
		<col name="ApprovalDateTime" type="DateTime" nullable="true" />
		<col name="CreatedByID" type="UniqueIdentifier" />
		<col name="CreatedDateTime" type="DateTime" />
		<col name="CompanyMask" type="VarBinary(32)" default="CompanyMaskReadOnly" />
		<col name="UID" type="UniqueIdentifier" />
		<col name="RecordSourceID" type="SmallInt" nullable="true" />
	</table>
	<rows>
		<row PageID="4f2c25f8-6c71-4399-abbf-cba6feacc2ed" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="2264903b-406d-9ffe-338e-d6db42201154" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
 Acumatica ERP Construction                         Edition includes the following functionality:[anchor|#_57afeebc-6e23-4ea8-be78-dd3d244cf2c1]
*Project accounting by cost codes. The cost codes functionality is available if the ''Cost Codes'' feature is enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) form.
*Project change management. The change orders functionality is available if the ''Change Orders'' feature is enabled on the on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] form.
*Stored material tracking in project pro forma invoices. The functionality is available if the ''Construction'' feature is enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] form.
*Retainage support. The following functionality is available if the ''Retainage Support'' feature is enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] form:
**Ability to account for retainage in commitments (purchase orders and subcontracts) and in Accounts Payable documents
**Ability to account for retainage in project invoices, which include the draft invoices (pro forma) and Accounts Receivable invoices
*Construction package. The following functionality is available if the ''Construction feature'' is enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] form:
**[[#_b407f85c-05d7-4fb4-af77-0f557f42c4ba|Subcontract management]
**[[#_80e4cbb0-cd29-400a-af88-61ba345aac59|Compliance tracking]
**[[#_0eec01d4-da58-4594-bf01-38e3618e0b1f|Construction-specific reports]

For more information on particular features, see the respective chapter of this document. {br}{TOC}[anchor|#_371526d2-967e-4cea-ac5d-6172b428d32f]
==Project Task Types==
A project task can be of the following types that can be set either on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PM_30_20_00|Project Tasks] ([~/?ScreenId=PM302000|PM302000]) form or on the '''Tasks''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PM_30_10_00|Projects] ([~/?ScreenId=PM301000|PM301000]) form:[anchor|#_764c769d-72dc-45bc-a020-cd150c183482]
*'''Cost Task''' - tasks of this type are visible on the '''Cost Budget''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PM_30_10_00|Projects] form only.
*'''Revenue Task''' - tasks of this type are visible on the '''Revenue Budget''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PM_30_10_00|Projects] form only.
*'''Cost and Revenue Task''' - tasks of this type are visible both on the '''Revenue Budget''' and '''Cost Budget''' tabs of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PM_30_10_00|Projects] form.
[anchor|#_b407f85c-05d7-4fb4-af77-0f557f42c4ba]
==Subcontract Management==
Subcontract is a document that represents a commitment with a vendor to provide goods and services for a project. Subcontract workflow is similar to the workflow of a purchase order that contains service lines and non-stock lines only. AP bills are entered directly for a subcontract once the work has been completed and the AP document has been received from the vendor.{br}

Subcontracts are entered on the [HelpRoot_Construction\SC_30_10_00|Subcontracts] ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000]) form. Subcontract lines can be linked to projects by a complex key of project, project task, inventory ID, cost code in the same way as the lines of purchase orders on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PO_30_10_00|Purchase Orders] ([~/?ScreenId=PO301000|PO301000]) form.{br}

Subcontract entity is based on purchase order of ''Normal'' type and inherits its common functionality:[anchor|#_0bcae16e-35c4-4c65-b64b-a97dc9c35f78]
*Ability to enter prepayments for subcontracts.
*Ability to enter partial AP bills for subcontracts.
*Ability to complete or cancel subcontracts fully or line by line.
*Support for document workflow options:
**Ability to approve or reject subcontracts using the standard assignment and approval maps rules.
**Ability to email subcontracts.
**Ability to print subcontracts.
*Support for other options consistent with purchase order functionality:
**Tracking as project commitments.
**Change order functionality for project commitments.
**Compliance tracking.
**Tax calculation.
**Vendor prices.

Subcontracts have the following specifics:[anchor|#_61a8e8af-c4ca-4b67-8625-7b820cef842b]
*Subcontracts do not utilize stock items and do not involve inventory management processes.
*Vendor-specific printed formats can be defined for subcontracts and purchase orders separately by the respective mailing IDs:
**Purchase Order: printed format of a purchase order entered on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PO_30_10_00|Purchase Orders] form.
**Subcontract: printed format of a subcontract entered on the [HelpRoot_Construction\SC_30_10_00|Subcontracts] form.
*Subcontracts do not utilize the purchase to order process and cannot be linked to sales orders.
*Subcontracts do not utilize the blanket order workflow, which is available for purchase orders.

Dedicated forms are provided for working with subcontracts:[anchor|#_3ff78970-a3c6-4fed-9dde-83c7f057cfb8]
*[HelpRoot_Construction\SC_30_10_00|Subcontracts] data entry form
*[HelpRoot_Construction\SC_50_30_00|Print/Email Subcontracts] ([~/?ScreenId=SC503000|SC503000]) mass-processing form

For more information on subcontract agreement forms and reports, see construction-specific reports.[anchor|#_80e4cbb0-cd29-400a-af88-61ba345aac59]
==Compliance Tracking==
Firms managing construction projects have requirements to protect their clients, vendors, suppliers, and partners from the many potential issues associated with compliance. These compliance issues might be associated with federal, state and local governmental requirements, but may also be legal and procedural. Compliance tracking allows a firm to establish the compliance items that should be captured for different types of entities, so that this information can be used for in-place warnings to users and for reports on project exposure.{br}

The below types of compliance items are provided by default and can be extended with more types to track and report on:[anchor|#_3ccd0f3c-92df-48e4-bdbf-cdd292aff0f8]
*''Certificate''
* ''Insurance''
* ''Lien Waiver''
* ''Notice''
* ''Other''

The user can configure common attributes that are available for all types of compliance, as well as define custom attributes for each compliance type in particular on the [HelpRoot_Construction\CL_30_10_00|'''Compliance Preferences'''] ([~/?ScreenId=CL301000|CL301000]) form. Once a compliance type is configured, the compliance items of that type can be recorded and viewed on the [HelpRoot_Construction\CL_40_10_00|Compliance Management] ([~/?ScreenId=CL401000|CL401000]) form.{br}

Each compliance item can be associated with multiple entities such as project, project task, cost code, vendor, customer, and with various types of documents. On the '''Compliance''' tab of each of the forms listed below, the users can enter and review the compliance items associated with entity:[anchor|#_e25cb398-2187-4946-ad42-2cc1884d62b2]
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_30_00|Vendors] ([~/?ScreenId=AP303000|AP303000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_10_00|Bills and Adjustments] ([~/?ScreenId=AP301000|AP301000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_20_00|Checks and Payments] ([~/?ScreenId=AP302000|AP302000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\AR_30_30_00|Customers] ([~/?ScreenId=AR303000|AR303000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\AR_30_10_00|Invoices and Memos] ([~/?ScreenId=AR301000|AR301000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\PM_30_10_00|Projects] ([~/?ScreenId=PM301000|PM301000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\PM_30_20_00|Project Tasks] ([~/?ScreenId=PM302000|PM302000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\PM_30_40_00|Project Transactions] ([~/?ScreenId=PM304000|PM304000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\PO_30_10_00|Purchase Orders] ([~/?ScreenId=PO301000|PO301000])
*[HelpRoot_Construction\SC_30_10_00|Subcontracts] ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\PM_30_80_00|Change Orders] ([~/?ScreenId=PM308000|PM308000])

Based on the entered information, the system warns users of any records with compliance issues where applicable. For example, if a compliance item is overdue the system throws a warning message.[anchor|#_0eec01d4-da58-4594-bf01-38e3618e0b1f]
==Construction-Specific Reports==
The following inquiries, dashboards, and reports are now available:[anchor|#_978d161b-5f3f-4caa-9238-7c320bb6010e]
*'''Commitments by Vendor Summary (CU000002)''' inquiry lists vendors with open commitments (Purchase Orders/Subcontracts) within the specified date range. Commitments are totaled together to provide an order quantity, open quantity, overall total, and the open balance across all commitments. Additionally, the list can be filtered for a single project, a single vendor, and/or inventory item. Use the hyperlink within the '''Vendor ID''' and '''Vendor Name''' columns to view the line item details by open commitment.
*'''Vendor Commitments Details (CU000001)''' inquiry lists open commitment line item details for the selected vendor, project, or inventory item (for example, labor, materials, subcontracts, and the like). Use the hyperlinks within the '''Account ID''', '''Project''', '''PO/Subcontract No''', '''Inventory ID''', or '''Cost Code''' columns, to obtain detailed information associated with the chosen column. For example, the hyperlink in the '''PO/Subcontract No.''' column will navigate to the Purchase Order or Subcontract form providing the user will access to available actions such as, printing or editing.
*'''Project Summary (CU000003)''' inquiry provides a high-level status of the contract, costs, and gross profit. Use the hyperlinks within the '''Project''', '''Description''', and '''Open Committed Costs''' columns to obtain detailed information associated with the chosen column. For example, clicking the link in the '''Open Committed Costs''' column will navigate to the Commitments inquiry providing a detailed list of commitments for the associated project.
*'''Project Dashboard (CU000013)''' dashboard. The Project Dashboard is customizable. The default configuration gives an overview of the costs by a project, contract status by a project, and gross profit by a project in a grid format. The columns of data shown in each grid can be displayed as separate widgets using a variety of chart types such as, doughnut.
*'''Project WIP (CU000004)''' report provides a way to track the progress and financial performance of project contracts while using that data to forecast future performance. Drilldown goes to Project WIP Detail report.
*'''Project WIP Detail (CU000005)''' report provides a way to track the progress and financial performance of project contracts while using that data to forecast future performance at a task and cost code level.
*'''Subcontract Short Form (CU000006)''' report is a snapshot of the contract details broken down by a task, cost code, and inventory item.
*:((({S:Warn}The report should be customized to reflect the needs of the company.
)))
*'''Subcontract Agreement Long Form (CU000011)''' report is a sample of a full contract outlining the details of the agreement.
*:((({S:Warn}The report should be customized to reflect the needs of the company.
)))
*'''Conditional Waiver on Progress Payment (CU000008)''' report provides a sample release of partial lien rights when the current payment has not been received and future payments are expected.
*'''Conditional Waiver on Final Payment (CU000007)''' report provides a sample release of the remaining lien rights when the current payment has not been received and no future payments are expected.
*'''Unconditional Waiver on Progress Payment (CU000010)''' report provides a sample release of partial lien rights when the current payment has been received and future payments are expected.
*'''Unconditional Waiver on Final Payment (CU000009)''' report provides a sample release of the remaining lien rights when the current payment has been received and no future payments are expected.
*'''Compliance by Vendor (CU000014)''' report lists compliance items matching the report parameters in three categories: Non-Project/Commitment Items, Project/Non-Commitment related items, and Project/Commitment related items.
*'''Compliance by Project (CU000012)''' report lists compliance items matching the report parameters in two categories for each project: Subcontractor(Vendor)/Non-Commitment related items and Subcontractor(Vendor)/Commitment related items.
*'''Project Profit Analysis (CU000015)''' report is a snapshot of the original profit compared to the revised profit.
*'''Project Performance (CU000016)''' report is a snapshot of the project performance to-date with both profit and markup values.
*'''Project Cost Budget Status (CU000017)''' report provides detail into the cost budget of a project showing budgeted, committed, and actual amounts resulting in the remaining budget values per project task and overall totals for the project. Drilldown in the project column navigates to the Projects form and drilldown into the task and description columns navigates to the Project Task form.
*'''Subcontract Audit (CU000018)''' report gives a snapshot of each subcontract showing the subcontract amount, changes, invoices, and outstanding balance.
*'''Subcontract (SC641000)''' report displays the subcontracts created in the Subcontracts module; you can print and email them.
*'''Subcontract Summary (SC610500)''' report shows summary information about subcontracts that are neither closed nor canceled.
*'''Subcontract Details by Vendor (SC611000)''' report displays detailed information about subcontracts that are neither closed nor canceled. The data in this report is grouped by vendor.
]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Overview of Construction Processes  Acumatica ERP Construction                         Edition         includes the following functionality: Project accounting by cost codes. The cost codes functionality is available if the              Cost Codes  feature is enabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features (CS100000)           form. Project change management. The change orders functionality is available if the  Change             Orders  feature is enabled on the on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features form. Stored material tracking in project pro forma invoices. The functionality is available           if the  Construction  feature is enabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features           form. Retainage support. The following functionality is available if the  Retainage             Support  feature is enabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features form: Ability to account for retainage in commitments (purchase orders and subcontracts)               and in Accounts Payable documents Ability to account for retainage in project invoices, which include the draft               invoices (pro forma) and Accounts Receivable invoices Construction package. The following functionality is available if the  Construction             feature  is enabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features form: Subcontract management Subcontract managementCompliance tracking Compliance trackingConstruction-specific reports Construction-specific reportsFor more information on particular features, see the respective chapter of this document.        Project Task Types A project task can be of the following types that can be set either on the   ([~/?ScreenId=PM302000|PM302000]) Project Tasks (PM302000) form or on the  Tasks  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=PM301000|PM301000]) Projects (PM301000) form: Cost Task  - tasks of this type are visible on the  Cost Budget  tab of the               ([~/?ScreenId=PM301000|PM301000]) Projects form only. Revenue Task  - tasks of this type are visible on the  Revenue Budget  tab of           the   ([~/?ScreenId=PM301000|PM301000]) Projects form only. Cost and Revenue Task  - tasks of this type are visible both on the  Revenue             Budget  and  Cost Budget  tabs of the   ([~/?ScreenId=PM301000|PM301000]) Projects form. Subcontract Management Subcontract is a document that represents a commitment with a vendor to provide goods and         services for a project. Subcontract workflow is similar to the workflow of a purchase order         that contains service lines and non-stock lines only. AP bills are entered directly for a         subcontract once the work has been completed and the AP document has been received from the         vendor. Subcontracts are entered on the   ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000]) Subcontracts (SC301000) form.         Subcontract lines can be linked to projects by a complex key of project, project task,         inventory ID, cost code in the same way as the lines of purchase orders on the   ([~/?ScreenId=PO301000|PO301000]) Purchase Orders (PO301000) form. Subcontract entity is based on purchase order of  Normal  type and inherits its common         functionality: Ability to enter prepayments for subcontracts. Ability to enter partial AP bills for subcontracts. Ability to complete or cancel subcontracts fully or line by line. Support for document workflow options: Ability to approve or reject subcontracts using the standard assignment and approval               maps rules. Ability to email subcontracts. Ability to print subcontracts. Support for other options consistent with purchase order functionality: Tracking as project commitments. Change order functionality for project commitments. Compliance tracking. Tax calculation. Vendor prices. Subcontracts have the following specifics: Subcontracts do not utilize stock items and do not involve inventory management           processes. Vendor-specific printed formats can be defined for subcontracts and purchase orders           separately by the respective mailing IDs: Purchase Order: printed format of a purchase order entered on the   ([~/?ScreenId=PO301000|PO301000]) Purchase Orders form. Subcontract: printed format of a subcontract entered on the   ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000]) Subcontracts form. Subcontracts do not utilize the purchase to order process and cannot be linked to sales           orders. Subcontracts do not utilize the blanket order workflow, which is available for purchase           orders. Dedicated forms are provided for working with subcontracts:  ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000]) Subcontracts data entry form  ([~/?ScreenId=SC503000|SC503000]) Print/Email Subcontracts (SC503000) mass-processing form For more information on subcontract agreement forms and reports, see construction-specific         reports. Compliance Tracking Firms managing construction projects have requirements to protect their clients, vendors,         suppliers, and partners from the many potential issues associated with compliance. These         compliance issues might be associated with federal, state and local governmental         requirements, but may also be legal and procedural. Compliance tracking allows a firm to         establish the compliance items that should be captured for different types of entities, so         that this information can be used for in-place warnings to users and for reports on project         exposure. The below types of compliance items are provided by default and can be extended with more         types to track and report on: Certificate Insurance Lien Waiver Notice Other The user can configure common attributes that are available for all types of compliance, as         well as define custom attributes for each compliance type in particular on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CL301000|CL301000]) '''Compliance Preferences''' (CL301000) form. Once a compliance type is configured, the         compliance items of that type can be recorded and viewed on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CL401000|CL401000]) Compliance Management (CL401000) form. Each compliance item can be associated with multiple entities such as project, project task, cost code, vendor, customer, and with various types of         documents. On the  Compliance  tab of each of the forms listed below, the users can         enter and review the compliance items associated with entity:  ([~/?ScreenId=AP303000|AP303000]) Vendors (AP303000)  ([~/?ScreenId=AP301000|AP301000]) Bills and Adjustments (AP301000)  ([~/?ScreenId=AP302000|AP302000]) Checks and Payments (AP302000)  ([~/?ScreenId=AR303000|AR303000]) Customers (AR303000)  ([~/?ScreenId=AR301000|AR301000]) Invoices and Memos (AR301000)  ([~/?ScreenId=PM301000|PM301000]) Projects (PM301000)  ([~/?ScreenId=PM302000|PM302000]) Project Tasks (PM302000)  ([~/?ScreenId=PM304000|PM304000]) Project Transactions (PM304000)  ([~/?ScreenId=PO301000|PO301000]) Purchase Orders (PO301000)  ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000]) Subcontracts (SC301000)  ([~/?ScreenId=PM308000|PM308000]) Change Orders (PM308000) Based on the entered information, the system warns users of any records with compliance         issues where applicable. For example, if a compliance item is overdue the system throws a         warning message. Construction-Specific Reports The following inquiries, dashboards, and reports are now available: Commitments by Vendor Summary (CU000002)  inquiry lists vendors with open           commitments (Purchase Orders/Subcontracts) within the specified date range. Commitments           are totaled together to provide an order quantity, open quantity, overall total, and the           open balance across all commitments. Additionally, the list can be filtered for a single           project, a single vendor, and/or  inventory item. Use the hyperlink within the  Vendor             ID  and  Vendor Name  columns to view the line item details by open           commitment. Vendor Commitments Details (CU000001)  inquiry lists open commitment line item           details for the selected vendor, project, or inventory item (for example, labor,           materials, subcontracts, and the like). Use the hyperlinks within the  Account ID ,              Project ,  PO/Subcontract No ,  Inventory ID , or  Cost Code            columns, to obtain detailed information associated with the chosen column. For example,           the hyperlink in the  PO/Subcontract No.  column will navigate to the Purchase Order           or Subcontract form providing the user will access to available actions such as, printing           or editing. Project Summary (CU000003)  inquiry provides a high-level status of the contract,           costs, and gross profit. Use the hyperlinks within the  Project ,  Description ,           and  Open Committed Costs  columns to obtain detailed information associated with the           chosen column. For example, clicking the link in the  Open Committed Costs  column           will navigate to the Commitments inquiry providing a detailed list of commitments for the           associated project. Project Dashboard (CU000013)  dashboard. The Project Dashboard is customizable.           The default configuration gives an overview of the costs by a project, contract status by           a project, and gross profit by a project in a grid format. The columns of data shown in           each grid can be displayed as separate widgets using a variety of chart types such as,           doughnut. Project WIP (CU000004)  report provides a way to track the progress and financial           performance of project contracts while using that data to forecast future performance.           Drilldown goes to Project WIP Detail report. Project WIP Detail (CU000005)  report provides a way to track the progress and           financial performance of project contracts while using that data to forecast future           performance at a task and cost code level. Subcontract Short Form (CU000006)  report is a snapshot of the contract details           broken down by a task, cost code, and inventory item. The report should be             customized to reflect the needs of the company. Subcontract Agreement Long Form (CU000011)  report is a sample of a full contract           outlining the details of the agreement. The report should be customized to reflect             the needs of the company. Conditional Waiver on Progress Payment (CU000008)  report provides a sample           release of partial lien rights when the current payment has not been received and future           payments are expected. Conditional Waiver on Final Payment (CU000007)  report provides a sample release           of the remaining lien rights when the current payment has not been received and no future           payments are expected. Unconditional Waiver on Progress Payment (CU000010)  report provides a sample           release of partial lien rights when the current payment has been received and future           payments are expected. Unconditional Waiver on Final Payment (CU000009)  report provides a sample release           of the remaining lien rights when the current payment has been received and no future           payments are expected. Compliance by Vendor (CU000014)  report lists compliance items matching the report           parameters in three categories: Non-Project/Commitment Items, Project/Non-Commitment           related items, and Project/Commitment related items. Compliance by Project (CU000012)  report lists compliance items matching the           report parameters in two categories for each project: Subcontractor(Vendor)/Non-Commitment           related items and Subcontractor(Vendor)/Commitment related items. Project Profit Analysis (CU000015)  report is a snapshot of the original profit           compared to the revised profit. Project Performance (CU000016)  report is a snapshot of the project performance           to-date with both profit and markup values. Project Cost Budget Status (CU000017)  report provides detail into the cost budget           of a project showing budgeted, committed, and actual amounts resulting in the remaining           budget values per project task and overall totals for the project. Drilldown in           the project column navigates to the Projects form and drilldown into the task and           description columns navigates to the Project Task form. Subcontract Audit (CU000018)  report gives a snapshot of each subcontract showing           the subcontract amount, changes, invoices, and outstanding balance. Subcontract (SC641000)  report displays the subcontracts created in the           Subcontracts module; you can print and email them. Subcontract Summary (SC610500)  report shows summary information about           subcontracts that are neither closed nor canceled. Subcontract Details by Vendor (SC611000)  report displays detailed information           about subcontracts that are neither closed nor canceled. The data in this report is           grouped by vendor. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="e1c9cda8-5b30-4e82-8a35-f98818a4f9c9" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" Content="&#xA;In this chapter, you will find activities that will help you learn about processing of subcontracts in the system." PlainText="Working with a Subcontract In this chapter, you will find activities that will help you learn about processing of     subcontracts in the system. " ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="e75bb19c-9fec-b3ac-33bc-b42065333d3f" RecordSourceID="22377" />
		<row PageID="a372a823-ac82-497d-94e0-b3bd53379ecd" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="09183167-0b7a-56c8-563f-d651250dbe74" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
The following activity will walk you through the process of configuring subcontract mailing. That is, you will learn how to create a notification template and specify mailing settings for a vendor class of subcontractors.
==Story==
Suppose that the SweetLife company hired the Standard Hardware Company subcontractor to perform some part of a job on building a hotel. The company is going to send a contract to the subcontractor by email. Acting as an administrator, you need to create a notification template for the subcontractor and configure a vendor class of the subcontractor to have this template in the mailing settings.
==Process Overview==
To configure subcontract mailing, you first create a template on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\SM_20_40_03|Notification Templates] ([~/?ScreenId=SM204003|SM204003]) form. You then add this template to the mailing list of the subcontract vendor class on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_20_10_00|Vendor Classes] ([~/?ScreenId=AP201000|AP201000]) form. On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_30_00|Vendors] ([~/?ScreenId=AP303000|AP303000]) form, you can check the mailing settings of a particular vendor.
==System Preparation==
Launch the Acumatica ERP website, and sign in as a sales manager by using the ''admin'' login and the ''123'' password.
==Step 1: Creating a Notification Template==
Do the following:[anchor|#_fa742785-635f-4638-890f-918dff014a89]
#Open the [HelpRoot_FormReference\SM_20_40_03|Notification Templates] (SM2040PL) form.[anchor|#_9b88544c-85ef-48fc-b2c6-8574aa939aca]
#On the form toolbar, click '''Add New Record'''.
#In the '''Screen Name''' box, select ''Subcontracts'' with the ''SC.30.10.00'' screen ID.
#In the '''Description''' box, type ''Subcontracts''.
#In the '''From''' box, select the ''System'' email account.
#:This is the default account from which emails with subcontracts will be sent to vendors.
#In the '''Subject''' box, type <tt>Subcontract email</tt>.
#In the text editor area of the '''Message''' tab, specify the following text:
#:<tt>Dear Vendor,</tt>
#:<tt>Please find your subcontract attached.</tt>
#:<tt>Sincerely yours,</tt>
#:<tt>SweetLife</tt>[anchor|#_4c9a5abb-c9e0-4cb5-8594-f19717895866]
#On the form toolbar, click '''Save'''.

==Step 2: Adding Notification Template to a Subcontractor Class==
To add a notification template, do the following:[anchor|#_157bbfb8-a804-4c3c-b8df-06b8f140a5bc]
#Open the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_20_10_00|Vendor Classes] ([~/?ScreenId=AP201000|AP201000]) form.
#In the '''Class ID''' box, select ''SUBCON''.
#On the '''Mailing Settings''' tab, do the following:
##In the '''Mailings''' table, make sure that the ''SUBCONTRACT'' mailing is listed and has the '''Active''' check box selected.
##For the ''SUBCONTRACT'' mailing, in the '''Email Account''' column, select the ''System'' email account.
##Make sure that ''SC.64.10.00'' is specified in the '''Report''' column. 
##:This is the identifier of the Subcontract printed form that will be used for generating a short form of a subcontract to be attached to an email.
##In the '''Notification Template''' column, select the ''Subcontracts'' notification template.
##In the '''Recipients''' table, click '''Add Row''', and in the '''Contact Type''' column, select the ''Remittance''. Leave the default values for the remaining settings.[anchor|#_b9322260-c8bf-4e08-922e-c6a7d2adf246]
#On the form toolbar, click '''Save'''.

==Step 3: Reviewing Subcontractor Mailing Settings==
Do the following:[anchor|#_9f1c4112-4096-4dc5-a3ef-87486ef4fc3d]
#Open the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_30_00|Vendors] ([~/?ScreenId=AP303000|AP303000]) form.
#In the '''Vendor''' box, select the ''HARDCO'' vendor.
#On the '''Mailing Settings''' tab, make sure that the settings of the ''SUBCONTRACT'' mailing have been copied from the ''SUBCON ''vendor class. 
]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Work with a Subcontract: Implementation Activity The following activity will walk you through the process of configuring subcontract                 mailing. That is, you will learn how to create a notification template and specify                 mailing settings for a vendor class of subcontractors. Story Suppose that the SweetLife company hired the Standard Hardware Company subcontractor                 to perform some part of a job on building a hotel. The company is going to send a                 contract to the subcontractor by email. Acting as an administrator, you need to                 create a notification template for the subcontractor and configure a vendor class of                 the subcontractor to have this template in the mailing settings. Process Overview To configure subcontract mailing, you first create a template on the   ([~/?ScreenId=SM204003|SM204003]) Notification Templates (SM204000) form.                 You then add this template to the mailing list of the subcontract vendor class on                 the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP201000|AP201000]) Vendor Classes (AP201000)                 form. On the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP303000|AP303000]) Vendors                 (AP303000) form, you can check the mailing settings of a particular vendor. System Preparation Launch the  Acumatica ERP website, and sign in as a sales manager by using the  admin  login and the                      123  password. Step 1: Creating a Notification Template Do the following: Open the   ([~/?ScreenId=SM204003|SM204003]) Notification Templates                     (SM2040PL) form. On the form toolbar, click  Add New Record . In the  Screen Name  box, select  Subcontracts  with                     the  SC.30.10.00  screen ID. In the  Description  box, type  Subcontracts . In the  From  box, select the  System  email                         account. This is the default account from which emails with subcontracts                         will be sent to vendors. In the  Subject  box, type  Subcontract                         email . In the text editor area of the  Message  tab, specify the                     following text: Dear Vendor, Please                             find your subcontract attached. Sincerely                             yours, SweetLife On the form toolbar, click  Save . Step 2: Adding Notification Template to a Subcontractor Class To add a notification template, do the following: Open the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP201000|AP201000]) Vendor Classes                     (AP201000) form. In the  Class ID  box, select  SUBCON . On the  Mailing Settings  tab, do the following: In the  Mailings  table, make sure that the                                  SUBCONTRACT  mailing is listed and has the                                  Active  check box selected. For the  SUBCONTRACT  mailing, in the  Email Account  column,                             select the  System  email account. Make sure that  SC.64.10.00  is specified in the  Report                              column.  This is the identifier of the Subcontract printed form that                                 will be used for generating a short form of a subcontract to be                                 attached to an email. In the  Notification Template  column, select the                                  Subcontracts  notification template. In the  Recipients  table, click  Add Row ,                             and in the  Contact Type  column, select the                                  Remittance . Leave the default values for the remaining                             settings. On the form toolbar, click  Save . Step 3: Reviewing Subcontractor Mailing Settings Do the following: Open the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP303000|AP303000]) Vendors                     (AP303000) form. In the  Vendor  box, select the  HARDCO  vendor. On the  Mailing Settings  tab, make sure that the settings                     of the  SUBCONTRACT  mailing have been copied from the  SUBCON  vendor                     class.  ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="113f0d01-a5db-4b03-93e3-68a08e6acf0a" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="dc23d4ae-3ed0-7722-8fb7-6010350dcdcc" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
The following activity will walk you through the process of working with a subcontract.
==Story==
Suppose that the SweetLife company hires a subcontractor, Standard Hardware Company, to install windows and doors in the hotel that is built by SweetLife. Initially, it is agreed that the Standard Hardware Company performs the following jobs:[anchor|#_4dd89ec0-8c41-4eb6-9d3b-f6fa65b1317e]
*Installation of windows
*Installation of doors and frames
*Building an entrance 

A project manager of the SweetLife company creates a subcontract, prints the subcontract, and sends an email with the subcontract. After some consideration, SweetLife agrees with the subcontractor that the subcontractor will install only windows, and another subcontractor will install doors later. So SweetLife pays to the subcontractor only for installing windows.{br}

Acting as the project manager, you need to create a subcontract in the system, print and email it. Then you need to create and release a bill for installing windows and create and release a check for the bill. Finally, you complete the subcontract.Subcontracts
==Process Overview==
When you work with a subcontract, the first step that you perform is creating a subcontract on the [HelpRoot_Construction\SC_30_10_00|Subcontracts] ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000]) form. After you created the subcontract, you print it (if necessary) and send by email to the subcontractor (if necessary). When the subcontractor finished the job or a part of the job of the subcontract and sent your company an invoice, you create a bill to pay for this job on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_10_00|Bills and Adjustments] ([~/?ScreenId=AP301000|AP301000]) form. After you paid, you create a check for the bill on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_20_00|Checks and Payments] ([~/?ScreenId=AP302000|AP302000]) form. When all jobs are paid, you complete the subcontract on the [HelpRoot_Construction\SC_30_10_00|Subcontracts] form.
==System Preparation==
Before you start working with subcontracts, do the following:[anchor|#_0a1c4cdd-aaa3-4894-bd34-fc3e4802c978]
#Launch the Acumatica ERP website, and sign in as a sales manager by using the ''brawner'' login and the ''123'' password.
#Make sure that the mailing settings for subcontractors have been configured, as described in [HelpRoot_Construction\Construction_Work_with_Subcontracts_Implem_Activity|Work with a Subcontract: Implementation Activity].

==Step 1: Creating a Subcontract==
To create a subcontract, do the following:[anchor|#_fa742785-635f-4638-890f-918dff014a89]
#Open the [HelpRoot_Construction\SC_30_10_00|Subcontracts] ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000]) form.[anchor|#_cd1bcfa2-4848-4bc5-8415-d1a62686c90f]
#On the form toolbar, click '''Add New Record'''.
#In the '''Vendor''' box, select ''HARDCO - Standard Hardware Company''. 
#In the '''Description''' box, type <tt>Installing of windows and doors</tt>.
#On the '''Document Details''' tab, add lines with the settings specified in the table below.
#:{| class="checklist" | width="100%" 
|- 
!width="16%" ! Inventory ID
!width="16%" ! Project
!width="16%" ! Cost Task
!width="16%" ! Cost Code
!width="16%" ! Line Description
!width="16%" ! Ext. Cost
|- 
| ''SUBCON''
|  ''HOTEL''
|  ''08''
|  ''08-510''
| <tt>Windows</tt>
| <tt>650,000.00</tt>
|- 
| ''SUBCON''
|  ''HOTEL''
|  ''08''
|  ''08-200''
| <tt>Doors and frames</tt>
| <tt>442,000.00</tt>
|- 
| ''SUBCON''
|  ''HOTEL''
|  ''08''
|  ''08-800''
| <tt>Entrance</tt>
| <tt>2,000,000.00</tt>
|}
#In the Summary area, in the '''Subcontract Total''' box, make sure that the total is ''3,092,000.00''.
#On the '''Other Information''' tab, clear the''' Don&rsquo;t Print''' and '''Don&rsquo;t Email''' check boxes.
#:If these check boxes are selected, the subcontract will get the ''Open'' status when it is taken off hold. If these check boxes are cleared, the subcontract will get the ''Pending Printing'' status first.
#Clear the '''Hold''' check box.
#:The system changes the subcontract status to ''Pending Printing''.[anchor|#_0120d33f-f991-4f88-8db0-b5388c62c18d]
#On the form toolbar, click '''Save'''.

==Step 2: Printing the Subcontract and Sending an Email with It==
Do the following:[anchor|#_157bbfb8-a804-4c3c-b8df-06b8f140a5bc]
#While you are still on the [HelpRoot_Construction\SC_30_10_00|Subcontracts] ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000]) form, click '''Reports''' > '''Print Subcontract''' on the form toolbar.
#:The system opens the [HelpRoot_Construction\SC_64_10_00|Subcontract] ([~/?ScreenId=SC641000|SC641000]) report.
#:((({S:Warn}For the learning purposes of this activity, you do not need to actually print the subcontract. In Click '''Print''' on the form toolbar to print the short form of the subcontract.
)))
#Return back to the subcontract on the [HelpRoot_Construction\SC_30_10_00|Subcontracts] form.
#On the form toolbar, click '''Actions''' > '''Email Subcontract'''.
#:The system creates an email activity associated with the subcontract. As a result, the '''Activities''' counter on the title bar of the form increases by one. Click that counter.
#Click '''Activities (1)''' on the title bar.
#In the '''Tasks and Activities''' dialog box, which opens, click the ''Subcontract email'' link to review the generated email.
#On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CR_30_60_15|Email Activity] ([~/?ScreenId=CR306015|CR306015]) form, which opens, review the '''From''' and '''To''' email addresses, the message of the email, and the summary information of the subcontract. 
#Click '''Files''' on the title bar.
#In the '''Files''' dialog box, which opens, in the '''File Name''' column, click the link to the attached PDF file. Review the short form of the subcontract that has been attached to the email generated for the vendor. 
#:The short form of the subcontract has been generated because the Subcontracts (SC641000) printed form is specified in the mailing settings for the vendor.
#Return back to the subcontract on the [HelpRoot_Construction\SC_30_10_00|Subcontracts] form.
#:Notice that the system changed the subcontract status to ''Open''.

==Step 3: Paying for Performed Work and Completing the Subcontract==
To pay for the work, do the following:[anchor|#_9f1c4112-4096-4dc5-a3ef-87486ef4fc3d]
#While you are still on the [HelpRoot_Construction\SC_30_10_00|Subcontracts] ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000]) form, click '''Actions''' > '''Enter AP Bill''' on the form toolbar.
#:The [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_10_00|Bills and Adjustments] ([~/?ScreenId=AP301000|AP301000]) form opens.
#On the '''Document Details''' tab, click the line for the ''Doors and frames'' and click '''Delete Row''' on the table toolbar. 
#Similarly delete the line for ''Entrance''.
#Clear the '''Hold''' check box, and then click '''Release''' on the form toolbar.
#Click '''Actions''' > '''Pay Bill/Apply Adjustment'''. 
#Do the following on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_20_00|Checks and Payments] ([~/?ScreenId=AP302000|AP302000]) form, which opens:
##In the Summary area, in the '''Payment Method''' box, select ''CASH''.
##:((({S:Warn}You do not have to select a different payment method if you do not need to. In this lesson, we do so only to skip the printing of the check or specifying the payment reference number before the document can be released. 
)))
##In the '''Cash Account''' box, select ''10100ST.''
##Clear the '''Hold''' check box.
##Click '''Release''' on the form toolbar.
##:As a result, the check and the bill get the ''Closed'' status and transactions are posted to the general ledger.
#Open the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PM_30_10_00|Projects] ([~/?ScreenId=PM301000|PM301000]) form, and in the '''Project ID''' box, select ''HOTEL''.
#On the '''Cost Budget''' tab, for the budget line with the ''08-510'' cost code, note that the costs have been updated with the paid amount.
#Open the [HelpRoot_Construction\SC_30_10_00|Subcontracts] form with the subcontract you have created, and click '''Actions''' > '''Complete Subcontract'''.
]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Work with a Subcontract: Process Activity The following activity will walk you through the process of working with a                 subcontract. Story Suppose that the SweetLife company hires a subcontractor, Standard Hardware Company,                 to install windows and doors in the hotel that is built by SweetLife. Initially, it                 is agreed that the Standard Hardware Company performs the following jobs: Installation of windows Installation of doors and frames Building an entrance  A project manager of the SweetLife company creates a subcontract, prints the                 subcontract, and sends an email with the subcontract. After some consideration,                 SweetLife agrees with the subcontractor that the subcontractor will install only                 windows, and another subcontractor will install doors later. So SweetLife pays to                 the subcontractor only for installing windows. Acting as the project manager, you need to create a subcontract in the system, print                 and email it. Then you need to create and release a bill for installing windows and                 create and release a check for the bill. Finally, you complete the                 subcontract.Subcontracts Process Overview When you work with a subcontract, the first step that you perform is creating a                 subcontract on the   ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000]) Subcontracts (SC301000) form.                 After you created the subcontract, you print it (if necessary) and send by email to                 the subcontractor (if necessary). When the subcontractor finished the job or a part                 of the job of the subcontract and sent your company an invoice, you create a bill to                 pay for this job on the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP301000|AP301000]) Bills and Adjustments (AP301000) form.                 After you paid, you create a check for the bill on the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP302000|AP302000]) Checks and Payments (AP302000) form.                 When all jobs are paid, you complete the subcontract on the   ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000]) Subcontracts form. System Preparation Before you start working with subcontracts, do the following: Launch the  Acumatica ERP website, and sign in as a sales manager by using the  brawner  login and                     the  123  password. Make sure that the mailing settings for subcontractors have been configured, as                     described in  Work with a Subcontract: Implementation Activity. Step 1: Creating a Subcontract To create a subcontract, do the following: Open the   ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000]) Subcontracts                     (SC301000) form. On the form toolbar, click  Add New Record . In the  Vendor  box, select  HARDCO - Standard Hardware                         Company .  In the  Description  box, type  Installing of                         windows and doors . On the  Document Details  tab, add lines with the settings                     specified in the table below. Inventory ID Project Cost Task Cost Code Line Description Ext. Cost SUBCON HOTEL 08 08-510 Windows 650,000.00 SUBCON HOTEL 08 08-200 Doors and frames 442,000.00 SUBCON HOTEL 08 08-800 Entrance 2,000,000.00 In the Summary area, in the  Subcontract Total  box, make                     sure that the total is  3,092,000.00 . On the  Other Information  tab, clear the  Don't Print  and  Don't                         Email  check boxes. If these check boxes are selected, the subcontract                         will get the  Open  status when it is taken off hold. If these check                         boxes are cleared, the subcontract will get the  Pending Printing                          status first. Clear the  Hold  check box. The system changes the subcontract status to                              Pending Printing . On the form toolbar, click  Save . Step 2: Printing the Subcontract and Sending an Email with It Do the following: While you are still on the   ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000]) Subcontracts (SC301000)                     form, click  Reports Print Subcontract  on the form toolbar. The system opens the   ([~/?ScreenId=SC641000|SC641000]) Subcontract                         (SC641000) report. For the learning purposes of this activity, you                         do not need to actually print the subcontract. In Click                              Print  on the form toolbar to print the short form                         of the subcontract. Return back to the subcontract on the   ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000]) Subcontracts form. On the form toolbar, click  Actions Email Subcontract . The system creates an email activity associated with the                         subcontract. As a result, the  Activities  counter on                         the title bar of the form increases by one. Click that counter. Click  Activities (1)  on the title bar. In the  Tasks and Activities  dialog box, which opens,                     click the  Subcontract email  link to review the generated email. On the   ([~/?ScreenId=CR306015|CR306015]) Email Activity                     (CR306015) form, which opens, review the  From  and                          To  email addresses, the message of the email, and the                     summary information of the subcontract.  Click  Files  on the title bar. In the  Files  dialog box, which opens, in the  File                         Name  column, click the link to the attached PDF file. Review the                     short form of the subcontract that has been attached to the email generated for                     the vendor.  The short form of the subcontract has been generated because the                         Subcontracts (SC641000) printed form is specified in the mailing settings                         for the vendor. Return back to the subcontract on the   ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000]) Subcontracts                         form. Notice that the system changed the subcontract status to                          Open . Step 3: Paying for Performed Work and Completing the Subcontract To pay for the work, do the following: While you are still on the   ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000]) Subcontracts (SC301000)                     form, click  Actions Enter AP Bill  on the form toolbar. The   ([~/?ScreenId=AP301000|AP301000]) Bills and Adjustments                         (AP301000) form opens. On the  Document Details  tab, click the line for the                          Doors and frames  and click  Delete Row  on the                     table toolbar.  Similarly delete the line for  Entrance . Clear the  Hold  check box, and then click                          Release  on the form toolbar. Click  Actions Pay Bill/Apply Adjustment .  Do the following on the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP302000|AP302000]) Checks and Payments (AP302000)                     form, which opens: In the Summary area, in the  Payment Method  box,                             select  CASH . You do not have to select a different payment                                 method if you do not need to. In this lesson, we do so only to skip                                 the printing of the check or specifying the payment reference number                                 before the document can be released.  In the  Cash Account  box, select                              10100ST. Clear the  Hold  check box. Click  Release  on the form toolbar. As a result,                                 the check and the bill get the  Closed  status and transactions                                 are posted to the general ledger. Open the   ([~/?ScreenId=PM301000|PM301000]) Projects                     (PM301000) form, and in the  Project ID  box, select                          HOTEL . On the  Cost Budget  tab, for the budget line with the  08-510  cost                     code, note that the costs have been updated with the paid amount. Open the   ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000]) Subcontracts                     form with the subcontract you have created, and click  Actions Complete Subcontract . ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="51f1ae82-0363-4e48-a0ed-9b1ab9ad6aca" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" Content="&#xA;In this chapter, you will find an activity that will help you learn about processing of compliance documents in the system." PlainText="Compliance Tracking In this chapter, you will find an activity that will help you learn about processing of     compliance documents in the system. " ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="049e0873-0566-f733-5ef9-e1173fca731f" RecordSourceID="22377" />
		<row PageID="a3163bc5-f0de-471a-9a2a-0e547ad13508" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="b6c40611-dca2-24a0-3af0-7a18f6c28c3e" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
If you work with a vendor that has no valid insurance policies, certificates, licenses, or other compliance documents, you expose your business to certain risks. In Acumatica ERP Construction Edition, you can track compliance items for different types of entities, such as vendors, projects, bills, checks, and subcontracts, so that this information can be used for in-place warnings to users.{br}

In this lesson, you will learn how to do the following:[anchor|#_51319559-9b31-4219-8298-e560f910d44f]
*Configure categories and statuses for compliance documents
*Enter compliance documents for a vendor
*Track expired compliance documents

==Story==
Suppose that the Standard Hardware Company vendor has provided the SweetLife company with their OSHA certificate and their General Liability insurance. You need to enter this information in the system.
==Process Overview==
You first specify compliance preference settings on the [HelpRoot_Construction\CL_30_10_00|'''Compliance Preferences'''] ([~/?ScreenId=CL301000|CL301000]) form. Then, you add compliance documents on the [HelpRoot_Construction\CL_40_10_00|Compliance Management] ([~/?ScreenId=CL401000|CL401000]) form. Finally, you review documents of a particular vendor on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_30_00|Vendors] ([~/?ScreenId=AP303000|AP303000]) form.
==System Preparation==
Sign in as a project manager by using the ''owen'' login and the ''123'' password.
==Step 1: Configuring Document Categories and Statuses==
To perform configuration, do the following:[anchor|#_fa742785-635f-4638-890f-918dff014a89]
#Open the [HelpRoot_Construction\CL_30_10_00|'''Compliance Preferences'''] ([~/?ScreenId=CL301000|CL301000]) form.
#On the '''Custom Attributes''' tab, in the '''Attribute''' box, select ''Insurance''.
#In the table, in the '''Value''' column, click '''Add Row''', and specify the following values:
#*General Liability Coverage
#*Worker&rsquo;s Compensation Insurance
#*Commercial Automotive Insurance
#*Surety Bonds
#*Asset Protection
#On the '''Custom Attributes''' tab, in the '''Attribute''' box, select ''Certificate''.
#In the table, in the '''Value''' column, click '''Add Row''', and specify the following values:
#*Safety Certification
#*Hazardous Materials Certification
#*Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OHSA)
#*Project Management Institute (PMI)
#*Leadership in Energy & Environmental Design (LEED)
#On the '''Custom Attributes''' tab, in the '''Attribute''' box, select ''Status''.
#In the table, in the '''Value''' column, click '''Add Row''', and specify the following values:
#*''Valid''
#* ''Expired''
#Save the changes.

==Step 2: Creating Compliance Documents==
To add documents, do the following:[anchor|#_157bbfb8-a804-4c3c-b8df-06b8f140a5bc]
#Open the [HelpRoot_Construction\CL_40_10_00|Compliance Management] ([~/?ScreenId=CL401000|CL401000]) form.
#On the '''All Records''' tab, add a row to the table with the following settings specified:
#*'''Document Type''': ''Certificate''
#* '''Creation Date''': Current date
#*'''Document Category''': ''Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OHSA)''
#* '''Status''': ''Valid''
#* '''Required''': Selected
#*'''Received from Vendor''': Selected
#*'''Effective Date''': Start of the current year
#*'''Expiration Date''': End of the current month
#*'''Vendor''': ''HARDCO''
#* '''Certificate Number''': 123456
#Save the changes.
#Add another row with the following settings specified:
#*'''Document Type''': ''Insurance''
#* '''Creation Date''': Current date
#*'''Document Category''': ''General Liability Coverage''
#* '''Status''': ''Valid''
#* '''Required''': Selected
#*'''Received from Vendor''': Selected
#*'''Effective Date''': Start of the current year
#*'''Expiration Date''': End of the current month
#*'''Limit''': 10,000,000
#*'''Vendor''': ''HARDCO''
#* '''Insurance Company''': Insurance of NY
#*'''Policy''': 654321
#Save the changes.

==Tracking the Compliance Documents==
Do the following:[anchor|#_75ca1123-b2eb-46b4-8b37-514b0c68c9c6]
#Open the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_30_00|Vendors] ([~/?ScreenId=AP303000|AP303000]) form.
#Select the ''HARDCO'' vendor and review the information about compliance documents on the '''Compliance''' tab.
#Change the business date to the first day of the next month.
#:Because we have specified the expiration date of the compliance document as the last day of the current month, the system now regards those documents as expired.
#Review the warnings for each line on the '''Compliance''' tab.
#Open the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_10_00|Bills and Adjustments] ([~/?ScreenId=AP301000|AP301000]) form.
#Start creating a bill for the ''HARDCO'' vendor.
#:As soon as you specify the ''HARDCO'' vendor, a warning about expired compliance appears next to it.
#Change the business date back to the current date.
]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Compliance Documents: Process Activity If you work with a vendor that has no valid insurance policies, certificates,                 licenses, or other compliance documents, you expose your business to certain risks.                 In Acumatica ERP Construction Edition, you can track compliance items for different                 types of entities, such as vendors, projects, bills, checks, and subcontracts, so                 that this information can be used for in-place warnings to users. In this lesson, you will learn how to do the following: Configure categories and statuses for compliance documents Enter compliance documents for a vendor Track expired compliance documents Story Suppose that the Standard Hardware Company vendor has provided the SweetLife company                 with their OSHA certificate and their General Liability insurance. You need to enter                 this information in the system. Process Overview You first specify compliance preference settings on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CL301000|CL301000]) '''Compliance Preferences''' (CL301000) form.                 Then, you add compliance documents on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CL401000|CL401000]) Compliance Management (CL401000) form.                 Finally, you review documents of a particular vendor on the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP303000|AP303000]) Vendors(AP303000)                 form. System Preparation Sign in as a project manager by using the  owen  login and the  123                  password. Step 1: Configuring Document Categories and Statuses To perform configuration, do the following: Open the   ([~/?ScreenId=CL301000|CL301000]) '''Compliance Preferences'''                     (CL301000) form. On the  Custom Attributes  tab, in the  Attribute                      box, select  Insurance . In the table, in the  Value  column, click  Add Row ,                     and specify the following values: General Liability Coverage Worker's Compensation Insurance Commercial Automotive Insurance Surety Bonds Asset Protection On the  Custom Attributes  tab, in the  Attribute                      box, select  Certificate . In the table, in the  Value  column, click  Add Row ,                     and specify the following values: Safety Certification Hazardous Materials Certification Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OHSA) Project Management Institute (PMI) Leadership in Energy & Environmental Design (LEED) On the  Custom Attributes  tab, in the  Attribute                      box, select  Status . In the table, in the  Value  column, click  Add Row ,                     and specify the following values: Valid Expired Save the changes. Step 2: Creating Compliance Documents To add documents, do the following: Open the   ([~/?ScreenId=CL401000|CL401000]) Compliance Management                     (CL401000) form. On the  All Records  tab, add a row to the table with the                     following settings specified: Document Type :  Certificate Creation Date : Current date Document Category :  Occupational Safety and Health                                 Administration (OHSA) Status :  Valid Required : Selected Received from Vendor : Selected Effective Date : Start of the current year Expiration Date : End of the current month Vendor :  HARDCO Certificate Number : 123456 Save the changes. Add another row with the following settings specified: Document Type :  Insurance Creation Date : Current date Document Category :  General Liability Coverage Status :  Valid Required : Selected Received from Vendor : Selected Effective Date : Start of the current year Expiration Date : End of the current month Limit : 10,000,000 Vendor :  HARDCO Insurance Company : Insurance of NY Policy : 654321 Save the changes. Tracking the Compliance Documents Do the following: Open the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP303000|AP303000]) Vendors(AP303000) form. Select the  HARDCO  vendor and review the information about compliance                     documents on the  Compliance  tab. Change the business date to the first day of the next month. Because we have                         specified the expiration date of the compliance document as the last day of                         the current month, the system now regards those documents as                     expired. Review the warnings for each line on the  Compliance  tab. Open the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP301000|AP301000]) Bills and Adjustments                     (AP301000) form. Start creating a bill for the  HARDCO  vendor. As soon as you specify the                              HARDCO  vendor, a warning about expired compliance appears next to                         it. Change the business date back to the current date. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="80551664-937c-4736-92f4-57eebb0eb474" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" Content="&#xA;In this chapter, you will find an activity that will help you learn about processing of joint payments in the system." PlainText="Processing Joint Payments In this chapter, you will find an activity that will help you learn about processing of joint     payments in the system. " ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="8fdd2901-b739-4424-94eb-08b6e5266848" RecordSourceID="22377" />
		<row PageID="160880eb-2f5b-42ce-890d-d7b8c50944c5" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="32393efc-bb0c-ed58-b421-bdc2168b0790" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
A joint check is a check generated for an accounts payable bill that includes joint payees. This check is used for making a payment jointly to two or more parties. A joint check is used as a guarantee that the funds associated with the material or work provided to a contractor (subcontractor or general contractor) on a project are paid to a vendor that is not an active member of the project team.{br}

In this lesson, you will learn how to do the following:[anchor|#_01577b3f-26e2-4a96-8c20-85a28fac2f5c]
*Specify joint payees for an accounts payable bill
*Specify joint amounts for different lines of an accounts payable bill
*Create joint checks and process the payments

==Story==
Suppose that a storm broke windows in the hotel that the SweetLife company is building. The company needs to replace the broken windows and clean the area. The Acme Doors & Glass vendor will do the job for the SweetLife company. Also, they subcontracted the OfficeUp Original and Conwaste company to dispose of any waste and clean the area.{br}

At the end, SweetLife needs to issue and print a joint check that reflects the joint payment amounts.
==Process Overview==
To make a joint payment, you first create an AP bill that includes joint payees on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_10_00|Bills and Adjustments] ([~/?ScreenId=AP301000|AP301000]) form. And then create and process a check for this bill on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_20_00|Checks and Payments] ([~/?ScreenId=AP302000|AP302000]) form.
==Configuration Overview==
For the purposes of this lesson, the following features have been enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) form:[anchor|#_4400de97-e13a-4798-8fbd-861348b0a39c]
*''Construction'' (under the ''Projects'' group of features)
*''Payment Application by Line''

On the '''Payment Settings''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_30_00|Vendors] ([~/?ScreenId=AP303000|AP303000]) form, the '''Pay by Line''' check box is selected for the ''DOORSCO'' vendor.
==System Preparation==
Sign in as a project manager by using the ''owen'' login and the ''123'' password.
==Step 1: Processing a Joint Bill==
Do the following:[anchor|#_fa742785-635f-4638-890f-918dff014a89]
#Open the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_10_00|Bills and Adjustments] ([~/?ScreenId=AP301000|AP301000]) form.[anchor|#_2075b8fe-946c-4e45-8f93-88c184f611fc]
#On the form toolbar, click '''Add New Record'''.
#In the '''Vendor''' box, select ''DOORSCO - Acme Doors & Glass''. 
#Select the '''Joint Payees''' check box.
#In the '''Description''' box, type <tt>Replacing broken windows after the storm</tt>.
#On the '''Document Details''' tab, add lines with the settings specified in the table below.
#:{| class="checklist" | width="100%" 
|- 
!width="16%" ! Inventory ID
!width="16%" ! Quantity
!width="16%" ! Unit Cost
!width="16%" ! Project
!width="16%" ! Cost Task
!width="16%" ! Cost Code
|- 
| ''WINDISMNTL''
|  ''8''
|  ''500.00''
|  ''HOTEL''
|  ''02''
|  ''02-000''
|- 
|  ''WINDISPOSE''
|  ''4''
|  ''200.00''
|  ''HOTEL''
|  ''02''
|  ''02-000''
|- 
|  ''WINCLEAN''
|  ''4''
|  ''100.00''
|  ''HOTEL''
|  ''02''
|  ''02-000''
|}
#On the '''Joint Payees''' tab, add lines with the settings specified in the table below.
#:{| class="checklist" | width="100%" 
|- 
!width="25%" ! Joint Payee (Vendor)
!width="25%" ! Joint Payee
!width="25%" ! Bill Line Nbr.
!width="25%" ! Joint Amount Owed
|- 
| 
| ''Conwaste''
|  ''2''
|  ''400.00''
|- 
|  ''OFFICEUP''
| 
|  ''3''
|  ''200.00''
|}
#:In the '''Bill Line Nbr.''' column, you specify the number of the bill line that corresponds to the item for which the joint payee is to receive the payment. The '''Balance''' of the line, which you can review on the '''Document Details''' tab, will be reduced by the amount specified in the '''Joint Amount Paid''' column when the payment is released. If the '''Pay by Line''' check box on the''' Financial Details''' tab is cleared for the bill, the '''Joint Amount Paid''' affects the balance of the entire bill.
#:On the '''Joint Payees''' tab, you can specify a joint payee in any of the following ways:
#*If the joint payee is registered in your system as a vendor, you can select that vendor in the '''Joint Payee (Vendor)''' column.
#*If there is no vendor record that corresponds to the joint payee, you can simply type the name in the text box in the '''Joint Payee''' column.
#:Note that the sum of the joint amounts must not be greater than or equal to the total amount of the bill. At first, the joint balance for each line equals the joint amount owed. Partial payments may be applied to the lines, and as a result, the joint balance would decrease until it is completely paid and thus reduced to zero.
#Clear the '''Hold''' check box in the Summary area of the form.
#Click '''Release''' on the form toolbar.

==Step 2: Processing a Joint Payment==
Do the following:[anchor|#_072f670e-05b3-4dcc-bbdc-cd11532340c8]
#While you are still on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_10_00|Bills and Adjustments] ([~/?ScreenId=AP301000|AP301000]) form, on the form toolbar, click '''Actions''' > '''Pay Bill/Apply Payment'''.
#:The '''Indicate Amounts to Pay''' dialog box opens.
#In the dialog box, do the following:
##In the '''Amount to Pay''' box, enter 400.
##:This amount defines the part of the payment that the ''Acme Doors & Glass'' vendor is going to receive. This amount cannot be greater than the amount displayed in the '''Max Available Amount''' box.
##In the '''Joint Amount to Pay''' column of the table below, enter 200 for the ''Conwaste'' joint payee and 100 for the ''OFFICEUP'' joint payee.
##Click '''Confirm'''.
##:As a result, three joint checks are created: 
##*A check for 400 USD, which is the vendor payment amount 
##*A check for 200 USD, which is the joint payment amount for the ''Conwaste'' joint payee
##*And a check for 100 USD, which is the joint payment amount for the ''OFFICEUP'' joint payee
#On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_20_00|Checks and Payments] ([~/?ScreenId=AP302000|AP302000]) form, open each check and clear the '''Hold''' check box.
#On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_50_50_00|Process Payments / Print Checks] ([~/?ScreenId=AP505000|AP505000]) form, select the unlabeled check box for each of the joint checks and click '''Process''' on the form toolbar to print the checks.
#:The form that is used to print check is opened. For learning purposes, you do not need to print the checks so you can close the form.
#On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_50_52_00|Release Payments] ([~/?ScreenId=AP505200|AP505200]) form, which opens, you can release the payments by clicking '''Process''' on the form toolbar.
#:Note that the unlabeled check boxes are selected automatically for the corresponding payments.
]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Joint Payments: Process Activity A joint check is a check generated for an accounts payable bill that includes joint                 payees. This check is used for making a payment jointly to two or more parties. A                 joint check is used as a guarantee that the funds associated with the material or                 work provided to a contractor (subcontractor or general contractor) on a project are                 paid to a vendor that is not an active member of the project team. In this lesson, you will learn how to do the following: Specify joint payees for an accounts payable bill Specify joint amounts for different lines of an accounts payable bill Create joint checks and process the payments Story Suppose that a storm broke windows in the hotel that the SweetLife company is                 building. The company needs to replace the broken windows and clean the area. The                 Acme Doors & Glass vendor will do the job for the SweetLife company. Also, they                 subcontracted the OfficeUp Original and Conwaste company to dispose of any waste and                 clean the area. At the end, SweetLife needs to issue and print a joint check that reflects the joint                 payment amounts. Process Overview To make a joint payment, you first create an AP bill that includes joint payees on                 the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP301000|AP301000]) Bills and Adjustments (AP301000)                 form. And then create and process a check for this bill on the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP302000|AP302000]) Checks and Payments (AP302000)                 form. Configuration Overview For the purposes of this lesson, the following features have been enabled on the                       ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features (CS100000)                 form: Construction  (under the  Projects  group of features) Payment Application by Line On the  Payment Settings  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP303000|AP303000]) Vendors (AP303000) form,                 the  Pay by Line  check box is selected for the  DOORSCO  vendor. System Preparation Sign in as a project manager by using the  owen  login and the  123                  password. Step 1: Processing a Joint Bill Do the following: Open the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP301000|AP301000]) Bills and Adjustments                     (AP301000) form. On the form toolbar, click  Add New Record . In the  Vendor  box, select  DOORSCO - Acme Doors &                         Glass .  Select the  Joint Payees  check box. In the  Description  box, type  Replacing broken                         windows after the storm . On the  Document Details  tab, add lines with the settings                     specified in the table below. Inventory ID Quantity Unit Cost Project Cost Task Cost Code WINDISMNTL 8 500.00 HOTEL 02 02-000 WINDISPOSE 4 200.00 HOTEL 02 02-000 WINCLEAN 4 100.00 HOTEL 02 02-000 On the  Joint Payees  tab, add lines with the settings                     specified in the table below. Joint Payee (Vendor) Joint Payee Bill Line Nbr. Joint Amount Owed Conwaste 2 400.00 OFFICEUP 3 200.00 In the  Bill Line Nbr.  column, you specify the                         number of the bill line that corresponds to the item for which the joint                         payee is to receive the payment. The  Balance  of the                         line, which you can review on the  Document Details                          tab, will be reduced by the amount specified in the  Joint Amount                             Paid  column when the payment is released. If the                              Pay by Line  check box on the  Financial                             Details  tab is cleared for the bill, the  Joint Amount Paid                          affects the balance of the entire bill. On the  Joint Payees                          tab, you can specify a joint payee in any of the following ways: If the joint payee is registered in your system as a vendor, you can                             select that vendor in the  Joint Payee (Vendor)  column. If there is no vendor record that corresponds to the joint payee, you                             can simply type the name in the text box in the  Joint Payee                              column. Note that the sum of the joint amounts must not be greater than or equal                         to the total amount of the bill. At first, the joint balance for each line                         equals the joint amount owed. Partial payments may be applied to the lines,                         and as a result, the joint balance would decrease until it is completely                         paid and thus reduced to zero. Clear the  Hold  check box in the Summary area of the                     form. Click  Release  on the form toolbar. Step 2: Processing a Joint Payment Do the following: While you are still on the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP301000|AP301000]) Bills and Adjustments (AP301000)                     form, on the form toolbar, click  Actions Pay Bill/Apply Payment . The  Indicate Amounts to Pay  dialog box                         opens. In the dialog box, do the following: In the  Amount to Pay  box, enter 400. This                                 amount defines the part of the payment that the  Acme Doors &                                     Glass  vendor is going to receive. This amount cannot be                                 greater than the amount displayed in the  Max Available Amount                                  box. In the  Joint Amount to Pay  column of the table                             below, enter 200 for the  Conwaste  joint payee and 100 for the                                  OFFICEUP  joint payee. Click  Confirm . As a result, three joint checks                                 are created:  A check for 400 USD, which is the vendor payment amount  A check for 200 USD, which is the joint payment amount for the                                          Conwaste  joint payee And a check for 100 USD, which is the joint payment amount for                                     the  OFFICEUP  joint payee On the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP302000|AP302000]) Checks and Payments                     (AP302000) form, open each check and clear the  Hold  check                     box. On the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP505000|AP505000]) Process Payments / Print Checks                     (AP505000) form, select the unlabeled check box for each of the joint checks and                     click  Process  on the form toolbar to print the                         checks. The form that is used to print check is opened. For learning                         purposes, you do not need to print the checks so you can close the                     form. On the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP505200|AP505200]) Release Payments                     (AP505200) form, which opens, you can release the payments by clicking                          Process  on the form toolbar. Note that the                         unlabeled check boxes are selected automatically for the corresponding                         payments. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="e4e8008c-b5ad-402a-872f-fac60024be73" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" Content="&#xA;In this chapter, you will find an activity that will help you learn about processing of lien waiver in the system." PlainText="Processing Lien Waivers In this chapter, you will find an activity that will help you learn about processing of lien     waiver in the system. " ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="a0294334-4ccd-5307-d13f-c1890a4b998e" RecordSourceID="22377" />
		<row PageID="40435d63-2ea5-4149-98cd-d924187f6f78" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="100a4816-233b-a397-d361-4f9561702ace" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
A lien waiver is a compliance document involved in the payment process for a project. The party that receives a payment (for instance, a contractor, subcontractor, or material supplier) signs a lien waiver to waive their rights against the property in exchange for the payment.
==Learning Objectives==
In this chapter, you will learn how to do the following:[anchor|#_a76539ea-c56f-4d34-85e0-de3be3918691]
*Configure automatic generation of lien waivers
*Set up warnings on outstanding lien waivers
*Configure the mailing of lien waivers
*Process lien waivers

==Lien Waiver Types==
Basic types of lien waivers:[anchor|#_76f56437-0c8a-44cf-8813-217c586d3c77]
*''Conditional'' waivers for ''partial'' (or progress) payment: Used when a progress payment on the project is expected. A signed lien waiver of this type becomes effective immediately after the payment has been received.
*''Conditional'' waivers for ''final'' payment: Used when the entire contract value is to be paid at one time or when the payment in question is the final payment for a project. A signed lien waiver of this type also becomes effective only after the payment has been received.
*''Unconditional'' waivers for ''partial'' (or progress payment): Used when a progress payment on the project is expected. A lien waiver of this type becomes effective after it has been signed, regardless of whether the payment has been actually received.
*''Unconditional'' waivers for ''final'' payment: Used for a one-time payment or for the final payment for a project. A lien waiver of this type becomes unconditionally effective once it has been signed even if no payment has been actually received.

Users can manually create new lien waivers, or automatic generation of lien waivers can be set up in the system, separately for conditional and unconditional lien waivers.]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Lien Waivers: General Information A lien waiver is a compliance document involved in the payment process for a project. The     party that receives a payment (for instance, a contractor, subcontractor, or material supplier)     signs a lien waiver to waive their rights against the property in exchange for the payment. Learning Objectives In this chapter, you will learn how to do the following: Configure automatic generation of lien waivers Set up warnings on outstanding lien waivers Configure the mailing of lien waivers Process lien waivers Lien Waiver Types Basic types of lien waivers: Conditional  waivers for  partial  (or progress) payment: Used when a progress      payment on the project is expected. A signed lien waiver of this type becomes effective      immediately after the payment has been received. Conditional  waivers for  final  payment: Used when the entire contract value is      to be paid at one time or when the payment in question is the final payment for a project. A      signed lien waiver of this type also becomes effective only after the payment has been      received. Unconditional  waivers for  partial  (or progress payment): Used when a progress      payment on the project is expected. A lien waiver of this type becomes effective after it has      been signed, regardless of whether the payment has been actually received. Unconditional  waivers for  final  payment: Used for a one-time payment or for      the final payment for a project. A lien waiver of this type becomes unconditionally effective      once it has been signed even if no payment has been actually received. Users can manually create new lien waivers, or automatic generation of lien waivers can be set     up in the system, separately for conditional and unconditional lien waivers. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="cc0432dd-51f0-4312-bb8b-1bd94cca171d" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="2a64f1f1-87af-f1de-715c-43aeb1e3c435" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
The following activity will walk you through the process of configuring generation of lien waivers.
==Story==
Suppose that the SweetLife company wants conditional lien waivers to be automatically generated when payments linked to AP bills are submitted. You need to configure mailing of lien waivers and their automatic generation.
==Process Overview==
Brief description of workflow (with forms, on which particular actions are performed).
==System Preparation==
Sign in as a project manager by using the ''owen'' login and the ''123'' password.
==Step 1: Configuring the Mailing of Lien Waivers==
The processing of lien waivers includes emailing the documents to vendors who should return them signed. So that the system can generate emails with lien waivers attached, mailing should be properly configured.{br}

To configure the mailing, do the following:[anchor|#_afdbb42c-8eb8-4bef-bb8c-ad9904c257f6]
#Create a notification template for lien waivers as follows:
##On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\SM_20_40_03|Notification Templates] (SM2040PL) form, click '''Add New Record''' on the form toolbar.
##In the '''Screen Name''' box, select the ''Print/Email Lien Waivers (CL502000)'' form.
##In the '''Description''' box, type <tt>Lien Waivers</tt>.
##In the '''Subject''' box, type<tt> Lien waiver email</tt>.
##In the text editor area on the '''Message''' tab, specify the following text:
##:''Dear Vendor,''
##: ''Here&rsquo;s your lien waiver.''
##: ''Sincerely yours,''
##: ''SweetLife''
##Save the changes.
#:When generating emails with lien waivers, the system will use the subject and the message body from the notification template.
#On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_20_10_00|Vendor Classes] ([~/?ScreenId=AP201000|AP201000]) form, select the ''SUBCON'' vendor class, click the '''Mailing Settings''' tab, and do the following:
##Make sure that the ''Conditional Final'' and ''Conditional Partial'' mailings are included in the '''Mailings''' table and marked as '''Active'''.
##For each of these mailings, select the ''Lien Waiver'' notification template in the '''Notification Template''' column and in the '''Recipients''' table below, add a row with ''Remittance'' selected in the '''Contact Type''' column and default settings specified in other columns.
##Make sure that in the '''Report''' column, ''CL642003'' is specified for the ''Conditional Final'' mailing and ''CL642001 ''for the ''Conditional Partial'' mailing. These are the identifiers of the printed forms that will be generated and attached to an email.
##Save the changes.
##:These settings will be copied for any new vendor of the class. Note that mailing settings may be overridden and set up as needed for any individual vendor. When generating emails with lien waivers, the system will specify the email address of the remittance contact of the vendor (which you can review on the '''Payment Settings''' tab of the Vendors form) as the recipient address. Emails will be sent from the default system email account.

==Step 2: Configuring Automatic Generation of Lien Waivers==
Do the following:[anchor|#_bbb8981e-330c-4ee3-879f-0bb7b74b4a2f]
#On the '''Lien Waiver Settings''' tab of the [HelpRoot_Construction\CL_30_10_00|Compliance Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=CL301000|CL301000]) form, do the following:
##Select the''' Automatically Generate Lien Waivers''' check box in the '''Conditional Lien Waivers''' group of elements.
##Review the default settings and click '''Save''' on the form toolbar.
##:Because the '''Hold Documents on Entry''' check box is selected on the '''General Settings''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_10_10_00|Accounts Payable Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=AP101000|AP101000]) form, a lien waiver will be generated when the status of the accounts payable check (or checks) changes from ''On Hold'' to ''Pending Printing'' or ''Balanced''. (If the '''Hold Documents on Entry''' check box is cleared, a lien waiver is generated immediately when the accounts payable check is created with the ''Pending Printing'' or ''Balanced'' status.)
##:The through date is set to be the last day of the posting period of the accounts payable bill. This date defines by which date the party that signs a lien waiver agrees to waive their rights for the work completed since the previous lien waiver (if any).
##:The amount of an automatically generated final conditional lien waiver will equal the amount of the accounts payable bill.
#On the '''Lien Waiver Settings''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PM_30_10_00|Projects] ([~/?ScreenId=PM301000|PM301000]) form, for the ''HOTEL'' project, review the '''Through Date''' setting and then, in the table below it, specify the following settings: 
#*'''Vendor Class''': ''SUBCON'' (this indicates that conditional lien waivers may be automatically generated only for vendors that belong to this vendor class)
#*'''Minimum Commitment Amount''': ''2000'' (lien waivers will be automatically generated for commitments whose amount is larger than or equal to the specified minimum amount)
#Save the changes.
#On the '''General Settings''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_20_10_00|Vendor Classes] ([~/?ScreenId=AP201000|AP201000]) form, for the ''SUBCON'' vendor class, select the '''Generate Lien Waivers Automatically''' check box to indicate that lien waivers will be automatically generated for vendors that belong to this vendor class. The lien waiver settings specified for the particular project will be used for generating the lien waivers.
#On the '''General Info tab''' of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_30_00|Vendors] ([~/?ScreenId=AP303000|AP303000]) form, create a vendor with the following settings specified:
#*'''Vendor ID''': ARCHCO
#*'''Vendor Name''': Architectural Design Company
#*'''Email''': main@abc.con
#*'''Vendor Class''': ''SUBCON''
#Make sure that the '''Generate Lien Waivers Based on Project Settings''' check box is selected.
#Save the changes.
]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Lien Waivers: Implementation Activity The following activity will walk you through the process of configuring generation of                 lien waivers. Story Suppose that the SweetLife company wants conditional lien waivers to be automatically                 generated when payments linked to AP bills are submitted. You need to configure                 mailing of lien waivers and their automatic generation. Process Overview Brief description of workflow (with forms, on which particular actions are                 performed). System Preparation Sign in as a project manager by using the  owen  login and the  123                  password. Step 1: Configuring the Mailing of Lien Waivers The processing of lien waivers includes emailing the documents to vendors who should                 return them signed. So that the system can generate emails with lien waivers                 attached, mailing should be properly configured. To configure the mailing, do the following: Create a notification template for lien waivers as follows: On the   ([~/?ScreenId=SM204003|SM204003]) Notification Templates                             (SM2040PL) form, click  Add New Record  on the form                             toolbar. In the  Screen Name  box, select the  Print/Email Lien Waivers                                 (CL502000)  form. In the  Description  box, type  Lien                             Waivers . In the  Subject  box, type  Lien waiver                             email . In the text editor area on the  Message  tab, specify the following                                     text: Dear Vendor, Here's your lien                                     waiver. Sincerely                                 yours, SweetLife Save the changes. When generating emails with lien waivers, the system will use the                         subject and the message body from the notification template. On the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP201000|AP201000]) Vendor Classes                     (AP201000) form, select the  SUBCON  vendor class, click the  Mailing                         Settings  tab, and do the following: Make sure that the  Conditional Final  and  Conditional                                 Partial  mailings are included in the  Mailings  table and                             marked as  Active . For each of these mailings, select the  Lien Waiver  notification                             template in the  Notification Template  column and in the                                  Recipients  table below, add a row with  Remittance                              selected in the  Contact Type  column and default settings                             specified in other columns. Make sure that in the  Report  column,  CL642003  is specified                             for the  Conditional Final  mailing and  CL642001  for the                                  Conditional Partial  mailing. These are the identifiers of the                             printed forms that will be generated and attached to an email. Save the changes. These settings will be copied for any new vendor of                                 the class. Note that mailing settings may be overridden and set up                                 as needed for any individual vendor. When generating emails with                                 lien waivers, the system will specify the email address of the                                 remittance contact of the vendor (which you can review on the                                      Payment Settings  tab of the Vendors form) as the                                 recipient address. Emails will be sent from the default system email                                 account. Step 2: Configuring Automatic Generation of Lien Waivers Do the following: On the  Lien Waiver Settings  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=CL301000|CL301000]) Compliance                         Preferences Compliance Preferences (CL301000) form, do the following: Select the  Automatically Generate Lien Waivers  check box in the                                  Conditional Lien Waivers  group of elements. Review the default settings and click  Save  on the form                                 toolbar. Because the  Hold Documents on Entry  check box is                                 selected on the  General Settings  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP101000|AP101000]) Accounts Payable Preferences                                 (AP101000) form, a lien waiver will be generated when the status of                                 the accounts payable check (or checks) changes from  On Hold                                  to  Pending Printing  or  Balanced . (If the  Hold                                     Documents on Entry  check box is cleared, a lien waiver is                                 generated immediately when the accounts payable check is created                                 with the  Pending Printing  or  Balanced                                  status.) The through date is set to be the last day of the                                 posting period of the accounts payable bill. This date defines by                                 which date the party that signs a lien waiver agrees to waive their                                 rights for the work completed since the previous lien waiver (if                                 any). The amount of an automatically generated final                                 conditional lien waiver will equal the amount of the accounts                                 payable bill. On the  Lien Waiver Settings  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=PM301000|PM301000]) Projects Projects (PM301000) form, for the  HOTEL  project, review the                          Through Date  setting and then, in the table below it, specify the                     following settings:  Vendor Class :  SUBCON  (this indicates that conditional lien                             waivers may be automatically generated only for vendors that belong to                             this vendor class) Minimum Commitment Amount :  2000  (lien waivers will be                             automatically generated for commitments whose amount is larger than or                             equal to the specified minimum amount) Save the changes. On the  General Settings  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP201000|AP201000]) Vendor Classes (AP201000)                     form, for the  SUBCON  vendor class, select the  Generate Lien Waivers                         Automatically  check box to indicate that lien waivers will be                     automatically generated for vendors that belong to this vendor class. The lien                     waiver settings specified for the particular project will be used for generating                     the lien waivers. On the  General Info tab  of the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP303000|AP303000]) Vendors Vendors                     (AP303000) form, create a vendor with the following settings specified: Vendor ID : ARCHCO Vendor Name : Architectural Design Company Email : main@abc.con Vendor Class :  SUBCON Make sure that the  Generate Lien Waivers Based on Project                         Settings  check box is selected. Save the changes. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="81816f40-baf1-42a8-89e1-4ba162254861" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="15b085fd-8be5-ab57-424e-2746bc6b8107" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
The following activity will walk you through the process of working with lien waivers.
==Story==
Suppose that the SweetLife company pays bills to a subcontractor. You need to create and pay these bills in the system and make sure that the related lien waivers have been generated.
==System Preparation==
Sign in as a project manager by using the ''owen'' login and the ''123'' password.
==Step 1: '''Working with Lien Waivers'''==
Do the following:[anchor|#_ec2df785-4d5c-4386-bbba-5ffd04ffedaf]
#On the [HelpRoot_Construction\SC_30_10_00|Subcontracts] ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000]) form, create a subcontract for the ''ARCHCO'' vendor with the following document line specified on the '''Document Details''' tab:
#*'''Inventory ID''': ''MATERIAL''
#* '''Project''': ''HOTEL''
#* '''Project Task''': ''02 - SITEWORK''
#* '''Cost Code''': 02-000
#*'''Order Qty.''': 100
#*'''Unit Cost''': 500
#*:The total amount of this commitment is ''50000'', which exceeds the minimum commitment amount specified for the vendor and project.
#Save the changes. 
#:(Now you can review the new commitment record on the '''Commitments''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PM_30_10_00|Projects] ([~/?ScreenId=PM301000|PM301000]) form for the ''HOTEL'' project.)
#Take the subcontract off hold–that is, clear the '''Hold''' check box.
#On the form toolbar, click '''Actions''' > '''Enter AP Bill'''.
#:The [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_10_00|Bills and Adjustments] ([~/?ScreenId=AP301000|AP301000]) form opens, with ''Bill'' selected in the '''Type''' box by default and with document details copied from the subcontract.
#Take the bill off hold–that is, clear the '''Hold''' check box.
#Click '''Release''' on the form toolbar to release the bill.
#On the form toolbar, click '''Actions''' > '''Pay Bill/Apply Adjustment'''.
#:The [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_20_00|Checks and Payments] ([~/?ScreenId=AP302000|AP302000]) form opens, with details copied from the bill.
#Review the status of the document–the check should be on hold. Review the '''Compliance''' tab–it should be empty at this point.
#While on the '''Compliance''' tab, clear the '''Hold''' check box in the Summary area and then save the changes.
#:Note that a lien waiver record appears in the table on the '''Compliance''' tab.
#:Note that the same lien waiver record appears on the '''Compliance''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PM_30_10_00|Projects] ([~/?ScreenId=PM301000|PM301000]), [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_30_00|Vendors] ([~/?ScreenId=AP303000|AP303000]), [HelpRoot_Construction\SC_30_10_00|Subcontracts] ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000]), and [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_10_00|Bills and Adjustments] ([~/?ScreenId=AP301000|AP301000]) forms for the involved documents.
#:Also, the record appears on the [HelpRoot_Construction\CL_40_10_00|Compliance Management] ([~/?ScreenId=CL401000|CL401000]) form.
#On the ''Print/Email Lien Waivers'' (CL502000) form, do the following:
##In the '''Action''' box, select ''Email Lien Waivers''.
##Select the unlabeled check box for the lien waiver that you want to email to the vendor.
##Click '''Process''' on the form toolbar.
#:If an email has been successfully created, the lien waiver is marked as processed (that is, the Processed check box becomes selected in the lien waiver details). 
#Review the list of outgoing emails on the '''All Records''' tab of the Outgoing (CO409020) form–the newly created email should be at the top of the list.
#:Click the link in the '''Subject''' column and review the email on the Email Activity form that opens. Click '''Files''' on the title bar to review the printed form of the lien waiver attached to the email.
#On the '''Lien Waivers''' tab of the [HelpRoot_Construction\CL_40_10_00|Compliance Management] form, review the details of the processed lien waiver.
#:When you receive a signed copy of the lien waiver, you need to manually mark it as received by selecting the '''Received from Vendor''' check box. (Note that the check box should remain cleared for the next exercise.)

==Step 2: Working with Outstanding Lien Waivers==
An outstanding lien waiver is a lien waiver that has not been marked as received and whose '''Through Date''' is earlier than the current business date in the system. Do the following:[anchor|#_cd007c0a-b10b-460b-81a3-b450c8d0c9dc]
#On the '''Lien Waiver Settings''' tab of the [HelpRoot_Construction\CL_30_10_00|Compliance Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=CL301000|CL301000]) form, select the following check boxes and save the changes:
#*'''Warn of Outstanding Lien Waivers During AP Bill Entry''': A warning will appear if the system finds an outstanding lien waiver when the user attempts to enter an accounts payable bill on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_10_00|Bills and Adjustments] ([~/?ScreenId=AP301000|AP301000]) form.
#*'''Warn of Outstanding Lien Waivers when Selecting AP Bill for Payment''': A warning will appear if the system finds an outstanding lien waiver when the user attempts to select an accounts payable bill for a payment on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_20_00|Checks and Payments] ([~/?ScreenId=AP302000|AP302000]) form.
#*:Note that these warnings may also appear on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_50_30_00|Prepare Payments] ([~/?ScreenId=AP503000|AP503000]) form during the processing.
#*'''Stop Payment of AP Bill When There Are Outstanding Lien Waivers''': The system will show an error message and stop the payment in the following circumstances:
#**On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_10_00|Bills and Adjustments] form, when a user clicks '''Actions''' &gt; '''Pay Bill/Apply Adjustment''' on the form toolbar for an accounts payable bill that has a linked outstanding lien waiver.
#**On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_20_00|Checks and Payments] form, when a user attempts to take off hold or release a check that has a linked outstanding lien waiver.
#**On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_50_30_00|Prepare Payments], [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_50_50_00|Process Payments / Print Checks] ([~/?ScreenId=AP505000|AP505000]), or [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_50_52_00|Release Payments] ([~/?ScreenId=AP505200|AP505200]) form, when the user initiates the processing of the document.
#Change the business date to the last day of the next month. 
#:Thus, the lien waiver that was generated in the previous exercise will be considered as an outstanding lien waiver because it hasn&rsquo;t been marked as received and its '''Through Date''' is earlier than the current business date.
#On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_10_00|Bills and Adjustments] form, do the following: 
##Start entering a new bill for the ''ARCHCO'' vendor.
##:When you start entering a document detail line and specify a related project, a warning appears next to the Vendor box in the Summary area of the form. This warning appears because the '''Warn of Outstanding Lien Waivers During AP Bill Entry''' check box is selected on the [HelpRoot_Construction\CL_30_10_00|Compliance Preferences] form.
##Enter all necessary settings and save the changes to create the bill anyway.
##Clear the '''Hold''' check box in the Summary area and click '''Release''' on the form toolbar.
##Click '''Actions '''&gt; '''Pay Bill/Apply Adjustment'''.
##:An error message is displayed notifying you that no payment can be created for the bill because it is linked to at least one outstanding lien waiver. This message appears because the '''Stop Payment of AP Bill When There Are Outstanding Lien Waivers''' check box is selected on the [HelpRoot_Construction\CL_30_10_00|Compliance Preferences] form.
#On the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_20_00|Checks and Payments] ([~/?ScreenId=AP302000|AP302000]) form, create a new check for the ''ARCHCO'' vendor, and on the '''Documents to Apply''' tab, select the bill created in the previous step and specify a line number in respective columns.
#:Immediately after that, the system displays a warning that the vendor has at least one outstanding lien waiver.
#:This warning appears because the '''Warn of Outstanding Lien Waivers when Selecting AP Bill for Payment''' check box is selected on the [HelpRoot_Construction\CL_30_10_00|Compliance Preferences] form.
#:Now, before you continue your work with this vendor, you may want to remind them that you need to receive the signed lien waiver first (and manually mark the corresponding lien waiver as received).
#Change the business date back to the current date.
]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Lien Waivers: Process Activity The following activity will walk you through the process of working with lien                 waivers. Story Suppose that the SweetLife company pays bills to a subcontractor. You need to create                 and pay these bills in the system and make sure that the related lien waivers have                 been generated. System Preparation Sign in as a project manager by using the  owen  login and the  123                  password. Step 1:  Working with Lien Waivers Do the following: On the   ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000]) Subcontracts                     (SC301000) form, create a subcontract for the  ARCHCO  vendor with the                     following document line specified on the  Document Details  tab: Inventory ID :  MATERIAL Project :  HOTEL Project Task :  02 - SITEWORK Cost Code : 02-000 Order Qty. : 100 Unit Cost : 500 The total amount of this                                 commitment is  50000 , which exceeds the minimum commitment                                 amount specified for the vendor and project. Save the changes.  (Now you can review the new commitment record on the                              Commitments  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=PM301000|PM301000]) Projects Projects (PM301000) form for the  HOTEL  project.) Take the subcontract off hold–that is, clear the  Hold  check box. On the form toolbar, click  Actions Enter AP Bill . The   ([~/?ScreenId=AP301000|AP301000]) Bills and                             Adjustments Bills and Adjustments (AP301000) form opens, with  Bill  selected in                         the  Type  box by default and with document details                         copied from the subcontract. Take the bill off hold–that is, clear the  Hold  check box. Click  Release  on the form toolbar to release the bill. On the form toolbar, click  Actions Pay Bill/Apply Adjustment . The   ([~/?ScreenId=AP302000|AP302000]) Checks and Payments(AP302000) form opens, with details copied from the bill. Review the status of the document–the check should be on hold. Review the                          Compliance  tab–it should be empty at this point. While on the  Compliance  tab, clear the  Hold  check box in the                     Summary area and then save the changes. Note that a lien waiver record appears                         in the table on the  Compliance  tab. Note that the same lien                         waiver record appears on the  Compliance  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=PM301000|PM301000]) Projects Projects (PM301000),   ([~/?ScreenId=AP303000|AP303000]) Vendors Vendors (AP303000),   ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000]) Subcontracts                         (SC301000), and   ([~/?ScreenId=AP301000|AP301000]) Bills and                             Adjustments Bills and Adjustments (AP301000) forms for the involved                         documents. Also, the record appears on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CL401000|CL401000]) Compliance Management                         (CL401000) form. On the  Print/Email Lien Waivers  (CL502000) form, do the following: In the  Action  box, select  Email Lien Waivers . Select the unlabeled check box for the lien waiver that you want to                             email to the vendor. Click  Process  on the form toolbar. If an email has been successfully created, the lien waiver is marked as                         processed (that is, the Processed check box becomes selected in the lien                         waiver details).  Review the list of outgoing emails on the  All Records  tab of the Outgoing                     (CO409020) form–the newly created email should be at the top of the                         list. Click the link in the  Subject  column and review the email on                         the Email Activity form that opens. Click  Files  on the title bar to                         review the printed form of the lien waiver attached to the email. On the  Lien Waivers  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=CL401000|CL401000]) Compliance Management form, review                     the details of the processed lien waiver. When you receive a signed copy of                         the lien waiver, you need to manually mark it as received by selecting the                              Received from Vendor  check box. (Note that the check box should                         remain cleared for the next exercise.) Step 2: Working with Outstanding Lien Waivers An outstanding lien waiver is a lien waiver that has not been marked as received and                 whose  Through Date  is earlier than the current business date in the system.                 Do the following: On the  Lien Waiver Settings  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=CL301000|CL301000]) Compliance                         Preferences Compliance Preferences (CL301000) form, select the following check boxes and                     save the changes: Warn of Outstanding Lien Waivers During AP Bill Entry : A warning                             will appear if the system finds an outstanding lien waiver when the user                             attempts to enter an accounts payable bill on the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP301000|AP301000]) Bills                                 and Adjustments Bills and Adjustments (AP301000) form. Warn of Outstanding Lien Waivers when Selecting AP Bill for                                 Payment : A warning will appear if the system finds an                             outstanding lien waiver when the user attempts to select an accounts                             payable bill for a payment on the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP302000|AP302000]) Checks and Payments                             (AP302000) form. Note that these warnings may also appear on the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP503000|AP503000]) Prepare Payments Prepare Payments (AP503000) form during the                                 processing. Stop Payment of AP Bill When There Are Outstanding Lien Waivers :                             The system will show an error message and stop the payment in the                             following circumstances: On the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP301000|AP301000]) Bills and Adjustments Bills and Adjustments form, when a user clicks                                          Actions  >  Pay Bill/Apply Adjustment  on the                                     form toolbar for an accounts payable bill that has a linked                                     outstanding lien waiver. On the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP302000|AP302000]) Checks and Payments form, when a user attempts to take off hold or release a                                     check that has a linked outstanding lien waiver. On the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP503000|AP503000]) Prepare Payments Prepare Payments,   ([~/?ScreenId=AP505000|AP505000]) Process Payments / Print Checks Process Payments / Print Checks (AP505000), or   ([~/?ScreenId=AP505200|AP505200]) Release Payments Release Payments (AP505200) form, when the user                                     initiates the processing of the document. Change the business date to the last day of the next month.  Thus, the lien                         waiver that was generated in the previous exercise will be considered as an                         outstanding lien waiver because it hasn't been marked as received and its                              Through Date  is earlier than the current business date. On the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP301000|AP301000]) Bills                         and Adjustments Bills and Adjustments form, do the following:  Start entering a new bill for the  ARCHCO  vendor. When you start                                 entering a document detail line and specify a related project, a                                 warning appears next to the Vendor box in the Summary area of the                                 form. This warning appears because the  Warn of Outstanding Lien                                     Waivers During AP Bill Entry  check box is selected on the                                       ([~/?ScreenId=CL301000|CL301000]) Compliance Preferences Compliance Preferences form. Enter all necessary settings and save the changes to create the bill                             anyway. Clear the  Hold  check box in the Summary area and click                                  Release  on the form toolbar. Click  Actions  >  Pay Bill/Apply Adjustment . An error                                 message is displayed notifying you that no payment can be created                                 for the bill because it is linked to at least one outstanding lien                                 waiver. This message appears because the  Stop Payment of AP Bill                                     When There Are Outstanding Lien Waivers  check box is                                 selected on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CL301000|CL301000]) Compliance Preferences Compliance Preferences form. On the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP302000|AP302000]) Checks and Payments                     (AP302000) form, create a new check for the  ARCHCO  vendor, and on the                          Documents to Apply  tab, select the bill created in the previous step                     and specify a line number in respective columns. Immediately after that, the                         system displays a warning that the vendor has at least one outstanding lien                         waiver. This warning appears because the  Warn of Outstanding Lien                             Waivers when Selecting AP Bill for Payment  check box is selected on                         the   ([~/?ScreenId=CL301000|CL301000]) Compliance Preferences Compliance Preferences form. Now, before you continue your                         work with this vendor, you may want to remind them that you need to receive                         the signed lien waiver first (and manually mark the corresponding lien                         waiver as received). Change the business date back to the current date. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="c1a585c1-0769-4494-98c3-2dd167d58edb" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" Content="&#xA;In order to support the functionality provided by Acumatica ERP Construction                         Edition the appropriate changes are made for specific Acumatica ERP forms. The list of changes is provided below.[anchor|#_73324d3b-1039-4211-bd1f-cb298ad0b290]&#xA;*[HelpRoot_Construction\CN__con_Compliance_Tab|Compliance Tab]&#xA;*[HelpRoot_Construction\CN__con_Multiple_Accounts_Tab|Multiple Accounts Tab]&#xA;*[HelpRoot_Construction\CN__con_Project_Task_Type_Box|Project Task Type Box]&#xA;*[HelpRoot_Construction\SC_30_10_00|Subcontracts]&#xA;*[HelpRoot_Construction\SC_50_30_00|Print/Email Subcontracts]&#xA;*[HelpRoot_Construction\SC_10_10_00|Subcontracts Preferences]&#xA;*[HelpRoot_Construction\CL_40_10_00|Compliance Management]&#xA;*[HelpRoot_Construction\CL_30_10_00|'''Compliance Preferences''']&#xA;" PlainText="Construction Form Reference In order to support the functionality provided by  Acumatica ERP Construction                         Edition the     appropriate changes are made for specific  Acumatica ERP     forms. The list of changes is provided below. Compliance TabMultiple Accounts TabProject Task Type Box ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000]) Subcontracts ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000]) ([~/?ScreenId=SC503000|SC503000]) Print/Email Subcontracts ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000]) ([~/?ScreenId=SC503000|SC503000]) ([~/?ScreenId=SC101000|SC101000]) Subcontracts Preferences ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000]) ([~/?ScreenId=SC503000|SC503000]) ([~/?ScreenId=SC101000|SC101000]) ([~/?ScreenId=CL401000|CL401000]) Compliance Management ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000]) ([~/?ScreenId=SC503000|SC503000]) ([~/?ScreenId=SC101000|SC101000]) ([~/?ScreenId=CL401000|CL401000]) ([~/?ScreenId=CL301000|CL301000]) '''Compliance Preferences'''" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="351cbab3-936b-4d28-d0c7-55a0c00c83a2" RecordSourceID="22377" />
		<row PageID="50240155-f6b0-4a1a-b65f-13eeb5842839" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="e0f0d79f-acf8-1093-e601-8c7019b7437b" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
The '''Compliance''' tab is added to multiple Acumatica ERP forms to support functionality of the applied Construction package. This topic lists altered Acumatica ERP forms and provides reference information for the '''Compliance''' tab functionality.[anchor|#_99d387eb-8b0c-4916-a1d4-27523d6ffb85]
*Finance
**Accounts Payable:
***[HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_30_00|Vendors] ([~/?ScreenId=AP303000|AP303000])
***[HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_10_00|Bills and Adjustments] ([~/?ScreenId=AP301000|AP301000])
***[HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_20_00|Checks and Payments] ([~/?ScreenId=AP302000|AP302000])
**Accounts Receivable:
***[HelpRoot_FormReference\AR_30_30_00|Customers] ([~/?ScreenId=AR303000|AR303000])
***[HelpRoot_FormReference\AR_30_10_00|Invoices and Memos] ([~/?ScreenId=AR301000|AR301000])
*Organization
**Projects:
***[HelpRoot_FormReference\PM_30_10_00|Projects] ([~/?ScreenId=PM301000|PM301000])
***[HelpRoot_FormReference\PM_30_20_00|Project Tasks] ([~/?ScreenId=PM302000|PM302000])
***[HelpRoot_FormReference\PM_30_40_00|Project Transactions] ([~/?ScreenId=PM304000|PM304000])
*Distribution
**Purchase Orders:
***[HelpRoot_FormReference\PO_30_10_00|Purchase Orders] ([~/?ScreenId=PO301000|PO301000])
**Subcontracts:
***[HelpRoot_Construction\SC_30_10_00|Subcontracts] ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000])
{br}{TOC}
==Table==
The '''Compliance''' tab contains the table that lists compliance documents created by the user. The table contains only those compliance documents, which are associated with the entity that is created on the form. You can add and update compliance documents within this tab.{br}

The table toolbar includes only standard buttons. For the list of standard buttons, see [HelpRoot_Interface\Details_Toolbar|Table Toolbar].[anchor|#_f721120e-3edd-4c0a-9a17-677562652f2a]
===Table Columns===
{| class="checklist" | width="100%" 
|- 
!width="20%" ! Column
!width="80%" ! Description
|- 
| '''Document Type'''
| 
The type of the compliance document. The following document types are available:[anchor|#_b3b2e3fb-cc65-426c-b9c0-aad35ca9cbc2]
*''Certificate''
* ''Insurance''
* ''Notice''
* ''Lien Waiver''
* ''Other''

|- 
|  '''Creation Date'''
| The date when the compliance document was created. By default, the current date is set. The user is able to change the date manually.
|- 
| '''Document Type Option'''
| The document type option of the compliance’s document type. The list of document type options should be set manually on the [HelpRoot_Construction\CL_30_10_00|'''Compliance Preferences'''] ([~/?ScreenId=CL301000|CL301000]) form.
|- 
| '''Status'''
| The status of the compliance document. The list of values should be set manually on the [HelpRoot_Construction\CL_30_10_00|'''Compliance Preferences'''] form.
|- 
| '''Is Required'''
| A check box that indicates (if selected) that the document is mandatory for working with a specific project or project task. This flag is for informational purposes only. It shows that the compliance document is required before implementing some activities on a project.
|- 
| '''Received'''
| A check box that indicates (if selected) that the document is received by user. The ''Received'' check box allows the user to track when the payment for document is received, so the next payment is not delayed.
|- 
| '''Received Date'''
| The date when the compliance document is received. The date should be set manually by the user on the '''Compliance''' tab after the document is received.
|- 
| '''Sent Date'''
| The date when the compliance document is sent. The date should be set manually by the user on the '''Compliance''' tab after the document is sent.
|- 
| '''Effective Date'''
| The date when the compliance document takes effect. The date should be set manually by the user while adding the document on the '''Compliance''' tab.
|- 
| '''Expiration Date'''
| The date when the compliance document will expire. The date should be set manually by the user while adding the document on the '''Compliance''' tab.
|- 
| '''Limit'''
| The amount of insurance liability set for the compliance document. The amount should be set manually by the user while adding the document on the '''Compliance''' tab.
|- 
| '''Method Sent'''
| The method of sending the document.
|- 
| '''Project'''
| The reference to a project to which a compliance document relates. By default, it is set to the identifier of the project selected in the Summary area of the form. If specified, current document will be displayed on the '''Compliance''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PM_30_10_00|Projects] ([~/?ScreenId=PM301000|PM301000]) form of the selected project.
|- 
| '''Cost Task'''
| The reference to a cost task available within the project. If specified, current document will be displayed on the '''Compliance''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PM_30_20_00|Project Tasks] ([~/?ScreenId=PM302000|PM302000]) form of the selected task of the ''Cost Task'' type.
|- 
| '''Revenue Task'''
| The reference to a revenue task within the project. If specified, current document will be displayed on the '''Compliance''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PM_30_20_00|Project Tasks] form of the selected task of the ''Revenue Task'' type.
|- 
| '''Cost Code'''
| The cost code assigned to the compliance document.
|- 
| '''Customer'''
| The reference number of the customer associated with the compliance document. By default, it is set to the identifier of the customer selected in the Summary area of the form. If specified, current document will be displayed on the '''Compliance tab''' of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AR_30_30_00|Customers] ([~/?ScreenId=AR303000|AR303000]) form of the selected customer.
|- 
| '''Customer Name'''
| The name of the customer associated with the compliance document.
|- 
| '''Vendor'''
| The reference number of the vendor associated with the compliance document. By default, it is set to the identifier of the vendor selected in the Summary area of the form. If specified, current document will be displayed on the '''Compliance''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_30_00|Vendors] ([~/?ScreenId=AP303000|AP303000]) form of the selected vendor.
|- 
| '''Vendor Name'''
| The name of the vendor associated with the compliance document.
|- 
| '''Secondary Vendor'''
| The reference number of the secondary vendor associated with the compliance document. If specified, current document will be displayed on the '''Compliance''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_30_00|Vendors] form of the selected vendor.
|- 
| '''Secondary Vendor Name'''
| The name of the secondary vendor associated with the compliance document.
|- 
| '''Purchase Order'''
| The unique identifier of the purchase order associated with the compliance document. By default, it is set to the identifier of the purchase order selected in the Summary area of the form. If specified, current document will be displayed on the '''Compliance''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PO_30_10_00|Purchase Orders] ([~/?ScreenId=PO301000|PO301000]) form of the selected purchase order.
|- 
| '''Purchase Order Line Item'''
| The unique identifier of the purchase order line item. It can be specified only after a purchase order is selected.
|- 
| '''Subcontract'''
| The unique identifier of the subcontract associated with the compliance document. By default, it is set to the identifier of the subcontract selected in the Summary area of the form. If specified, current document will be displayed on the '''Compliance''' tab of the [HelpRoot_Construction\SC_30_10_00|Subcontracts] ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000]) form of the selected subcontract.
|- 
| '''Subcontract Line Item'''
| The unique identifier of the subcontract line. It can be specified only after a subcontract is selected.
|- 
| '''Invoice'''
| The reference number of the invoice associated with the compliance document. By default, it is set to the identifier of the invoice selected in the Summary area of the form. If specified, current document will be displayed on the '''Compliance''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AR_30_10_00|Invoices and Memos] ([~/?ScreenId=AR301000|AR301000]) form of the selected invoice.
|- 
| '''Invoice Amount'''
| The amount of the invoice.
|- 
| '''Bill'''
| The reference number of the bill associated with the compliance document. By default, it is set to the identifier of the bill selected in the Summary area of the form. If specified, current document will be displayed on the '''Compliance''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_10_00|Bills and Adjustments] ([~/?ScreenId=AP301000|AP301000]) form of the selected bill.
|- 
| '''Bill Amount'''
| The bill amount to be paid for the document.
|- 
| '''Lien Waiver Amount'''
| The amount covered by the lien waiver.
|- 
| '''Sponsor Organization'''
| The name of the sponsor organization.
|- 
| '''Certificate Number'''
| The number of the certificate.
|- 
| '''Insurance Company'''
| The name of the insurance company.
|- 
| '''Policy'''
| The insurance policy number.
|- 
| '''Account'''
| The account associated with the vendor (Expense account) or customer (Sales account).
|- 
| '''AP Check'''
| The reference number of the check associated with the compliance document.
|- 
| '''AR Payment'''
| The reference number of the payment associated with the compliance document.
|- 
| '''Project Transaction'''
| The reference number of the project transaction associated with the compliance document.
|- 
| '''Payment Date'''
| The date when the check is created.
|- 
| '''Receipt Date'''
| The date when the inventory receipt is made.
|- 
| '''Date Issued'''
| The date when the document is issued.
|- 
| '''Through Date'''
| The date when the goods are shipped.
|- 
| '''Receive Date'''
| The date when the goods are received.
|- 
| '''Received By'''
| The person responsible for receiving goods.
|- 
| '''Source'''
| 
The source of the check. One of the following values is allowed:[anchor|#_9cc8fe31-bc37-463a-9d43-ad3ec8fe4951]
*''AP Inv''
* ''PO/Sub''
* ''Project''
* ''Customer''

|- 
|  '''Requires Joint Check'''
| A check box that indicates (if selected) that the joint check is required.
|- 
| '''Joint Vendor'''
| The reference number of the joint vendor associated with the compliance document. If specified, current document will be displayed on the '''Compliance''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_30_00|Vendors] form of the selected vendor.
|- 
| '''Joint Amount'''
| The amount to be paid to joint payees according to the joint check.
|- 
| '''Joint Release'''
| A check box that indicates (if selected) that the joint release is received.
|- 
| '''AP Payment Method'''
| The payment method associated with the vendor.
|- 
| '''AR Payment Method'''
| The customer’s default payment method.
|}]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Compliance Tab The  Compliance  tab is added to multiple  Acumatica ERP forms to support functionality of the applied Construction package. This topic lists         altered  Acumatica ERP forms and provides reference information for the  Compliance  tab functionality. Finance Accounts Payable:  ([~/?ScreenId=AP303000|AP303000]) Vendors (AP303000)  ([~/?ScreenId=AP301000|AP301000]) Bills and Adjustments (AP301000)  ([~/?ScreenId=AP302000|AP302000]) Checks and Payments (AP302000) Accounts Receivable:  ([~/?ScreenId=AR303000|AR303000]) Customers (AR302000)  ([~/?ScreenId=AR301000|AR301000]) Invoices and Memos (AR301000) Organization Projects:  ([~/?ScreenId=PM301000|PM301000]) Projects (PM301000)  ([~/?ScreenId=PM302000|PM302000]) Project Tasks (PM302000)  ([~/?ScreenId=PM304000|PM304000]) Project Transactions (PM304000) Distribution Purchase Orders:  ([~/?ScreenId=PO301000|PO301000]) Purchase Orders (PO301000) Subcontracts:  ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000]) Subcontracts (SC301000) Table The  Compliance  tab contains the table that lists compliance documents created by the         user. The table contains only those compliance documents, which are associated with the         entity that is created on the form. You can add and update compliance documents within this         tab. The table toolbar includes only standard buttons. For the list of standard buttons, see            Table Toolbar. Table Columns Column Description Document Type The type of the compliance document. The following document types are                   available: Certificate Insurance Notice Lien Waiver Other Creation Date The date when the compliance document was created. By default, the current date                 is set. The user is able to change the date manually. Document Type Option The document type option of the compliance’s document type. The list of                 document type options should be set manually on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CL301000|CL301000]) '''Compliance Preferences'''                 (CL301000) form. Status The status of the compliance document. The list of values should be set                 manually on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CL301000|CL301000]) '''Compliance Preferences''' form. Is Required A check box that indicates (if selected) that the document is mandatory for                 working with a specific project or project task. This flag is for informational                 purposes only. It shows that the compliance document is required before implementing                 some activities on a project. Received A check box that indicates (if selected) that the document is received by user.                 The  Received  check box allows the user to track when the payment for document                 is received, so the next payment is not delayed. Received Date The date when the compliance document is received. The date should be set                 manually by the user on the  Compliance  tab after the document is                 received. Sent Date The date when the compliance document is sent. The date should be set manually                 by the user on the  Compliance  tab after the document is sent. Effective Date The date when the compliance document takes effect. The date should be set                 manually by the user while adding the document on the  Compliance  tab. Expiration Date The date when the compliance document will expire. The date should be set                 manually by the user while adding the document on the  Compliance  tab. Limit The amount of insurance liability set for the compliance document. The amount                 should be set manually by the user while adding the document on the                    Compliance  tab. Method Sent The method of sending the document. Project The reference to a project to which a compliance document relates. By default,                 it is set to the identifier of the project selected in the Summary area of the form.                 If specified, current document will be displayed on the  Compliance  tab of the                     ([~/?ScreenId=PM301000|PM301000]) Projects (PM301000) form of the selected project. Cost Task The reference to a cost task available within the project. If specified,                 current document will be displayed on the  Compliance  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=PM302000|PM302000]) Project Tasks (PM302000) form of the selected task of the  Cost                   Task  type. Revenue Task The reference to a revenue task within the project. If specified, current                 document will be displayed on the  Compliance  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=PM302000|PM302000]) Project Tasks form of the selected task of the  Revenue Task                  type. Cost Code The cost code assigned to the compliance document. Customer The reference number of the customer associated with the compliance document.                 By default, it is set to the identifier of the customer selected in the Summary area                 of the form. If specified, current document will be displayed on the  Compliance                   tab  of the   ([~/?ScreenId=AR303000|AR303000]) Customers (AR303000) form of the selected                 customer. Customer Name The name of the customer associated with the compliance document. Vendor The reference number of the vendor associated with the compliance document. By                 default, it is set to the identifier of the vendor selected in the Summary area of                 the form. If specified, current document will be displayed on the  Compliance                  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP303000|AP303000]) Vendors (AP303000) form of the selected                 vendor. Vendor Name The name of the vendor associated with the compliance document. Secondary Vendor The reference number of the secondary vendor associated with the compliance                 document. If specified, current document will be displayed on the  Compliance                  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP303000|AP303000]) Vendors form of the selected vendor. Secondary Vendor Name The name of the secondary vendor associated with the compliance                 document. Purchase Order The unique identifier of the purchase order associated with the compliance                 document. By default, it is set to the identifier of the purchase order selected in                 the Summary area of the form. If specified, current document will be displayed on                 the  Compliance  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=PO301000|PO301000]) Purchase Orders (PO301000) form of                 the selected purchase order. Purchase Order Line Item The unique identifier of the purchase order line item. It can be specified only                 after a purchase order is selected. Subcontract The unique identifier of the subcontract associated with the compliance                 document. By default, it is set to the identifier of the subcontract selected in the                 Summary area of the form. If specified, current document will be displayed on the                    Compliance  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000]) Subcontracts (SC301000) form of                 the selected subcontract. Subcontract Line Item The unique identifier of the subcontract line. It can be specified only after a                 subcontract is selected. Invoice The reference number of the invoice associated with the compliance document. By                 default, it is set to the identifier of the invoice selected in the Summary area of                 the form. If specified, current document will be displayed on the  Compliance                  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=AR301000|AR301000]) Invoices and Memos (AR301000) form of the selected                 invoice. Invoice Amount The amount of the invoice. Bill The reference number of the bill associated with the compliance document. By                 default, it is set to the identifier of the bill selected in the Summary area of the                 form. If specified, current document will be displayed on the  Compliance  tab                 of the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP301000|AP301000]) Bills and Adjustments (AP301000) form of the selected bill. Bill Amount The bill amount to be paid for the document. Lien Waiver Amount The amount covered by the lien waiver. Sponsor Organization The name of the sponsor organization. Certificate Number The number of the certificate. Insurance Company The name of the insurance company. Policy The insurance policy number. Account The account associated with the vendor (Expense account) or customer (Sales                 account). AP Check The reference number of the check associated with the compliance                 document. AR Payment The reference number of the payment associated with the compliance                 document. Project Transaction The reference number of the project transaction associated with the compliance                 document. Payment Date The date when the check is created. Receipt Date The date when the inventory receipt is made. Date Issued The date when the document is issued. Through Date The date when the goods are shipped. Receive Date The date when the goods are received. Received By The person responsible for receiving goods. Source The source of the check. One of the following values is allowed: AP Inv PO/Sub Project Customer Requires Joint Check A check box that indicates (if selected) that the joint check is                 required. Joint Vendor The reference number of the joint vendor associated with the compliance                 document. If specified, current document will be displayed on the  Compliance                  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP303000|AP303000]) Vendors form of the selected vendor. Joint Amount The amount to be paid to joint payees according to the joint check. Joint Release A check box that indicates (if selected) that the joint release is                 received. AP Payment Method The payment method associated with the vendor. AR Payment Method The customer’s default payment method. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="07191998-206b-4e00-9a53-6ff05f5e1419" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="9a26a9d8-2912-b4fa-8c76-006f9b98a665" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
Multiple UI elements are added to the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CR_30_40_00|Opportunities] ([~/?ScreenId=CR304000|CR304000]) form to support the multiple quotes functionality provided with application of the Construction package.{br}

This topic provides reference information for the UI elements added to the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CR_30_40_00|Opportunities] form.
==Summary Area==
The following elements were added to the Summary area of the form.[anchor|#_48707ed2-2288-44e9-a4bb-bae1aaf6c7ad]
{| class="checklist" | width="100%" 
|- 
!width="20%" ! Element
!width="80%" ! Description
|- 
| '''Cost'''
| The estimated cost of the deal with the opportunity.
|- 
| '''Gross Margin'''
| The gross margin of the opportunity.
|- 
| '''Gross Margin, %'''
| The gross margin of the opportunity expressed as a percentage.
|- 
| '''Multiple Accounts'''
| A check box that indicates (if selected) that actions on the '''Multiple Quotes''' tab are enabled for working with multiple quotes.
|}
==Multiple Quotes Tab==
This tab provides the list of quotes associated with the created opportunity. It allows subcontractors to enter cost/amount information on its quotations to multiple General Contractors bidding on the same opportunity.[anchor|#_d5cbca08-8298-4b7e-b5ef-fa0a374f8e3f]
===Table===The table toolbar includes only standard buttons. For the list of standard buttons, see [HelpRoot_Interface\Details_Toolbar|Table Toolbar].
{| class="checklist" | width="100%" 
|- 
!width="20%" ! Column
!width="80%" ! Description
|- 
| '''Business Account'''
| The business account of the prospective customer.
|- 
| '''Contact'''
| The representative to be contacted about the quote.
|- 
| '''Quoted Amount'''
| The estimated amount of the deal with the quote.
|- 
| '''Cost Estimate'''
| The cost estimate of the quote.
|- 
| '''Gross Margin'''
| The gross margin of the quote. It is calculated automatically as &ldquo;Quoted Amount – Cost Estimate&ldquo;.
|- 
| '''Gross Margin, %'''
| The gross margin of the quote expressed as a percentage.
|- 
| '''Quoted On'''
| The date when the quote was added.
|- 
| '''Selected'''
| A check box that indicates (if selected) that the information of the selected quote is displayed in the Summary area of the form.
|- 
| '''Final Amount'''
| The estimated amount of the deal with the opportunity. It should be automatically prefilled with the value entered to ''Quoted Amount'' field. The value can be changed manually.
|- 
| '''Final Gross Margin'''
| The final gross margin of the quote. It is calculated automatically as &ldquo;Final Amount - Cost&ldquo;.
|- 
| '''Final Gross Margin, %'''
| The final gross margin of the quote expressed as a percentage.
|}
==Related Articles==
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\CR_30_40_00|Opportunities] ([~/?ScreenId=CR304000|CR304000])]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Multiple Accounts Tab Multiple UI elements are added to the   ([~/?ScreenId=CR304000|CR304000]) Opportunities (CR304000) form to         support the multiple quotes functionality provided with application of the Construction         package. This topic provides reference information for the UI elements added to the   ([~/?ScreenId=CR304000|CR304000]) Opportunities form. Summary Area The following elements were added to the Summary area of the form. Element Description Cost The estimated cost of the deal with the opportunity. Gross Margin The gross margin of the opportunity. Gross Margin, % The gross margin of the opportunity expressed as a percentage. Multiple Accounts A check box that indicates (if selected) that actions on the  Multiple                   Quotes  tab are enabled for working with multiple quotes. Multiple Quotes Tab This tab provides the list of quotes associated with the created opportunity. It allows         subcontractors to enter cost/amount information on its quotations to multiple General         Contractors bidding on the same opportunity. Table The table toolbar includes only standard buttons. For the list of standard buttons,           see  Table Toolbar. Column Description Business Account The business account of the prospective customer. Contact The representative to be contacted about the quote. Quoted Amount The estimated amount of the deal with the quote. Cost Estimate The cost estimate of the quote. Gross Margin The gross margin of the quote. It is calculated automatically as "Quoted Amount                 – Cost Estimate". Gross Margin, % The gross margin of the quote expressed as a percentage. Quoted On The date when the quote was added. Selected A check box that indicates (if selected) that the information of the selected                 quote is displayed in the Summary area of the form. Final Amount The estimated amount of the deal with the opportunity. It should be                 automatically prefilled with the value entered to  Quoted Amount  field. The                 value can be changed manually. Final Gross Margin The final gross margin of the quote. It is calculated automatically as "Final                 Amount - Cost". Final Gross Margin, % The final gross margin of the quote expressed as a percentage.  ([~/?ScreenId=CR304000|CR304000]) ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="a3319101-e962-430f-b685-5316a8c6a8a4" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="89ac1d41-857a-b05c-15ec-d298b4e01e60" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
The ''Type'' attribute is added to the project task entity to support the functionality provided with application of the Construction package. Adding the attribute affected the following Acumatica ERP forms. {br}{TOC}
==Projects==
Form ID:  ([~/?ScreenId=PM301000|PM301000])[anchor|#_1b6a1eb5-5fab-4a1f-a4f2-602a42cc3cdc]
===Tasks Tab===The following column was added to the table.
{| class="checklist" | width="100%" 
|- 
!width="20%" ! Column
!width="80%" ! Description
|- 
| '''Type'''
| The type of the project task. The following types are available:[anchor|#_3dfb25b1-72b6-44e8-a709-3a3d3604a0d5]
*Cost Task
*Revenue Task
*Cost and Revenue Task

|}
==Project Tasks==
Form ID:  ([~/?ScreenId=PM302000|PM302000])[anchor|#_2b22ce33-40e9-4673-8ba0-70f51ce8d7a1]
===Summary Area===The following element was added to the area.
{| class="checklist" | width="100%" 
|- 
!width="20%" ! Element
!width="80%" ! Description
|- 
| '''Type'''
| The type of the project task. The following types are available:[anchor|#_5d2795e8-8571-44dd-9c7b-c39e0e7e9c8e]
*Cost Task
*Revenue Task
*Cost and Revenue Task

|}
==Project Templates==
Form ID:  ([~/?ScreenId=PM208000|PM208000])[anchor|#_fdb22c02-1e11-474e-bc48-f6ed4a1cb580]
===Tasks Tab===The following column was added to the table.
{| class="checklist" | width="100%" 
|- 
!width="20%" ! Column
!width="80%" ! Description
|- 
| '''Type'''
| The type of the project task. The following types are available:[anchor|#_d65fc68c-332b-4ab6-9eeb-a3a107054847]
*Cost Task
*Revenue Task
*Cost and Revenue Task

|}
==Related Articles==
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\PM_30_10_00|Projects] ([~/?ScreenId=PM301000|PM301000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\PM_30_20_00|Project Tasks] ([~/?ScreenId=PM302000|PM302000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\PM_20_80_00|Project Templates] ([~/?ScreenId=PM208000|PM208000])]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Project Task Type Box The  Type  attribute is added to the project task entity to support the functionality         provided with application of the Construction package. Adding the attribute affected the         following  Acumatica ERP forms.  Projects Form ID:  (PM301000)  ([~/?ScreenId=PM301000|PM301000])Tasks Tab The following column was added to the table. Column Description Type The type of the project task. The following types are available: Cost Task Revenue Task Cost and Revenue Task Project Tasks Form ID:  (PM302000)  ([~/?ScreenId=PM302000|PM302000])Summary Area The following element was added to the area. Element Description Type The type of the project task. The following types are available: Cost Task Revenue Task Cost and Revenue Task Project Templates Form ID:  (PM208000)  ([~/?ScreenId=PM208000|PM208000])Tasks Tab The following column was added to the table. Column Description Type The type of the project task. The following types are available: Cost Task Revenue Task Cost and Revenue Task  ([~/?ScreenId=PM301000|PM301000])  ([~/?ScreenId=PM302000|PM302000])  ([~/?ScreenId=PM208000|PM208000]) ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="dc6a00f9-3913-47bb-b28d-105be0e0d20a" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="7eb14db4-fd08-6515-94a9-a741204407c4" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
Form ID:  ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000]){br}

On this form, you can view existing subcontracts, create new subcontracts, and add lines to subcontracts. Once a subcontract has been saved, it can be approved, rejected, or canceled by any employee assigned to review this subcontract.{br}{TOC}
==Form Toolbar==
The form toolbar includes standard and form-specific buttons. For the list of standard buttons, see [HelpRoot_Interface\Form_Toolbar|Form Toolbar]. The form-specific buttons are listed below.[anchor|#_770fc7f2-7392-46c2-ab6f-8b0111afe5c3]
{| class="checklist" | width="100%" 
|- 
!width="20%" ! Button
!width="80%" ! Description
|- 
| '''Approve'''
| Provides the following menu commands, which you can click to invoke actions:[anchor|#_8194715d-09f9-4c5b-b431-a663971e52af]
*'''Approve''': Approves the current subcontract.
*:This action is available if the ''Approval Workflow'' feature is enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features]  ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) form.
*'''Reject''': Rejects the current subcontract. After a subcontract has been rejected, you can change its status to ''On Hold'', correct the subcontract, take it off hold, and save your changes, which subjects the subcontract to approval again.
*:This action is available if the ''Approval Workflow'' feature is enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] form.
*'''Email Subcontract''': Emails (based on the settings of the ''SUBCONTRACT'' mailing) the subcontract to the vendor specified in this subcontract.
*:For more information, see [HelpRoot_Financials\AR__con_Predefined_Mailings_for_Customers_and_Vendors|Mailings for Customers].
*'''Mark as Do Not Email''': Causes the '''Don’t Email''' check box (on the '''Other Information''' tab) to be selected for the subcontract, to skip the step of emailing the subcontract.
*'''Enter AP Bill''': Creates an accounts payable bill based on the current subcontract. This action opens the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_10_00|Bills and Adjustments] ([~/?ScreenId=AP301000|AP301000]) form with a new accounts payable bill that has all the details copied from the subcontract.
*'''Complete Subcontract''': Completes the current subcontract, which changes its status to ''Closed''.
*'''Cancel Subcontract''': Cancels the subcontract, which changes its status to ''Canceled''. A subcontract with this status cannot be edited. You can later manually change its status to ''On Hold'' (by selecting the '''Hold''' check box) and edit the subcontract.
*'''Validate Addresses''': Validates the account addresses through integration with a specialized third-party software or service.
*:This action appears only if the ''Address Validation'' feature is enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] form.
*'''Recalculate Prices''': Opens the [[#_6e0cb5d7-179c-4c12-997d-6341da69c689|Recalculate Prices] dialog box, which you can use to specify the extent to which you want to refresh the prices and discounts for the document.
*'''Create Prepayment''': Creates a prepayment linked to this subcontract. The system opens the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_10_00|Bills and Adjustments] ([~/?ScreenId=AP301000|AP301000]) form with a new prepayment request (based on the subcontract) that is ready to be saved. The prepayment can be used to pay for this subcontract directly when the goods are received.

|- 
| '''Inquiries'''
| Provides the following menu command, which you can click for quick access to the inquiry form:[anchor|#_fa9ece10-bf8b-4dc9-8c3d-1fba052b488a]
*'''Vendor Details''': Opens the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_40_20_00|Vendor Details] ([~/?ScreenId=AP402000|AP402000]) form, which displays the data related to the vendor from which the goods in this subcontract are ordered.

|- 
| '''Reports'''
| Provides the following menu command, which you can click for quick navigation to the report:[anchor|#_77392c9e-c056-4e16-b78f-7830928ec833]
*'''Print Subcontract''': To print the current subcontract by using the [HelpRoot_Construction\SC_64_10_00|Subcontract] ([~/?ScreenId=SC641000|SC641000]) report.

|}[anchor|#_6e0cb5d7-179c-4c12-997d-6341da69c689]
==Recalculate Prices Dialog Box==
You use this dialog box to specify the options to be used for updating the prices (referred to in subcontract as unit costs) and discounts for the subcontract.[anchor|#_dc2cb78f-1213-439f-8fbf-ad08ac4f85df]
{| class="checklist" | width="100%" 
|- 
!width="20%" ! Element
!width="80%" ! Description
|- 
| '''Recalculate'''
| The way prices and discounts are recalculated. You can select one of the following options:[anchor|#_fcc233d8-f124-4448-91d8-c554d930949d]
*''Current Line'': To recalculate prices and discounts for the selected line
*''All Lines'': To recalculate prices and discounts for all lines

|- 
| '''Set Current Unit Prices'''
| A check box that indicates (if selected) that the system must replace the item prices with the current prices in the selected line or all lines.
|- 
| '''Override Manual Prices'''
| A check box that indicates (if selected) that the system must replace the item prices that have been modified manually (in the '''Unit Cost''' or '''Ext. Cost''' column) with the current prices. The check box is available for selection if the '''Set Current Unit Prices''' check box is selected.
|- 
| '''Recalculate Discounts'''
| A check box that indicates (if selected) that the system must recalculate the discounts for the selected line or all lines.
This check box is available only if the ''Customer and Vendor Discounts'' feature is enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features]  ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) form.
|- 
| '''Override Manual Line Discounts'''
| A check box that indicates (if selected) that the system should cancel the manual discounts for the selected line or all lines (depending on the option selected in the '''Recalculate''' box) and search for applicable automatic discounts. This check box is available only if the ''Customer and Vendor Discounts'' feature is enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] form.
|- 
| colspan="2" | This dialog box has the following button.
|- 
| '''OK'''
| Closes the dialog box and applies the selected options to the subcontract.
|}
==Document Summary Area==
In this area, you can enter summary information for a new subcontract. You can also find an existing subcontract by its subcontract number and view (and edit, if needed) its details.[anchor|#_511b07f3-88aa-42e7-9d38-295eefd23a31]
{| class="checklist" | width="100%" 
|- 
!width="20%" ! Element
!width="80%" ! Description
|- 
| '''Subcontract Nbr.'''
| The unique reference number of the subcontract, which the system assigns based on the numbering sequence assigned to subcontracts, as specified on the [HelpRoot_Construction\SC_10_10_00|Subcontracts Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=SC101000|SC101000]) form.
|- 
| '''Hold'''
| A check box that you select to give the subcontract the ''On Hold'' status. You can clear the check box to change the status of the subcontract to ''Open''.
|- 
| '''Status'''
| The system-generated status of the subcontract, which is one of the following options:[anchor|#_97a1a987-8335-456e-8fd8-1941f6b4ca1d]
*''On Hold'': The subcontract is a draft and can be edited manually.
*''Open'': The subcontract has been processed in accordance with the settings on the [HelpRoot_Construction\SC_10_10_00|Subcontracts Preferences] form but has not been completed yet.
*''Pending Approval'': The subcontract has not been approved by all the assigned persons, and this approval is required. The subcontract’s assignment for approval is performed according to the approval map selected for subcontracts on the [HelpRoot_Construction\SC_10_10_00|Subcontracts Preferences] form.
*:This status is available only if the ''Approval Workflow'' feature is enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features]  ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) form and an approval map has been specified in the '''Approval Map''' box of the [HelpRoot_Construction\SC_10_10_00|Subcontracts Preferences] form.
*''Rejected'': The subcontract was rejected by one of the persons assigned to approve it.
*:This status is available only if the ''Approval Workflow'' feature is enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] form and an approval map has been specified in the '''Approval Map''' box of the [HelpRoot_Construction\SC_10_10_00|Subcontracts Preferences] form.
*''Pending Printing'': Printing is required for the document but has not been performed yet. The subcontract should be printed if the '''Print Orders''' check box (on the '''Purchase Settings''' tab) is selected for the vendor on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_30_00|Vendors] ([~/?ScreenId=AP303000|AP303000]) form.
*''Pending Email'': Emailing is required for this document, but it has not been performed yet. The subcontract should be emailed if the '''Send Orders by Email''' check box (on the '''Purchase Settings''' tab) is selected for the vendor on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_30_00|Vendors] form.
*''Closed'': All the ordered services have been received.
*''Canceled'': The subcontract was canceled through the '''Cancel Subcontract''' action (on the '''Actions''' menu of the form toolbar). A subcontract with this status cannot be edited.

|- 
| '''Approved'''
| A check box that indicates (if selected) that the subcontract has been approved. This element is available only if the ''Approval Workflow'' feature is enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] form.
|- 
| '''Date'''
| The date when the subcontract was created. All transactions included in this document will have this date.
|- 
| '''Start Date'''
| The date when the vendor has promised that the items listed in the subcontract will be received at their destination location.
|- 
| '''Description'''
| A brief description of the subcontract.
|- 
| '''Vendor'''
| The vendor from which the items will be purchased, by its ID.
|- 
| '''Owner'''
| The user name of the employee who is responsible for the subcontract.
|- 
| '''Currency'''
| The currency the subcontract will be paid in.
|- 
| '''Vendor Ref.'''
| The reference number of the vendor document related to this subcontract. This element is required if the '''Require Vendor Reference''' check box is selected on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_10_10_00|Accounts Payable Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=AP101000|AP101000]) form.
|- 
| '''Line Total'''
| The total sum of the '''Extended Amount''' entries for all lines in the current subcontract. This value is calculated by the system, and you cannot manually change it.
|- 
| '''Discount Total'''
| The discount total calculated for the document. This total includes discounts of the ''Group'' and ''Document'' levels. The discounts of the ''Group'' and ''Document'' levels are listed on the '''Discount Details'''tab; the ''Line'' discounts are shown on the '''Document Details''' tab. This box is available only if the ''Customer & Vendor Discounts'' feature is enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] form.
|- 
| '''VAT Exempt Total'''
| The document total that is exempt from VAT. This total is calculated as the taxable amount for the tax with the '''Include in VAT Exempt Total''' check box selected on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\TX_20_50_00|Taxes] ([~/?ScreenId=TX205000|TX205000]) form. This box is available only if the ''VAT Reporting'' feature is enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] form.
|- 
| '''VAT Taxable Total'''
| 
The document total that is subject to VAT. The VAT taxable amount is displayed in this box only if the '''Include in VAT Taxable Total''' check box is selected for the applicable tax on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\TX_20_50_00|Taxes] ([~/?ScreenId=TX205000|TX205000]) form. If the check box is cleared, this box is empty.((({S:Warn}If the document contains multiple transactions with different taxes applied and each of the applied taxes has this check box selected, the taxable amount calculated for each line of the document is added to the '''VAT Taxable Total''' box of the document.
)))
This box is available only if the ''VAT Reporting'' feature is enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] form.
|- 
| '''Tax Total'''
| The total tax amount for all lines added to the current subcontract. This value, also calculated by the system, is the sum of the tax amounts for each line.
|- 
| '''Subcontract Total'''
| The total sum for the subcontract, including taxes. This read-only value is the sum of the '''Line Total''' and '''Tax Total''' values.
|- 
| '''Control Total'''
| The subcontract’s total amount (including taxes), which you must enter manually when you attempt to save the subcontract with the ''Open'' status. This value must be the same as the '''Subcontract Total''' value, which the system has calculated automatically. This box appears only if the '''Validate Total on Entry''' check box is selected on the [HelpRoot_Construction\SC_10_10_00|Subcontracts Preferences] form.
|}
==Document Details Tab==
The '''Document Details''' tab has a table with detailed information about the non-stock items to be purchased according to the subcontract.{br}

The table toolbar includes standard buttons and buttons specific to this table. For the list of standard buttons, see [HelpRoot_Interface\Details_Toolbar|Table Toolbar]. The table-specific buttons are listed below.[anchor|#_7690dd34-699e-4367-a155-ab1432de2ee5]
===Shortcut Menu===If you right-click within the rows of a table, the system opens a shortcut menu. Most of the commands you see in the menu are duplicates of actions on the table toolbar. The unique menu commands are listed below.
{| class="checklist" | width="100%" 
|- 
!width="20%" ! Button
!width="80%" ! Description
|- 
| '''Insert Row'''
| Inserts a blank row above the row that is currently selected in the table.
|- 
| '''Cut Row'''
| Copies the selected row or rows to the clipboard.
|- 
| '''Insert Cut Row'''
| Inserts the row or rows that have been copied to the clipboard above the currently selected row or rows.
|}[anchor|#_5ba0c0e3-6e81-4b2d-8538-ff94f058c82f]
===Table Columns===
{| class="checklist" | width="100%" 
|- 
!width="20%" ! Column
!width="80%" ! Description
|- 
| '''Branch'''
| The branch to receive the item.
|- 
| '''Inventory ID'''
| The identifier of the stock or non-stock item, which has been configured on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\IN_20_25_00|Stock Items] ([~/?ScreenId=IN202500|IN202500]) or [HelpRoot_FormReference\IN_20_20_00|Non-Stock Items] ([~/?ScreenId=IN202000|IN202000]) form, respectively. You can select any inventory item if the '''Allow Adding New Items to Subcontracts On the Fly''' check box is selected in the settings of the related project on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PM_30_10_00|Projects] ([~/?ScreenId=PM301000|PM301000]) form; if the check box is cleared, you can select only inventory items that are presented in the cost budget of the related project.
You can also enter the alternate ID in this box; if you do, the system will search for the corresponding non-stock item and replace the alternate ID you entered with the corresponding ID.
|- 
| '''Project'''
| The project with which this subcontract line is associated.
|- 
| '''Project Task'''
| The project task with which this subcontract is associated.
|- 
| '''Cost Code'''
| The cost code with which this subcontract is associated.
|- 
| '''Line Description'''
| A description of the subcontract line, which is copied from the item’s description.
|- 
| '''UOM'''
| The unit of measure (UOM) in which the quantity of the item is specified. If the value in the '''Qty. on Receipts''' column is greater than zero, you cannot change the UOM for this line.
|- 
| '''Order Qty.'''
| The quantity of the item that has been ordered, expressed in the unit of measure specified in the '''UOM''' column.
|- 
| '''Unit Cost'''
| The cost per UOM of the non-stock item. If you enter the unit cost (vendor price) manually and save the document, this value will not be updated by the system when you change the document date. If you want to replace this value with the vendor price currently available for the item, use the '''Recalculate Prices''' action.
|- 
| '''Ext. Cost'''
| The extended cost of the non-stock item, which is the unit cost multiplied by the quantity. If you enter the extended cost manually and save the document, the value will not be updated by the system when you change the document date. If you want the extended cost to be recalculated automatically based on the applicable vendor price, use the '''Recalculate Prices''' action.
|- 
| '''Discount Percent'''
| If the ''Vendor and Customer Discounts'' feature is not enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features]  ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) form, the percent of the discount that has been entered manually or calculated based on the discount amount entered manually for this line item. If the ''Vendor and Customer Discounts'' feature is enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] form, the percent of the line-level discount that has been applied manually or automatically. If the '''Manual Discount''' check box is selected, you can enter the percent manually and the discount amount will be calculated automatically.
|- 
| '''Discount Amount'''
| If the ''Vendor and Customer Discounts'' feature is not enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] form, the amount of the discount that has been specified manually or calculated based on the discount percent entered manually. If the ''Vendor and Customer Discounts'' feature is enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] form, the amount of the line-level discount that has been applied manually or automatically to this line. If the '''Manual Discount''' check box is selected, you can enter the discount amount manually and the discount percent will be calculated automatically.
|- 
| '''Manual Discount'''
| A check box that indicates (if selected) that the discount has been applied manually. With this check box selected, you can enter either the discount percent or the discount amount, or you can select the discount code of one of the discounts intended for manual application.
|- 
| '''Discount Code'''
| The code of the line discount that has been applied to this line automatically. This column appears only if the '''Customer and Vendor Discounts''' feature is enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] form.
|- 
| '''Discount Sequence'''
| The identifier of a discount sequence that has been applied to this line. The column is hidden by default and available only if the ''Customer & Vendor Discounts'' feature is enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] form.
|- 
| '''Amount'''
| The amount calculated (after the discount has been taken) for the item.
|- 
| '''Alternate ID'''
| The alternate ID used for this inventory item-subitem pair by the vendor. For more information on using alternate IDs, see [HelpRoot_InvMgmt\IN__con_Item_Cross-References|Item Cross-References].
|- 
| '''Tax Category'''
| The tax category assigned to the ordered non-stock item.
|- 
| '''Account'''
| The expense account used to record the purchased non-stock item that does not require receipt (by default, the account specified for the item in the '''Use COGS /Expense Account From''' box on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\IN_20_60_00|Posting Classes] ([~/?ScreenId=IN206000|IN206000]) form). If needed, you can select the account manually.
|- 
| '''Description'''
| The description of the account used.
|- 
| '''Sub.'''
| The subaccount used to record the purchased non-stock item that does not require receipt (by default, the subaccount generated in accordance with the rule defined in the '''Combine COGS / Expense Sub. From''' box on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\IN_20_60_00|Posting Classes] form).
|- 
| '''Base Order Qty.'''
| The quantity of the non-stock item ordered, expressed in the base unit of measure. This quantity is used for calculating discounts if the ''Base UOM'' option is selected in the '''Apply Quantity Discounts To''' box on the '''Price/Discount Settings''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_10_10_00|Accounts Payable Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=AP101000|AP101000]) form.
|- 
| '''Line Nbr.'''
| The number of the document line. The system regenerates this number automatically when you add lines to the table.
|- 
| '''Line Order'''
| The order number of the document line. The system regenerates this number automatically when you reorder the lines in the table.
|- 
| '''Requested'''
| The date when the non-stock item was requested.
|- 
| '''Completed'''
| A check box that indicates (if selected) that the purchasing of the non-stock item requested by this line of the subcontract has been completed.
|- 
| '''Canceled'''
| A check box that indicates (if selected) that this line of the subcontract has been canceled.
|- 
| '''Manual Cost'''
| A check box that indicates (if selected) that the amount has been applied manually.
|- 
| '''Received Amt.'''
| The amount received by the subcontract line.
|- 
| '''Received Qty.'''
| The quantity received by the subcontract line.
|}
==Tax Details Tab==
The '''Tax Details''' tab has a table that holds information related to the taxes to be paid on the purchase of the ordered non-stock items.{br}

The table toolbar includes only standard buttons. For the list of standard buttons, see [HelpRoot_Interface\Details_Toolbar|Table Toolbar].[anchor|#_53326f9c-a62f-4a96-a496-96e3027f8ded]
{| class="checklist" | width="100%" 
|- 
!width="20%" ! Column
!width="80%" ! Description
|- 
| '''Tax ID'''
| The identifier of the specific tax applied to the current subcontract.
|- 
| '''Tax Rate'''
| The tax rate used for the tax.
|- 
| '''Taxable Amount'''
| The taxable amount for this document.
|- 
| '''Tax Amount'''
| The tax amount for this tax and this document.
|}
==Vendor Info Tab==
The '''Vendor Info''' tab contains detailed information about the vendor to supply the ordered non-stock items.[anchor|#_df601fdb-ed76-45bb-a1aa-8a4c4b1d78dc]
===Vendor Contact Section===In this section, you provide the vendor’s contact information.
{| class="checklist" | width="100%" 
|- 
!width="20%" ! Element
!width="80%" ! Description
|- 
| '''Override'''
| A check box that you select to override (edit) the default contact settings for the vendor.
|- 
| '''Business Name'''
| The business name of the vendor contact for matters related to this purchase order.
|- 
| '''Attention'''
| The attention line as it is used in your company’s business letters, which would be used to direct the letter to the proper person if the letter is not addressed to any specific person. The box may contain something like ''Purchase Orders Department'' or ''To whom it may concern''.
|- 
| '''Phone 1'''
| The main phone number of the vendor contact for matters related to this subcontract.
|- 
| '''Email'''
| The email address of the vendor contact for matters related to this subcontract.
|}[anchor|#_86b031b0-9029-4fa0-b6b1-d942575ca770]
===Vendor Address Section===In this section, you provide the vendor’s address information.
{| class="checklist" | width="100%" 
|- 
!width="20%" ! Element
!width="80%" ! Description
|- 
| '''Override'''
| A check box that you select to override (that is, to edit) the default shipping address for the vendor.
|- 
| '''Validated'''
| A check box that indicates (if selected) that the address has been validated with a third-party specialized software or service. This element appears only if the '''Address Validation''' feature is enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features]  ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) form.
|- 
| '''Address Line 1'''
| The first line of the vendor’s contact address.
|- 
| '''Address Line 2'''
| The second line of the vendor’s contact address.
|- 
| '''City'''
| The city of the vendor’s contact address.
|- 
| '''Country'''
| The country of the vendor’s contact address.
|- 
| '''State'''
| The state of the vendor’s contact address.
|- 
| '''Postal Code'''
| The postal code of the vendor’s contact address.
|}[anchor|#_f8f32831-c8be-42ba-a1b2-0c763ecf80b0]
===Info Section===In this section, you can specify credit terms and tax zone for the subcontract.
{| class="checklist" | width="100%" 
|- 
!width="20%" ! Element
!width="80%" ! Description
|- 
| '''Terms'''
| 
The specific credit terms to be used for the subcontract.((({S:Warn}If the ''Vendor Relations'' feature is enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features]  ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) form, the system uses the credit terms of the vendor selected in the '''Pay-to Vendor''' box.
)))
|- 
| '''Vendor Tax Zone'''
| The tax zone of the vendor’s location.
|- 
| '''Pay-to Vendor'''
| The vendor that the system should use by default in the Accounts Payable bills or debit adjustments created based on this subcontract. If vendor relations are set up for the vendor selected in the '''Vendor''' box of the Summary area of the current form, the system inserts into this box the pay-to vendor specified for the selected vendor in the '''Pay-to Vendor''' box on the '''Payment Settings''' tab on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_30_00|Vendors] ([~/?ScreenId=AP303000|AP303000]) form). If vendor relations are not set up, the system inserts into this box the vendor currently selected in the '''Vendor''' box of this subcontract. You can overwrite the vendor in this box, if needed. This box is available only if the ''Vendor Relations'' feature is enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features] form.
|}
==Approval Details Tab==
This tab provides detailed information about approvals of this subcontract. The approval map for subcontract is also specified on the '''Approval''' tab of the [HelpRoot_Construction\SC_10_10_00|Subcontracts Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=SC101000|SC101000]) form. The system automatically assigns subcontracts for approval when they are released. The rules used for assignment are defined on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_55_00|Assignment and Approval Maps] ([~/?ScreenId=EP205500|EP205500]) form.{br}

This tab is available if the ''Approval Workflow'' feature is enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features]  ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) form and if the '''Require Approval''' check box is selected on the [HelpRoot_Construction\SC_10_10_00|Subcontracts Preferences] form.{br}

The table toolbar includes only standard buttons. For the list of standard buttons, see [HelpRoot_Interface\Details_Toolbar|Table Toolbar].[anchor|#_ff0921ba-f3e2-41ba-b247-29279ae50f16]
{| class="checklist" | width="100%" 
|- 
!width="20%" ! Column
!width="80%" ! Description
|- 
| '''Approver'''
| The employee ID of the person assigned to approve the subcontract.
|- 
| '''Approver Name'''
| The name of the employee assigned to approve the subcontract.
|- 
| '''Approved By'''
| The employee ID of the person who actually approved this subcontract.
|- 
| '''Approved By Name'''
| The name of the employee who actually approved the subcontract.
|- 
| '''Date'''
| The date of approval.
|- 
| '''Status'''
| The status of the subcontract, which is ''Pending Approval'', ''Approved'', or ''Rejected'', depending on the approval action performed.
|- 
| '''Workgroup'''
| The workgroup of the employee assigned to approve the subcontract.
|}
==Discount Details Tab==
The '''Discount Details''' tab has a table that shows the details of the vendor discounts that have been applied to the document.{br}

This tab is available only if the ''Customer and Vendor Discounts'' feature is enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features]  ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) form.{br}

The table toolbar includes only standard buttons. For the list of standard buttons, see [HelpRoot_Interface\Details_Toolbar|Table Toolbar].[anchor|#_1d34bd17-a7b4-44e5-8077-0688e6387d45]
{| class="checklist" | width="100%" 
|- 
!width="20%" ! Column
!width="80%" ! Description
|- 
| '''Skip Discount'''
| A check box that you select to cancel a ''Group-'' or ''Document''-level discount for the document. Selecting the check box updates the document’s total and the line amounts, but does not remove the record of the canceled discount from this table.
|- 
| '''Discount Code'''
| The discount code of the vendor discount applied to the document automatically or manually.
|- 
| '''Sequence ID'''
| The identifier of the discount sequence applied to the document.
|- 
| '''Type'''
| The type of discount applied to the document (''Group'' or ''Document'').
|- 
| '''Manual Discount'''
| A check box that indicates (if selected) that the vendor discount shown in this row has been applied manually from the ''Group-'' or ''Document''-level discounts marked as ''Manual'' on the Vendor [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_20_40_00|Vendor Discount Codes] ([~/?ScreenId=AP204000|AP204000]) form.
|- 
| '''Discountable Amt.'''
| The amount used as a base for discount calculation if the discount is defined as based on the amount.
|- 
| '''Discountable Qty.'''
| The quantity used as a base for discount calculation if the discount is defined as based on the item quantity.
|- 
| '''Discount Amt.'''
| The amount of the discount.
|- 
| '''Discount Percent'''
| The discount percent if by definition the discount is calculated as a percentage.
|- 
| '''Free Item'''
| The inventory ID of the free non-stock item, if one is specified by the discount applied to the document.
|- 
| '''Free Item Qty.'''
| The quantity of the free non-stock item.
|}
==Other Information Tab==
The '''Other Information''' tab contains other information related to the subcontract, such as the branch ordering the services, the workgroup, and the reference numbers of the related documents (requisition document and prepayment).[anchor|#_185386ab-87f9-4fcd-bf72-a3b43d7cda29]
{| class="checklist" | width="100%" 
|- 
!width="20%" ! Element
!width="80%" ! Description
|- 
| '''Requisition Ref. Nbr.'''
| The reference number of the requisition document associated with the subcontract, if any. To create the requisition documents, use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\RQ_30_20_00|Requisitions] ([~/?ScreenId=RQ302000|RQ302000]) form. This box is available only if the '''Purchase Requisitions''' feature is enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features]  ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) form.
|- 
| '''Prepayment Ref. Nbr.'''
| The reference number of the prepayment request linked to this subcontract, if any.
|- 
| '''Workgroup ID'''
| The workgroup to which the subcontract was assigned for processing.
|- 
| '''Don’t Print'''
| A check box that indicates (if selected) that the current subcontract should not be printed.
|- 
| '''Printed'''
| A check box that indicates (if selected) that the current subcontract has been printed. To print the subcontract, select '''Print Subcontract''' on the '''Reports''' menu; this causes the system to automatically select the check box.
|- 
| '''Don’t Email'''
| A check box that indicates (if selected) that the subcontract should not be emailed.
|- 
| '''Emailed'''
| A check box that indicates (if selected) indicates that the current subcontract was emailed. To email a subcontract, select '''Email Subcontract''' on the '''Actions''' menu; this causes the system to automatically select the check box.
|- 
| '''Open Quantity'''
| The total value of '''Base Order Qty.''' column of all subcontract lines.
|- 
| '''Open Balance'''
| The total value of '''Amount''' column of all subcontract lines.
|}
==Attributes Tab==
The '''Attributes''' tab contains the list of attributes related to the subcontract, such as brand, lead age, gender, and industry.{br}

The table toolbar includes only standard buttons. For the list of standard buttons, see [HelpRoot_Interface\Details_Toolbar|Table Toolbar].[anchor|#_83652b12-af9d-4443-9359-9cd97b0051e5]
{| class="checklist" | width="100%" 
|- 
!width="20%" ! Column
!width="80%" ! Description
|- 
| '''Attribute'''
| The description of the attribute assigned to the subcontract.
|- 
| '''Required'''
| A check box that indicates (if selected) that the attribute is mandatory.
|- 
| '''Value'''
| The value of the attribute assigned to the subcontract.
|}
==Compliance Tab==
The '''Compliance''' tab contains the list of compliance documents assigned to the subcontract. You can add and update compliance documents within this tab. The table has the columns listed below.{br}

The table toolbar includes only standard buttons. For the list of standard buttons, see [HelpRoot_Interface\Details_Toolbar|Table Toolbar].[anchor|#_4f869e30-4ca7-447c-ad22-8d001f7259f6]
===Table Columns===
{| class="checklist" | width="100%" 
|- 
!width="20%" ! 
!width="80%" ! 
|- 
| '''Document Type'''
| 
The type of the compliance document. The following document types are available:[anchor|#_b3b2e3fb-cc65-426c-b9c0-aad35ca9cbc2]
*''Certificate''
* ''Insurance''
* ''Notice''
* ''Lien Waiver''
* ''Other''

|- 
|  '''Creation Date'''
| The date when the compliance document was created. By default, the current date is set. The user is able to change the date manually.
|- 
| '''Document Type Option'''
| The document type option of the compliance’s document type. The list of document type options should be set manually on the [HelpRoot_Construction\CL_30_10_00|'''Compliance Preferences'''] ([~/?ScreenId=CL301000|CL301000]) form.
|- 
| '''Status'''
| The status of the compliance document. The list of values should be set manually on the [HelpRoot_Construction\CL_30_10_00|'''Compliance Preferences'''] form.
|- 
| '''Is Required'''
| A check box that indicates (if selected) that the document is mandatory for working with a specific project or project task. This flag is for informational purposes only. It shows that the compliance document is required before implementing some activities on a project.
|- 
| '''Received'''
| A check box that indicates (if selected) that the document is received by user. The ''Received'' check box allows the user to track when the payment for document is received, so the next payment is not delayed.
|- 
| '''Received Date'''
| The date when the compliance document is received. The date should be set manually by the user on the '''Compliance''' tab after the document is received.
|- 
| '''Sent Date'''
| The date when the compliance document is sent. The date should be set manually by the user on the '''Compliance''' tab after the document is sent.
|- 
| '''Effective Date'''
| The date when the compliance document takes effect. The date should be set manually by the user while adding the document on the '''Compliance''' tab.
|- 
| '''Expiration Date'''
| The date when the compliance document will expire. The date should be set manually by the user while adding the document on the '''Compliance''' tab.
|- 
| '''Limit'''
| The amount of insurance liability set for the compliance document. The amount should be set manually by the user while adding the document on the '''Compliance''' tab.
|- 
| '''Method Sent'''
| The method of sending the document.
|- 
| '''Project'''
| The reference to a project to which a compliance document relates. By default, it is set to the identifier of the project selected in the Summary area of the form. If specified, current document will be displayed on the '''Compliance''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PM_30_10_00|Projects] ([~/?ScreenId=PM301000|PM301000]) form of the selected project.
|- 
| '''Cost Task'''
| The reference to a cost task available within the project. If specified, current document will be displayed on the '''Compliance''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PM_30_20_00|Project Tasks] ([~/?ScreenId=PM302000|PM302000]) form of the selected task of the ''Cost Task'' type.
|- 
| '''Revenue Task'''
| The reference to a revenue task within the project. If specified, current document will be displayed on the '''Compliance''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PM_30_20_00|Project Tasks] form of the selected task of the ''Revenue Task'' type.
|- 
| '''Cost Code'''
| The cost code assigned to the compliance document.
|- 
| '''Customer'''
| The reference number of the customer associated with the compliance document. By default, it is set to the identifier of the customer selected in the Summary area of the form. If specified, current document will be displayed on the '''Compliance tab''' of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AR_30_30_00|Customers] ([~/?ScreenId=AR303000|AR303000]) form of the selected customer.
|- 
| '''Customer Name'''
| The name of the customer associated with the compliance document.
|- 
| '''Vendor'''
| The reference number of the vendor associated with the compliance document. By default, it is set to the identifier of the vendor selected in the Summary area of the form. If specified, current document will be displayed on the '''Compliance''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_30_00|Vendors] ([~/?ScreenId=AP303000|AP303000]) form of the selected vendor.
|- 
| '''Vendor Name'''
| The name of the vendor associated with the compliance document.
|- 
| '''Secondary Vendor'''
| The reference number of the secondary vendor associated with the compliance document. If specified, current document will be displayed on the '''Compliance''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_30_00|Vendors] form of the selected vendor.
|- 
| '''Secondary Vendor Name'''
| The name of the secondary vendor associated with the compliance document.
|- 
| '''Purchase Order'''
| The unique identifier of the purchase order associated with the compliance document. By default, it is set to the identifier of the purchase order selected in the Summary area of the form. If specified, current document will be displayed on the '''Compliance''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PO_30_10_00|Purchase Orders] ([~/?ScreenId=PO301000|PO301000]) form of the selected purchase order.
|- 
| '''Purchase Order Line Item'''
| The unique identifier of the purchase order line item. It can be specified only after a purchase order is selected.
|- 
| '''Subcontract'''
| The unique identifier of the subcontract associated with the compliance document. By default, it is set to the identifier of the subcontract selected in the Summary area of the form. If specified, current document will be displayed on the '''Compliance''' tab of the [HelpRoot_Construction\SC_30_10_00|Subcontracts] ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000]) form of the selected subcontract.
|- 
| '''Subcontract Line Item'''
| The unique identifier of the subcontract line. It can be specified only after a Subcontract is selected.
|- 
| '''Invoice'''
| The reference number of the invoice associated with the compliance document. By default, it is set to the identifier of the invoice selected in the Summary area of the form. If specified, current document will be displayed on the '''Compliance''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AR_30_10_00|Invoices and Memos] ([~/?ScreenId=AR301000|AR301000]) form of the selected invoice.
|- 
| '''Invoice Amount'''
| The amount of the invoice.
|- 
| '''Bill'''
| The reference number of the bill associated with the compliance document. By default, it is set to the identifier of the bill selected in the Summary area of the form. If specified, current document will be displayed on the '''Compliance''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_10_00|Bills and Adjustments] ([~/?ScreenId=AP301000|AP301000]) form of the selected bill.
|- 
| '''Bill Amount'''
| The bill amount to be paid for the document.
|- 
| '''Lien Waiver Amount'''
| The amount covered by the lien waiver.
|- 
| '''Sponsor Organization'''
| The name of the sponsor organization.
|- 
| '''Certificate Number'''
| The number of the certificate.
|- 
| '''Insurance Company'''
| The name of the insurance company.
|- 
| '''Policy'''
| The insurance policy number.
|- 
| '''Account'''
| The account associated with the vendor (Expense account) or customer (Sales account).
|- 
| '''AP Check'''
| The reference number of the check associated with the compliance document.
|- 
| '''AR Payment'''
| The reference number of the payment associated with the compliance document.
|- 
| '''Project Transaction'''
| The reference number of the project transaction associated with the compliance document.
|- 
| '''Payment Date'''
| The date when the check is created.
|- 
| '''Receipt Date'''
| The date when the inventory receipt is made.
|- 
| '''Date Issued'''
| The date when the document is issued.
|- 
| '''Through Date'''
| The date when the goods are shipped.
|- 
| '''Receive Date'''
| The date when the goods are received.
|- 
| '''Received By'''
| The person responsible for receiving goods.
|- 
| '''Source'''
| 
The source of the check. One of the following values is allowed:[anchor|#_9cc8fe31-bc37-463a-9d43-ad3ec8fe4951]
*''AP Inv''
* ''PO/Sub''
* ''Project''
* ''Customer''

|- 
|  '''Requires Joint Check'''
| A check box that indicates (if selected) that the joint check is required.
|- 
| '''Joint Vendor'''
| The reference number of the joint vendor associated with the compliance document. If specified, current document will be displayed on the '''Compliance''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_30_00|Vendors] ([~/?ScreenId=AP303000|AP303000]) form of the selected vendor.
|- 
| '''Joint Amount'''
| The amount to be paid to joint payees according to the joint check.
|- 
| '''Joint Release'''
| A check box that indicates (if selected) that the joint release is received.
|- 
| '''AP Payment Method'''
| The payment method associated with the vendor.
|- 
| '''AR Payment Method'''
| The customer’s default payment method.
|}
==Related Articles==
*[HelpRoot_Construction\SC_10_10_00|Subcontracts Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=SC101000|SC101000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\IN_20_20_00|Non-Stock Items] ([~/?ScreenId=IN202000|IN202000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_30_00|Vendors] ([~/?ScreenId=AP303000|AP303000])]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Subcontracts Form ID:  (SC301000)  ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000])On this form, you can view existing subcontracts, create new subcontracts, and add lines to         subcontracts. Once a subcontract has been saved, it can be approved, rejected, or canceled         by any employee assigned to review this subcontract. Form Toolbar The form toolbar includes standard and form-specific buttons. For the list of standard         buttons, see  Form Toolbar. The form-specific buttons         are listed below. Button Description Approve Provides the following menu commands, which you can click to invoke actions: Approve : Approves the current subcontract. This action is available                       if the  Approval Workflow  feature is enabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features (CS100000) form. Reject : Rejects the current subcontract. After a subcontract has been                     rejected, you can change its status to  On Hold , correct the subcontract,                     take it off hold, and save your changes, which subjects the subcontract to                     approval again. This action is available if the  Approval Workflow                        feature is enabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features form. Email Subcontract : Emails (based on the settings of the                        SUBCONTRACT  mailing) the subcontract to the vendor specified in this                       subcontract. For more information, see  Mailings for Customers. Mark as Do Not Email : Causes the  Don’t Email                      check box (on the  Other Information  tab) to be selected                     for the subcontract, to skip the step of emailing the subcontract. Enter AP Bill : Creates an accounts payable bill based on the current                     subcontract. This action opens the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP301000|AP301000]) Bills and Adjustments (AP301000)                     form with a new accounts payable bill that has all the details copied from the                     subcontract. Complete Subcontract : Completes the current subcontract, which changes                     its status to  Closed . Cancel Subcontract : Cancels the subcontract, which changes its status                     to  Canceled . A subcontract with this status cannot be edited. You can                     later manually change its status to  On Hold  (by selecting the  Hold                      check box) and edit the subcontract. Validate Addresses : Validates the account addresses through integration                     with a specialized third-party software or service. This action appears only                       if the  Address Validation  feature is enabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features form. Recalculate Prices : Opens the  Recalculate Prices Recalculate Prices dialog box, which you can use to specify the extent                     to which you want to refresh the prices and discounts for the document. Create Prepayment : Creates a prepayment linked to this subcontract. The                     system opens the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP301000|AP301000]) Bills and Adjustments (AP301000) form with a new                     prepayment request (based on the subcontract) that is ready to be saved. The                     prepayment can be used to pay for this subcontract directly when the goods are                     received. Inquiries Provides the following menu command, which you can click for quick access to                 the inquiry form: Vendor Details : Opens the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP402000|AP402000]) Vendor Details (AP402000)                     form, which displays the data related to the vendor from which the goods in this                     subcontract are ordered. Reports Provides the following menu command, which you can click for quick navigation                 to the report: Print Subcontract : To print the current subcontract by using the   ([~/?ScreenId=SC641000|SC641000]) Subcontract (SC641000) report. Recalculate Prices Dialog Box You use this dialog box to specify the options to be used for updating the prices (referred         to in subcontract as unit costs) and discounts for the subcontract. Element Description Recalculate The way prices and discounts are recalculated. You can select one of the                 following options: Current Line : To recalculate prices and discounts for the selected                     line All Lines : To recalculate prices and discounts for all lines Set Current Unit Prices A check box that indicates (if selected) that the system must replace the item                 prices with the current prices in the selected line or all lines. Override Manual Prices A check box that indicates (if selected) that the system must replace the item                 prices that have been modified manually (in the  Unit Cost  or  Ext. Cost                  column) with the current prices. The check box is available for selection if the                    Set Current Unit Prices  check box is selected. Recalculate Discounts A check box that indicates (if selected) that the system must recalculate the                 discounts for the selected line or all lines. This check box is available only if                   the  Customer and Vendor Discounts  feature is enabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features (CS100000) form. Override Manual Line Discounts A check box that indicates (if selected) that the system should cancel the                 manual discounts for the selected line or all lines (depending on the option                 selected in the  Recalculate  box) and search for applicable automatic                 discounts. This check box is available only if the  Customer and Vendor                   Discounts  feature is enabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features                 form. This dialog box has the following button. OK Closes the dialog box and applies the selected options to the                 subcontract. Document Summary Area In this area, you can enter summary information for a new subcontract. You can also find an         existing subcontract by its subcontract number and view (and edit, if needed) its         details. Element Description Subcontract Nbr. The unique reference number of the subcontract, which the system assigns based                 on the numbering sequence assigned to subcontracts, as specified on the   ([~/?ScreenId=SC101000|SC101000]) Subcontracts Preferences (SC101000) form. Hold A check box that you select to give the subcontract the  On Hold  status.                 You can clear the check box to change the status of the subcontract to                  Open . Status The system-generated status of the subcontract, which is one of the following                   options: On Hold : The subcontract is a draft and can be edited manually. Open : The subcontract has been processed in accordance with the                     settings on the   ([~/?ScreenId=SC101000|SC101000]) Subcontracts Preferences form but has not been completed                     yet. Pending Approval : The subcontract has not been approved by all the                     assigned persons, and this approval is required. The subcontract’s assignment                     for approval is performed according to the approval map selected for                     subcontracts on the   ([~/?ScreenId=SC101000|SC101000]) Subcontracts Preferences form. This status is                       available only if the  Approval Workflow  feature is enabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features (CS100000) form and an approval map has been                       specified in the  Approval Map  box of the   ([~/?ScreenId=SC101000|SC101000]) Subcontracts Preferences form. Rejected : The subcontract was rejected by one of the persons assigned                     to approve it. This status is available only if the  Approval Workflow                        feature is enabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features form and an approval                       map has been specified in the  Approval Map  box of                         the   ([~/?ScreenId=SC101000|SC101000]) Subcontracts Preferences form. Pending Printing : Printing is required for the document but has not                     been performed yet. The subcontract should be printed if the  Print Orders                      check box (on the  Purchase Settings  tab) is selected for the vendor on                     the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP303000|AP303000]) Vendors (AP303000) form. Pending Email : Emailing is required for this document, but it has not                     been performed yet. The subcontract should be emailed if the  Send Orders by                       Email  check box (on the  Purchase Settings  tab) is selected for the                     vendor on the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP303000|AP303000]) Vendors form. Closed : All the ordered services have been received. Canceled : The subcontract was canceled through the  Cancel                       Subcontract  action (on the  Actions  menu of the form toolbar). A                     subcontract with this status cannot be edited. Approved A check box that indicates (if selected) that the subcontract has been                 approved. This element is available only if the  Approval Workflow  feature is                 enabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features form. Date The date when the subcontract was created. All transactions included in this                 document will have this date. Start Date The date when the vendor has promised that the items listed in the subcontract                 will be received at their destination location. Description A brief description of the subcontract. Vendor The vendor from which the items will be purchased, by its ID. Owner The user name of the employee who is responsible for the subcontract. Currency The currency the subcontract will be paid in. Vendor Ref. The reference number of the vendor document related to this subcontract. This                 element is required if the  Require Vendor Reference  check box is selected on                 the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP101000|AP101000]) Accounts Payable Preferences (AP101000) form. Line Total The total sum of the  Extended Amount  entries for all lines in the                 current subcontract. This value is calculated by the system, and you cannot manually                 change it. Discount Total The discount total calculated for the document. This total includes discounts                 of the  Group  and  Document  levels. The discounts of the  Group                  and  Document  levels are listed on the  Discount Details tab; the                    Line  discounts are shown on the  Document Details  tab. This box is                 available only if the  Customer & Vendor Discounts  feature is enabled on                 the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features form. VAT Exempt Total The document total that is exempt from VAT. This total is calculated as the                 taxable amount for the tax with the  Include in VAT Exempt Total  check box                 selected on the   ([~/?ScreenId=TX205000|TX205000]) Taxes (TX205000) form. This box is                 available only if the  VAT Reporting  feature is enabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features form. VAT Taxable Total The document total that is subject to VAT. The VAT taxable amount is displayed in                   this box only if the  Include in VAT Taxable Total  check box is selected for                   the applicable tax on the   ([~/?ScreenId=TX205000|TX205000]) Taxes (TX205000) form. If the                   check box is cleared, this box is empty. If the document contains multiple transactions with different taxes applied                   and each of the applied taxes has this check box selected, the taxable amount                   calculated for each line of the document is added to the  VAT Taxable Total                    box of the document. This box is available only if the  VAT Reporting  feature is enabled on the                       ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features form. Tax Total The total tax amount for all lines added to the current subcontract. This                 value, also calculated by the system, is the sum of the tax amounts for each                 line. Subcontract Total The total sum for the subcontract, including taxes. This read-only value is the                 sum of the  Line Total  and  Tax Total  values. Control Total The subcontract’s total amount (including taxes), which you must enter manually                 when you attempt to save the subcontract with the  Open  status. This value                 must be the same as the  Subcontract Total  value, which the system has                 calculated automatically. This box appears only if the  Validate Total on                   Entry  check box is selected on the   ([~/?ScreenId=SC101000|SC101000]) Subcontracts Preferences                 form. Document Details Tab The  Document Details  tab has a table with detailed information about the non-stock         items to be purchased according to the subcontract. The table toolbar includes standard buttons and buttons specific to this table. For the         list of standard buttons, see  Table Toolbar. The         table-specific buttons are listed below. Shortcut Menu If you right-click within the rows of a table, the system opens a shortcut menu. Most           of the commands you see in the menu are duplicates of actions on the table toolbar. The           unique menu commands are listed below. Button Description Insert Row Inserts a blank row above the row that is currently selected in the                 table. Cut Row Copies the selected row or rows to the clipboard. Insert Cut Row Inserts the row or rows that have been copied to the clipboard above the                 currently selected row or rows. Table Columns Column Description Branch The branch to receive the item. Inventory ID The identifier of the                  stock or                  non-stock item, which has been configured on the                     ([~/?ScreenId=IN202500|IN202500]) Stock Items (IN202500) or   ([~/?ScreenId=IN202000|IN202000]) Non-Stock Items (IN202000)                 form ,                 respectively .                  You can select any                 inventory item if the  Allow Adding New Items to Subcontracts On the                   Fly  check box is selected in the settings of the related project on                 the   ([~/?ScreenId=PM301000|PM301000]) Projects (PM301000) form; if the check box is cleared,                 you can select only inventory items that are presented in the cost budget of the                 related                   project. You                   can also enter the alternate ID in this box; if you do, the system will search for                   the corresponding non-stock item and replace the alternate ID you entered with the                   corresponding ID. Project The project with which this subcontract line is associated. Project Task The project task with which this subcontract is associated. Cost Code The cost code with which this subcontract is associated. Line Description A description of the subcontract line, which is copied from the item’s                 description. UOM The unit of measure (UOM) in which the quantity of the item is specified. If                 the value in the  Qty. on Receipts  column is greater than zero, you cannot                 change the UOM for this line. Order Qty. The quantity of the item that has been ordered, expressed in the unit of                 measure specified in the  UOM  column. Unit Cost The cost per UOM of the non-stock item. If you enter the unit cost (vendor                 price) manually and save the document, this value will not be updated by the system                 when you change the document date. If you want to replace this value with the vendor                 price currently available for the item, use the  Recalculate Prices                  action. Ext. Cost The extended cost of the non-stock item, which is the unit cost multiplied by                 the quantity. If you enter the extended cost manually and save the document, the                 value will not be updated by the system when you change the document date. If you                 want the extended cost to be recalculated automatically based on the applicable                 vendor price, use the  Recalculate Prices  action. Discount Percent If the  Vendor and Customer Discounts  feature is not enabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features (CS100000) form, the percent of the discount that has                 been entered manually or calculated based on the discount amount entered manually                 for this line item. If the  Vendor and Customer Discounts  feature is enabled                 on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features form, the percent of the line-level discount                 that has been applied manually or automatically. If the  Manual Discount  check                 box is selected, you can enter the percent manually and the discount amount will be                 calculated automatically. Discount Amount If the  Vendor and Customer Discounts  feature is not enabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features form, the amount of the discount that has been specified                 manually or calculated based on the discount percent entered manually. If the                    Vendor and Customer Discounts  feature is enabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features form, the amount of the line-level discount that has                 been applied manually or automatically to this line. If the  Manual Discount                  check box is selected, you can enter the discount amount manually and the discount                 percent will be calculated automatically. Manual Discount A check box that indicates (if selected) that the discount has been applied                 manually. With this check box selected, you can enter either the discount percent or                 the discount amount, or you can select the discount code of one of the discounts                 intended for manual application. Discount Code The code of the line discount that has been applied to this line automatically.                 This column appears only if the  Customer and Vendor Discounts  feature is                 enabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features form. Discount Sequence The identifier of a discount sequence that has been applied to this line. The                 column is hidden by default and available only if the  Customer & Vendor                   Discounts  feature is enabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features                 form. Amount The amount calculated (after the discount has been taken) for the item. Alternate ID The alternate ID used for this inventory item-subitem pair by the vendor. For                 more information on using alternate IDs, see  Item Cross-References. Tax Category The tax category assigned to the ordered non-stock item. Account The expense account used to record the purchased non-stock item that does not                 require receipt (by default, the account specified for the item in the  Use COGS                   /Expense Account From  box on the   ([~/?ScreenId=IN206000|IN206000]) Posting Classes (IN206000)                 form). If needed, you can select the account manually. Description The description of the account used. Sub. The subaccount used to record the purchased non-stock item that does not                 require receipt (by default, the subaccount generated in accordance with the rule                 defined in the  Combine COGS / Expense Sub. From  box on the   ([~/?ScreenId=IN206000|IN206000]) Posting Classes form). Base Order Qty. The quantity of the non-stock item ordered, expressed in the base unit of                 measure. This quantity is used for calculating discounts if the  Base UOM                  option is selected in the  Apply Quantity Discounts To  box on the                    Price/Discount Settings  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP101000|AP101000]) Accounts Payable Preferences                 (AP101000) form. Line Nbr. The number of the document line. The system regenerates this number                 automatically when you add lines to the table. Line Order The order number of the document line. The system regenerates this number                 automatically when you reorder the lines in the table. Requested The date when the non-stock item was requested. Completed A check box that indicates (if selected) that the purchasing of the non-stock                 item requested by this line of the subcontract has been completed. Canceled A check box that indicates (if selected) that this line of the subcontract has                 been canceled. Manual Cost A check box that indicates (if selected) that the amount has been applied                 manually. Received Amt. The amount received by the subcontract line. Received Qty. The quantity received by the subcontract line. Tax Details Tab The  Tax Details  tab has a table that holds information related to the taxes to be         paid on the purchase of the ordered non-stock items. The table toolbar includes only standard buttons. For the list of standard buttons, see            Table Toolbar. Column Description Tax ID The identifier of the specific tax applied to the current subcontract. Tax Rate The tax rate used for the tax. Taxable Amount The taxable amount for this document. Tax Amount The tax amount for this tax and this document. Vendor Info Tab The  Vendor Info  tab contains detailed information about the vendor to supply the         ordered non-stock items. Vendor Contact Section In this section, you provide the vendor’s contact information. Element Description Override A check box that you select to override (edit) the default contact settings for                 the vendor. Business Name The business name of the vendor contact for matters related to this purchase                 order. Attention The attention line as it is used in your company’s business letters, which                 would be used to direct the letter to the proper person if the letter is not                 addressed to any specific person. The box may contain something like  Purchase                   Orders Department  or  To whom it may concern . Phone 1 The main phone number of the vendor contact for matters related to this                 subcontract. Email The email address of the vendor contact for matters related to this                 subcontract. Vendor Address Section In this section, you provide the vendor’s address information. Element Description Override A check box that you select to override (that is, to edit) the default shipping                 address for the vendor. Validated A check box that indicates (if selected) that the address has been validated                 with a third-party specialized software or service. This element appears only if the                    Address Validation  feature is enabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features (CS100000) form. Address Line 1 The first line of the vendor’s contact address. Address Line 2 The second line of the vendor’s contact address. City The city of the vendor’s contact address. Country The country of the vendor’s contact address. State The state of the vendor’s contact address. Postal Code The postal code of the vendor’s contact address. Info Section In this section, you can specify credit terms and tax zone for the subcontract. Element Description Terms The specific credit terms to be used for the subcontract. If the  Vendor Relations  feature is enabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features (CS100000) form, the system uses the credit terms of                   the vendor selected in the  Pay-to Vendor  box. Vendor Tax Zone The tax zone of the vendor’s location. Pay-to Vendor The vendor that the system should use by default in the Accounts Payable bills                 or debit adjustments created based on this subcontract. If vendor relations are set                 up for the vendor selected in the  Vendor  box of the Summary area of the                 current form, the system inserts into this box the pay-to vendor specified for the                 selected vendor in the  Pay-to Vendor  box on the  Payment Settings  tab                 on the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP303000|AP303000]) Vendors (AP303000) form). If vendor relations are not                 set up, the system inserts into this box the vendor currently selected in the                    Vendor  box of this subcontract. You can overwrite the vendor in this box,                 if needed. This box is available only if the  Vendor Relations  feature is                 enabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features form. Approval Details Tab This tab provides detailed information about approvals of this subcontract. The approval         map for subcontract is also specified on the  Approval  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=SC101000|SC101000]) Subcontracts Preferences (SC101000) form. The system automatically assigns subcontracts         for approval when they are released. The rules used for assignment are defined on the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP205500|EP205500]) Assignment and Approval Maps (EP205500) form. This tab is available if the  Approval Workflow  feature is enabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features (CS100000) form and if the  Require Approval  check box is         selected on the   ([~/?ScreenId=SC101000|SC101000]) Subcontracts Preferences form. The table toolbar includes only standard buttons. For the list of standard buttons, see            Table Toolbar. Column Description Approver The employee ID of the person assigned to approve the subcontract. Approver Name The name of the employee assigned to approve the subcontract. Approved By The employee ID of the person who actually approved this subcontract. Approved By Name The name of the employee who actually approved the subcontract. Date The date of approval. Status The status of the subcontract, which is  Pending Approval ,                    Approved , or  Rejected , depending on the approval action                 performed. Workgroup The workgroup of the employee assigned to approve the subcontract. Discount Details Tab The  Discount Details  tab has a table that shows the details of the vendor discounts         that have been applied to the document. This tab is available only if the  Customer and Vendor Discounts  feature is enabled         on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features (CS100000) form. The table toolbar includes only standard buttons. For the list of standard buttons, see            Table Toolbar. Column Description Skip Discount A check box that you select to cancel a  Group-  or  Document -level                 discount for the document. Selecting the check box updates the document’s total and                 the line amounts, but does not remove the record of the canceled discount from this                 table. Discount Code The discount code of the vendor discount applied to the document automatically                 or manually. Sequence ID The identifier of the discount sequence applied to the document. Type The type of discount applied to the document ( Group  or                  Document ). Manual Discount A check box that indicates (if selected) that the vendor discount shown in this                 row has been applied manually from the  Group-  or  Document -level                 discounts marked as  Manual  on the Vendor   ([~/?ScreenId=AP204000|AP204000]) Vendor Discount Codes                 (AP204000) form. Discountable Amt. The amount used as a base for discount calculation if the discount is defined                 as based on the amount. Discountable Qty. The quantity used as a base for discount calculation if the discount is defined                 as based on the item quantity. Discount Amt. The amount of the discount. Discount Percent The discount percent if by definition the discount is calculated as a                 percentage. Free Item The inventory ID of the free non-stock item, if one is specified by the                 discount applied to the document. Free Item Qty. The quantity of the free non-stock item. Other Information Tab The  Other Information  tab contains other information related to the subcontract,         such as the branch ordering the services, the workgroup, and the reference numbers of the         related documents (requisition document and prepayment). Element Description Requisition Ref. Nbr. The reference number of the requisition document associated with the                 subcontract, if any. To create the requisition documents, use the   ([~/?ScreenId=RQ302000|RQ302000]) Requisitions (RQ302000) form. This box is available only if the                    Purchase Requisitions  feature is enabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features (CS100000) form. Prepayment Ref. Nbr. The reference number of the prepayment request linked to this subcontract, if                 any. Workgroup ID The workgroup to which the subcontract was assigned for processing. Don’t Print A check box that indicates (if selected) that the current subcontract should                 not be printed. Printed A check box that indicates (if selected) that the current subcontract has been                 printed. To print the subcontract, select  Print Subcontract  on the                    Reports  menu; this causes the system to automatically select the check                 box. Don’t Email A check box that indicates (if selected) that the subcontract should not be                 emailed. Emailed A check box that indicates (if selected) indicates that the current subcontract                 was emailed. To email a subcontract, select  Email Subcontract  on the                    Actions  menu; this causes the system to automatically select the check                 box. Open Quantity The total value of  Base Order Qty.  column of all subcontract                 lines. Open Balance The total value of  Amount  column of all subcontract lines. Attributes Tab The  Attributes  tab contains the list of attributes related to the subcontract, such         as brand, lead age, gender, and industry. The table toolbar includes only standard buttons. For the list of standard buttons, see            Table Toolbar. Column Description Attribute The description of the attribute assigned to the subcontract. Required A check box that indicates (if selected) that the attribute is                 mandatory. Value The value of the attribute assigned to the subcontract. Compliance Tab The  Compliance  tab contains the list of compliance documents assigned to the         subcontract. You can add and update compliance documents within this tab. The table has the         columns listed below. The table toolbar includes only standard buttons. For the list of standard buttons, see            Table Toolbar. Table Columns Document Type The type of the compliance document. The following document types are                   available: Certificate Insurance Notice Lien Waiver Other Creation Date The date when the compliance document was created. By default, the current date                 is set. The user is able to change the date manually. Document Type Option The document type option of the compliance’s document type. The list of                 document type options should be set manually on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CL301000|CL301000]) '''Compliance Preferences'''                 (CL301000) form. Status The status of the compliance document. The list of values should be set                 manually on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CL301000|CL301000]) '''Compliance Preferences''' form. Is Required A check box that indicates (if selected) that the document is mandatory for                 working with a specific project or project task. This flag is for informational                 purposes only. It shows that the compliance document is required before implementing                 some activities on a project. Received A check box that indicates (if selected) that the document is received by user.                 The  Received  check box allows the user to track when the payment for document                 is received, so the next payment is not delayed. Received Date The date when the compliance document is received. The date should be set                 manually by the user on the  Compliance  tab after the document is                 received. Sent Date The date when the compliance document is sent. The date should be set manually                 by the user on the  Compliance  tab after the document is sent. Effective Date The date when the compliance document takes effect. The date should be set                 manually by the user while adding the document on the  Compliance  tab. Expiration Date The date when the compliance document will expire. The date should be set                 manually by the user while adding the document on the  Compliance  tab. Limit The amount of insurance liability set for the compliance document. The amount                 should be set manually by the user while adding the document on the                    Compliance  tab. Method Sent The method of sending the document. Project The reference to a project to which a compliance document relates. By default,                 it is set to the identifier of the project selected in the Summary area of the form.                 If specified, current document will be displayed on the  Compliance  tab of the                     ([~/?ScreenId=PM301000|PM301000]) Projects (PM301000) form of the selected project. Cost Task The reference to a cost task available within the project. If specified,                 current document will be displayed on the  Compliance  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=PM302000|PM302000]) Project Tasks (PM302000) form of the selected task of the  Cost                   Task  type. Revenue Task The reference to a revenue task within the project. If specified, current                 document will be displayed on the  Compliance  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=PM302000|PM302000]) Project Tasks form of the selected task of the  Revenue Task                  type. Cost Code The cost code assigned to the compliance document. Customer The reference number of the customer associated with the compliance document.                 By default, it is set to the identifier of the customer selected in the Summary area                 of the form. If specified, current document will be displayed on the  Compliance                   tab  of the   ([~/?ScreenId=AR303000|AR303000]) Customers (AR303000) form of the selected                 customer. Customer Name The name of the customer associated with the compliance document. Vendor The reference number of the vendor associated with the compliance document. By                 default, it is set to the identifier of the vendor selected in the Summary area of                 the form. If specified, current document will be displayed on the  Compliance                  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP303000|AP303000]) Vendors (AP303000) form of the selected                 vendor. Vendor Name The name of the vendor associated with the compliance document. Secondary Vendor The reference number of the secondary vendor associated with the compliance                 document. If specified, current document will be displayed on the  Compliance                  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP303000|AP303000]) Vendors form of the selected vendor. Secondary Vendor Name The name of the secondary vendor associated with the compliance                 document. Purchase Order The unique identifier of the purchase order associated with the compliance                 document. By default, it is set to the identifier of the purchase order selected in                 the Summary area of the form. If specified, current document will be displayed on                 the  Compliance  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=PO301000|PO301000]) Purchase Orders (PO301000) form of                 the selected purchase order. Purchase Order Line Item The unique identifier of the purchase order line item. It can be specified only                 after a purchase order is selected. Subcontract The unique identifier of the subcontract associated with the compliance                 document. By default, it is set to the identifier of the subcontract selected in the                 Summary area of the form. If specified, current document will be displayed on the                    Compliance  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000]) Subcontracts (SC301000) form of                 the selected subcontract. Subcontract Line Item The unique identifier of the subcontract line. It can be specified only after a                 Subcontract is selected. Invoice The reference number of the invoice associated with the compliance document. By                 default, it is set to the identifier of the invoice selected in the Summary area of                 the form. If specified, current document will be displayed on the  Compliance                  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=AR301000|AR301000]) Invoices and Memos (AR301000) form of the selected                 invoice. Invoice Amount The amount of the invoice. Bill The reference number of the bill associated with the compliance document. By                 default, it is set to the identifier of the bill selected in the Summary area of the                 form. If specified, current document will be displayed on the  Compliance  tab                 of the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP301000|AP301000]) Bills and Adjustments (AP301000) form of the selected bill. Bill Amount The bill amount to be paid for the document. Lien Waiver Amount The amount covered by the lien waiver. Sponsor Organization The name of the sponsor organization. Certificate Number The number of the certificate. Insurance Company The name of the insurance company. Policy The insurance policy number. Account The account associated with the vendor (Expense account) or customer (Sales                 account). AP Check The reference number of the check associated with the compliance                 document. AR Payment The reference number of the payment associated with the compliance                 document. Project Transaction The reference number of the project transaction associated with the compliance                 document. Payment Date The date when the check is created. Receipt Date The date when the inventory receipt is made. Date Issued The date when the document is issued. Through Date The date when the goods are shipped. Receive Date The date when the goods are received. Received By The person responsible for receiving goods. Source The source of the check. One of the following values is allowed: AP Inv PO/Sub Project Customer Requires Joint Check A check box that indicates (if selected) that the joint check is                 required. Joint Vendor The reference number of the joint vendor associated with the compliance                 document. If specified, current document will be displayed on the  Compliance                  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP303000|AP303000]) Vendors (AP303000) form of the selected                 vendor. Joint Amount The amount to be paid to joint payees according to the joint check. Joint Release A check box that indicates (if selected) that the joint release is                 received. AP Payment Method The payment method associated with the vendor. AR Payment Method The customer’s default payment method.  ([~/?ScreenId=SC101000|SC101000])  ([~/?ScreenId=IN202000|IN202000])  ([~/?ScreenId=AP303000|AP303000]) ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="bffacbcd-2b66-4c70-881c-aad334a3d615" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="41c9bb84-bba8-7ccf-7337-de8db9b4e02c" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
Form ID:  ([~/?ScreenId=SC503000|SC503000]){br}

On this form, you can print the all subcontracts or those you select or send the needed subcontracts by email. Also, you can apply the '''Mark as Do not Email''' action to selected subcontracts to ensure that they aren’t sent by email. This causes the Don’t Email check box on the [HelpRoot_Construction\SC_30_10_00|Subcontracts] ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000]) form to be selected for the particular subcontracts.{br}{TOC}
==Form Toolbar==
The form toolbar includes standard and form-specific buttons. For the list of standard buttons, see [HelpRoot_Interface\Form_Toolbar|Form Toolbar]. The form-specific buttons are listed below.[anchor|#_1e617ac1-d522-40f5-b3c5-17fb215e3ce0]
{| class="checklist" | width="100%" 
|- 
!width="20%" ! Button
!width="80%" ! Description
|- 
| '''Process'''
| Processes the documents you have selected in the table.
|- 
| '''Process All'''
| Processes all documents listed in the table.
|}
=='''Selection Area'''==
In the Selection area, you can select (by owner or workgroup or both) the documents to be displayed in the table on this form. You also select the action to be applied to the documents you process.[anchor|#_55a53475-fd41-42c3-9139-e9b2cdc716b9]
{| class="checklist" | width="100%" 
|- 
!width="20%" ! Element
!width="80%" ! Description
|- 
| '''Action'''
| 
The action to be performed on the selected subcontracts if the '''Process''' or '''Process All''' action is invoked:[anchor|#_4b7623e0-4f1f-47ec-a4e1-889ee5c0213f]
*''Email Subcontract'': Generates emails for the subcontracts in accordance with the mailing settings on the [HelpRoot_Construction\SC_10_10_00|Subcontracts Preferences] ([~/?ScreenId=SC101000|SC101000]) form.
*''Mark as Do Not Email'': Marks the subcontracts as not requiring emailing.
*''Print Subcontract'': Prints the subcontracts you select in the table.

|- 
| '''Assigned To'''
| 
A box and the '''Me''' check box, which you use as follows to select the employee to whom the subcontracts to be displayed in the table are assigned:[anchor|#_d269e1d2-65a7-4a85-a7f0-5d6afe0288ed]
*Select the '''Me''' check box to display the subcontracts assigned to you. The box will display your user name.
*Clear the '''Me''' check box and select another user to view the subcontracts assigned to the user.
*Leave the elements blank to view the subcontracts of all users of the selected workgroup (if one is specified) or all workgroups (if no workgroup is specified).

|- 
| '''Workgroup'''
| 
A box and the '''My''' check box, which you use in the following ways to select the workgroup the subcontracts to be displayed are assigned to:[anchor|#_1db55fb2-fb1d-4458-9ff3-d010c6486935]
*Select the '''My''' check box to view the subcontracts assigned to your workgroup.
*Clear the '''My''' check box and select another workgroup to display the subcontracts assigned to everyone in the group or to a particular user of the group.
*Leave the elements blank to view the subcontracts assigned to all workgroups.

|}
==Table==
In this table, you can view the list of subcontracts that match any selection criteria you have specified. You can also select the documents to be processed—that is, those to be printed, emailed, or marked as not intended for emailing, depending on the action you have selected.[anchor|#_59800b26-fce6-4098-aae0-9be969a1ee65]
===Table Toolbar===The table toolbar includes standard buttons and buttons specific to this table. For the list of standard buttons, see [HelpRoot_Interface\Details_Toolbar|Table Toolbar]. The table-specific buttons are listed below.
{| class="checklist" | width="100%" 
|- 
!width="20%" ! Button
!width="80%" ! Description
|- 
| '''View Subcontract'''
| Navigates to the [HelpRoot_Construction\SC_30_10_00|Subcontracts] ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000]) form, so you can view the details of the selected subcontract.
|}[anchor|#_63689d94-32fe-4456-b5e4-9775857ff2de]
===Table Columns===
{| class="checklist" | width="100%" 
|- 
!width="20%" ! Column
!width="80%" ! Description
|- 
| '''Included'''
| An unlabeled check box that you select to include the document in processing if you click '''Process'''.
|- 
| '''Date'''
| The date when the subcontract was created.
|- 
| '''Subcontract Nbr.'''
| The subcontract number.
|- 
| '''Status'''
| The current status of the subcontract.
|- 
| '''Owner'''
| The employee ID of the owner of the subcontract.
|- 
| '''Employee Name'''
| The name of the employee who is the owner of the subcontract.
|- 
| '''Description'''
| Any description that has been provided for the subcontract.
|- 
| '''Approver'''
| The employee ID of the person who has approved the subcontract.
|- 
| '''Currency'''
| The currency used in the subcontract.
|- 
| '''Control Total'''
| The total amount of the subcontract document, which has been manually entered on the Subcontracts form only if '''Validate Total on Entry''' check box is selected on the Subcontracts Preferences form.
|- 
| '''Vendor'''
| The vendor associated with the subcontract.
|- 
| '''Vendor Name'''
| The name of the vendor associated with the subcontract.
|- 
| '''Vendor Class'''
| The class of vendors to which this vendor is assigned.
|}
==Related Articles==
*[HelpRoot_Construction\SC_30_10_00|Subcontracts] ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000])
*[HelpRoot_FormReference\SM_20_50_20|Automation Schedules] ([~/?ScreenId=SM205020|SM205020])]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Print/Email Subcontracts Form ID:  (SC503000)  ([~/?ScreenId=SC503000|SC503000])On this form, you can print the all subcontracts or those you select or send the needed         subcontracts by email. Also, you can apply the  Mark as Do not Email          action to selected subcontracts to ensure that they aren’t sent by email. This causes the         Don’t Email check box on the   ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000]) Subcontracts (SC301000) form to be selected         for the particular subcontracts. Form Toolbar The form toolbar includes standard and form-specific buttons. For the list of standard         buttons, see  Form Toolbar. The form-specific buttons         are listed below. Button Description Process Processes the documents you have selected in the table. Process All Processes all documents listed in the table. Selection Area In the Selection area, you can select (by owner or workgroup or both) the documents to be         displayed in the table on this form. You also select the action to be applied to the         documents you process. Element Description Action The action to be performed on the selected subcontracts if the  Process  or                      Process All  action is invoked: Email Subcontract : Generates emails for the subcontracts in accordance                     with the mailing settings on the   ([~/?ScreenId=SC101000|SC101000]) Subcontracts Preferences (SC101000)                     form. Mark as Do Not Email : Marks the subcontracts as not requiring                     emailing. Print Subcontract : Prints the subcontracts you select in the                     table. Assigned To A box and the  Me  check box, which you use as follows to select the                   employee to whom the subcontracts to be displayed in the table are assigned: Select the  Me  check box to display the subcontracts assigned to you.                     The box will display your user name. Clear the  Me  check box and select another user to view the subcontracts                     assigned to the user. Leave the elements blank to view the subcontracts of all users of the selected                     workgroup (if one is specified) or all workgroups (if no workgroup is                     specified). Workgroup A box and the  My  check box, which you use in the following ways to select                   the workgroup the subcontracts to be displayed are assigned to: Select the  My  check box to view the subcontracts assigned to your                     workgroup. Clear the  My  check box and select another workgroup to display the                     subcontracts assigned to everyone in the group or to a particular user of the                     group. Leave the elements blank to view the subcontracts assigned to all                     workgroups. Table In this table, you can view the list of subcontracts that match any selection criteria you         have specified. You can also select the documents to be processed—that is, those to be         printed, emailed, or marked as not intended for emailing, depending on the action you have         selected. Table Toolbar The table toolbar includes standard buttons and buttons specific to this table. For           the list of standard buttons, see  Table Toolbar.           The table-specific buttons are listed below. Button Description View Subcontract Navigates to the   ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000]) Subcontracts (SC301000) form, so you can                 view the details of the selected subcontract. Table Columns Column Description Included An unlabeled check box that you select to include the document in processing if                 you click  Process . Date The date when the subcontract was created. Subcontract Nbr. The subcontract number. Status The current status of the subcontract. Owner The employee ID of the owner of the subcontract. Employee Name The name of the employee who is the owner of the subcontract. Description Any description that has been provided for the subcontract. Approver The employee ID of the person who has approved the subcontract. Currency The currency used in the subcontract. Control Total The total amount of the subcontract document, which has been manually entered                 on the Subcontracts form only if  Validate Total on Entry  check box is                 selected on the Subcontracts Preferences form. Vendor The vendor associated with the subcontract. Vendor Name The name of the vendor associated with the subcontract. Vendor Class The class of vendors to which this vendor is assigned.  ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000])  ([~/?ScreenId=SM205020|SM205020]) ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="9572610a-44f6-43da-85b7-be4d68ffea90" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="0f64e3be-b39b-da02-6723-3847f8d9fa0c" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
Form ID:  ([~/?ScreenId=SC101000|SC101000]){br}

You use this form to provide the general settings for the Subcontracts module, such as numbering sequences for subcontracts, validation requirements for subcontracts, approval and mailing settings, and the list of attributes for subcontracts.{br}{TOC}
==Form Toolbar==
The form toolbar includes only standard buttons. For the list of standard buttons, see [HelpRoot_Interface\Form_Toolbar|Form Toolbar].
==General Settings Tab==
This tab contains three groups of settings that affect the basic operations available in the Subcontracts module.[anchor|#_4ef7aea9-6dfb-43c2-876f-03b16cca4f3f]
{| class="checklist" | width="100%" 
|- 
!width="50%" ! Element
!width="50%" ! Description
|- 
| '''Subcontract Numbering Sequence'''
| The numbering sequence to be used for assigning reference numbers to subcontracts.
|- 
| '''Validate Total on Entry'''
| A check box that indicates (if selected) that the system will require the user to validate the total amount for each subcontract. If this check box is selected, to save a subcontract with the '''Hold''' check box cleared, you must enter the total amount in the '''Control Total''' box on the [HelpRoot_Construction\SC_30_10_00|Subcontracts] ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000]) form. If this check box is cleared, the '''Control Total''' box does not appear on the [HelpRoot_Construction\SC_30_10_00|Subcontracts] form.
|- 
| '''Require Approval'''
| A check box that indicates (if selected) that the selected assignment map will be used to assign documents for approvals. If the check box is cleared, no approvals will be required and if an assignment map is selected in the '''Approval Map''' box, it will not be used.
|}[anchor|#_049f9ad2-939f-4207-b8d9-f036d6a6dd38]
===Approval Section===
You use this section to configure approvals for subcontracts. This section is available only if the ''Approval Workflow'' feature is enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features]  ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) form.{br}

The section includes the following elements.
{| class="checklist" | width="100%" 
|- 
!width="20%" ! Element
!width="80%" ! Description
|- 
| '''Approval Map'''
| The map to be used for subcontracts. To view or modify the assignment rules, use the [HelpRoot_FormReference\EP_20_55_00|Assignment and Approval Maps] ([~/?ScreenId=EP205500|EP205500]) form.
|- 
| '''Pending Approval Notification'''
| The notification template that the system will use to generate notification emails for employees who approve subcontracts. An employee will receive a notification about pending approval when a subcontract requires approval from this employee. For more information, see [HelpRoot_GettingStarted\CO__con_Centralized_Approvals|Approving Documents].
|}
==Mailing Settings Tab==
The '''Mailing Settings''' tab contains the list of predefined mailings that can be used for sending subcontracts and other documents to vendors electronically (by email). Mailing settings specified on this tab will be used as the default values for mailing settings specified for vendor classes, which in turn will be used as the default values for setting up mailings for particular vendors.{br}

For an overview of this functionality, see [HelpRoot_Financials\AP__con_Predefined_Mailings_for_Customers_and_Vendors|Configuring Predefined Mailings for Customers and Vendors]. For details on setting up vendor mailings, see [HelpRoot_Financials\SM__how_How_to_Set_Up_Mailings_For_Vendors|To Set Up Mailings for Vendors].{br}

This tab contains the following tables: '''Default Sources''' and '''Default Recipients'''.[anchor|#_b104f715-8b31-4d23-a6e3-15f749182cc3]
===Default Sources Table===
In the '''Default Sources''' table, you can view and modify the active mailings that can be used to send emails to vendors and employees. For each mailing, you can select either a report or an email template to be used by default as the body of the email.{br}

The table toolbar includes only standard buttons. For the list of standard buttons, see [HelpRoot_Interface\Details_Toolbar|Table Toolbar].
{| class="checklist" | width="100%" 
|- 
!width="20%" ! Column
!width="80%" ! Description
|- 
| '''Mailing ID'''
| The unique identifier of the mailing.
|- 
| '''Default Email Account'''
| The system email account to be used by default for sending emails for this mailing. If no account is specified, the default system account will be used.
|- 
| '''Report'''
| 
The report that, by default, will be used to structure the information available in a subcontract. For the email, the report will be used as the email’s body (or attachment), if a report is used rather than an email template.((({S:Warn}For each mailing, you can use as the email’s body either a report or a notification template.
)))
|- 
| '''Notification Template'''
| The template to be used by default to generate emails for the mailing, if an email template is used rather than a report.
|- 
| '''Format'''
| The format in which the report (if applicable) will be sent by default if no preferences are specified for a particular recipient on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_30_00|Vendors] ([~/?ScreenId=AP303000|AP303000]) form. Select one of the following options: ''Text'', ''HTML'', ''Excel'', or ''PDF''.
|- 
| '''Active'''
| A check box that indicates (if selected) that this mailing is active. Emails will be generated for only active mailings.
|}[anchor|#_75041009-ce16-4c3f-9a88-978f1b7b4bb8]
===Default Recipients Table===
This table contains the default recipient types for the mailing selected in the '''Default Sources''' table.{br}

The table toolbar includes only standard buttons. For the list of standard buttons, see [HelpRoot_Interface\Details_Toolbar|Table Toolbar].
{| class="checklist" | width="100%" 
|- 
!width="20%" ! Column
!width="80%" ! Description
|- 
| '''Contact Type'''
| 
The type of contact to receive mailings. You select one of the following options:[anchor|#_9d617ce8-2f17-44a4-af80-d3f7e33a4fc4]
*''Primary'': A primary contact of the customer
*''Remittance'': A remittance contact of the customer
*''Shipping'': A shipping contact of the customer
*''Employee'': An employee of your company who handles documents of specific customer classes or specific customers, or is otherwise associated with the classes or customers

|- 
| '''Contact ID'''
| The identifier of the mailing recipient. A particular recipient can be selected only if you have selected ''Employee'' as the contact type. This employee, if one is selected, will receive emails about changes in the documents of all customers.
|- 
| '''Format'''
| The format in which the report (if applicable) will be sent by default. Select one of the following options: ''HTML'', ''Excel'', or ''PDF''.
|- 
| '''Active'''
| A check box that indicates (if selected) that the contact or contact type is active. Only active recipients receive the emails for the mailing.
|- 
| '''BCC'''
| A check box that indicates (if selected) that the contact (or contact of this type) will receive a blind carbon copy (BCC) of the emails for this mailing.
|}
==Attributes Tab==
The '''Attributes''' tab contains the list of attributes that can be assigned to subcontracts. For more information see [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_20_50_00|Attributes] ([~/?ScreenId=CS205000|CS205000]) form. The table toolbar includes only standard buttons. For the list of standard buttons, see [HelpRoot_Interface\Details_Toolbar|Table Toolbar].[anchor|#_b7139c0d-adad-47e7-a640-f5234cb45f3f]
{| class="checklist" | width="100%" 
|- 
!width="20%" ! Column
!width="80%" ! Description
|- 
| '''Active'''
| A check box that indicates (if selected) that the attribute is active.
|- 
| '''Attribute ID'''
| The title of the attribute.
|- 
| '''Description'''
| The description of the attribute.
|- 
| '''Sort Order'''
| The number representing the order of the value in the resulting list of attribute values.
|- 
| '''Required'''
| A check box that indicates (if selected) that the attribute is required.
|- 
| '''Control Type'''
| 
The control type of the attribute. The attribute can have one of the following control types:[anchor|#_c800c036-2b19-433c-a416-abc2c5b30d61]
*''Check box'': The control is a check box that can be selected or cleared to turn the option on or off.
*''Combo'': The control is a combo box, which is a text box with a list box attached, so users can type or select the attribute value. For this type, you can enter a list of possible values.
*''Datetime'': The control is used to enter a date.
*''Multi Select Combo'': The control is a list box with a check box against each attribute value so users can select multiple options. For this type, you can enter a list of possible values.
*''Text'': The control is a text box in which the user can type text. For this type, you can specify an input validation option: an input mask or a regular expression.

|}
==Related Articles==
*[HelpRoot_Construction\SC_30_10_00|Subcontracts] ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000])
*[HelpRoot_Construction\SC_50_30_00|Print/Email Subcontracts] ([~/?ScreenId=SC503000|SC503000])]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Subcontracts Preferences Form ID:  (SC101000)  ([~/?ScreenId=SC101000|SC101000])You use this form to provide the general settings for the Subcontracts module, such as         numbering sequences for subcontracts, validation requirements for subcontracts, approval and         mailing settings, and the list of attributes for subcontracts. Form Toolbar The form toolbar includes only standard buttons. For the list of standard buttons, see            Form Toolbar. General Settings Tab This tab contains three groups of settings that affect the basic operations available in         the Subcontracts module. Element Description Subcontract Numbering Sequence The numbering sequence to be used for assigning reference numbers to                 subcontracts. Validate Total on Entry A check box that indicates (if selected) that the system will require the user                 to validate the total amount for each subcontract. If this check box is selected, to                 save a subcontract with the  Hold  check box cleared, you must enter the total                 amount in the  Control Total  box on the   ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000]) Subcontracts                 (SC301000) form. If this check box is cleared, the  Control Total  box does not                 appear on the   ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000]) Subcontracts form. Require Approval A check box that indicates (if selected) that the selected assignment map will                 be used to assign documents for approvals. If the check box is cleared, no approvals                 will be required and if an assignment map is selected in the  Approval                   Map  box, it will not be used. Approval Section You use this section to configure approvals for subcontracts. This section is available             only if the  Approval Workflow  feature is enabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features (CS100000) form. The section includes the following elements. Element Description Approval Map The map to be used for subcontracts. To view or modify the assignment rules,                 use the   ([~/?ScreenId=EP205500|EP205500]) Assignment and Approval Maps (EP205500) form. Pending Approval Notification The notification template that the system will use to generate notification                 emails for employees who approve subcontracts. An employee will receive a                 notification about pending approval when a subcontract requires approval from this                 employee. For more information, see  Approving Documents. Mailing Settings Tab The  Mailing Settings  tab contains the list of predefined mailings that can be used         for sending subcontracts and other documents to vendors electronically (by email). Mailing         settings specified on this tab will be used as the default values for mailing settings         specified for vendor classes, which in turn will be used as the default values for setting         up mailings for particular vendors. For an overview of this functionality, see  Configuring Predefined Mailings for Customers and Vendors. For details on         setting up vendor mailings, see  To Set Up Mailings for Vendors. This tab contains the following tables:  Default Sources  and  Default           Recipients . Default Sources Table In the  Default Sources  table, you can view and modify the active mailings that             can be used to send emails to vendors and employees. For each mailing, you can select             either a report or an email template to be used by default as the body of the email. The table toolbar includes only standard buttons. For the list of standard buttons, see                Table Toolbar. Column Description Mailing ID The unique identifier of the mailing. Default Email Account The system email account to be used by default for sending emails for this                 mailing. If no account is specified, the default system account will be                 used. Report The report that, by default, will be used to structure the information available                   in a subcontract. For the email, the report will be used as the email’s body (or                   attachment), if a report is used rather than an email template. For each mailing, you can use as the email’s body either a report or a                   notification template. Notification Template The template to be used by default to generate emails for the mailing, if an                 email template is used rather than a report. Format The format in which the report (if applicable) will be sent by default if no                 preferences are specified for a particular recipient on the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP303000|AP303000]) Vendors (AP303000) form. Select one of the following options:                    Text ,  HTML ,  Excel , or  PDF . Active A check box that indicates (if selected) that this mailing is active. Emails                 will be generated for only active mailings. Default Recipients Table This table contains the default recipient types for the mailing selected in the                Default Sources  table. The table toolbar includes only standard buttons. For the list of standard buttons, see                Table Toolbar. Column Description Contact Type The type of contact to receive mailings. You select one of the following                   options: Primary : A primary contact of the customer Remittance : A remittance contact of the customer Shipping : A shipping contact of the customer Employee : An employee of your company who handles documents of specific                     customer classes or specific customers, or is otherwise associated with the                     classes or customers Contact ID The identifier of the mailing recipient. A particular recipient can be selected                 only if you have selected  Employee  as the contact type. This employee, if one                 is selected, will receive emails about changes in the documents of all                 customers. Format The format in which the report (if applicable) will be sent by default. Select                 one of the following options:  HTML ,  Excel , or  PDF . Active A check box that indicates (if selected) that the contact or contact type is                 active. Only active recipients receive the emails for the mailing. BCC A check box that indicates (if selected) that the contact (or contact of this                 type) will receive a blind carbon copy (BCC) of the emails for this mailing. Attributes Tab The  Attributes  tab contains the list of attributes that can be assigned to         subcontracts. For more information see   ([~/?ScreenId=CS205000|CS205000]) Attributes (CS205000) form. The         table toolbar includes only standard buttons. For the list of standard buttons, see  Table Toolbar. Column Description Active A check box that indicates (if selected) that the attribute is active. Attribute ID The title of the attribute. Description The description of the attribute. Sort Order The number representing the order of the value in the resulting list of                 attribute values. Required A check box that indicates (if selected) that the attribute is                 required. Control Type The control type of the attribute. The attribute can have one of the following                   control types: Check box : The control is a check box that can be selected or cleared                     to turn the option on or off. Combo : The control is a combo box, which is a text box with a list box                     attached, so users can type or select the attribute value. For this type, you                     can enter a list of possible values. Datetime : The control is used to enter a date. Multi Select Combo : The control is a list box with a check box against                     each attribute value so users can select multiple options. For this type, you                     can enter a list of possible values. Text : The control is a text box in which the user can type text. For                     this type, you can specify an input validation option: an input mask or a                     regular expression.  ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000])  ([~/?ScreenId=SC503000|SC503000]) ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="8ab000d0-e321-4ae0-b0e9-5a7723cbcc96" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="e010b7c8-1b0b-bdcc-156e-db04ecbdd821" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
Form ID:  ([~/?ScreenId=CL401000|CL401000]){br}

You can use this form to create, view, and modify compliance documents.{br}

This form is available if the ''Construction'' feature is enabled on the [HelpRoot_FormReference\CS_10_00_00|Enable/Disable Features]  ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) form. {br}{TOC}
==Form Toolbar==
The form toolbar includes only standard buttons. For the list of standard buttons, see [HelpRoot_Interface\Form_Toolbar|Form Toolbar].
==Table==
The table shown on each filter tab contains the list of compliance documents that match the criteria of the selected filter tab. The table on each tab has the following columns.[anchor|#_be970fef-90db-449e-a84e-b8c5d6c9cdcd]
===Table columns===
{| class="checklist" | width="100%" 
|- 
!width="20%" ! Column
!width="80%" ! Description
|- 
| '''Document Type'''
| 
The type of the compliance document. The following document types are available:[anchor|#_b3b2e3fb-cc65-426c-b9c0-aad35ca9cbc2]
*''Certificate''
* ''Insurance''
* ''Notice''
* ''Lien Waiver''
* ''Other''

|- 
|  '''Creation Date'''
| The date when the compliance document was created. By default, the current date is set. The user is able to change the date manually.
|- 
| '''Document Type Option'''
| The document type option of the compliance’s document type. The list of document type options should be set manually on the [HelpRoot_Construction\CL_30_10_00|'''Compliance Preferences'''] ([~/?ScreenId=CL301000|CL301000]) form.
|- 
| '''Status'''
| The status of the compliance document. The list of values should be set manually on the [HelpRoot_Construction\CL_30_10_00|'''Compliance Preferences'''] form.
|- 
| '''Is Required'''
| A check box that indicates (if selected) that the document is mandatory for working with a specific project or project task. This flag is for informational purposes only. It shows that the compliance document is required before implementing some activities on a project.
|- 
| '''Received'''
| A check box that indicates (if selected) that the document is received by user. The ''Received'' check box allows the user to track when the payment for document is received, so the next payment is not delayed.
|- 
| '''Received Date'''
| The date when the compliance document is received. The date should be set manually by the user on the '''Compliance''' tab after the document is received.
|- 
| '''Sent Date'''
| The date when the compliance document is sent. The date should be set manually by the user on the '''Compliance''' tab after the document is sent.
|- 
| '''Effective Date'''
| The date when the compliance document takes effect. The date should be set manually by the user while adding the document on the '''Compliance''' tab.
|- 
| '''Expiration Date'''
| The date when the compliance document will expire. The date should be set manually by the user while adding the document on the '''Compliance''' tab.
|- 
| '''Limit'''
| The amount of insurance liability set for the compliance document. The amount should be set manually by the user while adding the document on the '''Compliance''' tab.
|- 
| '''Method Sent'''
| The method of sending the document.
|- 
| '''Project'''
| The reference to a project to which a compliance document relates. By default, it is set to the identifier of the project selected in the Summary area of the form. If specified, current document will be displayed on the '''Compliance''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PM_30_10_00|Projects] ([~/?ScreenId=PM301000|PM301000]) form of the selected project.
|- 
| '''Cost Task'''
| The reference to a cost task available within the project. If specified, current document will be displayed on the '''Compliance''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PM_30_20_00|Project Tasks] ([~/?ScreenId=PM302000|PM302000]) form of the selected task of the ''Cost Task'' type.
|- 
| '''Revenue Task'''
| The reference to a revenue task within the project. If specified, current document will be displayed on the '''Compliance''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PM_30_20_00|Project Tasks] form of the selected task of the ''Revenue Task'' type.
|- 
| '''Cost Code'''
| The cost code assigned to the compliance document.
|- 
| '''Customer'''
| The reference number of the customer associated with the compliance document. By default, it is set to the identifier of the customer selected in the Summary area of the form. If specified, current document will be displayed on the '''Compliance tab''' of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AR_30_30_00|Customers] ([~/?ScreenId=AR303000|AR303000]) form of the selected customer.
|- 
| '''Customer Name'''
| The name of the customer associated with the compliance document.
|- 
| '''Vendor'''
| The reference number of the vendor associated with the compliance document. By default, it is set to the identifier of the vendor selected in the Summary area of the form. If specified, current document will be displayed on the '''Compliance''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_30_00|Vendors] ([~/?ScreenId=AP303000|AP303000]) form of the selected vendor.
|- 
| '''Vendor Name'''
| The name of the vendor associated with the compliance document.
|- 
| '''Secondary Vendor'''
| The reference number of the secondary vendor associated with the compliance document. If specified, current document will be displayed on the '''Compliance''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_30_00|Vendors] form of the selected vendor.
|- 
| '''Secondary Vendor Name'''
| The name of the secondary vendor associated with the compliance document.
|- 
| '''Purchase Order'''
| The unique identifier of the purchase order associated with the compliance document. By default, it is set to the identifier of the purchase order selected in the Summary area of the form. If specified, current document will be displayed on the '''Compliance''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\PO_30_10_00|Purchase Orders] ([~/?ScreenId=PO301000|PO301000]) form of the selected purchase order.
|- 
| '''Purchase Order Line Item'''
| The unique identifier of the purchase order line item. It can be specified only after a purchase order is selected.
|- 
| '''Subcontract'''
| The unique identifier of the subcontract associated with the compliance document. By default, it is set to the identifier of the subcontract selected in the Summary area of the form. If specified, current document will be displayed on the '''Compliance''' tab of the [HelpRoot_Construction\SC_30_10_00|Subcontracts] ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000]) form of the selected subcontract.
|- 
| '''Subcontract Line Item'''
| The unique identifier of the subcontract line. It can be specified only after a Subcontract is selected.
|- 
| '''Invoice'''
| The reference number of the invoice associated with the compliance document. By default, it is set to the identifier of the invoice selected in the Summary area of the form. If specified, current document will be displayed on the '''Compliance''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AR_30_10_00|Invoices and Memos] ([~/?ScreenId=AR301000|AR301000]) form of the selected invoice.
|- 
| '''Invoice Amount'''
| The amount of the invoice.
|- 
| '''Bill'''
| The reference number of the bill associated with the compliance document. By default, it is set to the identifier of the bill selected in the Summary area of the form. If specified, current document will be displayed on the '''Compliance''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_10_00|Bills and Adjustments] ([~/?ScreenId=AP301000|AP301000]) form of the selected bill.
|- 
| '''Bill Amount'''
| The bill amount to be paid for the document.
|- 
| '''Lien Waiver Amount'''
| The amount covered by the lien waiver.
|- 
| '''Sponsor Organization'''
| The name of the sponsor organization.
|- 
| '''Certificate Number'''
| The number of the certificate.
|- 
| '''Insurance Company'''
| The name of the insurance company.
|- 
| '''Policy'''
| The insurance policy number.
|- 
| '''Account'''
| The account associated with the vendor (Expense account) or customer (Sales account).
|- 
| '''AP Check'''
| The reference number of the check associated with the compliance document.
|- 
| '''AR Payment'''
| The reference number of the payment associated with the compliance document.
|- 
| '''Project Transaction'''
| The reference number of the project transaction associated with the compliance document.
|- 
| '''Payment Date'''
| The date when the check is created.
|- 
| '''Receipt Date'''
| The date when the inventory receipt is made.
|- 
| '''Date Issued'''
| The date when the document is issued.
|- 
| '''Through Date'''
| The date when the goods are shipped.
|- 
| '''Receive Date'''
| The date when the goods are received.
|- 
| '''Received By'''
| The person responsible for receiving goods.
|- 
| '''Source'''
| 
The source of the check. One of the following values is allowed:[anchor|#_9cc8fe31-bc37-463a-9d43-ad3ec8fe4951]
*''AP Inv''
* ''PO/Sub''
* ''Project''
* ''Customer''

|- 
|  '''Requires Joint Check'''
| A check box that indicates (if selected) that the joint check is required.
|- 
| '''Joint Vendor'''
| The reference number of the joint vendor associated with the compliance document. If specified, current document will be displayed on the '''Compliance''' tab of the [HelpRoot_FormReference\AP_30_30_00|Vendors] form of the selected vendor.
|- 
| '''Joint Amount'''
| The amount to be paid to joint payees according to the joint check.
|- 
| '''Joint Release'''
| A check box that indicates (if selected) that the joint release is received.
|- 
| '''AP Payment Method'''
| The payment method associated with the vendor.
|- 
| '''AR Payment Method'''
| The customer’s default payment method.
|}
==Related Articles==
*[HelpRoot_Construction\CL_30_10_00|'''Compliance Preferences'''] ([~/?ScreenId=CL301000|CL301000])]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Compliance Management Form ID:  (CL401000)  ([~/?ScreenId=CL401000|CL401000])You can use this form to create, view, and modify compliance documents. This form is available if the  Construction  feature is enabled on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CS100000|CS100000]) Enable/Disable Features (CS100000) form.  Form Toolbar The form toolbar includes only standard buttons. For the list of standard buttons, see            Form Toolbar. Table The table shown on each filter tab contains the list of compliance documents that match the         criteria of the selected filter tab. The table on each tab has the following columns. Table columns Column Description Document Type The type of the compliance document. The following document types are                   available: Certificate Insurance Notice Lien Waiver Other Creation Date The date when the compliance document was created. By default, the current date                 is set. The user is able to change the date manually. Document Type Option The document type option of the compliance’s document type. The list of                 document type options should be set manually on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CL301000|CL301000]) '''Compliance Preferences'''                 (CL301000) form. Status The status of the compliance document. The list of values should be set                 manually on the   ([~/?ScreenId=CL301000|CL301000]) '''Compliance Preferences''' form. Is Required A check box that indicates (if selected) that the document is mandatory for                 working with a specific project or project task. This flag is for informational                 purposes only. It shows that the compliance document is required before implementing                 some activities on a project. Received A check box that indicates (if selected) that the document is received by user.                 The  Received  check box allows the user to track when the payment for document                 is received, so the next payment is not delayed. Received Date The date when the compliance document is received. The date should be set                 manually by the user on the  Compliance  tab after the document is                 received. Sent Date The date when the compliance document is sent. The date should be set manually                 by the user on the  Compliance  tab after the document is sent. Effective Date The date when the compliance document takes effect. The date should be set                 manually by the user while adding the document on the  Compliance  tab. Expiration Date The date when the compliance document will expire. The date should be set                 manually by the user while adding the document on the  Compliance  tab. Limit The amount of insurance liability set for the compliance document. The amount                 should be set manually by the user while adding the document on the                    Compliance  tab. Method Sent The method of sending the document. Project The reference to a project to which a compliance document relates. By default,                 it is set to the identifier of the project selected in the Summary area of the form.                 If specified, current document will be displayed on the  Compliance  tab of the                     ([~/?ScreenId=PM301000|PM301000]) Projects (PM301000) form of the selected project. Cost Task The reference to a cost task available within the project. If specified,                 current document will be displayed on the  Compliance  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=PM302000|PM302000]) Project Tasks (PM302000) form of the selected task of the  Cost                   Task  type. Revenue Task The reference to a revenue task within the project. If specified, current                 document will be displayed on the  Compliance  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=PM302000|PM302000]) Project Tasks form of the selected task of the  Revenue Task                  type. Cost Code The cost code assigned to the compliance document. Customer The reference number of the customer associated with the compliance document.                 By default, it is set to the identifier of the customer selected in the Summary area                 of the form. If specified, current document will be displayed on the  Compliance                   tab  of the   ([~/?ScreenId=AR303000|AR303000]) Customers (AR303000) form of the selected                 customer. Customer Name The name of the customer associated with the compliance document. Vendor The reference number of the vendor associated with the compliance document. By                 default, it is set to the identifier of the vendor selected in the Summary area of                 the form. If specified, current document will be displayed on the  Compliance                  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP303000|AP303000]) Vendors (AP303000) form of the selected                 vendor. Vendor Name The name of the vendor associated with the compliance document. Secondary Vendor The reference number of the secondary vendor associated with the compliance                 document. If specified, current document will be displayed on the  Compliance                  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP303000|AP303000]) Vendors form of the selected vendor. Secondary Vendor Name The name of the secondary vendor associated with the compliance                 document. Purchase Order The unique identifier of the purchase order associated with the compliance                 document. By default, it is set to the identifier of the purchase order selected in                 the Summary area of the form. If specified, current document will be displayed on                 the  Compliance  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=PO301000|PO301000]) Purchase Orders (PO301000) form of                 the selected purchase order. Purchase Order Line Item The unique identifier of the purchase order line item. It can be specified only                 after a purchase order is selected. Subcontract The unique identifier of the subcontract associated with the compliance                 document. By default, it is set to the identifier of the subcontract selected in the                 Summary area of the form. If specified, current document will be displayed on the                    Compliance  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=SC301000|SC301000]) Subcontracts (SC301000) form of                 the selected subcontract. Subcontract Line Item The unique identifier of the subcontract line. It can be specified only after a                 Subcontract is selected. Invoice The reference number of the invoice associated with the compliance document. By                 default, it is set to the identifier of the invoice selected in the Summary area of                 the form. If specified, current document will be displayed on the  Compliance                  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=AR301000|AR301000]) Invoices and Memos (AR301000) form of the selected                 invoice. Invoice Amount The amount of the invoice. Bill The reference number of the bill associated with the compliance document. By                 default, it is set to the identifier of the bill selected in the Summary area of the                 form. If specified, current document will be displayed on the  Compliance  tab                 of the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP301000|AP301000]) Bills and Adjustments (AP301000) form of the selected bill. Bill Amount The bill amount to be paid for the document. Lien Waiver Amount The amount covered by the lien waiver. Sponsor Organization The name of the sponsor organization. Certificate Number The number of the certificate. Insurance Company The name of the insurance company. Policy The insurance policy number. Account The account associated with the vendor (Expense account) or customer (Sales                 account). AP Check The reference number of the check associated with the compliance                 document. AR Payment The reference number of the payment associated with the compliance                 document. Project Transaction The reference number of the project transaction associated with the compliance                 document. Payment Date The date when the check is created. Receipt Date The date when the inventory receipt is made. Date Issued The date when the document is issued. Through Date The date when the goods are shipped. Receive Date The date when the goods are received. Received By The person responsible for receiving goods. Source The source of the check. One of the following values is allowed: AP Inv PO/Sub Project Customer Requires Joint Check A check box that indicates (if selected) that the joint check is                 required. Joint Vendor The reference number of the joint vendor associated with the compliance                 document. If specified, current document will be displayed on the  Compliance                  tab of the   ([~/?ScreenId=AP303000|AP303000]) Vendors form of the selected vendor. Joint Amount The amount to be paid to joint payees according to the joint check. Joint Release A check box that indicates (if selected) that the joint release is                 received. AP Payment Method The payment method associated with the vendor. AR Payment Method The customer’s default payment method.  ([~/?ScreenId=CL301000|CL301000]) ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="aa258542-c2ce-4264-b941-44f5c34560a0" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="7f0f77d6-b63b-7f8f-d451-4e68e81981a4" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
Form ID:  ([~/?ScreenId=CL301000|CL301000]){br}

With this form, you can create, view, and modify compliance attributes. You can enter the needed custom attributes for each compliance document type and define your custom statuses for compliance documents. Also you can add and update common attributes for all types of compliance documents. Custom attributes can be assigned only to compliance documents. Each organization could have their proper attributes for compliance documents. {br}{TOC}
==Form Toolbar==
The form toolbar includes standard buttons. For the list of standard buttons, see [HelpRoot_Interface\Form_Toolbar|Form Toolbar].
==Custom Attributes Tab==
On this tab, you can specify custom attributes for each type of the compliance document.[anchor|#_205bbbb6-3a84-4353-b26d-5152673d337e]
===Table Toolbar===The table toolbar includes standard buttons and buttons specific to this table. For the list of standard buttons, see [HelpRoot_Interface\Details_Toolbar|Table Toolbar]. The table-specific buttons are listed below.
{| class="checklist" | width="100%" 
|- 
!width="20%" ! Button
!width="80%" ! Description
|- 
| '''Attribute'''
| 
The menu containing the list of predefined attributes for compliance documents. The following attributes are allowed:[anchor|#_126c31d7-494e-4e0b-bbb1-7299cfd3c01e]
*''Certificate'': The type of the compliance document.
*''Insurance'': The type of the compliance document.
*''Lien Waiver'': The type of the compliance document.
*''Notice'': The type of the compliance document.
*''Status'': The status of the compliance document.

|}[anchor|#_66c6f171-7a15-4153-9ab3-b40ba70f797d]
===Table Columns===
{| class="checklist" | width="100%" 
|- 
!width="20%" ! Column
!width="80%" ! Description
|- 
| '''Value'''
| The value of the attribute of the compliance document. The values entered for the ''Certificate'', ''Insurance'', ''Lien Waiver'' and ''Notice'' attributes are used as the document type options. The values entered for the ''Status'' attribute are used as statuses of the compliance document.
|}
==Common Attributes Tab==
The table on this tab contains the list of attributes that can be assigned to compliance documents. You can add or delete common attributes on this tab. {br}

The table toolbar includes only standard buttons. For the list of standard buttons, see [HelpRoot_Interface\Details_Toolbar|Table Toolbar].[anchor|#_c3682f0f-8d48-4635-ab50-7d2e83f35b59]
===Table Columns===
{| class="checklist" | width="100%" 
|- 
!width="20%" ! Column
!width="80%" ! Description
|- 
| '''Attribute'''
| The name of the common attribute.
|- 
| '''Description'''
| The description of the common attribute.
|- 
| '''Required'''
| A check box that indicates (if selected) that the attribute is mandatory for the compliance document.
|}
==Related Articles==
*[HelpRoot_Construction\CL_40_10_00|Compliance Management] ([~/?ScreenId=CL401000|CL401000])]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Compliance Preferences Form ID:  (CL301000)  ([~/?ScreenId=CL301000|CL301000])With this form, you can create, view, and modify compliance attributes. You can enter the         needed custom attributes for each compliance document type and define your custom statuses         for compliance documents. Also you can add and update common attributes for all types of         compliance documents. Custom attributes can be assigned only to compliance documents. Each         organization could have their proper attributes for compliance documents.  Form Toolbar The form toolbar includes standard buttons. For the list of standard buttons, see  Form Toolbar. Custom Attributes Tab On this tab, you can specify custom attributes for each type of the compliance         document. Table Toolbar The table toolbar includes standard buttons and buttons specific to this table. For           the list of standard buttons, see  Table Toolbar.           The table-specific buttons are listed below. Button Description Attribute The menu containing the list of predefined attributes for compliance documents.                   The following attributes are allowed: Certificate : The type of the compliance document. Insurance : The type of the compliance document. Lien Waiver : The type of the compliance document. Notice : The type of the compliance document. Status : The status of the compliance document. Table Columns Column Description Value The value of the attribute of the compliance document. The values entered for                 the  Certificate ,  Insurance ,  Lien Waiver  and  Notice                  attributes are used as the document type options. The values entered for the                    Status  attribute are used as statuses of the compliance document. Common Attributes Tab The table on this tab contains the list of attributes that can be assigned to compliance         documents. You can add or delete common attributes on this tab.  The table toolbar includes only standard buttons. For the list of standard buttons, see            Table Toolbar. Table Columns Column Description Attribute The name of the common attribute. Description The description of the common attribute. Required A check box that indicates (if selected) that the attribute is mandatory for                 the compliance document.  ([~/?ScreenId=CL401000|CL401000]) ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="91aa94f3-55e3-4753-8cc2-fd6d5960fbc3" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="1ec6780a-6eaa-b94f-b454-fac5fbc87140" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
With the variety of reports for the Subcontracts module, you can promptly get detailed information about the subcontracts and analyze the data by various criteria.((({S:Warn}
Because the Subcontracts reports are generated by user request, they run on only accounts and subaccounts that the user is authorized to access, based on the user’s roles and membership in restriction groups.
)))
All Subcontracts reports can be generated in different formats, including PDFs, and can be printed or sent by email. Some reports generated as PDFs require digital signatures; see [HelpRoot_Administration\SM__con_Site_Security_Options|Security Policies in Acumatica ERP] for more details. {br}

Before you use reports, see [HelpRoot_Interface\Report_Processing_Options|Reports] for more information. 
==Subcontracts Reports==[anchor|#_3fe83207-8208-4f2f-8364-65a46db2b79c]
*'''Forms'''
** [HelpRoot_Construction\SC_64_10_00|Subcontract] ([~/?ScreenId=SC641000|SC641000]): Displays the subcontracts created in the Subcontracts module; you can print and email them.
*'''Audit'''
** [HelpRoot_Construction\SC_61_05_00|Subcontract Summary] ([~/?ScreenId=SC610500|SC610500]): For the date range you select, shows summary information about subcontracts that are neither closed nor canceled.
**[HelpRoot_Construction\SC_61_10_00|Subcontract Details by Vendor] ([~/?ScreenId=SC611000|SC611000]): For the date range you select, displays detailed information about subcontracts that are neither closed nor canceled. The data in this report is grouped by vendor.
]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Construction Reports With the variety of reports for the Subcontracts module, you can promptly get detailed         information about the subcontracts and analyze the data by various criteria. Because the Subcontracts reports are generated by user request, they run on only accounts           and subaccounts that the user is authorized to access, based on the user’s roles and           membership in restriction groups. All Subcontracts reports can be generated in different formats, including PDFs, and can be         printed or sent by email. Some reports generated as PDFs require digital signatures; see            Security Policies in Acumatica ERP for more details.  Before you use reports, see  Reports for more information.  Subcontracts Reports Forms  ([~/?ScreenId=SC641000|SC641000]) Subcontract (SC641000): Displays the subcontracts created in the               Subcontracts module; you can print and email them. Audit  ([~/?ScreenId=SC610500|SC610500]) Subcontract Summary (SC610500): For the date range you select, shows summary               information about subcontracts that are neither closed nor canceled.  ([~/?ScreenId=SC611000|SC611000]) Subcontract Details by Vendor (SC611000): For the date range you select, displays               detailed information about subcontracts that are neither closed nor canceled. The data               in this report is grouped by vendor. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="3000c072-3414-4a6c-a51b-64f7d3c9cb4c" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" Content="&#xA;Form ID:  ([~/?ScreenId=SC641000|SC641000]){br}&#xA;&#xA;By using this report, you can look through, print, and email the subcontracts created in the Subcontracts module. You can select a reference number of the particular subcontract you want to view.{br}&#xA;&#xA;The subcontracts are displayed as they will be printed.{br}&#xA;&#xA;See below for a description of each parameter on the '''Report Parameters''' tab. For more information about using other elements on the report form, see [HelpRoot_Interface\Report_Processing_Options|Reports].&#xA;==Report Parameters==&#xA;On the '''Report Parameters''' tab, use the following parameter to select the information to be displayed on the report:[anchor|#_a71b2731-6162-4c60-947e-ccc31e2db63f]&#xA;*'''Subcontract Number''': The number of the subcontract to be displayed. Select a number of the subcontract for which you want to build the report.&#xA;" PlainText="Subcontract Form ID:  (SC641000)  ([~/?ScreenId=SC641000|SC641000])By using this report, you can look through, print, and email the subcontracts created in         the Subcontracts module. You can select a reference number of the particular subcontract you         want to view. The subcontracts are displayed as they will be printed. See below for a description of each parameter on the  Report Parameters  tab. For more         information about using other elements on the report form, see  Reports. Report Parameters On the  Report Parameters  tab, use the following parameter to select the information         to be displayed on the report: Subcontract Number : The number of the subcontract to be displayed. Select a           number of the subcontract for which you want to build the report. " ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="5bfedac5-1b8f-c115-fb88-8461a162b350" RecordSourceID="22377" />
		<row PageID="a9348a1c-337d-46e5-9d9f-9b9b1c1f84d2" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="3f732547-1537-780b-34c9-a93c117117d1" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
Form ID:  ([~/?ScreenId=SC610500|SC610500]){br}

For a particular date range, this report shows summary information about the subcontracts that are neither closed nor canceled. The information presented for each subcontract includes the reference number, subcontract date, status, currency, vendor ID and name, ordered quantity, open quantity, line total, and open amount. The report also includes total values (for all subcontracts included in the report) for the ordered quantity, open quantity, line total, and open amount.{br}

See below for a description of each parameter on the '''Report Parameters''' tab. For more information about using other elements on the report form, see [HelpRoot_Interface\Report_Processing_Options|Reports].
==Report Parameters==
On the '''Report Parameters''' tab, use the following parameters to select the information to be displayed on the report:[anchor|#_2bcbb541-831b-479f-9a58-71e1cb87afb2]
*'''Start Date''': The start date of the date range to be reported on. A start date must be selected.
*'''End Date''': The end date of the date range; an end date must be selected. Only the subcontracts having dates that fall within the specified interval will be included in the report.
*'''Vendor ID''': The vendor for which you want to view subcontract information, by its ID. You can select a vendor to view only subcontracts created for this vendor, or leave the box blank to view a broader range of data.
*'''Inventory ID''': The non-stock item for which you want to view subcontract information. Select the ID of the non-stock to view only subcontracts created for purchasing this item.
]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Subcontract Summary Form ID:  (SC610500)  ([~/?ScreenId=SC610500|SC610500])For a particular date range, this report shows summary information about the subcontracts         that are neither closed nor canceled. The information presented for each subcontract         includes the reference number, subcontract date, status, currency, vendor ID and name,         ordered quantity, open quantity, line total, and open amount. The report also includes total         values (for all subcontracts included in the report) for the ordered quantity, open         quantity, line total, and open amount. See below for a description of each parameter on the  Report Parameters  tab. For more         information about using other elements on the report form, see  Reports. Report Parameters On the  Report Parameters  tab, use the following parameters to select the information         to be displayed on the report: Start Date : The start date of the date range to be reported on. A start date must           be selected. End Date : The end date of the date range; an end date must be selected. Only the           subcontracts having dates that fall within the specified interval will be included in the           report. Vendor ID : The vendor for which you want to view subcontract information, by its           ID. You can select a vendor to view only subcontracts created for this vendor, or leave           the box blank to view a broader range of data. Inventory ID : The non-stock item for which you want to view subcontract           information. Select the ID of the non-stock to view only subcontracts created for           purchasing this item. ]]></column>
		</row>
		<row PageID="a632390b-20fc-44f5-86f0-d2d650b5a85e" Language="en-US" PageRevisionID="1" ApprovalByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" ApprovalDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" CreatedByID="b5344897-037e-4d58-b5c3-1bdfd0f47bf9" CreatedDateTime="1970-01-23 00:00:00" UID="1340bc71-cdcd-941b-9f69-c78ac5500f90" RecordSourceID="22377">
			<column name="Content"><![CDATA[
Form ID:  ([~/?ScreenId=SC611000|SC611000]){br}

For a particular date range, this report displays detailed information about subcontracts that are neither closed nor canceled. The data in the report is grouped by the vendors for which the subcontracts were created.{br}

See below for a description of each parameter on the '''Report Parameters''' tab. For more information about using other elements on the report form, see [HelpRoot_Interface\Report_Processing_Options|Reports].
==Report Parameters==
On the '''Report Parameters''' tab, use the following parameters to select the information to be displayed on the report:[anchor|#_3c87c6d9-6a9a-430c-8306-65cf2a23b30f]
*'''Start Date''': The start date of the date range of the report; a start date must be specified.
*'''End Date''': The end date of the date range; a date must be specified here as well. Only subcontracts having dates that fall within the specified interval will be included in the report.
*'''Vendor ID''': The vendor for which you want to view subcontract information, by its ID. You can select a vendor to view only subcontracts created for this vendor, or leave the box blank to view a broader range of data.
*'''Inventory ID''': The non-stock item for which you want to view subcontract information. Select the inventory ID of the non-stock item to view only subcontracts created for purchasing this item.
]]></column>
			<column name="PlainText"><![CDATA[Subcontract Details by Vendor Form ID:  (SC611000)  ([~/?ScreenId=SC611000|SC611000])For a particular date range, this report displays detailed information about subcontracts         that are neither closed nor canceled. The data in the report is grouped by the vendors for         which the subcontracts were created. See below for a description of each parameter on the  Report Parameters  tab. For more         information about using other elements on the report form, see  Reports. Report Parameters On the  Report Parameters  tab, use the following parameters to select the information         to be displayed on the report: Start Date : The start date of the date range of the report; a start date must be           specified. End Date : The end date of the date range; a date must be specified here as well.           Only subcontracts having dates that fall within the specified interval will be included in           the report. Vendor ID : The vendor for which you want to view subcontract information, by its           ID. You can select a vendor to view only subcontracts created for this vendor, or leave           the box blank to view a broader range of data. Inventory ID : The non-stock item for which you want to view subcontract           information. Select the inventory ID of the non-stock item to view only subcontracts           created for purchasing this item. ]]></column>
		</row>
	</rows>
</data>